<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-04-18T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Rest as Good as a Change</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/04/18/rest-as-good-as-a-change/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/04/18/rest-as-good-as-a-change/</id>
    <published>2017-04-18T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-16T21:58:02+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="rest" src="/images/rest.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a week off over Easter.  I definitely needed it.  Particularly after the time change and the intensity of the NHS project, I just had to step away.  I seem to remember working through Easter and school half terms in the past, but it seems counter-productive now.  Quite an effort to get back into the swing of things today though.  We had a public holiday yesterday (Monday) and I ended up doing a half day on this and that, mainly writing up my phone meeting with a G.P. (UK doctor), planning, putting in a couple of funding requests and writing a draft business plan for the charity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My knee has been approved for jogging again, so I&amp;rsquo;m getting back into my morning run, and have switched round with my wife so she&amp;rsquo;s taking the twins to school in the morning.  If we&amp;rsquo;re going to deliver effectively on the NHS project and ensure we put in enough other funding requests for the long term then I need more work time.  Ironically it didn&amp;rsquo;t generate any more work time this morning as I fell asleep again after the alarm and I&amp;rsquo;m still sitting down to blog at the usual time.  Hopefully my body clock will be back to normal soon and I can squeeze out a few more work hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really did appreciate having a Monday without any meetings - it gave me time to sort out some goals for the week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;[ ] apply for other funding &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] City Bridge Trust - follow up would be electronic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Diana and Allan Morgenthau Charitable Trust - follow up would be by surface email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] apply for others in list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;[ ] generate next kind of solution for NHS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] get as much of their drupal site as we can &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Communications contact (phone? change manager?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] we need to move towards a new round of testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] finish writing up/distributing notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] legal support &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; business plan?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;[ ] follow up with Simon (after another review of the design sprint book)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;[ ] release next week of AV102 (fixes needed?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;[ ] some framework for premiums and mentors in AV &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] ask each mentor individually &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] ask each mentor individually about getting more involved following up with individual mentees &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;[ ] sort timings of scrums and weekly meetings &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Slack and email there are always a 1001 little admin things to do and questions to be answered.  My suspicion is that if I want AgileVentures to be something I can keep putting the majority of my time into, I have to prioritise doing those things that only I am in a position to do, e.g. taking the initiative putting in funding applications.  Our marketing intern Marufa took the initiative to find a site called &lt;a href="http://www.fundingcentral.org.uk/"&gt;Funding Central&lt;/a&gt; that lists potential funding opportunities for charities.  Before my break I did their guided search and came up with a handful of options.  On the last Friday of work I&amp;rsquo;d put together another funding proposal for an EU fund, but stupidly missed the deadline due to miscalculating the time difference with Europe.  They wouldn&amp;rsquo;t accept it after the deadline.  Here&amp;rsquo;s the proposal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1. Project title (10 words max).&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored IT &amp;amp; Software Development Mentorship for the Underprivileged&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;2. One-line introduction to your idea (140 characters max).&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donors provide sponsorship funds to support the mentorship of underprivileged individuals to improve their IT &amp;amp; software development skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3. Provide a summary of your idea highlighting how it relates to the theme ‘Equality Rebooted’, how it aims to make technological change/digital transformation more inclusive (100 words max).&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technological change and digital transformation relies on individuals from all walks of life having access to training and professional development in the skills of the new digital economy. Not everyone can afford professional mentorship, however a coordinated donor/sponsorship program can bring these benefits to anyone with an internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;4. Explain why your idea is innovative in the country or context where it will be implemented. If your idea is based on an existing concept, explain what is different about it (250 words max).&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our idea is innovative in as much as we are relying on the bare minimum of resources from the under-privileged individuals we are trying to support; simply time and internet connection. Mentorship and professional development are existing approaches used in industry, but are often unavailable to those with limited resources. Our idea works with funds from those more privileged individuals who want to give back to the community to help others get a leg up, and uses those funds to provide mentorship and professional development support to the under-privileged who are trying to make their way in the new digital economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;5. Describe clearly what impact you expect your idea to have and how you will achieve this (250 words max).&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact of our idea is a larger number of under-privileged individuals from a wider variety of backgrounds taking their place in the digital economy. Our approach will redress some of the inequalities currently seen in the digital workforce and will do so by pairing experienced mentors and professionals with under-privileged individuals to provide them with support and guidance on making use of the latest digital tools, and honing their skills according to a coherent professional development plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;6. Indicate at what scale your idea will operate initially and how it could be transferred to another area in Europe or scaled up at a national and/or European level in the future (200 words max).&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently working with U.S. based funders to provide mentorship and professional development support from U.K. based mentors to under-privileged individuals in Kenya and India. We also currently have volunteer U.S. and U.K. based mentors working with individuals in Slovenia, Sweden, Ukraine, Tunisia and various other countries. We would very much like funds to reach out to more potential sponsors and donors to put more of our volunteer efforts on a more sustainable footing. So far we have a 3000 member organisation being supported by a dozen professional mentors. In principle there is no limit to the scale at which we can operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;7. Outline how your idea could become financially sustainable over the next three years (200 words max).&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our operation relies on input from donors, corporate sponsorship, premium membership and contracts with non-profits, charities, government and businesses with a commitment to social responsibility. We are currently covering costs, but relying heavily on volunteer input. We currently have three donors, three corporate sponsors and fifty premium members, which is covering all our IT hosting and support costs, but not any staff costs. Our plan is to double the current income through these various methods in the next 6 months in order to start to employ staff to ensure there is consistent and reliable support for all our mentors and mentees. Funding from Equality Rebooted would very much increase the chances of us succeeding in our sustainability goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knocked out the above on the train into London for a day of wiki usability testing at NHS headquarters.  I&amp;rsquo;m not saying it&amp;rsquo;s of any serious quality, but I can generate text like that to order.  All the plans and ideas for AgileVentures bubble in my mind.  It was disappointing to miss the deadline by 30 minutes, but that energized me to take some of the above prose and use that to make a couple of email submissions to funding bodies I had found in the &lt;a href="http://www.fundingcentral.org.uk/"&gt;Funding Central&lt;/a&gt; site.  Doing that allowed me to tick off a couple of items on the weekly todo list, and I pushed forward to create a &lt;a href="https://www.agileventures.org/business-plan"&gt;draft business plan&lt;/a&gt; that might help us unlock pro-bono legal support, and maybe serve as a banner to rally the team around.  I also started reaching out to our mentors to see if they were interested in AV sponsoring their training for Agile/Scrum certificates. The Premium subscriptions seem to have plateaued, although they may start to rise again with the new MOOC and change in season, and there&amp;rsquo;s already some upgrades going on.  I suspect that I need to engage the other mentors more directly with the larger body of Premium members, and then focus my resources on supporting the mentors &amp;hellip; maybe?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment the business plan has this list of opportunities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay for mentors to receive additional training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay mentors explicitly for time mentoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve onboarding experience to increase numbers signing up for Premium membership (CRM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional outreach for contracts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional outreach for grants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to improve the whole onboarding for new members, but if we do have a spike in Premiums we will need mentors ready to handle it.  I&amp;rsquo;m getting to my limit of being able to keep up, particularly if I&amp;rsquo;m taking the lead on delivering contracts like the one we have with the NHS.  Let&amp;rsquo;s see what we can get done in the next six week chunk before my next &amp;lsquo;rest&amp;rsquo; :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NHS Design Sprint Day Six</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/31/nhs-design-sprint-day-six/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/31/nhs-design-sprint-day-six/</id>
    <published>2017-03-31T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-15T22:20:35+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Friday I had an intense day of meetings at NHS headquarters.  At the beginning of the week I had been suggesting to the change manager that Friday would be a day of prototype testing.  They&amp;rsquo;d arranged a series of meetings&amp;ndash;three in person, two phone calls.  Skype wasn&amp;rsquo;t working behind the NHS firewall, and due to the stop/start part-time nature of the whole thing it was clear that we were not going to have completed all the parts of the design sprint and got to testable prototypes for Friday.  The reality was that we were still doing expert interviews, and so I used the Friday to continue that process with five different stakeholders; specifically an NHS public champion, a CCG meta-commissioner, an HLP staff member, a service provider and an academic researcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took notes on all and recorded the in person meetings, but there wasn&amp;rsquo;t time to really digest in between sessions, which had a max 30 minutes intervals; during which time we were usually required to switch to a different room in the building due to the complicated NHS room booking system.  In small gaps in between the meetings, I started to get the change manager set up with a Slack for Healthy London Partnership (HLP), added HLP to the Wikipedia page on London Health Care, discovered there is no wikipedia page on Social Prescribing, failed to follow up with the lawyers on pro bono legal advice, and discovered that HLP is not a registered charity.  We also got a sketch of the following week&amp;rsquo;s plan in place, but the preponderance of phone offers made it look like if we were doing any usability studies it would be with HLP staff members rather than the other stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued the process of showing the experts our A3 sheets with the long term goal, how we might fail and implementation maps.  The public champion added the phrase &amp;ldquo;Self Informing Community Commissioning&amp;rdquo; to our long term goal, and I took notes on a new A3 sheet of all the additional ways they suggested we might fail, e.g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the different stakeholders operating in silos, and so we lose information that might help us achieve critical mass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small pilots with artificial communities difficult to get to work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commissioners scared of (funding?) groups without governance and insurance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(NHS?) System not set up to commission self prescribing/social brokering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fear from existing workforce that their jobs will go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voluntary sector scared by austerity and so avoid collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That we don&amp;rsquo;t learn from the social care (social brokering) experiment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One things that&amp;rsquo;s becoming very clear is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to get people to focus exclusively on how we might fail without them suggesting possible solutions, such as using wiki coordination to provide umbrellas for governance.  The public champion also pointed out that social prescription could be seen as just a re-branding of social brokering, something that had been promoted in the local authority context, but had been cut due to austerity measures over the last 10 years.  There&amp;rsquo;s a narrative here that suggests cuts to what could be considered &amp;ldquo;preventative&amp;rdquo; services have lead to increasing demand on frontline health care services that the NHS supports.  I showed the champion our implementation maps, indicating some of the different funding frameworks, and they explained the different &amp;ldquo;funding trousers&amp;rdquo; of health care and social care, and then drew their own map with a different funding model:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Public champion funding map" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/8nq3xdyv9027kaw/PublicChampion-map.JPG?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &amp;ldquo;IAGs&amp;rdquo; are &amp;ldquo;Information, Advice and Guidance&amp;rdquo; services.  The public champion had built their own social brokering site using DotNetNuke called the &lt;a href="http://www.londonbrokeragenetwork.com/"&gt;&amp;ldquo;London Brokerage Network&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.  The site is a paid members site which contains listings of different organisations providing advice and support services in London.  No sooner than we&amp;rsquo;d finished talking to the public champion, we were off to a new room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our new location we settled down for a phone call with a Senior Strategy Manager (Out of Hospital and Primary Care) for the SouthWest London region.  This was a new kind of stakeholder that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with, someone with a remit over multiple CCGs, who told us that in SW London the different CCGs were very interested in social prescribing and self-care, but they were currently using ad hoc programs derived from disparate funding initiatives.  The different SW London CCGs were apparently very interested to know more about what funding models were available to support social prescribing.  I asked about methods for information sharing and knowledge gathering and heard how the focus was on meetings and discussions at monthly intervals.  The tools used for sharing digitally tend to be the MS Office usual suspects, and Sharepoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No sooner were we off the phone than I was talking with another HLP staff member who was going to take over as the new &amp;ldquo;change manager&amp;rdquo;.  We looked together at the various implementation maps that we&amp;rsquo;d generated and they reacted strongly saying that we could look at a different model with lots of new stakeholders:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="HLP change manager funding map" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/167lb2jnu59vbig/HLP-change-manager-map.JPG?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was interested to get input on online services that HLP staff used and/or liked.  The new change manager told me that they quite liked the &lt;a href="http://clashofclans.wikia.com/wiki/Clash_of_Clans_Wiki"&gt;Clash of Clans wiki&lt;/a&gt;.  The outgoing change manager said that they personaly liked the BBC news web site.  After lunch we met a social prescribing service provider who was running an active social prescribing service in 8 G.P.&amp;rsquo;s offices.  The SP service provider was less interested in the funding, but gave us great specifics about the program taking place in their area and how they brokered between individual patients and community resources; from which I drew another map, but I think that will have to go in the next blog along with what I heard from the change manager about the &amp;ldquo;social prescribing network&amp;rdquo; and what we learnt speaking to an academic researcher who had been involved in running the evaluation study for the Hackney Social Prescribing system.  &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NHS Design Sprint Day Five</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/31/nhs-design-sprint-day-five/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/31/nhs-design-sprint-day-five/</id>
    <published>2017-03-31T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-11T21:47:53+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I worked from my home office and had a phone call with a CCG commissioner.  We tried Skype, but it seemed like the NHS firewall was blocking us again. We switched to iPhone FaceTime and we were able to speak eye to eye and I was able to show a few of our sketches, but it was basically just the phone.  I&amp;rsquo;m starting to get the impression that NHS work seems to involve a lot of phone calls.  I was speaking to a CCG Commissioner working in Hackney where they are running a social-prescribing service.  I talked them through the long term goals from our Design Sprint which they concurred with and added a note that patient activation is also a key challenge. I take this to mean getting patients to take the initiative for self-care and asking for social-prescribing (or taking up the suggestions of a social prescription provider).  The commissioner also mentioned that it can be difficult to evidence outcomes, e.g. reduction of demand on G.P.s or changes in levels of anxiety and depression for patients, partly because it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to measure, but also because these schemes take time to have an impact.  Apparently a &lt;a href="http://www.health.org.uk/programmes/shine-2014/projects/social-prescribing-integrating-gp-and-community-health-assets"&gt;recent independent evaluation&lt;/a&gt; has not shown significant changes in health outcomes, although qualitative interviews indicated a very positive participant experience.  The report includes some interview recordings which you can see here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align='center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PCxRLAM7wBQ"&gt;&lt;img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/PCxRLAM7wBQ/0.jpg" alt="Hackney Social Prescribing Interviews" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commissioner and I reviewed our team&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;How Might We Fail&amp;rdquo; notes together, and they concurred and added another problem that we might be competing with existing systems, such as directories of services already created by local authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked how Hackney came to have a Social Prescribing (SP) model and was told that there was a vibrant voluntary sector in Hackney and lots of very proactive G.P.s. Apparently CCGs tend to follow the clinicians lead, and so initiatives from doctors make all the difference.  Hackney CCG did a tender for setting up social prescribing and got a service provider to implement it for them.  I asked for more detail on where the original initiative came from, but since the commissioner had started after the program began we couldn&amp;rsquo;t be sure of the original source of the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commissioner also mentioned that SP has quite a high profile nationally - that it&amp;rsquo;s in all the NHS STPs (Sustainability and Transformation Plans) and in all the five year forward views.  I showed our implementation maps (over iPhone FaceTime) and the comissioner concurred with our diagrams; I mentioned Steve&amp;rsquo;s Capable Communities initiative in Harrow which got funding for SP by pulling down money from central government via the local authority and the commissioner indicated that sometimes local authority funding might actually be a better fit for SP.  Another possibility mentioned was social impact bonds, and the concern that some commissioners might have that maybe SP shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a core concern for a health care coordinator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commissioner indicated that the key is the community sector and that there was still debate at a national level about whether SP should be gate kept by GPs or would it work better with a model of self-referral.  Apparently &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Dixon_(doctor)"&gt;Michael Dixon&lt;/a&gt; is the clinical lead for SP at the national level and he is very aligned with the GP model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked the commissioner how they gathered and received information to inform the decision making processes.  The commissioner indicated it was very helpful to reach out to service providers and service users and to speak to individuals.  Asking public health individuals to go and gather evidence was helpful and that they spent time reading and researching with access to academic papers (e.g. via &amp;ldquo;openathens&amp;rdquo; which all NHS staff can access), googling things, looking up evidence based research, attending events and conferences.  I asked if they used any digital support such as writing up notes on what they&amp;rsquo;d read in Word, and was told that it was more of just saving relevant files and keeping a folder of research papers on particular subjects so that a good context would be in mind to inform decision making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comissioner also mentioned that neighbouring CCGs would call to ask about how to implement SP, indicating that peer sharing was an important mechanism.  Neighbouring CCGs would often have quite specific questions, and that the comissioner might send them outcome summaries or service specifications for their own SP implementation to give them help in understanding what to do.  Apparently these are not public documents per se, and might have commercially sensitive information that SP service providers would not want shared, since they might be competing for other CCG tenders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked the commissioner if they would be interested in using the proposed wiki solution, which they would, although they didn&amp;rsquo;t usually contribute to online resources like wikipedia.  The commissioners usual tools are apparently Word, Excel and email and of course lots of face to face communication and phone.  The commissioner indicated that, if they were to be using such an online wiki, that they&amp;rsquo;d probably need prompting (the commissioner gave an example of some other system where they got an email once every six months), and that, based on what other CCGs asked, that something like a FAQ or top-tips would be appreciated, e.g. the five key things you have to have in place to set up SP in your area, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commissioner indicated that they would be willing to try out some demo versions of our system in the next few weeks, and I had a lot to think about.  This process of phone calls without access to Skype or Hangouts was going to mean that we couldn&amp;rsquo;t do any usability testing with the majority of the people that the HLP change manager was reaching out to.  It was already Thursday and at least half the people booked for Friday were going to be contacting us by phone.   Thursday is supposed to be the day of the design Sprint where we generate a prototype for testing on Friday, but we were still completing expert interviews that are supposed to be completed on day one.  It was clear to me that Friday was going to just be more expert interviews and the design sprint was going to have to be split over two weeks, if not more &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.health.org.uk/programmes/shine-2014/projects/social-prescribing-integrating-gp-and-community-health-assets"&gt;independent evaluation of Hackney Social Prescribing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Dixon_(doctor)"&gt;NHS Lead on Social Prescribing: Michael Dixon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NHS Design Sprint Day Four</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/30/nhs-design-sprint-day-four/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/30/nhs-design-sprint-day-four/</id>
    <published>2017-03-30T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-10T22:02:02+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m getting a bit punch drunk keeping up with all the different AgileVentures projects and driving the NHS design sprint forward at the same time, as well as doing all the admin and legal stuff to get the NHS contracts all sorted before the end of the financial year, which is tomorrow.  I&amp;rsquo;ve just about managed to stay on top of the LocalSupport project, but my check ins on the AsyncVoter and Redeemify projects did little more than serve to remind me of the places we are blocked, or I am blocking things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Redeemify we&amp;rsquo;re stuck with CodeClimate not working on our pull requests, and no production environment setup.  On AsyncVoter we need to complete the move from Digital Ocean to Azure hosting.  I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to empower some new project managers with greater devops rights to move those projects forward.  On the NHS project we&amp;rsquo;d wrapped up Tuesday starting to work through with the change manager on some of the different hosted wiki platforms.  The idea is that this was part of the design sprint day two &amp;ldquo;lightning demos&amp;rdquo; where we look at great solutions from a range of companies.  Ideally every member of the sprint team would be bringing examples from a wide range of sources and industries.  I can ask the change manager to prepare some going forward, but here&amp;rsquo;s where the lack of members in our sprint team is a real handicap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least over the remainder of Tuesday and then during Wednesday morning on Skype we managed to review a good 10 or so hosted wiki solutions.  We paused briefly Wednesday morning to get the timeline straight for the project and the next few days.  The original &amp;ldquo;tender&amp;rdquo; had included an aggressive timeline, but our selection as vendor had been delayed.  The change manager and I came up with this adjusted timeline based on that delay and the upcoming public holidays:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;27th March - Work begins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5th April - Prototype developed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6th-7th; 18th April - Prototype tested&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;19th-27th April - User feedback incorporated into wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4th May - wiki is live with moderation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not clear what the outside constraints are that are driving this timetable.  Talking with the decider it seems there is a need to deliver something fast to help the folks on the ground (commissioners, GPs, patients, carers).  I&amp;rsquo;m concerned that if one wants to grow a successful community around a technological solution like a wiki then one needs to grow it slowly.  Rushing forward to a public launch of something increases the risk of long-term failure, but these are apparently the time/resource constraints, and we are a &amp;ldquo;can-do&amp;rdquo; bunch of folks, so we will do our best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked at eleven different wiki hosting services including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikispaces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikidot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tettra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Socialtext&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PBWorks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ourproject.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nuclino&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eXoCloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confluence Hosted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked through the first few with the change manager driving.  Here&amp;rsquo;s us trying to add comments to a wikispaces wiki:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="failing to see added comments on wikispaces wiki" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/hn9zulbam61b4pp/Screenshot%202017-03-30%2010.19.20.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where we were able to create a wiki, but for some reason our posted comments would not show up.   As we moved through the different solutions, I started to see a pattern emerging in terms of a kind of activity script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit the page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a heading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add (and resize) an image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a comment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discussions so far had made it clear to me that HLP staff were also key end-users of the imagined solution, so seeing the change manager (an HLP staff member) trying to navigate these wiki environments was very interesting.  We were getting blocked from signing up to some of the solutions as I couldn&amp;rsquo;t receive my email over the NHS wireless, but we were able to try Tettra, which had a really nice clean interface, reminiscent of the medium blogging tool:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tettra's interface, reminiscent of the medium blogging tool" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/88nk1nwpyvdc4lm/Screenshot%202017-03-30%2010.23.22.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we continued with me remote at my home office over Skype with the change manager at NHS headquarters.  We tried wikidot where we found that the process of adding an image was somewhat laborious.  We went back to Tettra to see how adding an image was there and it was pretty straightforward.  Next we tried PbWorks, where the interface was a little busier than Tettra, but there was good support for re-sizing an image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Resized image with PbWorks" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/74xnvyany1dzhxm/Screenshot%202017-03-31%2009.22.30.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moved on to Atlassian&amp;rsquo;s wiki confluence, which I was familiar with from my programming background.  I quite liked it, but I sensed that the interface might be a bit busy, given its usual target audience of tech specialists and programmers.  The problem here was also that I was interacting with the interfaces, and the change manager was just watching over Skype, unlike the day before when I&amp;rsquo;d been seeing him trying to manage the interfaces himself.  I consoled myself that this was all still really just us doing lightning demos.  We were trying to bring some of the possible alternatives into our minds, rather than conducting usability tests per se:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Atlassian's Confluence wiki" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/pbauj6vdnw45jy9/Screenshot%202017-03-31%2009.19.54.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also tried Nuclino which had a nice interface following the approach popularised by the Medium blog that Tettra also seemed to follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="the Nuclino wiki" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/9wzt2ogq6xdqlpl/Screenshot%202017-03-31%2009.19.14.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the ExoPlatform system we got quite lost in the interface and couldn&amp;rsquo;t work out how to even make an editable wiki.  We tried iMeet and Wikia.  On iMeet we didn&amp;rsquo;t get past creating a workspace (I note they&amp;rsquo;ve been pinging me every couple of days since, with their best shots at drip emails).  And the sign up process in Wikia took a while and ended up getting left in the background. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s more we could be looking at.  It was frustrating that we lost half an hour to trying Skype and Hangouts at the beginning of my remote day.  The NHS firewall appears to block Skype and maybe hangouts.  When I saw Brendan&amp;rsquo;s laptop the next day, it seemed like it might just have been wifi connectivity issues that could have been solved by plugging into a hard LAN cable.  The setup at NHS headquarters is interesting.  Open plan offices with flat screen tvs showing the BBC news channel.  Lots of meeting rooms with no computers in.  Staff work at their computers in the open plan office, but then generally seem to leave their computers to go meet in rooms where they can have discucssions without disturbing their co-workers.  Or make phone calls where they can only talk, but not show.  I would find it extraordinarily frustratingto be in meetings and discussions in the absence of the digital tools (the laptops) where you can really show each other things or collaborate on specifics.  Some meeting rooms appear to have sophisticated remote meeting systems in them, which is ironic when they could be using Skype or Hangouts, although of course there will be security and support constraints that the the NHS must adhere to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see that a large government organisation would be inclined to pay for a &amp;ldquo;it just works&amp;rdquo; secure remote meeting system, when Skype and Hangouts require a fair amount of technical know how and support.  Naturally NHS England will be very concerned about the security of all their systems.  It&amp;rsquo;s just a funnily different world than I&amp;rsquo;m used to where the computer is the primary conduit for both work and conversation.  The HLP team had been interested when I&amp;rsquo;d shown them Slack the previous day.  Perhaps through working together there can be some side-benefits via me introducing the team to some digital tools and practices that they aren&amp;rsquo;t yet familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big question now of course is how to continue the Sprint?  We were getting out lightning demos done, which was supposed to by the morning of day two, but we hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen the majority of our experts, and we needed to make time for sketching possible solutions; although I was questioning whether that made sense since the budget constraints required us to pick from existing solutions &amp;hellip; find out how we handled it all in tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s blog!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NHS Design Sprint Day Three</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/29/nhs-design-sprint-day-three/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/29/nhs-design-sprint-day-three/</id>
    <published>2017-03-29T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-10T21:42:21+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I realise that the sequencing on these sprint blogs is kind of off kilter, since I&amp;rsquo;m writing the blog on the morning of a given design sprint day, and actually talking about what happened the previous day :-/  Also, the normal five day design sprint schedule is being mashed into the available time, so let&amp;rsquo;s relax and go with the flow :-) Yesterday was Tuesday and I was down at NHS headquarters again.  In the last blog we&amp;rsquo;d left it with me trying to work out whether to continue the day 1 sprint activities into day 2 in order to complete them, or just drop them and move onto the official day 2 activities.  Remaining from day one were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Ask the experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Generate &amp;ldquo;How Might We &amp;hellip;?&amp;rdquo; notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Organise notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Vote on notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Pick target&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a meeting room from 10:30am-2:00pm, and I was just pondering what to do, when we were joined by two other members of the Healthy London Partnership team.  Serendipitously this seemed to match perfectly with continuing the day one agenda of asking the experts.  It would have been great to have all of these folks involved in the entire Sprint, but since that wasn&amp;rsquo;t possible, getting their input on the Goal, Risks and Maps that the change manager and I had generated the previous day would be critical.  We had time for our experts to introduce themselves and explain their roles in the organisation, when the &amp;ldquo;Decider&amp;rdquo; joined us and we flowed into showing the full team what we had generated the previous day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change manager and I had struggled with a good summary sentence of the overall goal the previous day, but the decider nailed it immediately with &amp;ldquo;Empowering people and enabling communities to take control&amp;rdquo;.  We seemed to be on the same page as far as the high level goal was concerned.  We talked the group through the risks, which they concurred with, and they added some more, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience of system is poor or too cluttered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Policy fatigue on the part of the Comissioners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of future enthusiasm from government on SP/SC initiatives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential contributors put off by concerns about legal status of contributions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and another from the change manager having reflected overnight that politics with a small &amp;ldquo;p&amp;rdquo; might be a problem, e.g. if contributors used any system we developed as a platform for excessive criticism of existing solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we took the group through the diagrams we had generated the previous day, which was particularly revealing.  As I explained the way that a commissioner who had been convinced to implement SP/SC might put out a tender to get bids from multiple SP service providers, the decider indicated that maybe it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a competitive process.  Maybe it would work better if it was collaborative.  He also pointed out that G.P.s and Patients/Carers could be ambassadors for the programs.  Patients and Carers could be petitioning G.P.s to use social prescribing in their areas, leading to G.P.s to petition Commissioners. And indeed it could be the Service Providers and Community Resource Providers who were collaborating to petition the commissioners, along with the G.P.s.  I added in arrows for these potential interactions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Social Prescription Implementation Map Updated with more input" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ikj26czyg78kf2r/updated_map.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly I got even more feedback on different models showing the diagram to Steve of Capable Communities that evening.  He&amp;rsquo;s managed to draw down money from central government to implement a Social Prescribing system in my local area (Harrow) without having to go through the process of convincing the commissioners at the CCG to release funds for the program.  He&amp;rsquo;s now working with the CCG and the local G.P.s, but brought the funds in by collaborating with the local authority.  Fascinating how these box and arrow diagrams can draw out the different perspectives on a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The diagram focusing on how the commissioner interacts with the materials and information drew out more from the decider on what makes up a commissioner&amp;rsquo;s day and when they might get a chance to actually use a wiki.  In addition, while commissioners might be the gatekeepers to unlocking funding, participation from the G.P.s was essential, and so ultimately any system would have to be meeting the needs of a much wider range of stakeholders to help SP/SC become a long term success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the team had to go on to other work, so that left the change manager and I, and I pushed us through the remaining activities.  Again it would have been great for more of the team to be involved, but we did our best; generating &amp;ldquo;How Might We &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; questions on post it notes, arranging them in categories on the wall, and then voting on them and placing them on the maps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Categorised &amp;quot;How Might We&amp;quot; post-it notes" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/j5yn7r0l78vnovc/hmw_notes_on_wall_portrait.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="&amp;quot;How Might We&amp;quot; notes added to implementation map" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/htsfa2h1zy7sy9x/hmw_on_maps_portrait.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was slightly artificial and I was realising that ideally we&amp;rsquo;d have had the input of a lot more experts (G.P.s, Patient Champions, Commissioners etc.) before doing this &amp;ldquo;HMW&amp;rdquo; phase, but we were working within the constraints we had.  Either way it seemed clear we were targetting a system that had to be transparent in terms of usability of finding relevant information and editing it.  It also seemed to me that part of the problem we were solving was just creating a framework for the HLP organisation itself to manage its information and resources in collaboration with a wider group of stakeholders.  If we could start with something that worked for HLP, we&amp;rsquo;d be half the way there, so I sat down with the change manager and started looking at different online wiki solutions together, recording the process using a quicktime screen recording.  More on those in tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s blog!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NHS Design Sprint Day Two</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/28/nhs-design-sprint-day-two/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/28/nhs-design-sprint-day-two/</id>
    <published>2017-03-28T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-08T22:31:57+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I was heading into London for the second day in a row to continue our impromptu design sprint with the Healthy London Partnership (HLP).  According to the Google Ventures book on the subject, &amp;ldquo;Day One&amp;rdquo; of a design sprint consists of the following elements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Set long term goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] List sprint questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Make a map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Ask the experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Generate &amp;ldquo;How Might We &amp;hellip;?&amp;rdquo; notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Organise notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Vote on notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Pick target&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sequence of events is designed to fit in a period from 10:00am to 4:30pm on a single day with a few breaks and an hour for lunch.  Actually there&amp;rsquo;s a fair bit of preparation before you can get started on day one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Choose a big challenge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Get a Decider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Recruit a Sprint Team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Schedule extra Experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Pick a facilitator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Block off five calendar days for whole team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Book a room with two whiteboards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge had already been set, of trying to increase the chances that Social Prescription and Self Care programs would be rolled out in many locations in London to benefit the health of individuals and communities while helping to control the rising cost of healthcare.  The team lead, who I&amp;rsquo;d met on Friday was the decider, but he was extraordinarily busy, and so had appointed his change manager as his delegate.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t realistic to grab a full week of anyone else&amp;rsquo;s time, so the sprint team was going to be the change manager and myself, as facilitator.  If we were doing a Sprint by the book, we&amp;rsquo;d have more people involved for the week and would have scheduled extra experts to be available to talk to on the Monday, but this was all at short notice and we were planning and doing in quick succession.  The change manager had reached out to people via email on Friday, and already had interest from 8 different people, but they were going to be a mixed bag of people who could talk either only on the phone or people who could come to the HLP offices in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggested that we try and split folks into experts and testers, and those who were only available electronically would give expert input at the beginning of the week, while those who could come in person could test the prototypes that we would generate by the end of the week.  We had a room with two whiteboards, but there was information we couldn&amp;rsquo;t rub off on one, and the wrong kinds of pens, so ultimately we ended up going with sheets of A3 paper as we tried to knock off as much of day one as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Long Term Goal" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/4tkxujc3bd75w25/long_term_goal_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our long term goal didn&amp;rsquo;t boil down into a wonderfully pithy statement, but the change manager and I seemed to be speaking the same language about what the project might want to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We generated two pages of &amp;ldquo;how might we fail&amp;rdquo; notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="How we might fail (1)" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/iaty72ys9211fe2/how_might_we_fail_one_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="How we might fail (2)" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/wen8yxuct4wq5tw/how_might_we_fail_two_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was doing a lot of writing, and the change manager was throwing out lots of ideas - I was adding mine in too.  We had the cart a little before the horse in the sense that we were already stacked towards thinking about a wiki solution that was proposed in the project tender, but either way I was definitely improving my understanding of how Clinical Commissioning Groups (CCGs) worked within the NHS in order to allocate resources for healthcare.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moved on to map-making, identifying key stakeholders.  The first map had a lot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patient (&amp;amp; Carer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commissioner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HLP Researcher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HLP Implementor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patient Champion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community Resource Provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Prescription Service provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;G.P.s (General Practitioners &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; U.K. doctors)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="First Stakeholder Map" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/dgicpsrce70xfze/map_one_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which we pruned back in a second version:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Second Stakeholder Map" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/62v1nl8vjb7ktva/map_two_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We identified the key component of the point of influencing the commissioners, and dove in deeper on that in another map that focused on just an HLP researcher and the commissioner as stakeholders, and what it would take to have the commissioner become aware of the material, absorb information from it and then actually take action:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="HLP Researcher and Commissioner Map" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/pslia27srgxazwg/map_three_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we ended up with a fourth diagram assuming that other stakeholders could participate in the creation of the materials, which pulled in another Stakeholder - a moderator:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Extended Commissioner influence Map" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/fjvqqyqb906v5q9/map_four_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brendan and I seemed to be making good progress, at least in terms of me better understanding the complexities of the interactions between the different stakeholders.  Given a stronger sprint structure we would now have our experts on tap to come in and be interviewed, talked through our high level goals, notes on how we might fail and associated maps.  However we were still in the process of booking our experts, and our time in the room had ended, so we called that a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the rest of the afternoon catching up with email, and putting out feelers for legal advice on the project&amp;rsquo;s terms &amp;amp; conditions.  I&amp;rsquo;d like to have digitalised all the notes and maps, but there wasn&amp;rsquo;t time, and the big question going in for day two was how were we going to fit the different components of the design sprint into the rest of the week.  Should we split day one over two days? Jump straight to day two?  Find out what we did in tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s blog! :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
