<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>All Good Things ...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/</id>
    <published>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-10T21:54:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="good things" src="/images/good_things.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been daily blogging for a year now.  Working day blogs that is.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging on weekends, or national holidays, or during my vacations.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty consistent.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of days where work was super busy due to the tail end of a design sprint or something, but I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to retro-actively blog and keep it one per work day.  I started blogging in June last year doing a blog on a different platform each day of the week, but fairly soon I fell into a pattern of blogging to our AgileVentures middleman site, and then re-releasing to Medium after I&amp;rsquo;d got a little distance from the blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the purpose of this blog frenzy?  My memory is that it was about trying to communicate more effectively.  I often end up assuming that people understand my thoughts and intentions and it turns out that actually they don&amp;rsquo;t.  Of course why would they?  There are few telepaths around.  I&amp;rsquo;m also a bit of a gabbler and my sense is that it&amp;rsquo;s not super easy to understand what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to communicate.  So blogging, get all the thoughts down in text, provide them in an accessible form for everyone to read, and maybe reduce my need to gabble on and on about things.  Win win, no?  There&amp;rsquo;s also the motivation that blogging at the start of each day is a kind of &amp;ldquo;morning pages&amp;rdquo; activity such as writers use to start off their days and clear their heads.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think writers usually publish their morning brain dump, but I have certainly found the process of starting each day with writing out my thoughts to be reassuring and relaxing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year when I was doing a lot more coding, the blogs tended to be all about the previous day&amp;rsquo;s coding.  As AgileVentures became an official charity and my admin load increased, they have tended to be about prioritization.  Starting the day with a blog is certainly less stressful than starting the day with a review of email and Slack conversations, which will generally lead to many adds to my ever-increasing todo list.  Has the time been well spent?  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had positive reactions to some blogs, but my sense is that the blogs are too long, too stream-of-consciousness, too un-focused to gain much traction.  I think I may have even alienated some with my uncensored and unedited thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was 17 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had trouble just generating text, and from even earlier I was always a talker.  It&amp;rsquo;s like my internal thought wheel is hooked up directly to my mouth, and at will I can hook it up to a pen or a keyboard and just dump my thoughts straight out, for better or for worse.  So I rarely have writer&amp;rsquo;s block, but it leaves me with a different problem.  How to edit the thicket of thoughts and ideas, so as to more effectively communicate them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to the end of a year of blogging prompts thoughts of changing things going forward.  There&amp;rsquo;ve been times in the past when rising early I&amp;rsquo;ve done 3 hours of programming before breakfast.  After recent design sprints I think about doing coding sprints, or other activities that fill the week in different ways.  Should it be one blog a week with the blog being edited and revised each day, so that a single polished blog can be released on Friday?  I guess it all depends on what one wants to achieve, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t the Buddhist in me been trying to follow a path of consecrated action, where one is totally unattached to the outcomes of activities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d have loved my blogs to have provoked more positive responses of &amp;ldquo;yes, let&amp;rsquo;s build a solution to that together &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, although there has been some of that.  What I really would like is for AgileVentures to be a healthy thriving community providing great learning experiences for many, while also helping charitable causes around the world.  The process of reflection over the last year does make me think that we&amp;rsquo;re far too text heavy in many, many parts of our interface with the world.  One of the most attractive ideas for me going forward is that I&amp;rsquo;d spend my blogging time each day focused on a part of the main AgileVentures site, converting it from text heavy to text light and adding images.  I have a hunch that, by doing this in strategic places throughout the site, we could improve the sign up rates, the number of members joining projects and the numbers signing up for Premium subscriptions, the source of our financial sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a feeling I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to shake the blogging habit.  The process has become too solidly part of my daily routine.  The thing that actually gets me started and ready to work in the mornings.  So, anyhow, starting tomorrow, blogs that focus on parts of the main AgileVentures site.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to work through it one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog released early for inclusion in our July newsletter, earlier blogs are all in draft form in GitHub and will be on this site soon&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Debugging MediaWiki</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/16/debugging-mediawiki/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/16/debugging-mediawiki/</id>
    <published>2017-05-16T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-12T21:01:40+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="mediawiki" src="/images/MediaWiki.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I finally got a clear shot at resolving some of our MediaWiki technical issues.  A key one was users getting loggged out after they create new accounts.  I had had some feedback from MediaWiki support that our cookies weren&amp;rsquo;t being set correctly on production.  So I created a new account for mediawiki on our staging box.  It created the following cookies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cookies created for new user account" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/f73wmvq1g31uh6o/Screenshot%202017-05-15%2010.56.38.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three of these were reported created on the main wiki: cpPosTime, UseDC, UseCDNCache. I navigated to the main page and was logged out, although now there was just one cookie:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="single cookie after redirect" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/mha525jx20y2yow/Screenshot%202017-05-15%2011.00.21.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigating around I stayed logged out, and then tried logging on, which worked and generated a couple more cookies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="more cookies after login" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/h68yx9n2tz9jpv5/Screenshot%202017-05-15%2011.01.59.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the fact that this was happening on our staging box made it seem like this was a Bitnami MediaWiki issue, or possibly something to do with the extensions we had configured on both.  So far the only extensions configured on the staging site are the moderation extension and the wikieditor.  I could try disabling these two to see if we get the same effect, or I could even try a completely fresh Bitnami MediaWiki deploy &amp;hellip; but faster might be to search the Bitnami forums.  A few searches didn&amp;rsquo;t reveal anything:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki%20logged%20out"&gt;https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki%20logged%20out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki%20create%20account"&gt;https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki%20create%20account&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki%20cookies"&gt;https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki%20cookies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki_session"&gt;https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki_session&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was about to post to the Bitnami forum, when I tried disabling the wikieditor and the Moderation extension, and then create account maintained a login.  I re-enabled the wikieditor appearing to confirm that the Moderation extension was the culprit.  I did a few extra tests and opened a &lt;a href="https://github.com/edwardspec/mediawiki-moderation/issues/11"&gt;ticket on the mediawiki-moderation github repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That kicked off a variety of interactions with the Moderation extension maintainer over the course of the day.  First up they asked me to try out a fix involving disabling a php function called &lt;code&gt;onLocalUserCreated&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;hooks/ModerationPreload.php&lt;/code&gt;.  That fixed the issue and the maintainer almost immediately released a fix, which I pulled into staging which now worked fine. The master branch of the extension now included that fix, and another fix that was supposed to resolve another key issue we were having; the failure of the moderation notice to display.  The set up we have is the Moderation extension sitting in an extensions directory within MediaWiki on the Azure/Bitnami instance, and we got it there via git.  So upgrading it involves just pulling down the latest code from GitHub.  This makes me a little nervous.  I&amp;rsquo;m more comfortable with upgrading libraries via something like rubygems and having a full test suite to run to check that everything is still working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually this is not so different from what I do with the autograders on AWS, where we update from git; although there at least we have staging and master branches.  I see that we do have some tests associated with both MediaWiki and the Moderation extension.  I&amp;rsquo;d like to have these running, ideally in CI.  At the moment everything is relying on time-consuming manual tests.  Argh! I&amp;rsquo;d love to have space to re-create a box from scratch, checking what tests we can run on the way and also do a step by step performance review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the moment I upgraded the Moderation extension via git and things seemed to be fine.  Two important bugs fixed, but then I noticed that although the Moderation notice was showing up on staging, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t there on production where we had SSL and the VisualEditor installed.  I added notes to the GitHub issue, and also reviewed all my comments to the VisualEditor team.  Nothing back on the IE, iPad and usability issues there and it had been a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Topic:Tqcoy1d9m5sbtf1e"&gt;Asking about iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Topic:Tql1dw7a2muih6ma"&gt;Usability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Topic:Tqcpj4g11oe3b2ht"&gt;graceful failures on IE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve still had no responses there, but I managed to track down the VisualEditor team on IRC, where I got some great feedback.  Looking at our production site MatmaRex was able to identify the Moderation extension as the culprit for the IE fails, and it looked like several related issues could be solved in one go if the Moderation extension could be adjusted to work with VisualEditor and IE11 in combination.  I got this input on trying to fail gracefully:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19:05] &lt;tansaku&gt; on a more general note, is there a way to have things fail more gracefully? so that if something like this happens the editor switches over to basic?
[19:07] &amp;lt;+MatmaRex&amp;gt; tansaku: no. if you have a syntax error in your script (and effectively, that&amp;rsquo;s how IE11 treats this), the whole MediaWiki script loading system goes out of whack. we really assume you don&amp;rsquo;t have syntax errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got a lead about how to work better on mobile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19:15] &amp;lt;+MatmaRex&amp;gt; tansaku: Wikimedia wikis use https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Extension:MobileFrontend to display a different skin for mobile views, and it has slightly different VisualEditor integration than normal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s something we can look at later.  Right now we&amp;rsquo;re stuck on getting VisualEditor and the Moderation extension to play well on IE11.  The moderator is telling me that IE11 doesn&amp;rsquo;t support the JavaScript &lt;code&gt;for ( A of B )&lt;/code&gt; syntax and more importantly that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support &lt;code&gt;FormData.entries()&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This looks bad. In IE11, there is no way to read the contents of FormData at all.
https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/Hh772723#methods&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the current implementation, reading FormData is essential for ajaxhook (VisualEditor support in Moderation) to work. Need to think of some way to workaround that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but they&amp;rsquo;ve had an idea:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we currently get from FormData, can be obtained by wrapping around mw.Api.prototype.api(). This should work in IE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the maintainer is investigating that, and in the meantime I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll try and complete adding our training materials to the wiki.  I think I also found the &lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Extension:VisualEditor#Complete_list_of_configuration_options"&gt;settings&lt;/a&gt; to remove some of the annoying VisualEditor popups in.  Back to the grindstone &amp;hellip; at least I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to document some of the process of debugging a MediaWiki bug.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Never Enough</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/15/never-enough/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/15/never-enough/</id>
    <published>2017-05-15T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-11T22:38:29+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="never enough" src="/images/never_enough.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However hard I work, it never seems like I&amp;rsquo;ve done enough.  We got the NHS Social Prescribing wiki &amp;ldquo;live&amp;rdquo; on Friday, and I also managed to do a round of updates and fixes on the MOOC.  Superficially I should be pleased at having gotten all that &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo;, but there are a set of usability issues on the wiki that are bothering me.  Maybe the ultimate solution is the philosophical one of not being attached to any future outcome so that one can enjoy every moments inner peace and stillness.  More often that not I am agonizing about the things not done, or whether the things I am doing are having the effects I intend, e.g. blogging supposedly centering me in the morning, but potentially being wasteful navel gazing &amp;hellip; :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s put this blog to work, and look at the issues that are bothering me about the wiki.  I had been hoping to work on them on Friday morning, but time seemed to get sucked into getting them into a trello board:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="HLP wiki trello board" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/4nqawtimebrqe43/Screenshot%202017-05-15%2009.53.52.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and then in a Skype call with the new HLP change manager.  That in itself was a major breakthrough and involved getting one of the NHS tech staff to provide a separate laptop with Skype enabled.  Huge relief as I could now show the change manager various aspects of the wiki operation without having to commute across town.  As we were Skyping, the updated version of the terms &amp;amp; conditions and privacy policy came in, and by the time I&amp;rsquo;d gotten that approved by the communications manager, I added that to the website, sorted out some very basic help guides etc. I&amp;rsquo;d used up my allotted time in the day for work on the wiki.  On reflection I think it was the right focus.  While part of me yearned to be working on the technical issues, having the correct legal cover was crucial.  Also, connecting with the change manager was unblocking them to finish putting all the content from the HLP PDF document into the wiki, and the first (and possibly only) experience that most people were likely to have of the wiki were going to be the content and the viewable portions.  One thing that was clear from the previous week of testing was that we needed a lot more content in there for this to be of any use to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So going back to the Trello board I could move the legal work into the &amp;ldquo;completed&amp;rdquo; column.  Another &amp;lsquo;view&amp;rsquo; item I had created was about improving the landing page.  I&amp;rsquo;d put two items in that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linking all the key topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making all the useful links at the bottom go to our own internal pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change manager had been able to do the former after I&amp;rsquo;d reviewed the process of making links with them.  There were however another set relating to Self-Care that would be linked to pages created from the second HLP PDF document, but that hadn&amp;rsquo;t been signed off by the &amp;ldquo;decider&amp;rdquo; so I&amp;rsquo;m stuck here not being able to click the relevant checkbox.  Pedant?  I know from Friday&amp;rsquo;s experience that I could easily burn a lot of time just editing things around, so I decided to leave this ticket &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo;.  It&amp;rsquo;s odd because there are lots of simple editing tasks, e.g. creating multiple new pages, that are relatively straightforward for me, particularly with my multi-monitor setup, that are quite time consuming for novice users.  At the same time, there are lots of more technical issues that those novice users can&amp;rsquo;t make progress on, so I must drag myself over to the more serious technical issues. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the particularly niggling ones is that creating an account seems to log folks in temporarily, but then they get logged out when they move off the page.  I had opened a &lt;a href="https://trello.com/invite/b/5J4lZIaT/53a4831a8f2f8dc0de936756c66e10d3/hlp-wiki"&gt;support ticket&lt;/a&gt; on the main mediawiki site about this, and got a response:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;definitively it&amp;rsquo;s not something I can reproduce on a local instance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On your wiki, after creating account, I see those cookies being set: cpPosTime, UseDC, UseCDNCache&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On next page I&amp;rsquo;m logged out, and when logging in again, those cookies are being set: bitnami&lt;em&gt;mediawiki&lt;/em&gt;session, bitnami&lt;em&gt;mediawikiUserID, bitnami&lt;/em&gt;mediawikiUserName&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, on a local 1.28, I get all cookies set after creating the account. the _session cookie is set when loading the createaccount page, but then replaced with another after the account gets created. However it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get replaced on your wiki on creating an account, and I have no idea why&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m so tempted to dive in here.  My first action might be to replicate what the MediaWiki person is indicating.  I&amp;rsquo;m also tempted to do the complete setup and install of the whole system on a clean machine.  Although that smells slightly of procrastinating.  I could just start checking the behaviour on our staging instance that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the visual editor and SSL as a way to attack this problem faster, but then again I have two more &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo; tickets.  One is the side navigtation issue which I&amp;rsquo;ve got done, so stick that in completed.  However, the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Help&amp;rdquo; pages that I&amp;rsquo;ve created are still just basic stubs, and it has to be a priority to fill those out further &amp;hellip; and there might be other things to add to that side navigation.  Close the ticket, make a new one on help &amp;hellip; wait - I have a ticket on making the help pages and uploading my training materials there &amp;hellip; I added another ticket on the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page, and spent a few moments moving that into the backlog and moving more important items to the top of the backlog; closing out some other tickets that I&amp;rsquo;ve dealt with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to the crux of my stalled decision-making process.  Filling out the help pages with my training materials feels like super high priority, but the training materials include the sign up process, which has this niggling bug, which if I can fix will change the way we document the site.  To cut this Gordian knot I think I&amp;rsquo;ll upload the training materials, documenting the current issue &amp;hellip; using that as a way to explore the issue, in the way that I sometimes work blog - so wiki work if you will.   I&amp;rsquo;ll hedge against being unable to fix the issue by documenting it.  In the same process I&amp;rsquo;ll be getting wiki usage documentation up.  Two birds, one stone?  Although I might be tempted just to check if we have the same issue on our staging wiki first &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I have a plan, and the Trello board is updated.  I have a niggling doubt that I haven&amp;rsquo;t reviewed all the meetings from last week and that I&amp;rsquo;m missing some other critical issues that need fixing.  Other annoying ones that I do have in the Trello &amp;ldquo;icebox&amp;rdquo; include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create pages defaults to the basic editor which many find confusing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moderation notices fail in some cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The visual editor doesn&amp;rsquo;t fail gracefully&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another knot in that if we can&amp;rsquo;t rely on the visual editor failing gracefully then it might not be such a good idea to make it the default for create pages &amp;hellip;  Anyway.  One knot at a time.  Plan is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get coffee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on first knot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on second knot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure once I&amp;rsquo;ve worked hard through these knots it will be more than enough :-) See you tomorrow :-) &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hard Launch</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/12/hard-launch/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/12/hard-launch/</id>
    <published>2017-05-12T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-10T21:54:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="launch" src="/images/launch.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s May 12th, the hard launch date for the wiki.  We talked about a soft launch on May 4th, and we had the basic system up for then.  The hard launch is now to have everything in place.  I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the week getting usability feedback from different stakeholders across London and now we&amp;rsquo;ve got to knuckle down and make sure everything is in place.  My personal action plan document has sprouted a whole section of stuff for the wiki:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] wiki launch 

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] adding t&amp;amp;c, privacy policy into the system &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] moderation notification to more than one user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] usability issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] default to visual editor on creating pages (or wikieditor?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] save at bottom of page can be confusing in text editor &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;  use wikieditor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] help pages - upload all my training materials &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] moderation notice fails to load when using text editor?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] can we make the search do an OR rather than an AND?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] I&amp;rsquo;m worried the first page has far too much text &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] spaces on end of email address causing problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] creating an account does not log you in, or even guide you to log in or lead you towards what to do next&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] hide the bitnami management corner element&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] help pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got open support tickets with various of these items.  I&amp;rsquo;d also like to be doing a full documentation of the entire wiki setup from scratch and practising recovery drills on another box, but it feels like I must focus the morning on triaging all the usability issues that came up this week and either fixing, working around or leaving as future work.  The danger is that any individual item could be dived in too deep, at the expense of getting a slew of other items sorted.  It&amp;rsquo;s maybe time to break out a Pivotal Tracker, or perhaps a Trello instance to start tracking everything that&amp;rsquo;s going on.  So I went ahead and did that.  Trello made more sense as I can&amp;rsquo;t immediately see us voting on the complexity of the issues (although maybe we should), and Waffle doesn&amp;rsquo;t make so much sense as we&amp;rsquo;re not tightly integrated with GitHub for this project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="trello for hlp wiki" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/e55gki5ir4aeq4o/Screenshot%202017-05-12%2010.30.23.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made this Trello private to the team rather than public as this is a paid project, and we&amp;rsquo;ve got the double concern of our client sensitivity and also having some motivation for people to pay our Premium fees to get access to extra material.  I was also distracted from blogging, helping an HLP staff member sort out a table in one of the wiki pages.  Again the NHS firewall prevents us doing screenshare via Hangouts or Skype with anyone there, so a series of screenshots in Slack let me show the change manager what I had done, but I&amp;rsquo;m not confident that I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to transfer the skill of doing the task itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, getting the Trello up has paid down my day&amp;rsquo;s anxiety debt a little.  There&amp;rsquo;s still lots to do, but at least I&amp;rsquo;ve got a better way of coordinating what we&amp;rsquo;re doing.  The frustrating thing here is that the budget is on a scale that has prevented me from financially incentivizing more Premium members to get involved.  This project is actually a perfect microcosm of all the issues that Agile is supposed to handle.  It just doesn&amp;rsquo;t have large tracts of programming activity.  Is that the fundamental mismatch here?  That I&amp;rsquo;m really interested in the problem solving and how the coding relates to project managment and delivering on client needs, when the majority of others are much more interested in just the code?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Handling Anxiety</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/10/handling-anxiety/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/10/handling-anxiety/</id>
    <published>2017-05-10T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-10T21:54:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="anxiety" src="/images/anxiety.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m playing a game of anxiety managment.  This morning I slept through my alarm and failed to get up for my morning run.  Skipping it, I got on with the rest of the morning routine.  I&amp;rsquo;ve realised I can listen to a technical blog on x2 while preparing the Japanese Kanji character tests for my kids during breakfast.  Maybe the multi-tasking is making me anxious? :-) To be honest I think the anxiety comes from worrying about having enough money to feed my kids and delivering successfully on the NHS project, as well as feeling that I&amp;rsquo;m not making the right choices about how to sustain the AgileVentures charity effectively.  I&amp;rsquo;m trying to listen to all these podcasts to keep up with the changing tech landscape, connect with others on twitter and put interesting content into the AV slack.  My anxiety was not decreased by ending up reviewing Slack and email before this morning&amp;rsquo;s blog - curses &amp;hellip; :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night I was trying to practice the guitar (outside a local church hall where my kids were doing activities), but couldn&amp;rsquo;t focus.  I calmed myself by spending thirty minutes creating private premium chat rooms for AV Premium members.  Over the last 9 months I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving AV Premium members individual support in direct messages and it&amp;rsquo;s not feeling so scalable.  AV Mentor Craig and I had been chatting about this in #mentor-notifications; and agreed that by having a dedicated private Premium support channel for each Premium member it would mean that there&amp;rsquo;s a place that mentors can join me in giving individual support.  Also it&amp;rsquo;s somewhere that mentors can see the history of support that the individual member is getting via Slack. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Craig had already joined me in one new Premium mob member&amp;rsquo;s private channel where we&amp;rsquo;re both able to give him support, and maybe a coherent setup here will allow me to step back a little and focus on increasing the number of Premiums and bringing in more contracts for AV.  So anyhow, while my guitar lay idle I created another handful of private Premium rooms and told the mentors about the backgrounds of the different Premium members hoping to get individual mentors interested in making connections with individual Premium members via these private channels.  I hooked up a few - members seem pleased to see the channels.  I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good way to go - I&amp;rsquo;ll keep adding handfuls of these private channels and then once they&amp;rsquo;re all set up I can hopefully take passes on giving support and gradually get more and more mentors involved &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That out of the way, I was paying down more anxiety by getting on with preparation for another MOOC launch.  I do now have the start date corresponding to the training course and got live the first phase of the TAs helping with the MOOC.  I also went ahead and added as MOOC staff members all those who&amp;rsquo;d shared their email addresses to join the pivotal tracker.  I&amp;rsquo;d held off on this before as it gives them power to edit the course.  Usually we just give them beta-access so they can see the content a week early, but they get blocked because they can&amp;rsquo;t see anything until the course actually goes live.  There doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be a workaround for this, so I went for distributing control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some NHS project anxiety was paid down yesterday when we ran a successful training event in Marylebone for a wider group of HLP staff members who seemed to enjoy using the wiki.  We got another set of valuable insights into the sticking points of the software, but then there&amp;rsquo;s the quandry of what changes to make to make the system easier to use.  We&amp;rsquo;ve gone with allowing anyone to make accounts, which meant that the set up before users could edit was much simpler in this second training session.  Here are the issues we encountered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Help Page currently goes to the general mediawiki site - should make it local&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the visual editor fails then when creating a page we don&amp;rsquo;t see the moderation popup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create page actions defaults to text editor which can be confusing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual editor pop up (that allows switching) doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a dismiss &amp;lsquo;X&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone would like the ability to upload pdfs, ppts, excel, word docs etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image upload hidden behind insert -&amp;gt; media - then upload tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start editing for VE appears too often (maybe when attempting to edit subsections)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had 5 HLP staff from the Prevention and Mental Health teams attend this training session; and they were enthusiastic about editing and experimenting with the wiki.  So much so that we focused the session on the basic editing, and didn&amp;rsquo;t go quite so deep into the moderation section.  The new change manager is also adding lots of extra content and I&amp;rsquo;m helping him with that, as well as how to get all the images out of the exising PDF.  What&amp;rsquo;s making me anxious about the hard launch on Friday is getting enough content in there.  Other things on my radar and causing my heart to race include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ensuring the banner is dynamic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practising a restore from backup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to be digitizing everything I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from the ongoing NHS design sprint and working with all the different stakeholders to get their materials into the system, but I have to put that to one side in order to get the two above items done.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got three more stakeholder meetings (usability testings) over the next two days which play merry havoc with my ability to make progress on technical issues due to intermittent connectivity as I commute around on trains.  Well I have some time this morning.  Time to get it done &amp;hellip; and lots of deep breathing to manage the anxiety :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>All in One Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/09/all-in-one-day/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/09/all-in-one-day/</id>
    <published>2017-05-09T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-10T21:54:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="four seasons" src="/images/four_seasons_one_day.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m struggling with what each blog should be.  Should it be a focused dive on one thing?  Should I be trying to cover everything that happened since the last blog?  Yesterday was pretty intense.  I could spend the whole blog on the AV community meeting we had at the end of the day yesterday.  There&amp;rsquo;d been a spurt of conversation in the #av&lt;em&gt;community&lt;/em&gt;talk channel triggered by Mikael&amp;rsquo;s reaction to my blog of a month ago about having to switch my focus away from AgileVentures.  The discussion was all around trying to understand how we could make AV sustainable.  It was Joao, Matt and myself in the meeting, which we could probably have publicized better, but then who takes the lead on these things?  I&amp;rsquo;m close to drowning trying to attend to the NHS project, ramping up the new run of the MOOC and keeping AV ticking over.  Perhaps we can repeat weekly &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d really liked all the independent conversation taking place in the #av&lt;em&gt;community&lt;/em&gt;talk channel and had resolved to stay in the background in the meeting.  I started off well and we went round trying to answer Joao&amp;rsquo;s question about what the AV product is.  We had a good chat, but I noticed that by the end it was me doing most of the talking :-( Joao had to go, but Matt and I carried on a little as I evangelised the design sprint concept.  We didn&amp;rsquo;t end up trying the &amp;ldquo;Market and Product Validation Checklist&amp;rdquo; that Matt had mentioned in the chat &amp;hellip; well, anyway, Matt got quite enthused about the idea of doing a design sprint so we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That all came at the end of a full day, where I was just hanging in there to get emails out to move forward on the private contract that will hopefully sustain me for the rest of year, and the communication with the lawyers about the NHS wiki terms &amp;amp; conditions.  The majority of the day had been taken up getting ready for a usability/outreach session with the &lt;a href="https://www.kcsc.org.uk/"&gt;Kensington &amp;amp; Chelsea Social Council&lt;/a&gt;; an umbrella group supporting the non-profit sector in the London borough of Kensington &amp;amp; Chelsea.  I have the feeling they are the equivalent entity to the Voluntary Action Harrow (VAH) group who we&amp;rsquo;ve built the Harrow Community Network for through the LocalSupport project.  I&amp;rsquo;d been put in touch with folks at the Kensington &amp;amp; Chelsea Social Council via NHS HLP as a group that were implementing Self Care in their area and might have interest in the wiki project we&amp;rsquo;ve developed.  Our NHS design sprint has sprawled out from its initial week (a few weeks back), and I&amp;rsquo;ve got a meeting with a different stakeholder each day this week, and I&amp;rsquo;m using those meetings to get further usability feedback on the MediaWiki system we&amp;rsquo;ve deployed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just about hanging on, making the arrangements to meet everyone, fitting in the travel etc.  I say just about because I had to push the marketing meeting back an hour yesterday at the last minute when I realised that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be back in time for it.  Not ideal.  I could have tried to do it in a coffee shop in Kensington &amp;amp; Chelsea, but I felt back at the home office would be more efficient.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got an extra meetup to fit in this week and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where my lunch breaks are going to fit in through the week!  Maybe I need to move the Martin Fowler scrum.  Pat has just said he can&amp;rsquo;t commit to share the hosting of the meeting.  I could move it earlier or even just put it on hold for while &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, we got the marketing meeting done.  At least I&amp;rsquo;m remembering to review the outstanding action items.  I feel like there must be some better meeting management system somewhere in between Trello and the text notes I&amp;rsquo;m pasting into Slack, but then again.  The main technical challenge for the day was seeing if I could get the HLP banner into the wiki.  I was getting stuck on it, and managed to hand off the task briefly to Lara, who played with a few settings and came up with a solution.  I had been adding the MediaWiki vector skin to insert a div for the HLP banner/navigation from their main site; but certain mediawiki elements would not move down.   Thanks to Lara&amp;rsquo;s input we got a great mockup editing the common.css for the site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight css"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;#hlp-banner&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sx"&gt;url('https://www.dropbox.com/s/2yokso0fkd3bivt/Screenshot%202017-05-08%2010.40.18.png?dl=1')&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;100%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;min-height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;123px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nf"&gt;#mw-head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;margin-top&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;123px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nc"&gt;.mw-wiki-logo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;background-image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;none&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had just taken a quick screen shot of the HLP site banner to play with.  I just got this into the main site on the train on the way into meeting Kensington &amp;amp; Chelsea Social Council, and then I also managed to make emails required in the site.  All a bit skin of the teeth, but it allowed me to get valuable feedback at the stakeholders&amp;rsquo; offices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat down with their strategic health lead and the manager of their Self-care program, and we could have easily been continuing the expert interviews of the previous weeks.  I could tell that there would be lots of great stuff to learn about how K&amp;amp;C was implementing self care, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to burn all the time on that.  We had to move on to a more testing footing.  We had our working &amp;ldquo;prototype&amp;rdquo;.  After understanding a bit more about how things worked at KCSC, I convinced them to try out our wiki on their systems.  Simply having them navigate to the site and seeing that it appeared correctly was already useful, particularly given the problems we&amp;rsquo;d had with some wikis on the NHS laptops/network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I encouraged the Self-care manager to navigate through the site, try some searches and then some editing.  It was all rather slap-dash from an academic usability standpoint, but there were some clear knowledge gains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you weren&amp;rsquo;t logged in, searching for things did not suggest page creation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches for multiple terms were not matching anything in our system (not much content in there)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The combination of required email confirmation and the visual editor could lead to a confusing user flow &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two reasonably high priority items are now to see if we can make the banner fully dynamic, and also whether we can drop the email confirmation requirement, since the moderation step still catches anything a user tries to post.  I&amp;rsquo;m definitely leaning towards having almost no requirements for becoming a user and push the burden onto the moderation queue - at least at the beginnning when there are few users.  If the moderation burden becomes too heavy, then we can start imposing additional constraints on user sign up; which makes me think I need to get the moderation plan and budget out of my head and onto paper.  Of course the ongoing interaction testing (training?) is what&amp;rsquo;s helping us understand how the moderation will actually work with this system.   We&amp;rsquo;re doing our hard launch on Friday.  I&amp;rsquo;ll take a deep breath; say to myself that we&amp;rsquo;ll address each issue in turn each day of this week and next week will be calmer :-) Taking it one day at a time &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=_JPjZvDJ2VQ"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4gqu79SLxRc"&gt;AV Community meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
