<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Tech Tests</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/02/10/tech-tests/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/02/10/tech-tests/</id>
    <published>2017-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-08T21:42:52+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m doing a tech test for FutureLearn and they&amp;rsquo;ve very kindly said that I can post my work publicly on GitHub, which I have promptly done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/tictactoe"&gt;https://github.com/tansaku/tictactoe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ve spent about 3 hours on it so far, mostly in different leisure centers, churches and halls waiting for my children to finish sporting activities.   I get 45 minutes on Tuesdays, Wednesdays and Thursdays while I wait for them to finish WoodCraft, football and Karate respectively; during which I can focus on my laptop without too many interruptions.  In a bit of tech test flurry I created a calculator in Ruby for CodeMentor yesterday, which got approved this morning, and I was reminded of the period last year where I got pneumonia and spent three weeks in bed doing almost nothing but kata on &lt;a href="http://www.codewars.com/"&gt;CodeWars&lt;/a&gt;. Interestingly, I&amp;rsquo;d encountered variations on the CodeMentor tech test in CodeWars.  If you want to get good at TechTests you could do worse than spending a while hacking through the kata on CodeWars and other sites like HackerRank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other Makers folks were overtaking my CodeWars score recently, but I think CodeWars just adjusted their calculations and I seem to have jumped back to the top of the list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="codewars ranking for my allies" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/xzq8o3mdiyqawmh/Screenshot%202017-02-10%2009.49.57.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which gives me ridiculous childish pleasure.  I&amp;rsquo;m so shallow &amp;hellip; (hangs head).  I&amp;rsquo;m still frustrated not to get to 1-kyu on CodeWars, even after I solved all the 1-kyu katas (1-kyus are the hardest).  Looks like there are now some new 1-kyu and 2-kyu katas that would allow me to get to 1-kyu without doing umpteen easier katas.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get to that if I have another major illness :-)  Anyhow, tech tests are a strange beast - little coding puzzles that companies hand out to potential hires to test their coding skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got into CodeWars because it was being recommended when I was a coach at MakersAcademy, and at the bootcamp we were focused on helping training folks up to be able to handle the tech tests that companies would give them after they graduated.  I previously did a worked tech test for the students there, the code for which you can see here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/vending-machine-kata"&gt;https://github.com/tansaku/vending-machine-kata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recorded screencasts of myself doing the entire thing to try and reveal the thought processes I was having as I went through it.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t have such fantastic feedback about it.  One junior staff member told me he thought the code made him &amp;ldquo;sad&amp;rdquo; and despite many other disucssions, I never got to discover what made him sad about it.  Another more senior staff member said that one student listening to the videos felt that it was too stop/start with me saying &amp;ldquo;umm&amp;rdquo; to much, which I can totally believe.  I think that lead to some scripted coding screencasts for the weekly challenges at Makers that ultimately were much more appreciated by the students.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;d been fun to do this TicTacToe tech test for FutureLearn, and I took an Outside-In approach, driving the code with acceptance tests, dropping down to some integration and unit tests. I got something that works more or less, in a single monolithic file, just pushing Sandi Metz&amp;rsquo; 100 line limit.  There&amp;rsquo;s something nerve-wracking for me, an academic by training, working with these industry tech tests.  I keep seeking that industry &amp;ldquo;special-sauce&amp;rdquo;.  The thing that makes the great coders.  My best guess at the moment is that actually it&amp;rsquo;s giving ground rather than fighting for a particular code style that is the key skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that confuses me is that we have directions like &amp;ldquo;do the simplest thing possible&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;always write your test first&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;red-green-refactor&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;you ain&amp;rsquo;t gonna need it&amp;rdquo; and others, but when you take any of these to their logical extremes people seem to get uncomfortable.  This TicTacToe problem is clearly highly constrained, so an alternate approach to take would be to build a TicTacToe engine, driving the design with unit tests, and then wrapping acceptance tests around later (if at all).  I&amp;rsquo;ve never been a big fan of that sort of approach as I worry I&amp;rsquo;m going to burn too much time writing stuff I don&amp;rsquo;t need, and they&amp;rsquo;d said only spend a couple of hours on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to do the whole thing driven from RSpec to avoid burning time on Cucumber, and was interested to see if I could write complete acceptance tests for the input/output on the command line, so I drove in that way and got my single monolithic class.  At the moment I have a roughly working system, but only for a few hard-coded games.  The computer&amp;rsquo;s current strategy is fixed and I don&amp;rsquo;t handle collisions for markers, so the game is not fully generic.  The tech test is currently a reasonable demonstration of my ability to craft different kind of tests, get a roughly working system, but I&amp;rsquo;m suddenly paranoid about whether this code is going to make more people &amp;ldquo;sad&amp;rdquo; in some indeterminate way and I still won&amp;rsquo;t be able to get an example of a version that would make people &amp;ldquo;happy&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can imagine doing it again, driving from unit tests (with the benefit of the initial experience) to make a nicely factored engine.  I could also layer on some acceptance tests to make sure the other high level failures are addressed, e.g. collisions handled etc., or I could continue refactoring the code with the existing tests.  I&amp;rsquo;ve used the existing test suite to eliminate some unneeded code and make the method names more self-explanatory.  But how will people feel about the lack of comments?  I like to focus on making the method and variable names self-documenting.  Having got this far I feel like I won&amp;rsquo;t be happy until it plays a fully generic game.  I know I&amp;rsquo;ll be spending more time on it today before I send FutureLearn the link :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eUhIV1c9CpU"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yFIOYN8SisA"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pivoting or Not</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/02/09/pivoting-or-not/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/02/09/pivoting-or-not/</id>
    <published>2017-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-08T21:37:17+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There was an interesting response to one of &lt;a href="http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2017/01/23/passing_a_threshold/"&gt;recent blog posts&lt;/a&gt; from an AV community member.  They posted the following in our community #random channel (where I had shared my blog post):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an additional source of income for AV, why not offer pairing sessions for payment for those who may be reluctant to commit to a monthly fee? These sessions could be given to mentors who would be paid a proportion of the fee, thus perhaps incentivising more mentor-type people to join as well. A bit similar to what AirPair used to do although perhaps more from a learning point of view rather than a professional problem solving one as that was. So perhaps a student could pay for a session on a particularly difficult piece of homework, or a private project they are doing, or to better learn some concept or technique they are having problems with, or even just to practice coding and pair programming but without having to commit themselves to working on a project, which might be intimidating to some (and pairing not always available). These students might also in future be drawn into collaborating on actual AV projects. But in any case the pairing sessions themselves would bring in additional income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And another community member responded, soon after, that they would pay for individual mentoring sessions, and we spent a little time discussing things in the &amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what happened to AirPair.  According to their &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AirPair"&gt;wikipedia page&lt;/a&gt; they raised over $1M after a Y Combinator presentation, but the site currently has some authentication errors and I&amp;rsquo;m not seeing any activity on the site or social media since mid-2016.  However, similar sites such as HackHands and CodeMentor seem to be &amp;hellip; oops, got distracted there.  I just went through the sign up processes for CodeMentor and HackHands.  Thought it would only take a couple of minutes, but CodeMentor included a timed assessment involving a pop quiz and a programming assignment.  Fortunately it was very similar to a kata I had completed not so long ago on Codewars, so I was able to polish it off pretty quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, talk about being easily distracted! :-) At least I&amp;rsquo;ve now got a good insight into the sign up experiences of those two companies.  So what our community member is suggesting is a lot like what I think CodeMentor and HackHands are offering.  What&amp;rsquo;s not clear is how beneficial it would be for AgileVentures.  It feels like it will be difficult for us to compete with venture-backed companies in the same space, although as suggested, perhaps we focus more on the learning side? I was originally tempted to respond in #random with my philosophy of openness in AgileVentures, but thought I&amp;rsquo;d save it for this blog.  One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve learned is that when people are giving you suggestions, they are generally not interested in hearing that you thought about them already, or why you haven&amp;rsquo;t taken them up.  Far better to thank them for the great suggestions and ask simple follow up questions to find more about what they are thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to bring in more money to AgileVentures, but I find helping individuals on their specific closed-source issues somewhat challenging.  Specifically because you often can&amp;rsquo;t get the whole code system on your own machine quickly.  Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;m a deeply flawed and impatient person, but I find it difficult to cope with making suggestions verbally and then having someone stumble around in their own interface, mis-interpreting what I&amp;rsquo;ve said.  I guess that&amp;rsquo;s what ScreenHero is for &amp;hellip; And maybe even uttering my honest thoughts here is self-destructive.  My hope with AgileVentures is to be doing the mentoring in the open, to enable more learners to learn from the contributions to open source projects.  Although I&amp;rsquo;ve come to see clearly that many learners crave privacy and are deeply embarrassed about asking questions in public, or in front of more than just a single mentor.  I assume this is all related to fear of failure, fear of being seen as less than competent etc.  I feel it to, but repeated practice has got me comfortable(-ish) with failing in public :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that our community member mentions not having to commit to a project.  From my point of view if you just make one comment in one of our PRs, or just get the code set up and then never do anything, it&amp;rsquo;s still a contribution.  It&amp;rsquo;s what a lot of people seem to do; but perhaps many more are put off by the perception of needing to commit to a project.   I guess my big worry is that for all the time I spend helping other individuals on their private projects and homeworks, I&amp;rsquo;m not getting any multiplier for the community.  I can&amp;rsquo;t share the code solution we discover, and I can&amp;rsquo;t share the video of the techniques we used to discover the solution; but then again how many others actually benefit from all the AV videos we&amp;rsquo;ve shared?  How many others are really following the support given in psuedo-public in Slack?  Maybe the majority are all just hideously embarrassed by all this and that&amp;rsquo;s why we keep struggling to achieve any sustained critical mass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mind does come round to feeling that the majority of people want polished content that they can consume in private.  There&amp;rsquo;s so much less pressure, it&amp;rsquo;s so much more convenient.  The cynic in me moans that so much of the polished content is not true to life, but then these days there are great screencasters out there (mainly outside of academia) showing folks how to actually do stuff, and maybe that&amp;rsquo;s always going to be more successful than a system that attempts to get the majority to overcome their fear of learning, of failing, in front of others &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=zBP6d2a0Rcc"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1nqdZoqlH7A"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Blog Posts:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2017/01/23/passing_a_threshold/"&gt;Passing a Threshold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Motivation Barrier</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/02/08/motivation-barrier/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/02/08/motivation-barrier/</id>
    <published>2017-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-06T21:49:29+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m writing this blog while text chatting with an HMRC tax representative trying to work out how to pay my tax bill online.  This is my get one item off my desk a day activity.  Just after writing that sentence I got to the tax representative and got guided through creating an online account, but the payment service is offline till Feb 17th, so I can&amp;rsquo;t technically clear my desk, since I&amp;rsquo;ll need to add an action item to my list, but at least I can clear away the paper bills and make them go &amp;ldquo;digital&amp;rdquo;.  I also signed up for paperless billing in the future, so hopefully they&amp;rsquo;ll be less paperwork cluttering up my desk in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process for motivating oneself to get all these little things is strange, at least for me.  I really can&amp;rsquo;t bear the thought of working through all the papers on my desk.  Chipping away a little at a time seems like the only strategy.  What&amp;rsquo;s difficult and/or frustrating is the variable amounts of time that dealing with each individual &amp;ldquo;item&amp;rdquo; can take.  I&amp;rsquo;d been psyching myself up to get to this tax bill, clearing other items before it, and it had finally got to the top of my &amp;ldquo;mental&amp;rdquo; pile, if not the physical one.  As I was climbing the stairs today I said to myself &amp;ldquo;ah, I can just pay that directly from a different account, and avoid depleting the current account that I use for day to day affairs&amp;rdquo;.  Naively I thought I could just do a bank transfer, as I do for my company tax payments, but not so.  Once I&amp;rsquo;d pulled the bill out it only had a payslip.  I could have written a cheque and sent it off, but then it might come out of my account at an inconvenient moment and money is a little tight at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t bear the thought of phoning the tax office and going on hold, so I was pleased to be able to use their chat solution.  Ironically I still wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to pay, but at least I am now in principle set up to pay online before the deadline.  The whole process has taken up about 30 minutes, during which I might have been blogging more thoroughly, but there might be some long term gains, in terms of taking the process digital in future.  I reflect that one&amp;rsquo;s perception of how long things will take is affected by many factors, and that very often one&amp;rsquo;s estimates end up being faulty.  Spiritually I&amp;rsquo;m trying to really live in the moment, at the moment; and all moments :-), with varying degrees of success, but at least occasionally with laughter :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another version of me might have ranted about the lack of the UK government digital wherewithal, but they do seem to be going in the right direction.  Of course I think as a taxpayer I should have much more control about how the money I contribute is spent.  The democratic process of voting for a representative who will have some influence on my behalf seems remarkably error prone and imprecise.  Although that said, I have been having a productice conversation with my local M.P. (Gareth Thomas, Labour) about traffic safety near local schools.  More on that on another occasion, but I recently discovered there&amp;rsquo;s a name for the idea I&amp;rsquo;ve long held dear about individual taxpayers choosing where their tax goes.  It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tax_choice"&gt;Tax Choice&lt;/a&gt;, and apparently Romania has implemented it to some degree.  I was speaking to an extended family member from Romania over the break and hearing about how it&amp;rsquo;s something they have to register for, and some people do it and some people don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US has a reasonable system, in my opinion, with contributions to non-profits being tax deductable, so you can effectively reduce your tax payments by choosing deserving causes.  It&amp;rsquo;s not quite the same however, as you&amp;rsquo;re not just allocating your tax, you&amp;rsquo;re also allocating your own funds as well.  In the UK we have GiftAid, which allows your charitable contributions to be added to by the government, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t reduce your tax bill.  You can make tax-deductibale charitable contributions in the UK if you are a company, or if your employer is signed up to a just-giving scheme, which is all rather too complicated if you ask me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;ve totally got sidetracked from my intended focus on motivation, it does all link up.  People&amp;rsquo;s donation to charitable causes is going to be related to their perception of how easy it is to do, and the possible associated benefits to themselves.  Where I was thinking about motivation yesterday was how I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting off promoting the &lt;a href="http://nonprofits.agileventures.org"&gt;AV nonprofits site&lt;/a&gt; that Michael, Raoul and I collaborated on last year.  We had some detailed constructive criticism from Freeranger that made me feel a little embarressed about distributing it widely.  We gradually worked through various of the issues, but there were a couple of wonky screenshots in the case-studies that I got stuck on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working through all the little fixes I got distracted by implementing the payment frameworks in the main developer site, and getting new screenshots for the case-studies felt like a fiddling difficult thing.  At least partly because they were other projects and I was waiting on UI improvements to be implemented.  As we were discussing the non-profit site in the marketing meeting yesterday, I made a bit of a breakthrough to push it forward.  Lara had a great new UI design for the MetPlus project that I pulled in, and I went in and edited the SnowAngels UI myself.  The static site on middleman is actually super easy to change compared to some sorts of changes on the main developer site.  Within thirty minutes I had the changes up, and then in another thirty I had a couple of Google AdWords ads set up to try and help drive traffic to that site for charities and non-profits who might need IT solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feels good to get it done, and funny in retrospect how it seemed such a blocker.  Will this generate any paying leads?  We&amp;rsquo;ll see.  It feels like there are a lot of other minor tweaks to be made in the &amp;ldquo;funnels&amp;rdquo; through the various sites that might lead developers and organisations to the point that they are contributing financially to the support of AgileVentures.  I did have a couple of hours spare for coding yesterday, but one went on ensuring all the Premium members are correctly represented in the database, and another hour went on a tech test that might lead to some income for me personally on a closed source project.  We&amp;rsquo;ve got a few more folks joinging the WebSiteOne project recently, but I don&amp;rsquo;t feel in a position to assign folks to work on particular parts of the funnel.  Motivation is complicated and I think we need to allow things to drift into place rather than force them &amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t want to crash into other people&amp;rsquo;s motivation barriers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2K-Rt8y2_Hk"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bUtVHE5mJW8"&gt;Marketing meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zOCxl7D1LeM"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mixed Bag</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/02/07/mixed-bag/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/02/07/mixed-bag/</id>
    <published>2017-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-02T21:21:36+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was pleased to be back blogging about code yesterday, but Monday didn&amp;rsquo;t see any further focus on code.  I replied to all the incoming Slack queries, but not all the emails, and fitted in a fair few meetings.  It had been a few weeks since we had a LocalSupport client meeting and we managed to sneak one in between the &amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum and the marketing meeting.  We were able to get five or six stories, chores and bug fixes accepted, and confirm the pivot from organization lising to volunteering; a thread that was picked up again in the Agile Book Club podcast later that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a slew of new action items there for me to follow up on, and reminds me I&amp;rsquo;d love an automated bot to help me do project board review.  We&amp;rsquo;ve lost any structure to LocalSupport and WebSiteOne sprints since we&amp;rsquo;ve dropped explicit kick-off and retrospective meetings.  Maybe that means we&amp;rsquo;re just failing at Agile, but I feel rock-bottom in terms of motivation for those kinds of meetings given the low level of enthusiasm for them in the past.  Both projects are seeing a resurgence of activity recently so maybe we should bring them back in at some point, but I&amp;rsquo;m also enamoured with the idea of doing everything in a distributed asynchronous fashion using voting bots and project management bots.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overnight we managed a vote in WebSiteOne, and I started getting set up with Arreche&amp;rsquo;s reworked slack integration bot that will hopefully provide a simpler interface and support multiple votes in parallel.   One step at a time, but I can&amp;rsquo;t help speculating about a project bot that would automate, or semi-automate working through the project boards.  I think the boards need to be reviewed once a week and every &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;current&amp;rdquo; ticket needs to be checked on.  The heuristic I use is to check if there&amp;rsquo;s been any activity in the last couple of days from the person taking the lead on the ticket.  If they&amp;rsquo;ve pushed commits to a PR, added comments to the tickets then it can be left, but if there&amp;rsquo;s been no activity of a while they need to be pinged to check on the status, see if the item can be re-assigned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full automation would be hard, but a semi-automated approach that presented each ticket in turn with its &amp;ldquo;state of decay&amp;rdquo; would be something to help reduce effort on the part of the project manager.  Even just a repeating alert to make sure the review was performed weekly would be helpful.  Maybe I should have had a quiet half hour to do that after the the client meeting, but I was straight into the marketing meeting as we reviewed our Google AdWords campaign performance, draft newsletter and content marketing strategy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to leave marketing early to pair with Corey on a sticky point on WebSiteOne, where we&amp;rsquo;d been going back in forth in a pull request to little apparent progress.  Once again the magic of the realtime hangout got us sorted.  I properly understood the problem that Corey was facing, which was writing an acceptance test for the the pop-up countdown timer.  Corey had been able to make it work by switching the Capybara driver from poltergeist to webkit, but that had the unfortunate side-effect of breaking a lot of other tests.  I was pretty sure we didn&amp;rsquo;t need to switch the driver to get this to work, or at least pretty much anything else would be less effort than fixing all the other mercury editor related tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used the debugger to see that the event countdown was present in the code being returned by the poltergeist driver:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight html"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"hidden-sm hidden-xs hidden-md"&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"next-event"&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;data-event-time=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"2014-02-03T07:00:00+00:00"&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;data-event-url=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"/events/scrum"&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;data-event-name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"Scrum"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"/events/scrum"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Scrum&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; is live!&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting the clean output was the usual pain that made me think there must be a better way to get formatted HTML output on the irb/byebug prompt.  So much so that I just took a blog break to file an &lt;a href="https://github.com/deivid-rodriguez/byebug/issues/327"&gt;issue on byebug&lt;/a&gt; and research the matter.  Corey wondered if the screen width might be an issue and a quick google got us to the solution which was a step to increase the width of the virtual browser so that the popup would be shown:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;And&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sr"&gt;/^the window size is wide$/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="no"&gt;Capybara&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;current_window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;resize_to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1300&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I guess I lied, there was a tiny chunk of coding focus in the middle of the day. Then it was lunch and &amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum and drie meeting catch up (they&amp;rsquo;ve decided to build the dashboard themselves), and Agile Book Club podcast episode 2, which was great fun.  I bought the three pack of e-books:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fifty Quick Ideas to Improve your User Stories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fifty Quick Ideas to Improve your Tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fifty Quick Ideas to Improve your Retrospectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great day really.  Now I just have to make sure that I follow up with the LocalSupport project elements, and get out some code to start tracking the sign ups that are coming in through the Google AdWords campaign.  I&amp;rsquo;m trying to stay focused on the moment and not worry too much about how every little step adds up to any particular long term goal. Let&amp;rsquo;s see what today brings :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uzpJp9YlBwU"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GlZn27yOhGU"&gt;LocalSupport Client Meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k_x6DByoiNk"&gt;Pairing with Corey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y43CuqQuWLo"&gt;Marketing Meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x5ksyXWhedk"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Doing the Right Thing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/02/06/doing-the-right-thing/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/02/06/doing-the-right-thing/</id>
    <published>2017-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-01T21:42:42+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over Thursday and Friday I pushed out what I&amp;rsquo;m calling an &amp;ldquo;escalating call to action&amp;rdquo; on the main AgileVentures site.  The idea had come up in a discussion with Michael in a scrum earlier in the week in which we&amp;rsquo;d been talking about what to display when the user was already logged in, because our initial stab at a call to action &amp;ldquo;Sign up now to start coding&amp;rdquo; was being shown to all users, independent of their logged in status:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="&amp;quot;Sign up now to start coding&amp;quot; banner button" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/yx69fbv0axhe7kc/Screenshot%202017-02-06%2009.37.58.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impetus to create/add this single &amp;ldquo;call to action&amp;rdquo; had come from a marketing meeting at the beginning of the week where we were looking at the sign up stats, and thinking in terms of funnels through the site.  Of course like all things there were many connections.  Ashley had talked a few months back about the site not really directing folks to take a particular action.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been agitating to think about things in terms of the lean startup funnel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="lean startup funnel" src="https://leansteps.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/funnel.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seemed to follow naturally that we might make the call to action vary according to the status of who was on the site, like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guest User &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Sign Up now to start coding!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logged in User &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Upgrade to Premium for more support&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Premium User &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;  &amp;ldquo;Upgrade to Premium Mob for group sessions with a Mentor&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday evening I spiked the view like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight erb"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_user&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;membership_type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Basic'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;new_subscription_path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Upgrade to Premium for additional support'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;elsif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;membership_type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Premium'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;new_subscription_path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;plan: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'premiummob'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Upgrade to Premium Mob for group sessions with a Mentor'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;new_user_registration_path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Sign up now to start coding!'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"btn btn-primary btn-block call-to-action "&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;style=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this is nasty logic in the view, but it was also an experiment.  I wanted to focus on the business logic in one place, not on the process of pulling that business logic into a model or service.  If I had a secure income it might be another story, but I got something basic working.  Then I wrapped it in tests, breaking it as I went along:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight gherkin"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;@vcr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kd"&gt;Feature&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Escalating Call to Action
  As a site admin
  So that we can move towards sustainability
  I would like users to see an escalating call to action depending on their subscription

  &lt;span class="kn"&gt;Background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Given&lt;/span&gt; the following plans exist
      &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;amount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;free_trial_length_days&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Premium&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;premium&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;1000&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;                      &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Premium&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Mob&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;premiummob&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;2500&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;                      &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="kn"&gt;Scenario&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Guest user sees call to action which links to sign up page
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Given&lt;/span&gt; I am on the &lt;span class="s"&gt;"home"&lt;/span&gt; page
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;When&lt;/span&gt; I click &lt;span class="s"&gt;"Sign up now to start coding!"&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; I should be on the &lt;span class="s"&gt;"sign up"&lt;/span&gt; page

  &lt;span class="kn"&gt;Scenario&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Logged in user sees call to action which links to premium subscription page
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Given&lt;/span&gt; I am logged in
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;And&lt;/span&gt; I am on the &lt;span class="s"&gt;"home"&lt;/span&gt; page
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;When&lt;/span&gt; I click &lt;span class="s"&gt;"Upgrade to Premium for additional support"&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; I should be on the &lt;span class="s"&gt;"premium sign up"&lt;/span&gt; page

  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;@stripe_javascript&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;@javascript&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="kn"&gt;Scenario&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Premium user sees call to action which links to premium mob subscription page
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Given&lt;/span&gt; I am logged in as a premium user with name &lt;span class="s"&gt;"John"&lt;/span&gt;, email &lt;span class="s"&gt;"john@gmail.com"&lt;/span&gt;, with password &lt;span class="s"&gt;"12345678"&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;When&lt;/span&gt; I click &lt;span class="s"&gt;"Upgrade to Premium Mob for group sessions with a Mentor"&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; I should be on the &lt;span class="s"&gt;"premium mob sign up"&lt;/span&gt; page
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically the tests took twice as long to write as the code, mainly due to a Capybara issue with the step that checks that we&amp;rsquo;ve arrived on the correct page, which had to be evolved from this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="sr"&gt;/^I should be on the "([^"]*)" page$/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;current_path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;eq&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;path_to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="sr"&gt;/^I should be on the "([^"]*)" page$/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;current_fullpath&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;eq&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;path_to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;current_fullpath&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="no"&gt;URI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;parse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;current_url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;request_uri&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;after consulting various StackOverflow posts on the subject.  The issue here was that in the (older?) version of Capybara that we are using, the current_path returns the path without the URL params e.g. &lt;code&gt;plan=premiummob&lt;/code&gt;, which we need, due to the current design of the subscription controller.  Of course even just writing this down I come back to thoughts from a couple of months back about refactoring the URLs to nest so we could have &lt;code&gt;/plan/premiummob/subscriptions/new&lt;/code&gt;.  Gosh, there&amp;rsquo;s just endless extra refactoring we could be doing before being able to conduct experiments on the business logic itself :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, anyway, that was all working and I pushed it out in the background of Friday, and as far as I can tell it&amp;rsquo;s been running over the weekend.  I was in perhaps a hasty rush to put this up.  A last gasp of me being focused on promoting the Premium plans.  There&amp;rsquo;s been no sudden flurry of Premium or Premium Mob sign ups over the weekend :-) It seems like the increase in basic signups is holding steady in a way I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect unless the MOOC was active, although that might just be my imagination.  In the same deploy I got the adwords Premium plan conversion live, so if anyone else does convert we can in principle track where they are coming from, but it follows that we should really get the basic sign up AdWord conversion tracking up, and get better stats on the influx of new users, if we&amp;rsquo;re interested in working out how much impact these site changes and AdWord campaigns are really having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then again my latest resurgence of Buddhist/Mindful thought is suggesting that strenuous effort in any direction is likely to be counter-productive.  That&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be particularly true for enlightenment.  I love Steve Hagen&amp;rsquo;s metaphor of an archery target.  With enlightenment apparently the closer you get to the center, the further away you actually are.  Somehow you are closest to dead center when you are totally on the periphery.  A pattern I do perceive is how my streneous attempts to resist things will bring them on more strongly or my attempt to grasp them will push them further from me.  It sort of feels like I am caught in a very strange counter-intuitive mental puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desperately struggling to try and increase the number of Premium members in AgileVentures may actually make it harder to achieve that end goal.  I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to be a lot more relaxed about all this.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think that hurrying is going to get me anywhere pleasant.  It&amp;rsquo;s probably just going to make the current moment hurried and unpleasant.  Everything just is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gacp_DDpO5M"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hzaQlua3_5s"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=si2W8keQG4o"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bob Martin&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Focusing on the Right Thing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/02/03/how-to-focus-on-the-right-thing/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/02/03/how-to-focus-on-the-right-thing/</id>
    <published>2017-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-28T21:29:23+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I keep trying to focus on the right thing.  From a Buddhist perspective maybe the right thing to focus on is the here and now, the precious moment of current perception, at least where possible.  Still I&amp;rsquo;m fascinated by this notion that one can use reason and data-analysis to work out how to achieve certain goals.  From a spiritual position, maybe being attached either way to the outcome of your goals is just going to lead to pain and disappointment?  I really don&amp;rsquo;t know :-) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a new Premium member sign up yesterday.  I have a suspicion that our Google AdWords campaign might be helping.  The Google analytics interface showed me that the number of folks looking at a Premium payment page had increased by 1, and that this came from someone clicking through on our ad when they had been conducting a search with the word &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo;, one that we&amp;rsquo;d added last week after following suggestions from the AdWords interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="hits on premium payment pages from &amp;quot;code&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;coding&amp;quot;" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/3jm3v72nx3jcj4v/Screenshot%202017-02-03%2009.57.27.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we were welcoming the new Premium member into the AV Premium Slack it turned out that one of the Mentors knew them and, asking in a DM, I found out that that Mentor had recommended joining AgileVentures some time back.  I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/pull/1545"&gt;adding the AdWords scripts&lt;/a&gt; that should allow us to track purchase completions on the site, which should provide better information in the future, but it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to think about the multi-dimensional nature of this process where an individual will, of course, be influenced by many things before making a purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s very interesting is to look at the data about folks coming to our free signup page over the last seven days:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="a week of sign up page activity" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/01zcjl43h6vfnk1/Screenshot%202017-02-03%2010.07.07.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four days ago we rolled out Michael&amp;rsquo;s enhanced call to action and the trend does seem to be up since then.  We also rolled out the additional keywords at the same time, so it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to make a watertight case for one or the other being solely responsible.  However more click throughs to the sign up page implies an increase in the number of folks considering signing up, which seems like a good thing.   I wonder if it&amp;rsquo;s worth setting up A/B tests?  Right now I&amp;rsquo;m focused on the idea of an escalating call to action whereby we provide a button in the same prominent place as the current &amp;ldquo;Sign up now to start coding!&amp;rdquo; that says &amp;ldquo;Upgrade to Premium for additional support&amp;rdquo; for those who are already signed up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="current call to action when not signed in" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/wvxg55gju8re883/Screenshot%202017-02-03%2010.10.23.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d spent the last few days dedicating most of my time to a project proposal for the drie folks, since that has the potential to bring in a lot of revenue, but they&amp;rsquo;ve demurred on that, so my focus swings back to seeing if we can get the Premium income to a level that will be sustainable.  I really don&amp;rsquo;t know.  Maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll end up destroying the soul of the community with prominent calls to upgrade to Premium.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m better off not trying to push the community towards generating enough revenue so that I can continue focusing on it full time?  Perhaps it should be just left alone, and I should go off and do contracting on other projects that won&amp;rsquo;t synergise with AgileVentures.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My furious task-switching comes from trying to focus on the thing that will bring in enough funds to support my family - perhaps I need to detach myself from that outcome in order to be truly happy?  There are loads of little issues with the site I&amp;rsquo;d love to fix.  I have a suspicion that the site performance may be deteriorating under the increasing load, or is that just my imagination?  The production site hasn&amp;rsquo;t been slow any time I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to load it, and no one has complained to me directly.  What we can clearly see is nearly a five-fold increase in sessions on the site since the AdWords campaign kicked off:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="activity over the last month" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/jyiq5cq82zey5wq/Screenshot%202017-02-03%2010.17.27.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can only see the last seven days on the NewRelic tracking of the site performance - seems like we&amp;rsquo;d have to upgrade to see more.  I just applied to their nonprofit program to see if we can get that at a discount.  NewRelic is showing our Apdex score dropping below 0.7 a couple of times a day, which means that sometimes folks are trying to load the site and not getting a page.  I started off the EventManager project for a couple of Premium F2F folks (who&amp;rsquo;ve since downgraded to Premium) as a place to experiment with Rails 5 websockets.  I started talking about a possible MicroServices architecture and now Matt is researching CDNs and ways to have the same assets served to different servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I have to be super-careful going for my focus on effectiveness.  I&amp;rsquo;d love to be throwing all (the minimal) development resources we have into the place that will give us the most bang for the buck.  At the same time, pushing people away from their intuitions from what they think is important and towards the ones I think will gain traction can easily be counter-productive.  There are feelings to be hurt, egos to be bruised, and ultimately I don&amp;rsquo;t know if my ideas are better than anyone else&amp;rsquo;s.  Still I&amp;rsquo;m enchanted by the idea of having an open mind to overturning assumptions about what is and isn&amp;rsquo;t needed.  At the moment I&amp;rsquo;m telling myself that if I can just get this escalating call to action feature out, I&amp;rsquo;ll have done the basics, and can move into a more relaxed posture :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the basics I mean that by rolling out the Premium plans and payment frameworks I&amp;rsquo;ve demonstrated that it&amp;rsquo;s possible to derive some income through this mechanism.  Now of course Bloc and others are already an existence proof that it&amp;rsquo;s possible for others to derive income online from mentoring services, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got it set up and working for us.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got the charity red-tape sorted, the bank account set up, we&amp;rsquo;re taking payments, covering our server costs and then some.  And all that without aggressively promoting Premium.  So, now, what&amp;rsquo;s the way to sustainability?  Can the offering be improved? Certainly.  Can the way it is described and featured on the individual Premium pages be improved?  Certainly.  Can the site and entire community be fixed up and supported better?  I&amp;rsquo;m sure of it.  However I feel like we&amp;rsquo;ve got to take that last step of actually letting people know directly on the site that this pathway is available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even having done so, there&amp;rsquo;ll be loads of little smoothings and tweakings to make the flow along that pathway smoother.  I hope the presence of a smooth pathway won&amp;rsquo;t ulimately be off-putting and counter-productive.  I&amp;rsquo;d love to continue devoting my full-time efforts to AgileVentures for the years to come, but I can&amp;rsquo;t do that unless the pathway is delivering the income to support myself and my loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should end there, but of course the imagined pathway of signing up to the site, and then upgrading to Premium and Premium Mob etc. is not the only pathway.  There&amp;rsquo;s the pathway for sponsors, paid projects and so forth.  I&amp;rsquo;ll keep task-switching and chasing the dream that all this can sustain my full time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1NzXE_BBAwk"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4m9l8cwoHY8"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
