<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-09-22T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Another free refill?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/22/another-free-refill/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/22/another-free-refill/</id>
    <published>2017-09-22T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-27T21:07:18+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="free refill" src="/images/freerefill.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I undertook a training session targeting small business manager to teach them how to improve profitability of business projects. The course instructor showed us a rather clear way to deal with profitabiliy. First, you estimate your break-even hourly rate, based on your history. Then, you don&amp;rsquo;t sell any project under the bottom line. After that, you prioritize your work to put the highest priority on the most profitable projects. Finally, you keep any accepted project above the bottom line. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is quite simple. It&amp;rsquo;s all down to the execution. I began to schedule my workday according to business priorities preferably to a sense of urgency that overcame me before. Then, everytime I felt I was at risk to hit the bottom line, I shifted my attention towards what I really sold to the client annd I reduced my objectives accordingly. Finally, I was trying to become a project reviewer for a well known MOOC platform. But the hourly rate was much too low. I felt relief to drop my candidature. Paid projects management improved greatly. But, a significant part of my workday, dedicated to volunteer projects, was out of the scope of this effort.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many commitments, workaholism, things we begin and we never achieve, any freelance worker faces these contradictions. The inherent contradiction is even stronger when you work on non-paid project. How to prioritize your volunteer works?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten working hours a day is my upper limit, considering that I&amp;rsquo;m not a computer nerd, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a family, hobbies, and a social life &amp;hellip; I was already busy ten hours a day. Adding anything to my schedule implied removing something else. I have been more or less active on professional social networks for three years. I first thought this commitment would improve my reputation and fuel my prospect pipeline. But in three years, the return was not very encouraging. I felt that my social network activity was fueled by bitterness or anxiety or ego or the three rather than by a clear sense of business opportunity! I decided to forget social networks. Two to three hours a week were freed thanks to this good resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to devote these hours to Agile Venture mob programming sessions. It&amp;rsquo;s a real community, with real developers. You can both learn by observing how skilled developers work and by doing things by yourself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still in the midstream of my prioritization effort. I&amp;rsquo;ve been very actively participating in MOOCs for five years. My skills greatly improved as a result of this effort.  But choosing which courses to invest on is not easy. Knowledge is a bit like indirects costs. You don&amp;rsquo;t really know how to assign it to your achievements. During the first years, the offer flourished. I tried many courses, from Economy to Computer Sciences. I progressively focused on Computer Science and left courses as they switched to paid offers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was giving up, a prominent MOOC platform offers me to beta-test courses for free. Free refill is the end of resolution and the beginning of passive hyperactivity! You may begin your training week with a course on Embedded systems and end, on friday, with a course on PythonML on friday, without completing any. Does it make sense to participate in a mob programming session about RSPEC on monday, another one about phoenix on wednesday, on the last one about React on friday, when you only need to develop a small web app with React?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AgileVenture Premium Mob includes some kind of Professional Development Planning Support. I may ask the team to help me clean my training plan. But I&amp;rsquo;m still afraid they will tell me to stop learning Tensor Flow or the nitty gritty of Intel Parallel Architecture if I don&amp;rsquo;t have any prospect to work in these fields in the next year! &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV Website Review Part 5</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/11/av-website-review-part-five/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/11/av-website-review-part-five/</id>
    <published>2017-07-11T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-03T21:43:26+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So what I really meant to do yesterday was to look at the flows going through various pages in the site via Google Analytics.  Here&amp;rsquo;s a view that compares June with May this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="behaviour flow around sign up page, may vs jun" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/hf47so53v8lnhyw/Screenshot%202017-07-11%2009.23.15.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s perhaps even more revealing to compare June this year with June last year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="behaviour flow around sign up page, jun 16 vs jun 17" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/j1yzvlujhm0qttm/Screenshot%202017-07-11%2009.27.31.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we can see clearly here is the big increase from those viewing &amp;rsquo;/code&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;/learn&amp;rsquo; (I shortened those and added sign up call to actions at the end of them recently) and the massize increase in those going to &amp;rsquo;/getting-started&amp;rsquo; (a few months back we adjusted it so that you go to &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; after signing in).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the 1200 people landing on the sign_up page in June, we had 380 just stop there and go no further.  I&amp;rsquo;m wondering if that figure could be improved by the deployment of a privacy policy and re-enabling email signups?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s perhaps more concerning is the 299 drop offs out of the 793 sessions on the &amp;lsquo;getting started&amp;rsquo; page.  Of course maybe the reality is that we can&amp;rsquo;t change either of these drop off rates significantly.   I&amp;rsquo;ve just experiemented with changes to the &amp;#39;getting started&amp;rsquo; page and so it seems sensible to leave that for a while.  Although maybe we should be A/B testing rather than comparing longitudinally?  Anyhow, I&amp;rsquo;ve got the privacy statement all linked up into the sign up page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="sign up page with privacy link" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ggj4vgtqytlm5jp/Screenshot%202017-07-11%2009.34.22.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I think the page looks pretty good.  We previously fixed up the icons and made both signup methods work, so the only garish thing remaining is this email signup disabled.  I found there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href="https://github.com/plataformatec/devise/wiki/How-To:-Use-Recaptcha-with-Devise"&gt;plugin for devise to add Google&amp;rsquo;s re-captcha&lt;/a&gt;.  Working through it I got stuck with the configuration, but fixed it and put in a PR to the repo with the fix:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/ambethia/recaptcha/pull/231&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and so was rewarded with seeing the following in my local spike:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="first pass at adding recaptcha" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/fxj5vfx9wzj5sb3/Screenshot%202017-07-11%2009.54.23.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but while I could click on the I&amp;rsquo;m not a robot, I got &amp;ldquo;verification failed&amp;rdquo; after signup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="verification failed" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/bieuh1rayk3l9i7/Screenshot%202017-07-11%2009.55.37.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the log was telling me was: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Filter chain halted as :check_captcha rendered or redirected
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added byebug to the check_captcha method I&amp;rsquo;d added to the registrations controller:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class="n"&gt;prepend_before_action&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;:check_captcha&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;only: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:create&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; 

  &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;super&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;unless&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="vi"&gt;@user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;new_record?&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="n"&gt;session&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:omniauth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kp"&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="n"&gt;flash&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:user_signup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Signed up successfully.'&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="no"&gt;Mailer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;send_welcome_message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="vi"&gt;@user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;deliver_now&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;enabled?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:welcome_email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;


  &lt;span class="kp"&gt;private&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;check_captcha&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;byebug&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;unless&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;verify_recaptcha&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="nb"&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;resource&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;resource_class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;sign_up_params&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="n"&gt;resource&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;validate&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Look for any other validation errors besides Recaptcha&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="n"&gt;respond_with_navigational&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;resource&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;render&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;:new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stepping through the code there made it look like the verification was failing - nothing else wrong.  The &lt;code&gt;verify_recaptcha&lt;/code&gt; method was returning false &amp;hellip; Not sure what&amp;rsquo;s going wrong there and I have the sinking feeling that adding the captcha as I have may screw up the other signup methods.  We&amp;rsquo;ll see.  First I just need proof positive that we can get it work at all &amp;hellip; It may be that I just can&amp;rsquo;t run it locally like this - I added the &lt;code&gt;localhost&lt;/code&gt; domain to the domains associated with keys to run locally, but maybe there&amp;rsquo;s more needed to run locally.  I can see that there&amp;rsquo;s a domain name verification setting in the reCaptcha settings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="recaptcha settings" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/53j9mi92omzrls9/Screenshot%202017-07-11%2010.04.42.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just trying a re-start and another step through &amp;hellip; which seemed to work without any changes.  Hmm, maybe the restart did it &amp;hellip; I also played with the layout to make it all look a little better:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="new layout" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/la5kden3qy8zsb1/Screenshot%202017-07-11%2010.12.41.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which I assume didn&amp;rsquo;t actually change things.  Test again without the byebug &amp;hellip; and that works although I note I get two &amp;ldquo;signed up successfully messages&amp;rdquo; - tried to screen shot, but they fade out a little fast, would like to fix that.  Also I get nicely redirected to the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page.  Okay, well that&amp;rsquo;s the spike - sure it breaks lots of things, but might as well push that up as a spike PR so see how it all runs on CI.  Guess we&amp;rsquo;ll need sandboxing &amp;hellip;?  Look at that tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV Website Review Part 4</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/10/av-website-review-part-four/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/10/av-website-review-part-four/</id>
    <published>2017-07-10T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-03T21:41:18+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="conflicted" src="/images/conflicted.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m conflicted about what to review on the website next.  Part of me wants to start breaking the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page up into pieces, and showing animated gifs for each.  There&amp;rsquo;s also the &amp;ldquo;About Us&amp;rdquo; page and the need for privacy statement pages.  We&amp;rsquo;ve also got all the text in the &amp;ldquo;Learn&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Code&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Pair&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Grow&amp;rdquo; sections, but I can also sense many other strands of the web attached there.  The presense of the &amp;ldquo;Email Registrations are temporarily disabled&amp;rdquo; on the &amp;ldquo;Sign up&amp;rdquo; page kind of bothers me.  It feels like it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a running sore.  That said, no one has complained about it explicitly recently.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We disabled the email registrations a couple of years ago when we were experiencing heavy spam sign ups.  In my &amp;ldquo;simplest first&amp;rdquo; doctrine I suggested just turning it off.  Others did suggest adding captchas and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t enthusiastic because I felt it was a kind of arms race and that we would be adding more functionality that we would have to maintain.  Maybe that was a mistake and I should have encouraged whoever was suggesting the captcha to implement one.  Recently my opinion is evolving. I turned on a &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/recaptcha/intro/"&gt;captcha system&lt;/a&gt; to protect our NHS HLP wiki from spambot sign ups.  It was a pretty straightforward configuration and it seems to have been completely successful in blocking the spam bots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thought I have for the sign up page is that by forcing people to sign up via either GitHub or Google, we ensure that more members have already completed the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; step 1 (sign up for GitHub) that I recently removed from the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page.  Ironically the Google sign up is now sort of redundant since the main reason we wanted to offer that was to enable us to connect people&amp;rsquo;s Google profiles to the data coming back from the Google Hangout plugin.  Since Google retired the API for that plugin 3 months ago we&amp;rsquo;re not getting any telemetry on who starts or joins Hangouts, and we&amp;rsquo;re in the process of looking at how to move over to Jitsi, which uses Gravatar rather than Google Plus.  So what direction does that push us in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should we drop the Google sign up?  Re-enable the email signup?  From a user point of view we should be providing the sign up options that are most convenient to the user.  We could be providing Twitter and Facebook login; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a priority, but having user accounts attached to their various social media identities might be useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most glaring issue on the Sign up page is the reference to the &amp;ldquo;Privacy statement&amp;rdquo; when we don&amp;rsquo;t actually have one.  I think the priority has to be that privacy statement and then linking it up.  I&amp;rsquo;m also tempted to work on the captcha component so we can remove the increasingly erroneous &amp;ldquo;temporarily disabled&amp;rdquo; - apparently there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href="https://github.com/plataformatec/devise/wiki/How-To:-Use-Recaptcha-with-Devise"&gt;gem&lt;/a&gt; that would allow us to integrate recaptcha with Devise.  Of course that&amp;rsquo;s all part of training Google&amp;rsquo;s AIs, but can we really fight that flow?  There&amp;rsquo;s also the concern that we&amp;rsquo;re not pushing people to get GitHub accounts, but I guess it&amp;rsquo;s better to get as many signed up as possible &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve created a &lt;a href="https://www.agileventures.org/privacy"&gt;privacy policy page&lt;/a&gt; based on the one we have for the NHS wiki.  Now I just need a pull request to link that into the footer and the Sign Up page &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV Website Review Part 3</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/07/av-website-review-part-three/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/07/av-website-review-part-three/</id>
    <published>2017-07-07T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-29T21:18:10+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Still struggling to get back to former health and energy levels.  Pleased to have reviewed and made some changes to the website.  Let&amp;rsquo;s continue.  Looking at &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; yesterday made me think about the projects page again.  Effectively the new &amp;ldquo;step 1&amp;rdquo; of &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; is a view of the projects that we don&amp;rsquo;t have, i.e. one with project maintainers, tech stacks and links to relevant Slack channels.  There have been recent improvements to the project page, specifically that the main list is now ordered by most recently active on Github, so there is a sense in which the main ordering of the projects is by most active (although it&amp;rsquo;s not clear that that&amp;rsquo;s the ordering) and we&amp;rsquo;ve adjusted the smaller list on the left to be alphabetical (and so consistently ordered), as well as filtering for inactive projects. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that people arriving on the page have much clarity about what&amp;rsquo;s going on.  We also have the issue that projects with attached images have those images very large and overly dominate the page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/3p6c4ginnxghgdo/Screenshot%202017-07-07%2010.13.22.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like just setting a smaller width on that could address that issue &amp;hellip; and yes, done that; added pull request.  Also noticed that actually we didn&amp;rsquo;t need to crimp the width per se - the bootstrap row/column setting was out of alignment - the column values adding up to 22 rather than 12.  So with a few changes the main project page for Wiki Edu now looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/873yfege210c0n0/Screenshot%202017-07-07%2010.31.40.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what I really wanted to do while blogging this was to work through all the projects in the left hand list and de-activate those that aren&amp;rsquo;t really doing anything at the moment.  I guess I will just blast through that. The other thing I wanted to address was how this layout doesn&amp;rsquo;t really have much precedence in other sites.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know that we are using the layout language that people are familiar with from elsewhere on the web.  Ironically it was just when I took over the project management role that the previous maintainer was trying to get in the project page redesign that had been under way for a long time, but he backed out of that, getting busy with other things and perhaps frustrated that I was asking him to submit pull requests that were super-focused on specific changes, rather than rolling in a collection of things that were unrelated to the main ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps that was a major mistake on my part.  I thought I was bringing in best-practices from other projects that I had worked on, but perhaps we lost a lot of work that could have leapt us forward in terms of the project page layout?  Michael and I chose to focus on the events pages for the main work we did when we first got involved.  To me there were screaming inconsistencies there that needed to be fixed first, but who knows what was the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; thing to have done.  We did what we did, making our best judgements, given the information available at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A layout that was a series of boxes, or rows in the table, would seem to make more sense than two separate lists where the ordering is somewhat unclear. Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://projects.saas-class.org/projects"&gt;past project showcase&lt;/a&gt; has a more comprehensible layout in some ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/tzf8s3mfpeqzujc/Screenshot%202017-07-07%2010.02.14.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They had another system for future projects that also had a layout that made more sense.  Just looking around I found a great &lt;a href="http://cs169.saas-class.org/faq/external-customer"&gt;guide they have for external &amp;ldquo;customers&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, and a group of Berkeley students called &lt;a href="https://www.calblueprint.org/"&gt;&amp;ldquo;BluePrint&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; doing the same thing as AgileVentures.  Frustratingly I can&amp;rsquo;t find the portal that the CS169 class uses to allow students to select upcoming projects.  I&amp;rsquo;ve emailed Armando to ask if that&amp;rsquo;s still around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I note we&amp;rsquo;ve got a &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1089"&gt;project improvements epic ticket&lt;/a&gt;.  Lots of things to keep trying and improving &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. just went and set all projects to &amp;ldquo;inactive&amp;rdquo; and am working through re-activating the ones I know that have activity &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV Website Review Part 2</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/06/av-website-review-part-two/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/06/av-website-review-part-two/</id>
    <published>2017-07-06T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-28T21:23:26+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m deeply tempted to continue with the premium page review.  I think making all the new questions have their explanations in pop-out form would probably be an improvement, but I know that&amp;rsquo;s a sticky hour or so of manipulating HTML.  Very unDRY, something we could, or perhaps should, be doing with a DB backed loop through a template, but setting up (and deploying that) would be another few hours and days.  I&amp;rsquo;m leaning towards further review of the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page, although we did make a change to that on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s too early to tell if those changes have had any impact.  We can look for changes via Google Analytics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/yyyf9ykhy0tc68u/Screenshot%202017-07-06%2009.17.13.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and compare Monday to Wednesday last week, with Monday to Wednesday this week.  The number of clicks through WebSiteOne has gone down, although we can see it went up for some other projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/39tiao9ajhshqib/Screenshot%202017-07-06%2009.18.11.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far too early to discern any trend.  I guess the question is whether to leave that single change (of removing the first two administrative steps) or to keep on &amp;ldquo;improving&amp;rdquo; the page.  Same quandry with the Premium page, I guess.  Just reviewing that now, I made some minor changes to the top of the page to remove the seemingly redundant link to &amp;ldquo;AgileVentures Premium&amp;rdquo; and an explanation text saying &amp;ldquo;the benefits are as follows&amp;rdquo; that seem to make no sense now that we have a list of questions.  Let&amp;rsquo;s at least do a sanity check on what we have in the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page.  So, step 1 currently says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browse the list of AgileVentures projects on agileventures.org, or the active projects listed in the table below, and learn more about the projects that interest you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can always set-up your own project, but we would recommend joining an existing one at first. This way you can meet other members, learn about our culture, principles and tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the odd thing is that we say browse the list of projects, but we don&amp;rsquo;t link there, and I could impulsively link that up, but would we rather the user focuses on the list of projects shown below?  The key thing we have in this list is the technologies used by the projects, the current maintainers and direct links to the relevant slack channels.  Of course it would be great if the main projects page showed all these things.  I&amp;rsquo;m thinking that a slimmed down more focused version of the above text would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find a project that interests you from the table below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the table, and then notes on &amp;ldquo;can&amp;rsquo;t find a project you like, see our complete list&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;want to set up your own project&amp;rdquo; after the table itself and also we could improve the table formatting somehow &amp;hellip; so I pushed the width out to 100%, increased the font size, bolded the headings and added a couple of other active projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/66ss4bwklwf5may/Screenshot%202017-07-06%2009.52.21.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as well as further cleaning up the text a little.  Reading through the rest of the getting started I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m reading a decsription of how some of the original developers intended the entire site to work.  There are cryptic references to WSO and other things that I think will make little sense.  Even after a few tidy ups what we have in step 2 is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how we communicate and coordinate projects:
* source code is kept in Github repos
* user stories (feature descriptions) are kept in project&amp;rsquo;s Pivotal Tracker (or other tracking systems)
* other documentation and detailed feature descriptions are kept in project&amp;rsquo;s section on agileventures.org
* real time discussion are done in Slack channels, in the specific channel for the project
* long-term discussions (where it is important to preserve history) are done on Pivotal Tracker, or in Github pull requests/issues or by commenting under specific documents in project&amp;rsquo;s section on agileventures.org 
* optionally recordings of PairProgramming sessions and standups are stored on YouTube. The list of videos for a specific project is under project&amp;rsquo;s section on agileventures.org
* technical information on the project is kept in documents under project&amp;rsquo;s section on agileventures.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all information that we want new members to absorb, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that many people will read and absorb.  We probably need to break this up into multiple steps (just like FreeCodeCamp) and have an activity associated with each.  Again it would be lovely to track people&amp;rsquo;s progress through this - I recall FreeCodeCamp has a separate page with an animated gif for each action, so they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to track with Google Analytics how far people are getting through the process.  Giving the user themselves a sense of progress through the task would also be great, as would having buttons that made it trivial to post a question to a project maintainer in the relevant slack channel (a bit like LinkedIn does to make it easy to send messages of a particular format).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course with all these different ideas there&amp;rsquo;s the question of which are the ones that are really worth pursuing.  I did get set up a few months back with being able to make nice animated gifs.   A nice animated gif of reaching out to a project maintainer and having them respond in a friendly fashion would probably be much more asorbable by lots of people than the current text of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Contacts&amp;rdquo; column contains the &amp;ldquo;Slack name&amp;rdquo; of one or more people that can help orient you to the project.&lt;br&gt;
Use this name to alert that person to a specific message when you post to the project slack channel.  For example, say you want to post a message to the MetPlus project channel, and make sure that &amp;ldquo;patrick&amp;rdquo; is aware of that message.  Here, you would go to the channel (and join the channel), and send a message like this:
&amp;ldquo;@patrick - hi, I am new to agile ventures and I would like to learn more about this project.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;patrick&amp;rdquo; will then be alerted to your message and respond back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;rsquo;s all question of where to expend the effort &amp;hellip;?  Once people have left the getting started page will they come back to follow through the steps?  Perhaps not, unless they are marking off progress.  It makes me want to split the getting-started pages into Step 1 (of 5), Step 2 (of 5), &amp;hellip; Step 5 (of 5) so that there&amp;rsquo;s much less text per individual page, and so that we can see the flow of people from page to page.  Of course a lot of this points to the need for a re-design of the project page, which we&amp;rsquo;ve thought we&amp;rsquo;ve needed for a long time.  There&amp;rsquo;s also the automated greeter bot in Slack, which I need to move to Azure, and make sure others can deploy to and change.  That greeter bot would ideally point people back to the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page, rather than off to GitHub as it does currently &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I think that&amp;rsquo;s the course I wanted to be on with these blogs.  Careful review of various pages in the site.  Set up an experiment on each, come back and review in a month to see what impact there&amp;rsquo;s been.  There&amp;rsquo;s certainly a good few other pages I can review over the course of the next month, e.g. the home page, the about page, the projects page, the event page, the opportunities page, the past scrums page, all the individual project pages &amp;hellip; the list goes on &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV Website Review Part 1</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/05/av-website-review-part-one/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/05/av-website-review-part-one/</id>
    <published>2017-07-05T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-27T21:12:10+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="new dawn" src="/images/new_dawn.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, new dawn.  I could be blogging about all the conversations we had about testing yesterday, but my new resolution is to get the AV website sorted out in terms of usability, readability and user flow one day at a time.  Immediately I&amp;rsquo;m torn between two sections.  There&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page that people either browse to, or get redirected to after sign in.  After discussions in the AV community meeting on Monday I removed the first two sections of that document:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-05%2009.29.00.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two sections are all things we&amp;rsquo;d like users to do, i.e. get set up with GitHub and Slack (and other things), but the danger is that the very first thing we are doing is directing folks away from our site.  The likelihood is that they signed up via GitHub and they&amp;rsquo;ve received a Slack invite.  It&amp;rsquo;s all very well asking folks to work through a set of administrative tasks when they are a &amp;ldquo;captive&amp;rdquo; audience, such as having already paid to take a class, but, really, we need to get people as quickly as possible to the higher engagement, fun activities, such as looking through the different active projects.  Anyway, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t belabour the point, but it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to look at the flow through from Google Analytics for this page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-04%2012.01.38.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we see there is a lot of drop offs and not many people clicking through on individual project pages.  The text associated with the first two &amp;ldquo;administrative&amp;rdquo; sections was forcing the table of active projects &amp;ldquo;below the fold&amp;rdquo;, i.e. making it something that people would have to scroll to get to.  Even so, the Google Analytics plugin for Chrome shows us what percentage of people are clicking through on which projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-05%2009.35.10.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So anyway, I removed the first two sections and we&amp;rsquo;ll see if there is any change.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s still room to reduce the amount of text, improve the layout and add graphics through this document, and so I&amp;rsquo;m torn about making more significant changes.  Particularly since it will take some weeks before we can really tell if there&amp;rsquo;s a difference.  We had 168 visits to the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page in the last month.  In addition I also want to make progress on the Premium page.  Previously Matt and I had worked on things so that when signed in users clicked on &amp;ldquo;Upgrade to Premium for additional support&amp;rdquo; on the home page, that instead of going to the payment page (with no information about Premium), it went to the description page for Premium, which made a lot more sense to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s functionality in the Google Analytics Chrome plugin to compare a period with the previous month, and I can see that there&amp;rsquo;s been a small increase in people clicking on the &amp;ldquo;Upgrade to Premium for additional support&amp;rdquo;.  We just redesigned the banner, but that only just went live, so we don&amp;rsquo;t have a clear indication for that increase:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-05%2009.48.57.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking through at the Premium description page we can now see some changes.  We adjusted the flow on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/commit/1af6bfe440133e4ade2b08e6fc7b8703825ec2b6"&gt;18th of May&lt;/a&gt;, and we can now see that the click through on &amp;ldquo;Get Started with Premium&amp;rdquo; has increased from 11% to 15% compared with the same period previously:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-05%2009.55.37.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the difficulty is that that change could just be due to a trend that we would have seen anyway, and also we don&amp;rsquo;t know that all those clicks are coming in via the new flow.  Users can reach this page by coming in through the pricing page, but having more people click on &amp;ldquo;Getting started with Premium&amp;rdquo; certainly feels like we are going in the right direction.  What&amp;rsquo;s frustrating is that we don&amp;rsquo;t have more info about what&amp;rsquo;s happening on this page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-05%2009.59.16.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Google analytics plugin is silent on the numbers of folks clicking on the subscribe buttons.  PayPal redirects to another site, while Stripe uses JavaScript to popup a credit card form.  I spent a chunk of time trying to see if I could see the flow around that page in the main Google Analytics site, but this was as close as I got:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-05%2010.15.30.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the exits could be people going to the PayPal page, but it&amp;rsquo;s unclear.  It makes me want to put the Chatlio &amp;ldquo;any questions&amp;rdquo; element in the site so that there&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity for people to tell us what they&amp;rsquo;re thinking as they browse the page.  Hmm, well I&amp;rsquo;ve burnt a lot of time reviewing the analytics and not a lot of time getting on to what I thought was my main thrust today, which is this rewording of the Premium description &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d posted some thoughts on that into a &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1583#issuecomment-310992734"&gt;WSO issue&lt;/a&gt; where Ashley had made a great point about how these new re-wordings didn&amp;rsquo;t include the term &amp;ldquo;Agile&amp;rdquo;.  What&amp;rsquo;s interesting is that in breaking out separate items to give support on, we lose sight of the bigger Agile picture.  Michael had mentioned that getting quick feedback on pull requests is crucial for Agile, but it&amp;rsquo;s also the case that the main &amp;ldquo;Agile&amp;rdquo; things that we offer, such as working with a team, doing scrums, retros, kick-offs, sprints etc. are not something that the Premium offering particularly supports - or at least not in its current form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes me think about things like having specific features like Sprint or retrospective support.  Of course that&amp;rsquo;s not as easy to break out as something that can be offered to Premium&amp;rsquo;s on a 121 basis without the associated selection of a project, introduction to the team etc. etc.  I have ideas about people signing up for a one off &amp;ldquo;sprint support package&amp;rdquo; at some higher price point, but there&amp;rsquo;s a ways to go there for that to make sense &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So anyhow, here&amp;rsquo;s another pass at questions for the Premium page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to find great developer jobs? Get help on the job search process?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to ace technical tests required to get interviews?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to accelerate your professional development?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to improve your coding and development skills?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to really understand Agile software development?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to put paid coding projects on your resume?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to make the world the better place?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to feel confident asking technical questions online?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to get discounts on important software and services for developers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I&amp;rsquo;ve now gone ahead and updated the Premium page using them and reworded the descriptions to make sense.  I think I could also be adjusting the full details to be popping up like we have in the FAQ, but I think this is enough for today.  The interesting thing will be to see if this has any noticeable impact on the click through rates or the number of people signing up &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. Side note, since shortening the text in the &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; page and adding a call to action &amp;ldquo;get started now&amp;rdquo; button, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen a good third of the people landing on the page clicking through on the &amp;ldquo;get started now&amp;rdquo; button.  Not that that says very much - what would be good to be seeing is month by month stats of footfall and percentage of people on the site actually signing up &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
