<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-10-02T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>The pilot+copilot organizational pattern</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/10/02/pilot-copilot-organizational-pattern/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/10/02/pilot-copilot-organizational-pattern/</id>
    <published>2017-10-02T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-04T21:52:30+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="pair flying" src="/images/pairflying.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2002, I graduated a distance-learning masters in applied mathematics. Every month, the university mailed me an A4 enveloppe containing the course support. I was supposed to learn from the course material and returned the completed assignments within a month. A month later, I would receive an answer key. Should I have a question, I could mail it to the professor and wait for his reply. The whole process was cumbersome. I was often behind schedule. Interactivity was near to zero. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on, I participated in the MOOC endeavour. The video of the instructor gave a feeling of a one-to-one training session. Discussion forums, deadlines, follow-up mails, peer-reviews grounded the learning process. There were meetups too. And a MOOC about Agile Development using Ruby On Rails offered remote pair-programming sessions between participants. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pair-programmming reuses the rather old organizational pattern of pilot+copilot : double-check, higher focusing, external view, and stronger engagement. You may object that programming is very different from flying. Yes, it is! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But programming requires a strong level of accuracy too. Your pairing fellow is both a watch dog that tells you not to call a library without checking how it works, not to cut and paste code across your work, and an inspiration to experiment with new ways of coding. As some aerobatic aircrafts don&amp;rsquo;t include a copilot seat, some programs are implemented by lone wolves in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools like teamviewer, logmein, skype, hangout or joinme have been instrumental to the success of remote pair working. There is still room for improvement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) In a face-to-face meeting, there is a desk between the two interlocutors. Webcams should recreate this confortable spacing. I&amp;rsquo;m neither a barber nor a dental professional!
2) Remote working platforms lack of interoperability. Some only run on Windows, some require to install a software, others are more suitable for mobile use&amp;hellip; and don&amp;rsquo;t try to connect to hangout with skype
3) Security is a weak point for all of these platforms. Choosing which window you share, which you don&amp;rsquo;t, masking your passwords or your personal information are not intuitive. In my earlier days, I remembered displaying my passwords on a recorded session. Not so good a security practice!
4) Optimizing the screen definition so that everybody can watch comfortably is not supported either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every desktop application from IDE to word processors will probably include some kind of remote pair working feature sooner or later. C9 already includes some simple pair-programming features, for instance.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bugs in the code? Don&amp;rsquo;t blame me, it&amp;rsquo;s my pair programming partner who fooled around!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Another free refill?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/22/another-free-refill/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/22/another-free-refill/</id>
    <published>2017-09-22T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-27T21:07:18+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="free refill" src="/images/freerefill.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I undertook a training session targeting small business manager to teach them how to improve profitability of business projects. The course instructor showed us a rather clear way to deal with profitabiliy. First, you estimate your break-even hourly rate, based on your history. Then, you don&amp;rsquo;t sell any project under the bottom line. After that, you prioritize your work to put the highest priority on the most profitable projects. Finally, you keep any accepted project above the bottom line. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is quite simple. It&amp;rsquo;s all down to the execution. I began to schedule my workday according to business priorities preferably to a sense of urgency that overcame me before. Then, everytime I felt I was at risk to hit the bottom line, I shifted my attention towards what I really sold to the client annd I reduced my objectives accordingly. Finally, I was trying to become a project reviewer for a well known MOOC platform. But the hourly rate was much too low. I felt relief to drop my candidature. Paid projects management improved greatly. But, a significant part of my workday, dedicated to volunteer projects, was out of the scope of this effort.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many commitments, workaholism, things we begin and we never achieve, any freelance worker faces these contradictions. The inherent contradiction is even stronger when you work on non-paid project. How to prioritize your volunteer works?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten working hours a day is my upper limit, considering that I&amp;rsquo;m not a computer nerd, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a family, hobbies, and a social life &amp;hellip; I was already busy ten hours a day. Adding anything to my schedule implied removing something else. I have been more or less active on professional social networks for three years. I first thought this commitment would improve my reputation and fuel my prospect pipeline. But in three years, the return was not very encouraging. I felt that my social network activity was fueled by bitterness or anxiety or ego or the three rather than by a clear sense of business opportunity! I decided to forget social networks. Two to three hours a week were freed thanks to this good resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to devote these hours to Agile Venture mob programming sessions. It&amp;rsquo;s a real community, with real developers. You can both learn by observing how skilled developers work and by doing things by yourself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still in the midstream of my prioritization effort. I&amp;rsquo;ve been very actively participating in MOOCs for five years. My skills greatly improved as a result of this effort.  But choosing which courses to invest on is not easy. Knowledge is a bit like indirects costs. You don&amp;rsquo;t really know how to assign it to your achievements. During the first years, the offer flourished. I tried many courses, from Economy to Computer Sciences. I progressively focused on Computer Science and left courses as they switched to paid offers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was giving up, a prominent MOOC platform offers me to beta-test courses for free. Free refill is the end of resolution and the beginning of passive hyperactivity! You may begin your training week with a course on Embedded systems and end, on friday, with a course on PythonML on friday, without completing any. Does it make sense to participate in a mob programming session about RSPEC on monday, another one about phoenix on wednesday, on the last one about React on friday, when you only need to develop a small web app with React?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AgileVenture Premium Mob includes some kind of Professional Development Planning Support. I may ask the team to help me clean my training plan. But I&amp;rsquo;m still afraid they will tell me to stop learning Tensor Flow or the nitty gritty of Intel Parallel Architecture if I don&amp;rsquo;t have any prospect to work in these fields in the next year! &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review More Greetings</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/04/av-ecosystem-review-more-greetings/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/04/av-ecosystem-review-more-greetings/</id>
    <published>2017-09-04T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-31T20:36:55+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Got my jogging and podcasting/tweeting done this AM, but kids still off school, which means I&amp;rsquo;m late to the keyboard.  Lots to do - low hanging fruit is probably other changes to the greeter bots.  The change I rolled out on Friday seems to be working; that&amp;rsquo;s the quick fix to ensure that channel names are hyperlinked in messages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-09-04%2010.16.25.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I guess I should get that merged into master, and I can probably kick through the other minor changes there &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve merged the license and code of conduct pull requests that I had outstanding.  So I punted on the code of conduct in the greeter bot, posting the following to our AV community channel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we&amp;rsquo;ve been discussing codes of conduct before and I know that various projects have them now, following GitHub&amp;rsquo;s lead of making them really easy to add.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard any objections yet, and I just added them as a recommendation in our &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m planning to add mention of them to our Slack greeter bot https://github.com/AgileVentures/greeter&lt;em&gt;bot/issues/6 but I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just check in with the community again before moving on that.  Would be good to discuss in a community meeting - which perhaps we should move to Fridays &amp;hellip; anyhow more on meeting times soon, but very interested in any input anyone cares to share here, or feel free to DM me directly :slightly&lt;/em&gt;smiling_face:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I got hyperlinks to our Premium mob offer and the user name in the main greeting bot, and pushed those live from a branch. I&amp;rsquo;m really promising myself that the next step is testing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before that I can&amp;rsquo;t help myself but try and get the names and channels linked up in the project greeter bot, so I went ahead and did that and ended up doing a quick manual test on the now un-used AV mentors slack instance, that allowed for a quick round of debugging.  Gosh I&amp;rsquo;m really not setting this up to allow for easy-onboarding of others - will need a big documentation effort to get folks into the new AV bot testing slack instance &amp;hellip; can&amp;rsquo;t help myself but get these quick fixes out first - actually make it so that there will be the equivalent of a ping to the project maintainers on channel join - or at least see if hyperlinking their name in the bot post has that effect &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Greetings and Meetings</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/01/av-ecosystem-review-greetings-and-meetings/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/01/av-ecosystem-review-greetings-and-meetings/</id>
    <published>2017-09-01T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-30T21:00:35+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="meeting" src="/images/meeting.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set the alarm this morning but still a late start as all my boys wanted help with their codecombat programming challenges, and they&amp;rsquo;re still off school for the summer.  Anyhow, there are several niggling things about the various greeter bots we have for AgileVentures and individual channels.  I&amp;rsquo;ve directed a few people to the #bots channel to get involved, but so far no one has gotten very far.  Is there some critical mass of activity on a project, or some critical level of support that&amp;rsquo;s required before some people will start submitting code?  One comment I had was that these bots are just tiny nodejs projects.  I guess for those wanting to cut their teeth on open source node projects a challengingly complex project is appealing in some sense.  Personally I have had just about enough of complexity and the simpler the better.  The key metric for me continues to be can we deliver something of value to the end user?  It&amp;rsquo;s whether the project delivers something of value to someone somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was really simple this week was setting up Slack repeating reminders so that we get alerts about when the scrums are upcoming, some project meetings and some mobs.  The syntax is super simple, e.g. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/remind #localsupport to prepare for weekly meeting @here in 30 minutes at 4:00pm every Thursday 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exciting thing with the new fixed URL videoconferencing from Jitsi is that the meeting ping, itself, can be set as a recurriung reminder:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/remind #localsupport to join the weekly meeting @here in http://meet.jit.si at 4:30pm every Thursday 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thinking to make my participation in the project meetings a biweekly thing, so that I can get private project work done on the &amp;ldquo;off-weeks&amp;rdquo; so to speak.  My only complaint is that the reminders aren&amp;rsquo;t directly editable. However they are easily listable and deletable.  I also see that they can be controlled by API:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://api.slack.com/methods/reminders.list"&gt;https://api.slack.com/methods/reminders.list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That makes me think we could possibly take the agile-bot out of the equation by simply having our main site hit Slack directly to set reminders based on events created or updated through the Rails interface &amp;hellip;  By having set up the LocalSupport meeting to rely on a permanent Jitsi URL, we take the need for a really experienced scrum master to start the videoconference out of the equation, and in principle anyone can stream the recording - although that is more fiddly in Jitsi.  It does seem like Jitsi performance might not be as good as Hangouts, particularly since they&amp;rsquo;re offering their new low latency setting, but I guess we should experiment with our own Jitsi hosting on Azure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s all very well for maintaining the run of existing projects, but that&amp;rsquo;s not going to immediately help with getting more folks involved in the greeter bots (or other new projects), or make the greeter bots seem a little more friendly.  Maybe I would be better off labelling them specifically as bots.  For the main project greeter, if I don&amp;rsquo;t have the message come from me, then I don&amp;rsquo;t get to see the response that people make to the bot.  In the group channels, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of weird to have an automated message from me when I&amp;rsquo;m inviting someone in for a vote.  What I really want to move towards is some kind of drip campaign that follows up with people who&amp;rsquo;ve joined project channels (and our community) to ask them if they need help and support.  I notice that Slack follows up with multiple emails after the fact when you&amp;rsquo;ve been invited to a Slack community, presumably to maximize the chances of getting new users into Slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the main greeter bot I&amp;rsquo;ve got four little changes to tick off:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hyperlinking to our free premium mob page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding mention of our code of conduct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;referring to the new person by name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hyperlinking to channel names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the project greeter bot I&amp;rsquo;ve got lots of issues, but my top ones are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;names of folks in message not being linked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;channel names not being linked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid reposting the intro if we&amp;rsquo;ve recently done so&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last would go a long way to making the bot seem more human, but it would also require the most complexity, i.e. some state would need to be held, or we&amp;rsquo;d need to pull messages out of the channel to check for recent posts.  That latter seems simpler, but also something that we should try after wrapping all this in tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m conflicted here - maybe the thing that would get more people involved would be making super-polished documentation on all this, or creatingnew project channels - project placeholders in our main site and getting started pages; but the itch I want to scratch is a few formatting issues, and also ensuring we have a global code of conduct in place (which should go in the getting started as well &amp;hellip;).  I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll let myself hit those issues first &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just picked off hyperlinking channels in the main greeter bot, and pushed that branch to production - hmm, no staging set up there - not so easy to test even on the bot-test instance I created - unless creating new accounts - can do &amp;hellip; should get set up with that properly.  Linking to channels and users from bot posts does seem like a relatively straightforward syntax fix:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://api.slack.com/docs/message-formatting#linking_to_channels_and_users"&gt;https://api.slack.com/docs/message-formatting#linking&lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt;channels&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt;users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gonna stop there today since I&amp;rsquo;m behind and hopefully this will give me impetus to get the few other rough edges sorted before the big push, which is setting up some proper testing infrastructure on these projects &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Behind Schedule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/08/31/av-ecosystem-review-behind-schedule/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/08/31/av-ecosystem-review-behind-schedule/</id>
    <published>2017-08-31T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-19T21:07:28+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="rush" src="/images/rush.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Woke up late, behind schedule.  Kids are off school, so helping them with Japanese and coding homework in the morning can easily burn time.  Feel like I&amp;rsquo;m crazily juggling private projects and catch up with all the AgileVentures projects.  Reality is that with the mobs, marketing meetings, and project meetings for AutoGraders, WSO, LocalSupport, and AsyncVoter that&amp;rsquo;s already a completely full week for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So not really time to review anything in the AV ecosystem extensively this morning.  I&amp;rsquo;m thinking I might have to put the project meetings on a fortnightly schedule in order to focus on private projects in the off weeks.  Yesterday I was so rushed I didn&amp;rsquo;t really consult my action plan and totally missed updating the #general channel with the day&amp;rsquo;s schedule for AV.  Maybe I should automate that &amp;hellip; There&amp;rsquo;s something comforting about the semi-automated approach where there&amp;rsquo;s still some manual involvement as it allows me to make tweaks at the last minute, but really got to automate as much admin as possible.  The repeating slack reminders do seem really helpful - would love to be able to update them programmatically from WSO, but at the moment, the trade off is between the time spent automating any indiviudual task and then just getting it done in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The WSO fixes for the scrum updates don&amp;rsquo;t seem to have worked, urgh.  I guess the most I can do right now is push live the &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; page changes that I made yesterday and move on.  Got to have some kind of focus on simplify, automate, eliminate, delegate over the coming weeks to get this ship back in shape &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review One Step at a Time</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/08/30/av-ecosystem-review-one-step-at-a-time/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/08/30/av-ecosystem-review-one-step-at-a-time/</id>
    <published>2017-08-30T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-18T21:30:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="one step duckling" src="/images/one_step_duckling.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gablurgh &amp;hellip; full day yesterday &amp;hellip; slow start today.  Let&amp;rsquo;s put the reviewing older posts and changes to the side for the moment and put down some more changes to the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page that we can review again in a month to see the effect.  So right now we have the following steps in &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a project that interests you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how we communicate and coordinate projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up development environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a closer look at chosen projects documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join a standup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start contributing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Optional) Start your own project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a low impact way for me to explore breaking these up is to create separate pages for each.  There&amp;rsquo;s also considering the order that we have here, and whether we should add or remove things.  What could be cool is a clear call to action on each element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finding a project that interests you seems like a reasonable start assuming that folks have basically got the idea that AgileVentures is all about joining teams and participating in projects.  We&amp;rsquo;ve got a custom table here that highlights our top projects, and also shows the primary technologies, and lead contact name, which is something that is missing from our project page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment step two is a list of stuff with no clear action for the member reading the section.  It&amp;rsquo;s potentially useful information about where things are found.  Is this the critical second step?  Do we derive any value from trying to get folks to read this here?  Or is it just a wall of text where we lose people?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things on my wishlist looking over this page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) contact name is a hyperlink to that person
b) technologies are dynamically pulled from GitHub
c) table of contents to let folks know what&amp;rsquo;s coming
d) text under table of projects to include image, or animated gif, of saying hello in Slack
e) good tracking from step to step
f) clear calls to action &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still maybe the simplest thing is to create pages like &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.agileventures.org/getting-started-2"&gt;https://www.agileventures.org/getting-started-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.agileventures.org/getting-started-3"&gt;https://www.agileventures.org/getting-started-3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.agileventures.org/getting-started-4"&gt;https://www.agileventures.org/getting-started-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.agileventures.org/getting-started-1"&gt;https://www.agileventures.org/getting-started-1&lt;/a&gt; could be an alternate mockup that I could share with key members for feedback &amp;hellip; okay all done.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll release this live yet - let&amp;rsquo;s see what folks in #av&lt;em&gt;community&lt;/em&gt;talk say first &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.agileventures.org/getting-started-1"&gt;https://www.agileventures.org/getting-started-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
