<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-10-02T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>The pilot+copilot organizational pattern</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/10/02/pilot-copilot-organizational-pattern/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/10/02/pilot-copilot-organizational-pattern/</id>
    <published>2017-10-02T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-04T21:52:30+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="pair flying" src="/images/pairflying.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2002, I graduated a distance-learning masters in applied mathematics. Every month, the university mailed me an A4 enveloppe containing the course support. I was supposed to learn from the course material and returned the completed assignments within a month. A month later, I would receive an answer key. Should I have a question, I could mail it to the professor and wait for his reply. The whole process was cumbersome. I was often behind schedule. Interactivity was near to zero. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on, I participated in the MOOC endeavour. The video of the instructor gave a feeling of a one-to-one training session. Discussion forums, deadlines, follow-up mails, peer-reviews grounded the learning process. There were meetups too. And a MOOC about Agile Development using Ruby On Rails offered remote pair-programming sessions between participants. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pair-programmming reuses the rather old organizational pattern of pilot+copilot : double-check, higher focusing, external view, and stronger engagement. You may object that programming is very different from flying. Yes, it is! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But programming requires a strong level of accuracy too. Your pairing fellow is both a watch dog that tells you not to call a library without checking how it works, not to cut and paste code across your work, and an inspiration to experiment with new ways of coding. As some aerobatic aircrafts don&amp;rsquo;t include a copilot seat, some programs are implemented by lone wolves in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools like teamviewer, logmein, skype, hangout or joinme have been instrumental to the success of remote pair working. There is still room for improvement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) In a face-to-face meeting, there is a desk between the two interlocutors. Webcams should recreate this confortable spacing. I&amp;rsquo;m neither a barber nor a dental professional!
2) Remote working platforms lack of interoperability. Some only run on Windows, some require to install a software, others are more suitable for mobile use&amp;hellip; and don&amp;rsquo;t try to connect to hangout with skype
3) Security is a weak point for all of these platforms. Choosing which window you share, which you don&amp;rsquo;t, masking your passwords or your personal information are not intuitive. In my earlier days, I remembered displaying my passwords on a recorded session. Not so good a security practice!
4) Optimizing the screen definition so that everybody can watch comfortably is not supported either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every desktop application from IDE to word processors will probably include some kind of remote pair working feature sooner or later. C9 already includes some simple pair-programming features, for instance.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bugs in the code? Don&amp;rsquo;t blame me, it&amp;rsquo;s my pair programming partner who fooled around!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Another free refill?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/22/another-free-refill/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/22/another-free-refill/</id>
    <published>2017-09-22T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-27T21:07:18+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="free refill" src="/images/freerefill.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I undertook a training session targeting small business manager to teach them how to improve profitability of business projects. The course instructor showed us a rather clear way to deal with profitabiliy. First, you estimate your break-even hourly rate, based on your history. Then, you don&amp;rsquo;t sell any project under the bottom line. After that, you prioritize your work to put the highest priority on the most profitable projects. Finally, you keep any accepted project above the bottom line. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is quite simple. It&amp;rsquo;s all down to the execution. I began to schedule my workday according to business priorities preferably to a sense of urgency that overcame me before. Then, everytime I felt I was at risk to hit the bottom line, I shifted my attention towards what I really sold to the client annd I reduced my objectives accordingly. Finally, I was trying to become a project reviewer for a well known MOOC platform. But the hourly rate was much too low. I felt relief to drop my candidature. Paid projects management improved greatly. But, a significant part of my workday, dedicated to volunteer projects, was out of the scope of this effort.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many commitments, workaholism, things we begin and we never achieve, any freelance worker faces these contradictions. The inherent contradiction is even stronger when you work on non-paid project. How to prioritize your volunteer works?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten working hours a day is my upper limit, considering that I&amp;rsquo;m not a computer nerd, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a family, hobbies, and a social life &amp;hellip; I was already busy ten hours a day. Adding anything to my schedule implied removing something else. I have been more or less active on professional social networks for three years. I first thought this commitment would improve my reputation and fuel my prospect pipeline. But in three years, the return was not very encouraging. I felt that my social network activity was fueled by bitterness or anxiety or ego or the three rather than by a clear sense of business opportunity! I decided to forget social networks. Two to three hours a week were freed thanks to this good resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to devote these hours to Agile Venture mob programming sessions. It&amp;rsquo;s a real community, with real developers. You can both learn by observing how skilled developers work and by doing things by yourself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still in the midstream of my prioritization effort. I&amp;rsquo;ve been very actively participating in MOOCs for five years. My skills greatly improved as a result of this effort.  But choosing which courses to invest on is not easy. Knowledge is a bit like indirects costs. You don&amp;rsquo;t really know how to assign it to your achievements. During the first years, the offer flourished. I tried many courses, from Economy to Computer Sciences. I progressively focused on Computer Science and left courses as they switched to paid offers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was giving up, a prominent MOOC platform offers me to beta-test courses for free. Free refill is the end of resolution and the beginning of passive hyperactivity! You may begin your training week with a course on Embedded systems and end, on friday, with a course on PythonML on friday, without completing any. Does it make sense to participate in a mob programming session about RSPEC on monday, another one about phoenix on wednesday, on the last one about React on friday, when you only need to develop a small web app with React?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AgileVenture Premium Mob includes some kind of Professional Development Planning Support. I may ask the team to help me clean my training plan. But I&amp;rsquo;m still afraid they will tell me to stop learning Tensor Flow or the nitty gritty of Intel Parallel Architecture if I don&amp;rsquo;t have any prospect to work in these fields in the next year! &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title/>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/08/29/av-ecosystem-review-yak-shaving/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/08/29/av-ecosystem-review-yak-shaving/</id>
    <published>2017-08-29T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-17T21:40:05+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay, I think I&amp;rsquo;m coming out of the jet-lag - still not sure things are making sense though, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of yak-shaving to get back to the workface.  I wrote two AV ecosystem review pieces on Thursday and Friday last week and I have to refer to them to remember what I worked out.  I was trying to review the changes I made to the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; and Premium pages at the end of July.  A lot of that seems to be me poring over Google Analytics stats and being a little unclear about the difference between &amp;ldquo;bounce rate&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;exit rate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;drop off&amp;rdquo;.  I&amp;rsquo;m starting to get clarity that the &amp;ldquo;bounce rate&amp;rdquo; only refers to &amp;ldquo;single visit sessions&amp;rdquo;, and is only calculated for visits that start on the page in question.  We saw a fairly substantial improvement in the bounce rate from the previous month and the same period the previous year, implying that more people landing on the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page are sticking around on our site.  The exit rate was also improving.  The exit rate is the percentage for all page views of a page that were the last in the users session.  So in summary: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bounce rate - Of all the sessions that started on a page, how many did not click through to any other page in the site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exit rate - Of all views of a page, what percentage were the last in the user&amp;rsquo;s session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drop off - Of all the sessions including this page, in what percentage did the session end here?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thinking that the difference in exit rate and drop off is due to the calculations being based on page views and sessions including a page respectively; where sessions may include the same page more than once, hence the exit rate can be 29% and the drop off rate be 37% (222/595) for the same period (July &amp;lsquo;17).  So overall, all the stats are going in the right direction following the changes to the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page, and I&amp;rsquo;ve burned a chunk of time understanding the nuances of Google Analytics, which perhaps I should have been spending on my next wheeze, which is splitting up the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page into a series of pages so that we can track the approximate flow through it via Google Analytics.  I&amp;rsquo;m thinking this might be simpler and more incrementally testable than trying to build a tracking system for users that reports back their progress.  I suspect that could be very powerful and useful too, but I think that the content is critical too, and we can move faster making changes to the content first (given our limited resources) &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Yak-shaving I thought I was going to be doing this morning was following up with dropbox and GitHub about image embeds, but that&amp;rsquo;s because I thought I was going to have to reconstruct another July blog.  Ironically there was enough wrangling just working out what I was writing up last week! :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it might still be a few days before I make any more explicit changes, as there&amp;rsquo;s the Premium page and other changes to review, but perhaps tomorrow I can take a quick stab at a sequence of getting started pages (one for each numbered element) and then leave that &amp;ldquo;in the oven&amp;rdquo; to come back in a month and review, assuming that I&amp;rsquo;ve really undertstood all these Google Analytic ideas.  That said, as long as things are going in approximately the right direction, perhaps perfect clarity is not as critical as I sometimes believe &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Bounce Drop</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/08/25/ecosystem-review-bounce-drop/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/08/25/ecosystem-review-bounce-drop/</id>
    <published>2017-08-25T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-16T21:59:51+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bounce rate" src="/images/bounce_rate.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, time to work out the difference between &amp;ldquo;bounce rate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;drop off&amp;rdquo;.  Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the jetlag or just me getting old, but reading &lt;a href="http://www.rankraiser.com/rankraiser/difference-between-google-bounce-rate-and-drop-offs/"&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m not immediately getting it.  Let&amp;rsquo;s dig in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bounce Rate is apparently the percentage of total visitors to a specific page in our site that saw only that page during their visit to our site.  Our getting started bounce rate was ~57% in July, and 80% in June, so that tells us that since we made the change at the beginning of July people have been hanging around a bit longer after visiting this page - at least more of them have been visiting at least one more page in our site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drop off (which gets shown in the Google Analytics visitor flow) is a combination of people leaving the site after having visited 1 or more pages.  In July we saw 37.3% of total traffic to the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page drop off there, compared to  40.8% in June.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmmm. So of the, say, 100 folks (sessions?) who loaded the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page in June, 80 only saw that single page.  While just over 40% of all sessions (that included &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo;?) ended there, while just under 60% carried on browsing.  All sessions must also be those 100 folks, and 40 ended there, but 60 went on &amp;hellip; that does not make sense.  I must be missing something, unless the drop-off is exluding the bounces, which on reflection it looks like it is.  That would imply that of the 20 folks who browsed through the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page, 8 ended their browsing journey there, while 12 of them carried on browsing &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can hypothesize that removing the links to GitHub, Pivotal Tracker and Google+ from the start of the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page could have had this sort of effect, but this all seems pretty inconclusive so far.  What we really want to be looking at is the numbers of people getting set up and contributing to projects, which the analytics is not telling us about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing to look at is how my change to the Premium page wording has affected things &amp;hellip; I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to pull the pricing or premium pages up in the behaviour flow graph since they are not showing up there (too few clicks perhaps?), although I notice the exit rate is shown in the plugin (but that&amp;rsquo;s different again from dropoff?).  The bounce rate as reported by the chrome plugin has dropped from 50% to 0%, which makes it seem like that&amp;rsquo;s a helpful change in terms of making the Premium page stickier &amp;hellip; Conversely for the same time period the bounce rate has increased from 20% to 50% on the Premium Mob page where we didn&amp;rsquo;t make any changes.  So that&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable argument for adjusting the language on the Premium Mob page too &amp;hellip; looks like I have more reading to do on what makes exit rate different from bounce rate &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.axzm.com/google-analytics-exit-percentage/"&gt;https://www.axzm.com/google-analytics-exit-percentage/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://onlineoptimizers.eu/the-important-difference-between-exit-rate-and-bounce-rate/"&gt;http://onlineoptimizers.eu/the-important-difference-between-exit-rate-and-bounce-rate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Return</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/08/24/av-ecosystem-review-return/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/08/24/av-ecosystem-review-return/</id>
    <published>2017-08-24T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-13T21:09:59+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ecosystem" src="/images/ecosystem.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m back from my travels and it&amp;rsquo;s time to get back to work, jet-lagged or not.  I was working on my travels but eschewed blogging and hangouts, as is my usual practice.  My plan now back is to keep focusing on the AgileVentures &amp;ldquo;ecosystem&amp;rdquo;, by which I mean the website, Slack, our Social Media and all parts of how AgileVentures interacts with members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I did manage to do while away was improve the performance on the events page, so it now loads in under two seconds rather than in more than five.  I think that&amp;rsquo;s an important step forward.  I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased with the changes wrought from my reviews in July, reinstating the password based signup (using Google&amp;rsquo;s ReCaptcha to fight spam bots), a &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; page that is shorter and emphasizes our key projects, and a more pointed Premium members page. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it feels like there is so much more to do on the getting started page before it really operates as a really scaffolded guide for those getting started in AgileVentures.  My hypothesis is that the majority of people take a look and see too much text, and don&amp;rsquo;t really have enough of a guide to help them really get started.  My hunch is something that could remember the user and scaffold them on their way towards submitting their first pull-request on a project could make a big difference.  A quick glance over the Premium membership page leaves me feeling it also has too much text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course it&amp;rsquo;s easy to come up with hypotheses, move heaven and earth to change things around, only to discover there&amp;rsquo;s not actually much impact.  The other thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been committing myself to is to measuring changes and testing alternatives.  My memory is that I made a few changes in July that I should be able to get some data on now.  However I haven&amp;rsquo;t even managed to push those &amp;ldquo;blogs&amp;rdquo; out, so I need to dig back through my pull requests to find out what I was doing &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There I notice that all my dropbox images are not showing up &amp;hellip; it looks like Dropbox has adjusted their file download so that images are served so that they won&amp;rsquo;t display in the browser.  Unfortunately this will mean that all my blogs on our nonprofit static site will be without embedded images &amp;hellip; or so I would have thought, but actually they show up there, meaning this may well be github markdown specific. Gah, talk about yak-shaving.   To see my previous blogs with images I need to move all the image files around in git.  Well, until if/when GitHub fixes then it will affect folks ability to review my drafts to let&amp;rsquo;s get it fixed &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so that took about five minutes and now I can see my first website review blog with images here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/av-static-website/blob/av_website_review_part_one_blog/source/blog_articles/2017-07-05-av-website-review-part-one.html.markdown"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/av-static-website/blob/av_website_review_part_one_blog/source/blog_articles/2017-07-05-av-website-review-part-one.html.markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first thing I should be checking up on is what effect we had from the changes I made to the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page.  The drop-off from that page for the period Jul 3rd - Jul 31st 2017 is (222 vs 595) 37.3% of total traffic; compared to Jun 4th -Jul 2nd 2017 is (344 vs 500) 40.8% of total traffic, which is an improvement, but not conclusive.  That change could be due to seasonal or random fluctuations. If I compare with the same period last year (72 vs 156) 31.6% we se a lower dropoff rate, for a much smaller overall number of site visitors &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frustratingly I can&amp;rsquo;t easily do comparisons in on the behaviour flow page in Google Analytics.  Conversely in the chrome plugin I can see these side by side, although I seem to be seeing PageView rather than session data. (Sessions = Unique PageViews?) The plugin shows that overall traffic to the page was down, but the bounce rate dropped by over 28% which is a big change &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, I&amp;rsquo;ll need to go through all this again tomorrow when I&amp;rsquo;m not jet-lagged &amp;hellip; apparently bounce rate is not the same as drop off:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rankraiser.com/rankraiser/difference-between-google-bounce-rate-and-drop-offs/"&gt;http://www.rankraiser.com/rankraiser/difference-between-google-bounce-rate-and-drop-offs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV Website Review Part 12</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/20/av-website-review-part-twelve/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/20/av-website-review-part-twelve/</id>
    <published>2017-07-20T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-12T21:17:52+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking a blogging/reviewing break for my Japan trip - perhaps I can get up to date pushing out some old blogs.  Over the last couple of weeks of these &amp;ldquo;reviews&amp;rdquo; of the AV website (and associated ecosystem) I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get some changes out to the main site.  I think it&amp;rsquo;s early to be assessing the changes - that should probably be the first thing to do in September when I plan to restart this series under the more accurate title &amp;ldquo;ecosystem review&amp;rdquo;.  The main changes I&amp;rsquo;ve enacted so far are getting a privacy statement linked up and reinstating email sign ups with a Google reCaptcha system to block the spambots signing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also simplified the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page and rewrote parts of the Premium page.  I can see there&amp;rsquo;s lots more work to do there.  The Premium plan overview page is still very text heavy, as are the individual Premium pages.  The events page is loading really slowly at the moment.  Six seconds is not good. New Relic shows that the slowness is a split between the index method in the controller and the index.html.erb template itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/pue0dkn4373lcbb/Screenshot%202017-07-20%2009.37.31.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m conflicted about whether to investigate that further, or try to deploy the new greeting bot with the new functionality and updates for the other project maintainers &amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;ve gone for deploying the new project greeting bot.  Here&amp;rsquo;s a maintainer testing it live in his main project channel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ov99d3ogm4jq9lw/Screenshot%202017-07-20%2009.59.55.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so the thing I need, to profile the events controller, is to clone the production data locally again, which I also did after opening some more project greeter bot tickets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/project_greeter_bot/issues/15"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/project_greeter_bot/issues/15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t immediately see a solution to the slow event page loading, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found our old open issue and added notes there:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1503"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1503&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got other fish to fry today, e.g. getting the NHS HLP wiki ssl certs renewed.  Gosh I&amp;rsquo;d love to be paid at market rates for keeping the AgileVentures ecosystem running &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
