<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2018-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Getting Back on Track</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/15/av-ecosystem-review-getting-back-on-track/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/15/av-ecosystem-review-getting-back-on-track/</id>
    <published>2018-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-24T21:25:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="track" src="/images/track.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bit of a wreck this morning.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep well - woke up at 4am brain full of kids football.  I did write down a new drill for training (I coach 7aside soccer for nine year olds) and then listened to standup comedy on audio for 2 hours to stop my brain endlessly turning over the same thoughts again and again.  Not dissimilar to last Sunday night/Monday morning.  Emotionally charged football matches.  This weekend&amp;rsquo;s was less intense (draw instead of a loss), but I worked three hours in the afternoon to get the APSoc&amp;rsquo;s membership database recreated on MS Access now that I got the green light from the client to switch.  This is all because LibreOffice is crashing too frequently and ZohoCreator looks like it doesn&amp;rsquo;t might not have all the functionality we need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made reasonable progress yesterday although I was popping paracetamol and ibuprofen to push on in the last hour.  I think I&amp;rsquo;ve got us back to the place we were in LibreOffice, and actually got a few more supporting tables to populate the dropdown lists correctly.  However there&amp;rsquo;s a clear additional chunk of functionality that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really been focusing on.  A load of specification for default values, computed fields and so forth.  I&amp;rsquo;d love to have a break from the project this week, so I think the thing to do is label what we have as an MS Access alpha version and re-work the schedule.  Here are screenshots of the different forms done in Access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ydoubyw95wb1zhc/Screenshot%202018-01-15%2009.28.44.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/eoi4nm5e655wnhq/Screenshot%202018-01-15%2009.29.14.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/rel3yqy4ur1rujc/Screenshot%202018-01-15%2009.31.58.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/jqch3s2dbyujrzi/Screenshot%202018-01-15%2009.32.19.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wonder if I should set up a Trello board for all the different bits of functionality?  I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll get the new schedule approved.  The old schedule had been:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Dec 8th - screenshots of membership database interface for you to approve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Dec 15th - alpha version of membership database for you to approve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 5th - beta version of membership database adjusted as per feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 31st - release version of membership database adjusted as per feedback, including full migration &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so if we have the alpha version now, then perhaps we can set the beta version for Jan 26th, and then release version on Feb 9th, so that&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 26th - beta version of membership database adjusted as per feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Feb 9th - release version of membership database adjusted as per feedback, including full migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which I put in an email to the client:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your email - hope you had a good weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now have an alpha version in MSAccess, which you can access here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[DROP BOX LINK]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you don&amp;rsquo;t have a copy of MSAccess please find screenshots of all the forms attached.
Thanks so much for all the detailed feedback over the last few weeks.  I believe we have a good chunk of the issues addressed in this MS Access alpha version, but certainly not all. In particular, as you noticed, the majority of fields are not folllowing the defaulted/calculated/midified rules from the database definition.   This is simply as we hadn&amp;rsquo;t started work on implementing them yet.   Please rest assured that they will be implemented in the next version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the software issues we encountered with LibreOffice we&amp;rsquo;d like to propose the following new schedule for delivery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 26th - beta version of membership database adjusted as per feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Feb 9th - release version of membership database adjusted as per feedback, including full migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our sincere apologies for the slippage and we hope the new schedule meets with your approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best, Sam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I&amp;rsquo;ll send that later today.  Now what I really want is some coffee and perhaps I can dive into my outstanding pull request on updating the WSO Premium model so that it can support the sponsor relations we need to more accurately represent our Premium membership data &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Starting Over</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/12/av-ecosystem-review-starting-over/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/12/av-ecosystem-review-starting-over/</id>
    <published>2018-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-21T21:15:23+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="starting over" src="/images/starting_over.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I sent the APSoc client the following email:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think we need to make some decisions about how to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment we are thinking that the best alternatives are to either go with MS Access, or with Zoho Creator.  Using the XLSX you just provided we&amp;rsquo;ve started projects in both MS Access and Zoho Creator.  It&amp;rsquo;s obviously not ideal to have to switch platform at this stage, but the instability of LibreOffice Base makes it seem like we can&amp;rsquo;t continue with that platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zoho Creator is a cloud solution that replicates much of the MSAccess/LotusApproach functionality, and comes with a £10 a month price tag, but reduced to £8 for charities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MS offers Access as part of Office 365 for £1.50 a month (for charities), and Access is also available standalone.  Access 2013 is available for £12 for charities and Access 2016 is available for about £95.  I&amp;rsquo;m keen to know if you already have a copy of Access and whether you have strong preferences here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that you were looking to avoid any monthly charges, and anticipate that you might prefer the standalone MS Access option.  If you do currently have a copy of MS Access please let us know which version you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let me know if you&amp;rsquo;d like a call to discuss the alternatives.  We&amp;rsquo;re planning to work through the weekend to get the project back on schedule on a new platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best, Sam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard back yet, so I guess I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a stab at moving the MS Access version forward.  Zoho Creator was nice and zippy, and MS Access feels sluggish, but I suspect that the monthly charge for Zoho could be a dealbreaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took about 40 minutes but I got a draft form for members up in Access 2007:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/5khkijp2qr728gj/Screenshot%202018-01-12%2011.33.31.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With at least one dropdown linking to a different table.  Overall the UI is easily better than the latest LibreOffice even though I&amp;rsquo;m using MSAccess from 10 years back.  Hmm, maybe I should have just started with Access for a simple life, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see.  Now I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to see what&amp;rsquo;s the best I can get out of Zoho &amp;hellip; I immediately run up against a couple of (perhaps minor) issues, which are that we can&amp;rsquo;t easily convert fields from multi-line to single-line and back again.  Also my attempts to adjust a drop down field to radio buttons fails.  I think I&amp;rsquo;ll give up there.  I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the client is going to be much happier with the results from MSAccess, and I can develop faster there too &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Painful Decisions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/11/av-ecosystem-review-painful-decisions/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/11/av-ecosystem-review-painful-decisions/</id>
    <published>2018-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-17T20:43:48+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="hardest thing and the right thing" src="/images/hardest-and-right.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The APSoc has responded calmly to the email I sent about the problems with LibreOffice Base.  Here&amp;rsquo;s what I sent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s disturbing to hear that you&amp;rsquo;re experiencing lock up.  We have been experiencing that too, but only with the system in edit mode, i.e. editing the UI, tables etc.  updates to tables have been working fine.  These lock ups are pretty much what caused us to be late delivering last week.  That you&amp;rsquo;re encountering them to makes me think that we have a particularly tricky issue to solve here and some important decisions to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rest assured that the problems fall on our side and not yours.  We&amp;rsquo;ve given a fixed quote for this, and will do whatever is necessary to deliver robust and stable software by the final deadline however many additional hours are required on our side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to be discussing the options in a team meeting today, and will come back to you with some alternative approaches to consider by the end of the day.  In the meantime I notice that, in the database pack we originally received from you, there are a number of file formats including XLSX, but notably we do not have an XLSX formatted file for the subscription or members tables; while we do have them for the gift aid, member types and recurring subs tables.  Is there any chance you could provide XLSX files for the subscription and members tables as this would help with debugging and testing alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks in advance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best, Sam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They responded with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah-ha … thanks for this … I’m glad it isn’t just me getting lock-ups and being stupid!  The lock-ups seem to happen as soon as I select “Queries” and use the Wizard.  Sometimes it just locks Libre and I can continue with other things; at other times everything locks until I kill Libre.  If I then try to restart Libre and access the beta file I get “General Error: General input/output error” until I refresh the Libre file from the supplied one.  This also happens if I try creating anything more than a very simple report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as including the files I requested and answering a few other outstanding questions and some other feedback on the interface.  I also had a call yesterday from Zoho indicating that the non-profit discount is 20% if we pay a year up front (instead of the usual 10%), which is not a huge boost, but I guess I at least use the new file from the client to check out Zoho&amp;rsquo;s offering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short order it gives me the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/3g8557dfmr00nzq/Screenshot%202018-01-11%2010.08.47.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see I can also import different sets of choices for the country field&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/c3nw135pu5wn6f2/Screenshot%202018-01-11%2010.12.35.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but I can see a fair chunk of work required to get this set up to where the client might be passing happy (including being able to generate all the forms and reports they like), and then there&amp;rsquo;s the question of the monthly fees.  In the meantime I got MS Access 2013 for £14.40 through the tt-exchange using AgileVentures charity status.  And &amp;hellip; they are going to physically deliver shrink-wrapped software to my address?  What, no download?  Seems like we won&amp;rsquo;t receive anything for five days, hmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see MS Access 2016 being offered for close to £100 from Tekgia on a charity offer.  Hmmm. So I had another go at getting in through the MS portal to no joy.  I did seem to be able to get access to the basic office suite through our existing nonprofit setup by going through the sam@agileventures.org login in my safari browser.  I finally found a help request form and submitted a help request:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://nonprofitcontactus.microsoftcrmportals.com/contact-us/"&gt;https://nonprofitcontactus.microsoftcrmportals.com/contact-us/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I would have pasted in here the help request but super-irritatingly I can&amp;rsquo;t go back to the form and they don&amp;rsquo;t send me a copy &amp;hellip; although they send me a notification that they&amp;rsquo;ll get back to me in about 5 business days:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/qwm32xhnsr14tuk/Screenshot%202018-01-11%2010.45.32.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ugh, I guess the main question on my mind is whether Zoho can produce the reports the client needs, and maybe more importantly the complex subforms &amp;hellip; the other alternatives I have are build their system from scratch in LibreOffice on PC, and/or force through and buy a copy of MS Access 2016.  £100 is not insane from Tekgia, but will be frustrating if we can get it for £1.50 a month as part of our MS nonprofit status, of I&amp;rsquo;ve doubled up having already spend £12 on MS access and I&amp;rsquo;ve missed the download button or it will arrive tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do have MS Access 2007 on my machine - should I perhaps start playing with that?  Quick answer is that I can&amp;rsquo;t import the LibreOffice odb format into MS Access 2007.  Also, it looks like Zoho does support subforms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.zoho.com/creator/help/forms/creating-subforms.html"&gt;https://www.zoho.com/creator/help/forms/creating-subforms.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been able to import the XLSX table into MS Access 2007, so that&amp;rsquo;s a basic route forward I guess &amp;hellip; painful decisions ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Damn Estimates</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/10/av-ecosystem-review-damn-estimates/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/10/av-ecosystem-review-damn-estimates/</id>
    <published>2018-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-21T21:12:38+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="distraction" src="/images/estimates.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I had an email from the APSoc client yesterday evening:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for Beta 3.  I’ve started having a look at this but not got far.  However some initial feedback …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whenever try to do any updates to a table, or use the wizard to set up and edit a query, the system locks me out (seemingly indefinitely) while using up to 20% of CPU and trashing the hard disk.  I end up having to kill the task in Task Manager and restart my machine to clear the problem.  This may well be something peculiar in my system and not down to you – but any clues appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Otherwise the forms generally look much better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Member Information Form&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NM N/L should work as follows.  (a) If person is a non-member then NM N/L checked should force N/L to be set ON.  (b) If person is non-member then NM N/L unchecked forces N/L to be OFF.  &amp;copy; If person is a member then NM N/L has no effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscription Payment Form&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expires field needs a simple list of dates, plus N/A and 9999.  Currently contains lots of duplicates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gift Aid Form&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t need checkboxes O/S, SO, 5for4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also doesn&amp;rsquo;t need Letters, Salutation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing Order Form&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t display!  Just have a blank pink screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More when I get a chance over the next couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is all great feedback, but makes me think we cannot continue with LibreOffice Base.  Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s reactionary, but I&amp;rsquo;ve now created the Standing Order Form twice and although I now have backups of it, it&amp;rsquo;s just randomly gone blank in the latest version that I&amp;rsquo;ve shared with the client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been thinking that the lock up problem had only been affecting me when I&amp;rsquo;d been editing the system and the querying portion of the system had been stable on their platform, as it appears to have been on mine.  To hear that they are having serious lock up issues makes me think there&amp;rsquo;s no real way forward here.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got no clear way to debug the crashes that I&amp;rsquo;m getting; and although I can see some chatter about this on the message boards, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can afford to invest 10&amp;rsquo;s of hours into tracking down the cause of the crash, particularly when there&amp;rsquo;s no guarantee that it&amp;rsquo;ll even be fixable.  The workflow with LibreOffice Base with the crashes is appalling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve done something terribly inappropriate with the system importing the legacy data and the way I have the forms setup etc. but I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to suspect something related to having switched from Mac to PC and back.  It all seemed fine, but maybe some weird line endings got in there.  In particular even though the system is open source, the lack of transparency of the system being developed makes me despair of getting to the bottom of things in short order.  In principle the database file is a zip file that can be unpacked and have its components inspected, but I was unable to unzip when the app was crashing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought LibreOffice Base was a good option as there was a large responsive community and an initial import of the client&amp;rsquo;s data went fine, and an initial setup of various relations went well.  It looked like it has all the functionality that we need, and that&amp;rsquo;s been born out during further development, but the crashing, lack of automatic backup and the monolithic file format makes me think we are better off cutting our losses and switching to Zoho or MSAccess.  The options as I see them are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue to push on and try to somehow debug the crashes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to recreate a version from scratch on PC only (might avoid crashing issue, might not)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set something up in Zoho&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set something up in MSAccess&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m leaning towards options 3 and 4 in that I suspect there&amp;rsquo;s a lower likelihood of encountering the crash issue, and perhaps more cohorent support, although I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I just got set up with a Zoho account and emailed them about non-profit discounts, but I don&amp;rsquo;t seem to have an XLSX file for the main members db, and although Zoho says it will import mdb files it can&amp;rsquo;t handle the ones from the APSoc dump.  The MSAccess Office 365 offering seems to be only available on PC.  TT-Exchange, which we&amp;rsquo;re already a member of, has MSAccess 2013 for £12, while the main MS page has Office365 for £1.50 a month per user.  Guess I&amp;rsquo;ll apply for the latter, but I get stuck - I start the application process, but then can&amp;rsquo;t select AgileVentures - we already have a charity account, but then I can&amp;rsquo;t log in to it.  Ugh, so stuck on two fronts there.  At least I&amp;rsquo;ve pushed forward on both pathways &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gah, so I need to ask the client for an XLS export of the member database to even test Zoho, and I maybe need to contact MicroSoft support to even get set up with their charity plan &amp;hellip; I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to email the client to let them know my concerns and ask for the appropriate files.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Distracted By The Real Thing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/09/av-ecosystem-review-distracted-by-the-real-thing/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/09/av-ecosystem-review-distracted-by-the-real-thing/</id>
    <published>2018-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-21T21:12:38+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="distraction" src="/images/distraction.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically after getting more sleep last night I feel groggier this morning.  Sunday night I couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep re-hashing my 9-year old twins lost football (soccer) match (I&amp;rsquo;m the coach).  Don&amp;rsquo;t want to be strung out thinking about it, but I am, pretty much every time they lose; although it&amp;rsquo;s particularly bad when I think the opposing coach is not setting a good example.  Despite the lack of sleep on Sunday, yesterday was a solid day.  I slept properly last night, but is this a cold coming on?  Urgh.  Been distracted this morning, but maybe by the right stuff?  I&amp;rsquo;ve done a quick Slack/Email review and edited the &lt;a href="https://www.agileventures.org/premium-f2f-offer"&gt;AV Premium F2F offer page&lt;/a&gt; to include connecting to me on LinkedIn.  I keep wondering what to do with the random folks connecting to me there - might as well be offering them a free hour of pairing on a charity project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now I want to just quickly follow through with Will&amp;rsquo;s advice on changes to the Premium Sponsorship form, and get the revised version out to a few folks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay. This is only a side note, but I read this interesting article about names: &lt;a href="http://www.kalzumeus.com/2010/06/17/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-names/"&gt;http://www.kalzumeus.com/2010/06/17/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-names/&lt;/a&gt; TLDR: have a single &amp;ldquo;name&amp;rdquo; field&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each question should have a reason. I want to know why you need to know what country I live in, for a premium membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resume could be a lot of work. Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t the questions ask everything you want to know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re working remotely, where is the company based? *&amp;rdquo; shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have an asterisk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edited-down mob programming videos might get more folks applying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Please upload a cover letter indicating how you think you would benefit from the Premium membership you are applying for&amp;rdquo; could become just &amp;ldquo;How do you think you would benefit from the Premium membership you are applying for?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now it&amp;rsquo;s much shorter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/m29aa7wl36fiuw5/Screenshot%202018-01-09%2010.32.39.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I must jump back to the APSoc membership database, and my new backup ritual which involves copying the previous day&amp;rsquo;s file in dropbox and relabelling it with the day I&amp;rsquo;m starting on.  Giving LibreOffice Base an extra 2GB of Java memory does not appear to have helped with the lock up issues.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;rsquo;s start with correctly populating the Local Group field in the membership form.  I create and populate a new table, and in short order I have the Local Group dropdown as requested:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/w93hp5cyr700a9i/Screenshot%202018-01-09%2010.45.43.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I duplicate the version and restart LibreOffice.  And then I work on a new dropdown for pay method on the subscription payment form.  I create the table, but then trying to set up the relation we get stuck again.  I go make coffee, come back, still stuck.  I kill the app, and re-start.  I&amp;rsquo;m lucky - this time we&amp;rsquo;re able to recover the corrupted file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/cms13nfe5rtu8nd/Screenshot%202018-01-09%2011.09.14.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ac9vdcxbhwlfpkk/Screenshot%202018-01-09%2011.10.30.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;ve got no basis to diagnose the issue &amp;hellip; I make a quick extra backup and continue, and I get it working:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/anclrh7bi983wpb/Screenshot%202018-01-09%2011.13.11.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no particular pattern - although I sense problems come when I double up on things, e.g. add a table in the SQL view by double clicking, but then also click the add button &amp;hellip; okay, enough for today. I&amp;rsquo;m going to pass this version on to the client, as I said I would do that daily this week.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Tight Corner</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/08/av-ecosystem-review-tight-corner/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/08/av-ecosystem-review-tight-corner/</id>
    <published>2018-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-10T21:59:40+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="tight corner" src="/images/tight_corner.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my estimates were all wrong.  I had hoped to complete the membership database beta for APSoc in two mornings last week, and then be able to move back to things that were arguably more core AV ecosystem.  The task itself was no harder than expected, but the repeatedly crashing LibreOffice Base lost two mornings&amp;rsquo; work and then slowed me to a crawl as I instituted a variety of different (and increasingly extreme) backup options.  Having missed the deadline for Friday, I&amp;rsquo;ve pushed back to the following Friday, and now potentially I lose another week of mornings that I would like to have devoted to the AV ecosystem.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m now weighing up whether I try and combine the dropbox backups I have with git, and I see there&amp;rsquo;s some interesting SO posts about this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/1960799/using-git-and-dropbox-together-effectively"&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/1960799/using-git-and-dropbox-together-effectively&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it looks like it could work.  But I think I&amp;rsquo;ll burn time with set up for potentially not much gain.  I think the key is doing the LibreOffice double save and restarting it each time I make any progress.  It feels late in the day to try and switch to another piece of software such as MSAccess.  Interacting in read/write mode with LibreOffice feels fairly stable.  It&amp;rsquo;s the occasional random lockups, when actually editing the interface, that cause me headaches.  Hopefully for the client it will be solid, but if not I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll have to pay for MSAccess and re-do it all there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with is boosting the allocated memory for the app.  Let&amp;rsquo;s see if that helps today.  Maybe I can sort out the Countries DB to have USA and UK at the top &amp;hellip; I try to create a countries table from scratch, but I have trouble setting the primary key.  And almost immediately I have the spinning beachball of death.  Is this something about the size and structure of the system I&amp;rsquo;ve created here within LibreOffice DB?  That I&amp;rsquo;m using it on Mac? Although I do get similar issues on PC.  Or is it that both my computers are too old and slow?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway I managed to create the adjusted countries table by just allowing the db to create its own primary key, and then finally pasting in data from Google sheets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/rkw7tt19t85jtqu/Screenshot%202018-01-08%2009.54.07.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now I can&amp;rsquo;t insert any records.  Seems like we lost all the auto-value settings on all the table IDs somewhere last week.  I&amp;rsquo;d better send this revised version off to the client, before they start testing the buggy one I sent on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you had a good weekend and apologies again for the deadline slippage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve just been working on the system and if you do run any more tests I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to work against this version (rather than the one sent on Friday):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LINK TO BETA VERSION 2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one has the the UK and USA at the top of the countries list, and another insert bug fixed (or rather refixed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that we&amp;rsquo;re behind schedule we&amp;rsquo;ll try and give you daily updates this week.  However - please don&amp;rsquo;t feel obliged to test things daily.  We just want to make sure that when you do get a chance to test that you&amp;rsquo;re working against the latest and greatest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, we plan to have all your items of feedback addressed by Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best, Sam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tight corner indeed - can I bank effectively and avoid coming a cropper?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
