<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-10-02T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>The pilot+copilot organizational pattern</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/10/02/pilot-copilot-organizational-pattern/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/10/02/pilot-copilot-organizational-pattern/</id>
    <published>2017-10-02T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-04T21:52:30+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="pair flying" src="/images/pairflying.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2002, I graduated a distance-learning masters in applied mathematics. Every month, the university mailed me an A4 enveloppe containing the course support. I was supposed to learn from the course material and returned the completed assignments within a month. A month later, I would receive an answer key. Should I have a question, I could mail it to the professor and wait for his reply. The whole process was cumbersome. I was often behind schedule. Interactivity was near to zero. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on, I participated in the MOOC endeavour. The video of the instructor gave a feeling of a one-to-one training session. Discussion forums, deadlines, follow-up mails, peer-reviews grounded the learning process. There were meetups too. And a MOOC about Agile Development using Ruby On Rails offered remote pair-programming sessions between participants. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pair-programmming reuses the rather old organizational pattern of pilot+copilot : double-check, higher focusing, external view, and stronger engagement. You may object that programming is very different from flying. Yes, it is! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But programming requires a strong level of accuracy too. Your pairing fellow is both a watch dog that tells you not to call a library without checking how it works, not to cut and paste code across your work, and an inspiration to experiment with new ways of coding. As some aerobatic aircrafts don&amp;rsquo;t include a copilot seat, some programs are implemented by lone wolves in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools like teamviewer, logmein, skype, hangout or joinme have been instrumental to the success of remote pair working. There is still room for improvement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) In a face-to-face meeting, there is a desk between the two interlocutors. Webcams should recreate this confortable spacing. I&amp;rsquo;m neither a barber nor a dental professional!
2) Remote working platforms lack of interoperability. Some only run on Windows, some require to install a software, others are more suitable for mobile use&amp;hellip; and don&amp;rsquo;t try to connect to hangout with skype
3) Security is a weak point for all of these platforms. Choosing which window you share, which you don&amp;rsquo;t, masking your passwords or your personal information are not intuitive. In my earlier days, I remembered displaying my passwords on a recorded session. Not so good a security practice!
4) Optimizing the screen definition so that everybody can watch comfortably is not supported either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every desktop application from IDE to word processors will probably include some kind of remote pair working feature sooner or later. C9 already includes some simple pair-programming features, for instance.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bugs in the code? Don&amp;rsquo;t blame me, it&amp;rsquo;s my pair programming partner who fooled around!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Another free refill?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/22/another-free-refill/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/22/another-free-refill/</id>
    <published>2017-09-22T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-27T21:07:18+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="free refill" src="/images/freerefill.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I undertook a training session targeting small business manager to teach them how to improve profitability of business projects. The course instructor showed us a rather clear way to deal with profitabiliy. First, you estimate your break-even hourly rate, based on your history. Then, you don&amp;rsquo;t sell any project under the bottom line. After that, you prioritize your work to put the highest priority on the most profitable projects. Finally, you keep any accepted project above the bottom line. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is quite simple. It&amp;rsquo;s all down to the execution. I began to schedule my workday according to business priorities preferably to a sense of urgency that overcame me before. Then, everytime I felt I was at risk to hit the bottom line, I shifted my attention towards what I really sold to the client annd I reduced my objectives accordingly. Finally, I was trying to become a project reviewer for a well known MOOC platform. But the hourly rate was much too low. I felt relief to drop my candidature. Paid projects management improved greatly. But, a significant part of my workday, dedicated to volunteer projects, was out of the scope of this effort.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many commitments, workaholism, things we begin and we never achieve, any freelance worker faces these contradictions. The inherent contradiction is even stronger when you work on non-paid project. How to prioritize your volunteer works?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten working hours a day is my upper limit, considering that I&amp;rsquo;m not a computer nerd, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a family, hobbies, and a social life &amp;hellip; I was already busy ten hours a day. Adding anything to my schedule implied removing something else. I have been more or less active on professional social networks for three years. I first thought this commitment would improve my reputation and fuel my prospect pipeline. But in three years, the return was not very encouraging. I felt that my social network activity was fueled by bitterness or anxiety or ego or the three rather than by a clear sense of business opportunity! I decided to forget social networks. Two to three hours a week were freed thanks to this good resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to devote these hours to Agile Venture mob programming sessions. It&amp;rsquo;s a real community, with real developers. You can both learn by observing how skilled developers work and by doing things by yourself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still in the midstream of my prioritization effort. I&amp;rsquo;ve been very actively participating in MOOCs for five years. My skills greatly improved as a result of this effort.  But choosing which courses to invest on is not easy. Knowledge is a bit like indirects costs. You don&amp;rsquo;t really know how to assign it to your achievements. During the first years, the offer flourished. I tried many courses, from Economy to Computer Sciences. I progressively focused on Computer Science and left courses as they switched to paid offers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was giving up, a prominent MOOC platform offers me to beta-test courses for free. Free refill is the end of resolution and the beginning of passive hyperactivity! You may begin your training week with a course on Embedded systems and end, on friday, with a course on PythonML on friday, without completing any. Does it make sense to participate in a mob programming session about RSPEC on monday, another one about phoenix on wednesday, on the last one about React on friday, when you only need to develop a small web app with React?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AgileVenture Premium Mob includes some kind of Professional Development Planning Support. I may ask the team to help me clean my training plan. But I&amp;rsquo;m still afraid they will tell me to stop learning Tensor Flow or the nitty gritty of Intel Parallel Architecture if I don&amp;rsquo;t have any prospect to work in these fields in the next year! &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV Website Review Part 8</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/17/av-website-review-part-nine/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/17/av-website-review-part-nine/</id>
    <published>2017-07-17T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-09T21:40:28+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="times up" src="/images/expired.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So no one joined the LocalSupport channel over the weekend and thus there&amp;rsquo;s no immediate chance to see the new project greeting bot in action.  Other project maintainers have come back to me with mixed responses.  Some enthusiastic, some more cautious.  I also saw there are some &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/recaptcha/docs/faq"&gt;special keys for testing &amp;ldquo;reCaptcha&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, which makes me feel like I should put some more effort into that spike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think what I really want though is to update the project greeting bot so that it supports multiple projects, mentions the person by name and even has a pause before it posts.  Force of habit&amp;ndash;I just dropped a load of issues in the repo for the bot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/project_greeter_bot/issues/1"&gt;mention name of member who joins channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/project_greeter_bot/issues/2"&gt;add pause to post so it&amp;rsquo;s not quite so fast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/project_greeter_bot/issues/3"&gt;support multiple projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/project_greeter_bot/issues/4"&gt;could this all be done with a slash command?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/project_greeter_bot/issues/5"&gt;tests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/project_greeter_bot/issues/6"&gt;easier in ruby?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s tempting when thinking about supporting multiple projects to put a database or caching system in there, but a hash in the code will do for now.  And I start to want to put a testing framework in there, but I know I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to easily round-trip the whole thing, so I do a manual test on the low level stuff in node, and on the high level stuff in a second Slack instance.  It all seems to work.  I could deploy.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got one free-tier member asking for a simple project to get set up on - it could be this one &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got to get the autograders working on EC2 and so many other things.  I can&amp;rsquo;t allow myself more than another 15 minutes on this.  I think I deploy.  Again by force of habit I submit a PR:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/project_greeter_bot/pull/7"&gt;https://github.com/tansaku/project_greeter_bot/pull/7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no CI yet, but it allows me to attach the ticket to the issue.  I could deploy that branch directly &amp;hellip;?  That actually provides a great route for getting out of trouble.  Will do that.  While that builds I could quickly make a test for the reCaptcha stuff &amp;hellip;?  I satisfy myself with creating a ticket:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1735"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1735&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the new bot is deployed, and I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of other features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/project_greeter_bot/issues/8"&gt;avoid re-posting to the same person&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/project_greeter_bot/issues/9"&gt;avoid posting if we&amp;rsquo;ve recently done so&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/project_greeter_bot/issues/10"&gt;should we prefer to DM people the intro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/project_greeter_bot/issues/11"&gt;allow people to request instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so many things that might or might not be useful &amp;hellip; anyway, times up &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV Website Review Part 8</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/14/av-website-review-part-eight/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/14/av-website-review-part-eight/</id>
    <published>2017-07-14T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-09T21:19:01+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="robots" src="/images/robots.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the discussion in marketing was about adding a time limit to the message about the Premium Mob special offer, and any changes can now be submitted as a pull request.  There also seemed to be general agreement that we should avoid bots doing the greeting of new members in the #new_members channel.  There was interest though in the idea of having bots greet new members when they joined project channels.  I also reached out to a few project managers and got positive responses to the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue is that new members joining a channel doesn&amp;rsquo;t generate any kind of notification on Slack (at least on default settings) - having explained it to a few people and everyone agreeing that it means that we miss when members join new channels I just sent Slack a question about it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was wondering if there is any setting in Slack that will allow channel joins to show up as a stronger notification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment in our AgileVentures Slack, we get a little notice in the channel, e.g. Member name joined #general&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but I notice that the member joining doesn&amp;rsquo;t cause the channel to get the bold highlight as there is with a new message, and not the number that&amp;rsquo;s associated with being mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I can write a bot that will detect new members joining and a channel and responding to them, but is there a setting that allows us to adjust the notifications status of channel joins?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wouldn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to set it so that all members were bothered by channel joins, but it would be useful for admins, and perhaps nominated members of a channel who were focused on greeting activities.  Does that make sense?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If not something in main Slack is there any plugin that already addresses this issue?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say I&amp;rsquo;ve been very tempted to rustle up a quick bot that will do some greetings for us.  I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be reviewing the AV website, but this has turned into a review of the AV ecosystem and I think that makes sense.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think I should tinker more with the main website until I&amp;rsquo;ve got the results of the few experiments I&amp;rsquo;m running at the moment and in the flow through the site, that point when members join Slack channels seems pretty critical.  It&amp;rsquo;s also an opportunity to get set up with a deployment flow on the bot project.  Although, should it be part of the greeter bot, or a separate instance?  Either way I definitely want to test this on a separate Slack instance before dropping it on our main Slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing I was thinking of last night was whether we could have a bot like AsyncVoter that was activated by a slash command; then project managers could add the greeter bot to their channel, and then configure it themselves via Slack?  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure - I&amp;rsquo;ll have to enumerate all these different Slack integrations at some point.  Anyhow, I can&amp;rsquo;t help myself from quickly deploying another bot against a test Slack instance to see if I can get the basic channel greeting behaviour I want &amp;hellip; and thirty minutes later I have one deployed on Azure/Dokku, after a quick round of tests on a separate slack instance to find the exact notification I want to match, getting stuck on the syntax for environment variables on dokku, but I now have it live on the #localsupport channel.  The code is just this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;var Botkit = require('botkit');

var controller = Botkit.slackbot({
  debug: false
});

var bot = controller.spawn({
  token: process.env.PROJECT_GREETER_SLACK_BOT_TOKEN,
  retry: 20
}).startRTM()

var greet = "Welcome to LocalSupport! :slightly_smiling_face: To install the codebase see: https://github.com/AgileVentures/LocalSupport/blob/develop/docs/installation.md#installation and our #localsupport-install channel if you need help"

greet += "\n\n\n see https://github.com/AgileVentures/LocalSupport/blob/develop/CONTRIBUTING.md for how to contribute to the project, but feel free to ask questions here too :-)"

controller.on('member_joined_channel', function(bot, message){
  // console.log('member_joined_channel')
  // bot.say({channel: message.channel, text: greet});
  if(message.channel === process.env.PROJECT_SLACK_CHANNEL_ID){
    bot.reply(message, greet);
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and the deployment was just this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh dokku@agileventures.eastus.cloudapp.azure.com apps:create projectgreeterbot-production
ssh dokku@agileventures.eastus.cloudapp.azure.com config:set projectgreeterbot-production PROJECT_GREETER_SLACK_BOT_TOKEN=XXXXX
ssh dokku@agileventures.eastus.cloudapp.azure.com config projectgreeterbot-production set PROJECT_SLACK_CHANNEL_ID=C0KK907B5
git push azure-production master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with all the code at: https://github.com/tansaku/project&lt;em&gt;greeter&lt;/em&gt;bot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and we get this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/tunznnlxylbjteo/Screenshot%202017-07-14%2010.32.58.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should we label it more clearly as a bot?  I have mixed feelings - I&amp;rsquo;d like people to feel they could reply directly to me using @tansaku, but perhaps it degrades my credibility as a real person on Slack &amp;hellip;?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV Website Review Part 7</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/13/av-website-review-part-seven/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/13/av-website-review-part-seven/</id>
    <published>2017-07-13T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-05T20:20:50+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So overnight some new folks signed up for the AgileVentures slack.  It seems like the greeter bot on Azure/Dokku has succesfully greeted a handful of new members, so I&amp;rsquo;ve turned off the greeter bot on EC2 and shut down the instance, which should save us $5 a month, or so.  Look after the pennies and the pounds will look after themselves they say.  Lots of pennies still to save methinks.  Anyhow, my calculated gamble seems to have worked.  We got one user having a double greeting in the changeover, but they&amp;rsquo;ve actually responded positively and, otherwise, normal service has been restored.  So now in principle we can have simpler management of the greeter bot message.  Federico and others can submit PRs to update the message, and even deploy it themselves.  I guess I should just test that with a new message &amp;hellip; so I put in a pull request:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/greeter_bot/pull/3"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/greeter_bot/pull/3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;merged that and pushed that up to dokku from the command line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;→ git remote -v
azure-production    dokku@agileventures.eastus.cloudapp.azure.com:greeterbot-production (fetch)
azure-production    dokku@agileventures.eastus.cloudapp.azure.com:greeterbot-production (push)
origin  git@github.com:tansaku/greeter_bot.git (fetch)
origin  git@github.com:tansaku/greeter_bot.git (push)
→ git push azure-production master
Counting objects: 4, done.
Delta compression using up to 8 threads.
Compressing objects: 100% (4/4), done.
....
-----&amp;gt; Shutting down old containers in 60 seconds
=====&amp;gt; fc005e593ed37166e80f04c0b0093f367771bff7aa055e4bc2900fa8a9a2850b
=====&amp;gt; Application deployed:
       http://greeterbot-production.agileventures.eastus.cloudapp.azure.com

To agileventures.eastus.cloudapp.azure.com:greeterbot-production
   f7db8d3..53ef0fc  master -&amp;gt; master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so of course ideally we&amp;rsquo;d have a staging instance which was pointing at a different Slack instance to check that was all working and tests wrapping different parts of the system, but I&amp;rsquo;m doing my usual &amp;ldquo;get the round trip working first&amp;rdquo;.  I took the liberty of pushing out the Premium Mob special offer on both twitter and facebook, and I&amp;rsquo;ll now happily wait to see if the next person who joins Slack gets the updated message.  The code change is so small that it feels pretty safe.  There may be an issue with how it formats in Slack, but I quickly tested that by pasting the message in, and this slackbot seems to get it&amp;rsquo;s hyperlinks auto linked in the way expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I guess that&amp;rsquo;s a short one today.  In parallel we&amp;rsquo;re starting to have some tiny traction from having added Chatlio to the site.  I&amp;rsquo;m just talking in #new&lt;em&gt;projects to a new member who first contacted us on Chatlio &amp;hellip; they were reaching out to me in DM and I got them to ask their questions in #new&lt;/em&gt;projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am just curious to understand about Agile Ventures as an organisation like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who decides on whether a project would be accepted by Agile Ventures or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with a charity aspect, can the project also have a commercial angle to it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had always felt a need for better products in education sector and obviously, technology is the enabler for it. I am just trying to think Loud and just wondering if I come up with some products which at present is just at an idea stage, will I be able to take that idea to product stage using a platform like yours?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the idea reaches proof of concept, may be then we could use platforms like Kickstarter etc to raise funds?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway thanking all of you in advance for taking time to read  this&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I responded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately the decision about whether a project is accepted into AgileVentures is up to the charity trustees and charity members&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we have a charity constitution with objectives of 1) open education accessible to all AND 2) helping charities, non-profits and other socially beneficial causes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the process usually starts with someone proposing a project here and us discussing whether it&amp;rsquo;s appropriate - if you scroll up you can see some examples of that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;projects do occasionally have commercial angles to them - I believe #take&lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;away was for a normal business where the owner had agreed to make the project completely open source for learning purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where we&amp;rsquo;d have difficulty is supporting a project that was for a for-profit business where the code was close-sourced.  It might still have educational benefit to the volunteer coders, but really developers should receive payment for that sort of work, and while we&amp;rsquo;re happy to help our members make connections with private businesses, we can&amp;rsquo;t really support those projects directly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you&amp;rsquo;re most welcome to brainstorm product and project ideas.  Our platform could certainly help you take that to the product stage given commitment to open source and open development so that all our members could benefit from the experience, and especially if you&amp;rsquo;re committed to non-profit and charitable objectives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do wonder if we need a more formal route for project proposals.  That&amp;rsquo;s another part of the website ecosystem - in the first instance I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep focusing on the onboarding route for new members.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV Website Review Part 6</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/12/av-website-review-part-six/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/12/av-website-review-part-six/</id>
    <published>2017-07-12T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-04T21:50:59+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So my spike of adding ReCaptcha to the sign up page went pretty well.  It all seems to be passing in CI.  I was expecting lots of the sign up tests to break, but they all passed.  I guess because they don&amp;rsquo;t have javascript enabled?  It tempts me to get this merged in and into the flow.  Or should I be strict and get more detailed tests around them?  I switched on JavaScript and got this error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Given I am not logged in      # features/step_definitions/user_steps.rb:59
      undefined method `submit' for #&amp;lt;Capybara::Poltergeist::Driver:0x007fc4b81becf0&amp;gt; (NoMethodError)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which appears to derive from Poltergeist not supporting the sign out step below&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;When&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="sr"&gt;/^I sign out$/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;driver&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;submit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;:delete&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;destroy_user_session_path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So one could spend time converting the tests for the logout, directly (at some test running time cost), and/or investigating how the Poltergeist driver might do the same thing.  It reminds me of a conversation I had with Lokesh the other day about what we want from our tests, that they:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;are reliable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;catch bugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;are quick to put together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficulty is getting all these four at the same time.  There&amp;rsquo;s also the question about getting testing at the different levels of acceptance, integration and unit, and the level of black-boxiness they operate with.  Of course my new resolution is to focus my mornings on actually making changes to the website (and surrounding ecosystem), rather than just blogging about the generalities.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s probably a concise blog post on the subject (and maybe I could generate it), but priorities.  Of course my mind is scattered from the intense discussions about microservices for the AsyncVoter project, and so I had resolved this morning to look at another part of the AgileVentures ecosystem, which is the little greeting bot that I have running in node on an Amazon EC2 instance.  Thinking about the funnel of folks coming into AgileVentures, we have something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See Google AdWord or hear about us on podcast or through MOOC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Land on AV website home page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some set of navigation steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Land on the AV Sign up page (hopefully soon with captcha)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now after the sign up point, the member is redirected to the Getting Started page, which I just think should mention that a Slack invite has been sent.  Perhaps a flash notice to let them know to check their email for the Slack invite?  One that doesn&amp;rsquo;t dissappear too fast.  Maybe the sign up page itself should say that a slack invite will be sent?  I created an issue for that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1724&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is that just re-arranging deck chairs?  So then there&amp;rsquo;s the ongoing flow of how and whether the member works through the &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; page.  There&amp;rsquo;s also the experience they have in Slack.  It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating that we can&amp;rsquo;t have an integrated experience where the Slack &amp;ldquo;chat&amp;rdquo; and website &amp;ldquo;documentation&amp;rdquo; are both available in parallel.  Anyhow, what we do have is this automated greeting when the user joins the Slack instance, which comes from my avatar and looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="automated greeting" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/uibnox5ijldnhz8/Screenshot%202017-07-12%2009.50.29.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;rsquo;s not ideal that again we&amp;rsquo;re directing folks to a third party site (GitHub), but that partly reflected my frustration with editing in the Mercury editor in the main AV site.  Part of me wants to tear Mercury out of WSO and replace it with a markdown system, or have pages in WSO pull in from GitHub or something, but is the simpler thing to just try getting that page into Mercury?  Or would it be better to be pointing the new members directly to our AV &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page?  So I did &lt;a href="https://www.agileventures.org/joining-a-project"&gt;that&lt;/a&gt;, and it looks okay, but the contents section still points to GitHub.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know how well we support &amp;ldquo;in page&amp;rdquo; anchors.  It&amp;rsquo;s these little things that make GitHub&amp;rsquo;s markdown so appealing.  Do we replicate?  Point to?  Not sure.  Either way, I&amp;rsquo;m struck by &amp;ldquo;LOTS OF TEXT&amp;rdquo; which is what our design sprint is pointing us away from &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we&amp;rsquo;re also paying Amazon, monthly, a small amount for running this bot when we could be doing it cheaper on Azure, so I want to move that over.  Also Federico is keen for me to add the special offer about a free Mob session for liking us on Facebook or following us on Twitter.  I also want to get it set up so others can edit it &amp;hellip; let me at least try and remember how to access that code.  It&amp;rsquo;s in this repo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/greeter_bot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically the bot is completely trivial.  I can&amp;rsquo;t immediately access it due to my IP address having changed - so it&amp;rsquo;s time to add the new one to EC2 security; and I&amp;rsquo;m in.  It&amp;rsquo;s just a git repo on a linux box and trivial to update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s interesting is that this has been running for six months&amp;ndash;no trouble and no tests.  So anyway, I just ended up attempting to deploy the greeter bot on Azure/Dokku, which basically involved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote add azure-production dokku@agileventures.eastus.cloudapp.azure.com:greeterbot-production
ssh dokku@agileventures.eastus.cloudapp.azure.com apps:create greeterbot-production
ssh dokku@agileventures.eastus.cloudapp.azure.com config:set greeterbot-production GREETER_SLACK_BOT_TOKEN=XXXXXXX
git remote 
git pull origin master
git push azure-production master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in the greeter bot directory locally. And maybe that&amp;rsquo;s working?  The logs look promising:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;→ ssh dokku@agileventures.eastus.cloudapp.azure.com logs greeterbot-production
2017-07-12T09:14:08.250109458Z app[web.1]: 
2017-07-12T09:14:08.250159913Z app[web.1]: &amp;gt; greeter_bot@1.0.0 start /app
2017-07-12T09:14:08.250165992Z app[web.1]: &amp;gt; node server.js
2017-07-12T09:14:08.250169031Z app[web.1]: 
2017-07-12T09:14:08.938145069Z app[web.1]: info: ** No persistent storage method specified! Data may be lost when process shuts down.
2017-07-12T09:14:08.964844990Z app[web.1]: info: ** Setting up custom handlers for processing Slack messages
2017-07-12T09:14:08.978923602Z app[web.1]: info: ** API CALL: https://slack.com/api/rtm.start
2017-07-12T09:14:09.788834373Z app[web.1]: notice: ** BOT ID: tansaku ...attempting to connect to RTM!
2017-07-12T09:14:09.853519358Z app[web.1]: notice: RTM websocket opened
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of course, we may have the same issue that we had on drie that the container sleeps and the websocket dies, and maybe I should have gone for the (simpler?) option of just deploying an ubuntu box on Azure and copying the thing over there &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve shut down the EC2 bot and so we&amp;rsquo;ll run this experiment.  The greeter bot is just waiting for &lt;code&gt;team_join&lt;/code&gt; events, which I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to simulate, and really the question is will Azure/Dokku work in full round trip with real users on Slack.   Of course I could do a direct test on a secondary Slack instance and create a new user to check it out - actually I could create a new user with some random email address on the main instance, although that means messy test users cluttering up the main Slack. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I just wait for someone new to join - I can always post them the message myself if the Azure/Dokku deploy doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.  I&amp;rsquo;ve burned enough time this morning and it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on to admin/Slack/Emails.  Would have been cleaner to start in the test Slack instance, but now the experiment&amp;rsquo;s in progress &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it works Federico and others can submit PRs to change the greeter bot message and even deploy the changes themselves &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
