<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>All Good Things ...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/</id>
    <published>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-10T21:54:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="good things" src="/images/good_things.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been daily blogging for a year now.  Working day blogs that is.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging on weekends, or national holidays, or during my vacations.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty consistent.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of days where work was super busy due to the tail end of a design sprint or something, but I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to retro-actively blog and keep it one per work day.  I started blogging in June last year doing a blog on a different platform each day of the week, but fairly soon I fell into a pattern of blogging to our AgileVentures middleman site, and then re-releasing to Medium after I&amp;rsquo;d got a little distance from the blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the purpose of this blog frenzy?  My memory is that it was about trying to communicate more effectively.  I often end up assuming that people understand my thoughts and intentions and it turns out that actually they don&amp;rsquo;t.  Of course why would they?  There are few telepaths around.  I&amp;rsquo;m also a bit of a gabbler and my sense is that it&amp;rsquo;s not super easy to understand what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to communicate.  So blogging, get all the thoughts down in text, provide them in an accessible form for everyone to read, and maybe reduce my need to gabble on and on about things.  Win win, no?  There&amp;rsquo;s also the motivation that blogging at the start of each day is a kind of &amp;ldquo;morning pages&amp;rdquo; activity such as writers use to start off their days and clear their heads.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think writers usually publish their morning brain dump, but I have certainly found the process of starting each day with writing out my thoughts to be reassuring and relaxing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year when I was doing a lot more coding, the blogs tended to be all about the previous day&amp;rsquo;s coding.  As AgileVentures became an official charity and my admin load increased, they have tended to be about prioritization.  Starting the day with a blog is certainly less stressful than starting the day with a review of email and Slack conversations, which will generally lead to many adds to my ever-increasing todo list.  Has the time been well spent?  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had positive reactions to some blogs, but my sense is that the blogs are too long, too stream-of-consciousness, too un-focused to gain much traction.  I think I may have even alienated some with my uncensored and unedited thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was 17 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had trouble just generating text, and from even earlier I was always a talker.  It&amp;rsquo;s like my internal thought wheel is hooked up directly to my mouth, and at will I can hook it up to a pen or a keyboard and just dump my thoughts straight out, for better or for worse.  So I rarely have writer&amp;rsquo;s block, but it leaves me with a different problem.  How to edit the thicket of thoughts and ideas, so as to more effectively communicate them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to the end of a year of blogging prompts thoughts of changing things going forward.  There&amp;rsquo;ve been times in the past when rising early I&amp;rsquo;ve done 3 hours of programming before breakfast.  After recent design sprints I think about doing coding sprints, or other activities that fill the week in different ways.  Should it be one blog a week with the blog being edited and revised each day, so that a single polished blog can be released on Friday?  I guess it all depends on what one wants to achieve, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t the Buddhist in me been trying to follow a path of consecrated action, where one is totally unattached to the outcomes of activities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d have loved my blogs to have provoked more positive responses of &amp;ldquo;yes, let&amp;rsquo;s build a solution to that together &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, although there has been some of that.  What I really would like is for AgileVentures to be a healthy thriving community providing great learning experiences for many, while also helping charitable causes around the world.  The process of reflection over the last year does make me think that we&amp;rsquo;re far too text heavy in many, many parts of our interface with the world.  One of the most attractive ideas for me going forward is that I&amp;rsquo;d spend my blogging time each day focused on a part of the main AgileVentures site, converting it from text heavy to text light and adding images.  I have a hunch that, by doing this in strategic places throughout the site, we could improve the sign up rates, the number of members joining projects and the numbers signing up for Premium subscriptions, the source of our financial sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a feeling I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to shake the blogging habit.  The process has become too solidly part of my daily routine.  The thing that actually gets me started and ready to work in the mornings.  So, anyhow, starting tomorrow, blogs that focus on parts of the main AgileVentures site.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to work through it one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog released early for inclusion in our July newsletter, earlier blogs are all in draft form in GitHub and will be on this site soon&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title/>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/09/sticky-feelings/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/09/sticky-feelings/</id>
    <published>2017-06-09T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-05T22:07:01+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;title: Sticky Feelings
date: 2017-06-09
tags: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;author: Sam Joseph&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="sticky" src="/images/sticky.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m heading south of the river again for an NHS meeting - I&amp;rsquo;ve just typed up my draft marketing/moderation report and got it into a PDF format that I can share with the NHS folks.  I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten the bloody dongle I need for the old style projectors - will have to order a spare one of those to leave in my bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with this week is my own reactions to two emotionally charged interactions on Slack. I have always found difficult social interactions terribly sticky in my mind, i.e. I keep reviewing the same thing over and over again.  I particularly remember working at the University of Hawaii when my eldest son was about two years old and lying awake at midnight reliving interactions with the head of department over and over in my head.  There&amp;rsquo;s also been a partial pattern of coming into conflict with people when I join new organisations, at least I have a memory of a pattern and difficult (and mentally sticky) interactions with people when I started work at Toshiba; at an internet startup in Tokyo, when starting at the University of Hawaii.  I think I recognised that pattern and learnt from it, although it&amp;rsquo;s longer ago now and as we go back twenty years or so I can&amp;rsquo;t remember whether the particular interactions were quite so sticky before I moved to Hawaii over ten years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least for me, whenever I have an emotionally charged disagreement with someone I find myself dwelling on it repeatedly.  I think I&amp;rsquo;ve slowly improved in my handling of these things, but I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure that I&amp;rsquo;m being as effective as I might.  The two particularly emotionally charged interactions this week were with two AgileVentures members on Slack.  One is a premium member and the other is a free-tier member.  The Premium member got rather angry about a meeting cancelled at the last minute.  I think I reacted in reasonably apologetic tones, but I think my attempt at an explanation lead to more anger.  A follow up post from that individual (I&amp;rsquo;m worried to mention names for fear of further inflaming things) left me reeling in a very highly charged emotional state.  In the past I might have responded directly in Slack, but in a hopefully more sensible approach I wrote out my feelings in a text document, and responded later to the individual that I had heard what they said, and let them know I had written a long response and offered to share that, or possibly to meet in order to talk face to face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that&amp;rsquo;s a better way to go and as it happened a podcast with Erin Flynn the next day gave similar advice.  Still I was frustrated at the strength of my feelings and I spent an hour on writing them up.  In the process I think I definitely did understand the person&amp;rsquo;s point of view better, but also strengthened my own feelings that they are over-reacting to a degree.  While writing that out may have addressed my immediate highly intense feelings it has not stopped me from visiting and re-visiting the interaction repeatedly over the subsequent days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On reflection it feels that my attempt at an explanation did not help and merely fanned the flames.  In deep irony that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m always telling my children - get that apology in, and wait for the person to calm down before trying to explain.  Erin Flynn was saying focus on saying that you are sorry the person feels the way they do, but do not apologise for your actions, per se.  At least (I assume) that you are in a place where you can decide that&amp;rsquo;s appropriate, rather than just doing it reactively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have more examples of how the apology/reaction can backfire.  The most difficult thing for me however is the unpleasant sensation that it all creates for me repeatedly over the next few days;  waking up in the morning, last thing at night.  A mental movie plays in my head of the interaction.  How can I describe it? I re-experience the interaction over again and the same strong emotions come up.  What are those emotions?  A feeling of embarrassment of not having handled the interaction correctly.  A feeling of anger towards the person for directing anger at me.  There&amp;rsquo;s a kind of revulsion, a desire to just stop thinking about this thing that appears to have me re-living unpleasant emotions again and again when I would rather be focusing on other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the Buddhist/awakening stuff seems to suggest that it is helpful to simply observe the emotions; to try and be present in the body. I try to do that but often get caught up again in the unpleasant emotions and find myself overwhelmed with a desire that the unpleasant emotions would stop.  That can often lead to more feelings of anger towards the person involved in the initial interaction, and so the cycle continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At HPU it tended to be the students who I would occasionally have challenging interactions with, more than the staff, but that was possibly due to me working remotely from the other side of the world.  At MakersAcademy there were some tricky interactions with students, but it was ultimately the staff interactions that were hardest.  I can remember being overwhelmed with frustration at the actions of one individual and being repeatedley consumed by reliving my feelings about my interaction with them all through a family weekend. I ended up writing a short essay on it all.  Sharing that with the person then seemed to end up backfiring as they said they had felt be-littled by it.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t find that out till much later though.  I was busy trying to honestly share my feelings on our interaction and when they suggested sharing with the rest of the team I happily did so.  The team&amp;rsquo;s reaction seemed to be that I was attacking this one individual.  There it all seemed to be complicated by the fact that I was in a position of some authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back at that situation it seems like I should have shared my short essay with some of the other senior team members before going to the individual in question.  I&amp;rsquo;m still shocked by how it all seemed to blow up in my face.  I&amp;rsquo;m now on good terms with the individual in question, but I still regret how it all turned out.  The individual in question had come across as a very confident assertive individual.  However the interaction with the essay was a traumatic one because I was someone in a position of authority.  I was approaching the situation as one where equals would be discussing how they interacted with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was another occasion when I had a prolonged interaction on Slack with a student about their decision to leave MakersAcademy.  They were being very critical of our course in what I felt was a logically incoherent fashion.  I&amp;rsquo;d been working hard to reach out and try and help the student stay on the course.  I shared my Slack interaction with the team in the interests of transparency and ultimately I don&amp;rsquo;t think it was too my benefit.  There&amp;rsquo;s a convincing argument to be made that I was just continuing an academic debate with the student far past the point that it was constructive.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.  I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t feel very good about it.  It was very mentally sticky, and my openness and transparency about the interaction didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have any positive consequences that I can see, other than to garner the feedback that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a very productive conversation, which I kind of knew already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsequently I have occasionally had very mentally sticky interactions at AgileVentures.  One of the key senior people appeared to get very angry and withdrew themselves from interaction with the organisation.  That particular individual often expressed themselves in what I found as very aggressive terms.  The final straw that broke the camel&amp;rsquo;s back appeared to be me not responding in Slack. I had made a somewhat reactive comment to something they said, but then didn&amp;rsquo;t want to engage in further discussion.  I relive that over and over again.  The individual subsequently wrote up a long list of their grievances, and I avoided responding to it directly.  Learning from my Makers Academy experience I wrote up my responses separately and shared them with two other senior team members, got feedback, polished etc., but by the time I was ready to post the individual in question had archived the discussion and it seemed like my input wasn&amp;rsquo;t being waited for, or necessarily needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should be digging out that response and sending it over to put my own demons to bed?  The timing seems wrong.  My sense is that individual is calmer as a result of having been able to write out how they felt.  I strongly disagree with many of their assertions and feel they were being unreasonable, demanding and unfair.  I relive those emotions with what I hope is gradually decreasing frequency.  More recently I have been writing up separate responses to someone who regularly engages in intense debate on the AgileVentures Slack, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted them back and in that case I don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be reliving things so much.  I still think their logic is deeply flawed, but I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped believing that trying to convince them of my point of view has much merit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that brings us back to this week.  I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about the first interaction where I&amp;rsquo;ve written up my response and have held off posting it.  The stickiness and unpleasantness of that interaction is vying for time in my head with another unpleasant interaction that came up later in the same day, this time with a non-premium member.  This individual had been upset on several occasions about their code (pull requests) being ignored.  I had said (as I often do on those occasions) that one option was to upgrade to Premium membership to get priority code reviews.  There was also a long running infrastructure issue on that project that I felt needed addressing first.  The individual had said they couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford the Premium membership and I had mentioned the possibility of sponsorship.  A week later and seemingly out of the blue (to me) the individual expressed that they were insulted by being asked for money to review their code and the offer of sponsorship and wanted to leave the project and AgileVentures.  I said that I was sorry that they felt that way, but that was great feedback and thanked them for it.  I also mentioned that I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I had asked them for money to review their code, but I guess I was splitting hairs; but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself.  It felt like a nasty accusation and I needed to defend myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more immediate consequence was that we engaged in a repeated back and forth in which we told each other a lot more about each other&amp;rsquo;s feelings.  It felt like quite a heated argument.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure neither of us felt very good.  Ironically it&amp;rsquo;s the former interaction with the Premium member that&amp;rsquo;s proving much stickier.  The non-premium member then surprised me by turning up in the planning meeting for the project, being very civil, taking on tasks etc. when I just thought they&amp;rsquo;d said they were leaving.  So confusing.  I really give up. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what the right thing is to do with all this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it really the case that you just shouldn&amp;rsquo;t respond to anyone&amp;rsquo;s assertions about yourself?  Is defending yourself just a way to get into an unpleasant fight?  Should one listen and not respond and always take a week before responding, even if that means you give no response?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NHS Wiki Marketing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/08/nhs-wiki-marketing/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/08/nhs-wiki-marketing/</id>
    <published>2017-06-08T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-04T21:38:30+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="marketing" src="/images/marketing.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crazy day yesterday - felt pretty under attack.  I&amp;rsquo;d love to lay it all in text, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can indulge myself beyond what I typed up in private notes yesterday and I have a meeting with the NHS folks tomorrow, and I think highest priority is having at least part of a draft of a marketing report for them to look at.  I&amp;rsquo;m worried if I blog about anything else I&amp;rsquo;ll just not get the report done, as I lost hours yesterday to reacting to what felt like emotionally charged posts on Slack.  So, what is the set of stuff that will go into the NHS Wiki marketing report?  Ironically I go to open Slack to find out as I have recently posted it into the #marketing channel &amp;hellip; here we go (and quickly turn Slack off before getting distracted):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monthly moderation reports need to be submitted including the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of rejected contributions with reasons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capacity required for moderation and time spent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any issues with the process and practice of moderation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other data as agreed to aid evaluation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly reports must also include marketing data including the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number of user log-ins (unique and repeated)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of users that logged in who commented or added to the wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What sections of the resource receive the most activity from users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geographical location and role of user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information of promotion/marketing of the resource&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other data as agreed to assist evaluation (i.e.uptime/downtime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s work through each of these and pull up some numbers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of rejected contributions with reasons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;71 rejected submissions of which 8 were tests by admin staff and 63 were &amp;ldquo;spam&amp;rdquo; (irrelevant) submissions &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capacity required for moderation and time spent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this first month the 63 &amp;ldquo;spam&amp;rdquo; submissions were all very clearly irrelevant to the site, i.e. submissions on topics completely unrelated to healthcare.  The moderation was largely handled by the automated system.  Admins spent at most a couple of hours reviewing submissions, rejecting &amp;ldquo;spam&amp;rdquo; submissions and marking spammers as such.  Existing stakeholders were quickly marked as moderator approved (requiring no more than a couple of hours over the month), and as such there were no moderated submissions for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any issues with the process and practice of moderation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment the ratio of spam to normal submissions is rather high and created the slight risk that a normal submission may be lost in the spam listings.  These automated spam submissions might be handled more effectively with MediaWiki policing like AbuseFilter, SpamBlacklist or ConfirmEdit, but these need testing to see the impact they might have on the submission process for regular users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other data as agreed to aid evaluation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No other data yet requested&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The number of user log-ins (unique and repeated)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logins are not required to view the site.   Site traffic from Google Analytics indicates that over the last month there were 293 visits to the site, corresponding to 134 different unique users.  The average session&amp;rsquo;s duration was 5 minutes and 40 seconds, which involved visiting on average 4.6 pages. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of users that logged in who commented or added to the wiki&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11 users were active in the last 30 days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;| #Actions   | UserName       |
| ---------- | -------------- |
| 62         | JTong          |
| 30         | Suzi.griffiths |
| 13         | Peterilves     |
| 7          | Prusal         |
| 7          | Whifra         |
| 5          | Kim Hunt       |
| 5          | Dnewton        |
| 4          | Mulash         |
| 2          | JacquiWheeler  |
| 2          | Mags           |
| 1          | Shanooman      |

(from https://wiki.healthylondon.org/Special:ActiveUsers)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What sections of the resource receive the most activity from users&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top ten visited pages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="top ten visited pages" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/xy8ca86qjt9iq6i/Screenshot%202017-06-08%2018.17.25.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top ten accessed pages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;| #Revisions | Page name                                                         |
| &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- | &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;                                                    |
| 48         | Social Prescribing and Self Care Wiki                             |
| 25         | Social Prescribing                                                |
| 14         | Test Page                                                         |
| 14         | Policy and strategy in social prescribing                         |
| 14         | Help                                                              |
| 11         | Steps towards implementation                                      |
| 10         | Social prescribing for children, young people, parents and carers |
| 9          | Making Every Contact Count                                        |
| 9          | Self Management                                                   |
| 7          | Monitoring and evaluating social prescribing                      |&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(from https://wiki.healthylondon.org/Special:MostRevisions)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical location and role of user&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="top ten country visitors" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/y45nxt2d7p6dcp0/Screenshot%202017-06-08%2010.16.06.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="top ten cities" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/37u5brazchus1jt/Screenshot%202017-06-08%2010.16.38.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="demographics" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/y54sw2w7dvyhz1i/Screenshot%202017-06-08%2018.13.52.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information of promotion/marketing of the resource&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AgileVentures has promoted the site through their monthly newsletter to their member base of over 4000 around the world, and linked the wiki into the Social Prescribing page on Wikipedia, as well as reaching out and inviting all the stakeholders involved in the design sprint to contribute.  We&amp;rsquo;ve also developed the following text for promoting the wiki on the HLP website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Healthy London Partnerships (HLP) Proactive Care team presents a shared editable website (a &amp;ldquo;wiki&amp;rdquo;) dedicated to Social Prescribing &amp;amp; Self Care. This wiki is available as an open resource for everyone who is interested in Social Prescribing &amp;amp; Self Care and related subject matters.  The wiki uses the same MediaWiki software that powers Wikipedia, and can be edited by any approved user. In the first instance the wiki is a repository for resources to support NHS commissioners and others to implement and develop social prescribing and self-care in their localities. Social prescribing, sometimes referred to as community referral, is a means of enabling GPs, nurses and other primary care professionals to refer people to a range of local, non-clinical services.  The wiki is hosted by the AgileVentures charity on behalf of the Healthy London Partnership.  AgileVentures ran a design sprint with the Proactive care team and stakeholders from all over London NHS and voluntary sector partners to identify the mediawiki solution as the one most likely to meet stakeholder needs.  Please check out the wiki at https://wiki.healthylondon.org and sign up for a free account in order to start contributing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other data as agreed to assist evaluation (i.e.uptime/downtime)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Azure guarantees a 99% uptime for their Azure service: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/support/legal/sla/cloud-services/v1_0/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There we go, that&amp;rsquo;s a way to stay focused - blog the report that needs to be written &amp;hellip; now to get this off to the NHS &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Life is Complicated</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/07/life-is-complicated/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/07/life-is-complicated/</id>
    <published>2017-06-07T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-08-31T21:19:57+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="life is complicated" src="/images/life_is_complicated.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well no surprise to anyone, but life appears to be rather complex :-) I try to listen to a tech podcast daily to keep up with techworld and I just listened to &lt;a href="https://www.greaterthancode.com/podcast/episode-020-jenn-schiffer/"&gt;Jenn Schiffer on &amp;ldquo;&amp;gt;Code&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; which was a fascinating episode.  Of the many and complex thoughts it spurred, here are two:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I try to blog honestly and thoughtfully every work day, but I know I still hold loads back for fear of offence or creating difficult to manage situations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;personality cult vs open source - I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow managed to miss bad press about the personalities of Linus Torvalds, Eric S. Raymond etc.  I&amp;rsquo;m so impressed with linux/git that it&amp;rsquo;s complicated to hear that Linus &amp;ldquo;isn&amp;rsquo;t a good person&amp;rdquo;.  Less so with ESR, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been pointing people to read &lt;em&gt;The Cathedral and the Bazaar&lt;/em&gt; for many years &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we could definitely do with a lot less hero worship, but I wonder who gets to decide who is and isn&amp;rsquo;t a &amp;ldquo;good person&amp;rdquo;?  I guess if people are on record making certain sorts of statements that&amp;rsquo;s one thing, but I wonder what makes someone fundamentally good or fundamentally bad?  I asked all these questions in the &amp;ldquo;&amp;gt;Code&amp;rdquo; Slack and already I&amp;rsquo;m kind of worried if I&amp;rsquo;m going to have stepped over a line and have rubbed people up the wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things making my brain twist and turn include the camera light on my macbook being stuck on, making me think of the continual cameras in Orwell&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;1984.&lt;/em&gt;  I think I will probably have to reboot the computer to fix it, which takes up a chunk of time to manage all the open stuff on my computer.  I also had a potential Premium member enquiring about how our AgileVentures professional development support works (I accidentally looked at my email before blogging) which is great, but my reply seems to have bounced with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an email abuse report for an email message received from IP 217.70.183.197 on Wed, 7 Jun 2017 01:20:00 -0700.
The message below did not meet the sending domain&amp;rsquo;s authentication policy.
For more information about this format please see http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc5965.txt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Feedback-Type: auth-failure
User-Agent: XMR/2.2
Version: 1.0
Original-Mail-From: &amp;lt;sam@agileventures.org&amp;gt;
Arrival-Date: Wed, 7 Jun 2017 01:20:00 -0700
Message-ID: &amp;lt;c1afb083-78cf-a23a-745c-473a8e1465a0@agileventures.org&amp;gt;
Authentication-Results: hotmail.com; spf=softfail (sender IP is 217.70.183.197; identity alignment result is pass and alignment mode is relaxed) smtp.mailfrom=sam@agileventures.org; dkim=none (identity alignment result is pass and alignment mode is relaxed) header.d=agileventures.org; x-hmca=fail header.id=sam@agileventures.org
Source-IP: 217.70.183.197
Auth-Failure: spf
Reported-Domain: agileventures.org
DKIM-Domain: agileventures.org
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s unclear is whether the email will have been delivered with a flag, or will have bounced.  It&amp;rsquo;s worrying because maybe that means that the email I last sent to LaunchCode about collaboration didn&amp;rsquo;t get through.  I&amp;rsquo;m fairly sure many of my emails do get through.  I&amp;rsquo;ve previously emailed Gandi (my domain hoster) about this, but they haven&amp;rsquo;t responded.  Might it be my email client?  I need to reboot anyway, so time to upgrade my Thunderbird client I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also find that the non-profit discount that we&amp;rsquo;re getting on Hootsuite is 50% rather than 100% - my mistake.  So now we&amp;rsquo;re committed to £40 a month for something that I&amp;rsquo;m not sure we actually need.  I guess we can cancel, but this is something that the marketing folks are interested in having.  Hootsuite (which I don&amp;rsquo;t know well) appears to allow you to set up a Social Media posting plan and sending tweets and facebook posts and things to a branded social media account.  We were introduced to Hootsuite by a Premium member who&amp;rsquo;s been volunteering on the marketing team.  We also now have two marketing interns and several other members regularly attending our twice-weekly marketing meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of things going on under the purview of marketing, including the new monthly newsletter, these social media posting plans, promoting our Agile Book Club podcast, to name a few, as well as trying to work out how to make our websites better communicate what we do.  I&amp;rsquo;m totally convinced that we can&amp;rsquo;t succeed without the right communication, but I&amp;rsquo;m also confused about the value of something like a social media posting plan.  I also worry that questioning the value of it might offend some people, and/or be interpreted as me quashing their ideas.  As a senior AV member it seems that my opinions carry a lot of weight, and I have to be careful about expressing a lack of enthusiasm for a particular approach or direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was something that came up in the context of the MakersAcademy bootcamp where we talked about how CEO&amp;rsquo;s of companies might not realise they were always seen as carrying a couple of pistols.  There&amp;rsquo;s apparently this idea that junior people will sometimes silently throw out their ideas and initiatives if they perceive a senior person is not enthusiastic about something.  It maybe follows that this is a particularly serious issue in volunteer organisations where coming across as negative about a particular idea might lead a volunteer to completely give up and not volunteer their time in the future.  Now of course I don&amp;rsquo;t imagine anyone is going to complain if I say we can&amp;rsquo;t allocate financial budget to something, but why should that be any different to temporal budget, i.e. hours spent on something?  I guess that&amp;rsquo;s where measurement comes in.  Perhaps I should be relying far less on my intuition about what is and isn&amp;rsquo;t an effective approach; embrace all approaches, whatever I think of them, and focus on helping whoever suggests the approaches to get involved in measuring their effectiveness &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thread of complexity that links some of these topics together is that when I reviewed the first Social Media posting plan, I suggested replacing posts including quotes of Mark Zuckerberg with quotes from open source luminaries like Linus Torvalds, ESR and David Heinemeier Hansson.  Posting quotes from Facebook&amp;rsquo;s founder made me feel nervous, because of my misgivings about the facebook system, partly arising from me being hacked on there a few years back, and news stories about the algorithms facebook employs to adjust what you see, and posts from FreeCodeCamps&amp;rsquo; Quincy Larson and a sort of general feeling of unease that I get when I look at a facebook feed mixing updates and images from friends and family with adverts for products whose values I question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the &amp;gt;Code podcast is giving me pause for thought about some of these open source luminaries and even the idea that we should be promoting &amp;ldquo;famous&amp;rdquo; individuals.  I mean the whole concept of the social media posting plan seems rather artificial to me.  I would much rather be having posts about individuals in our organisation, or from individuals in our organisation about what they thought and they were doing.  As I understand it, the social media posting plan is about brand building.  Other brands are regularly posting on social media, so we need to do so as well in order to compete?   Is it dangerous to express concerns since that will demotivate people to try things?  I guess I come back to trying to focus on the measurement process.  But then sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to measure and take time to measure, so in the meantime you try to use your intuition. I&amp;rsquo;m tying myself in knots &amp;hellip; life does indeed appear complicated :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Saddle Sore</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/06/saddle-sore/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/06/saddle-sore/</id>
    <published>2017-06-06T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-08-30T21:07:11+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="saddle sore" src="/images/saddle-sore.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday it was back in the saddle after a break and I&amp;rsquo;m feeling a little saddle sore already :-) Fairly productive first day I guess - a lot of meetings and a few critical admin tasks taken care of.  Let&amp;rsquo;s look back at those meetings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noon Martin Fowler scrum - caught up with Matt and Lokesh, and talked through Lokesh&amp;rsquo;s PR on LocalSupport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1pm  Marketing meeting - caught up with Michael, Lara, Federico, Marufa, Blandine and Matt - managed to finish up in 45 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4:15pm Kent Beck scrum - just me and Michael - just a quick catch up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4:45pm Impromptu WSO coordination meeting - Michael, myself and Matt - talked through SSL certificate upgrade and github issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5:45pm AV Community meeting - Michael, JP, myself and Matt - talked about funding me and the upcoming design sprint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The critical admin things I got done were revising the AV charity tender documents that will hopefully allow me to generate some income from all the work I put into AV, sending emails to a mix of charity and private clients (past, current and potential future), and deploying the latest code for WSO, which had the pleasing side-effect of re-directing all the MOOC student pairing sessions into the correct chat channels (rather than spamming Slack #general).  I also managed to go through another round of creating private premium chat channels and engaging with AV mentors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not much room for coding in all this.  There&amp;rsquo;s a bit of talking about it.  I was able to just snatch at the security renewal issue between the WSO meeting and the AV Community meeting.  It seems like the following is enough to renew the certificate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo certbot certonly --manual
Saving debug log to /var/log/letsencrypt/letsencrypt.log
Please enter in your domain name(s) (comma and/or space separated)  (Enter 'c'
to cancel):develop.agileventures.org
Cert is due for renewal, auto-renewing...
Renewing an existing certificate
Performing the following challenges:
http-01 challenge for develop.agileventures.org
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;assuming that one types in the correct domain.  Given that the challenge is replied to correctly from the server, one gets new certificates saved locally and they can be updated in heroku like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo heroku certs:update /etc/letsencrypt/live/develop.agileventures.org/fullchain.pem /etc/letsencrypt/live/develop.agileventures.org/privkey.pem -r develop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so I need to get that done for the staging and production servers.  It also seems that the fixed part of the challenge key is not changing and so we definitely need to move that into an environment variable (if not change it completely) and then also work out if there&amp;rsquo;s some further way of automating this.  Apparently we can run &lt;code&gt;certbot renew&lt;/code&gt; but when I tried a dry run, it indicates I need to configure an authentication script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;The error was: PluginError('An authentication script must be provided with --manual-auth-hook when using the manual plugin non-interactively.',). Skipping.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to punt on the automation and focus on this first renewal manually and the change that will pull the fixed part of our token into an environment variable.  Going to make that the priority after this blog is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to yesterday&amp;rsquo;s meetings, I had been feeling pretty good about the marketing meeting in that we had worked through all the business pretty efficiently and avoiding long and meandering discussions.  I was focusing on not &amp;ldquo;blocking&amp;rdquo; anyone.  Ideas and suggestions were celebrated.  That they might have been mentioned before, or that they might have logically inconsistencies was only subtly alluded to, if at all.  I had a strong sense of &amp;ldquo;the more people in the meeting, the more important it is to avoid disagreement&amp;rdquo;.  That might sound like awful group think, but meetings are a kind of trap that people often feel they can&amp;rsquo;t leave.  Long discussions with point and counter-point should be moved into other meetings where everyone has &amp;ldquo;opted-in&amp;rdquo; specfically for that debate.  At least that&amp;rsquo;s my best guess at the moment - the &amp;ldquo;efficiently-run&amp;rdquo; meeting seemed to go down well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was confusion in my mind about whether the Agile Book Club podcast would go ahead since one member was suggesting a change of day.  Since we still hadn&amp;rsquo;t mixed episodes 2-10 I was tempted to try and use that slot for mixing rather than recording more.  That didn&amp;rsquo;t work out either and since I&amp;rsquo;m off early on Friday I suggested we try and do an impromptu WebsiteOne meeting.  That backfired in that the podcast member who had suggested the change of day hadn&amp;rsquo;t meant for this week, and my sense was that was frustrating for them.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m imagining a more intense set of emotions from the person than was there.  We were only communicating in Slack.  I ended up feeling pretty bad about it with the incident going round and round in my mind all night and now this morning.  Why should I end up focusing on that negative in a day with several other positives?  Is that evolutionary?  Are hurt feelings the danger signs that paleolithic humans needed to pay attention and sort out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve projected/imagined higher emotional states in the past? Maybe, or perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s that I&amp;rsquo;ve just apologised too profusely to the point where I&amp;rsquo;ve just added irritation to injury?  The podcast member was re-iterating that we should have just asked.  I had an outstanding question to them in Slack about the change of day.  We didn&amp;rsquo;t have the previous week&amp;rsquo;s Slack message confirming the topics that we&amp;rsquo;d talked about having.  The member in question is in a distant timezone which seems to make having the podcasts on Monday somewhat precarious because it makes them first thing on Monday morning for that person, and so there&amp;rsquo;s not much room to give alerts about potential changes of plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I find it difficult if something I&amp;rsquo;m planning for gets changed at the last minute.  I had been hoping that the individual might have joined us for the WSO meeting or AV community meeting, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t push things, sensing (or imagining) their frustration.  Why is this so sticky for me?  Similarly when my son&amp;rsquo;s football team loses (I&amp;rsquo;m the coach).  I think it&amp;rsquo;s my &amp;ldquo;hard ego shell&amp;rdquo; as Eckhart Tolle and Steve Taylor might call it.  I&amp;rsquo;m very attached to an image of myself as a punctual, reliable, organised, dedicated, effective, good and considerate person.  Things that appear to reflect on me as inconsiderate or ineffective are painful.  Logically what they reflect is that I&amp;rsquo;m human and make mistakes.  The stickiness is me beating myself up about the damaged self-image &amp;hellip; maybe :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s something else here I&amp;rsquo;m grappling with.  Communication.  We&amp;rsquo;ve got all these meetings going on, most of them being recorded and shared on YouTube, and that helps the wider team catch up sometimes, but realistically most people are not going to have time to watch the videos.  I think I (and others?) can end up with the false sense of having communicated something.  You say something in five meetings, maybe even to the same small group of people, and you unconciously think you&amp;rsquo;ve communicated it.  That might work well in a paleolithic village where the process of collocated gossiping will mean pretty much everyone knows everything quickly.  Much as I want to spend more time coding, I think the real problem to crack is communication internally and externally.  I suspect most people coming into AgileVentures from outside are confused about what we offer, and I think we have poor information flow internally about things like the AV community meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That came up from a big chat in #av-community-talk and we added an event on the main site, but then there&amp;rsquo;s still the occasional comment about &amp;ldquo;how would I find out about this sort of thing?&amp;rdquo; and I guess it&amp;rsquo;s either accept that you browse your way to knowledge on things and that there&amp;rsquo;s no reliable way of reaching out to everyone, or we solve that problem of working out what is the one correct way to communicate with all the of the people in our distributed team.  I suspect that people are getting their information from different sources &amp;hellip; email, slack, their calender, meetings, private chats with friends etc.  Maybe the AV Community Talk meeting needs to go in the newsletter.  Maybe the site needs more popups to alert people to things in a drip campaign fashion.  There was a great feedback feature on an e-commerce site I was using last night.  When I paused on the payment page for a long time it asked me for quick feedback and I said the shipping prices were too high.  I guess that&amp;rsquo;s the kind of information we&amp;rsquo;ll be hoping to get from the design sprint, but if our site could be rigged to get ongoing quick impressions from people about joining up, making purchasing decisions etc &amp;hellip; Interesting times.  I think the one thing I can be sure of is a few more saddle sores &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Back in the Saddle</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/05/back-in-the-saddle/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/05/back-in-the-saddle/</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-08-29T21:39:49+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="saddle" src="/images/saddle.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m just coming off the back of another half-term that I (mostly) took off to spend time with my family.  Ever since my first son was born and money was a little tight, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to squeeze every working moment out of a day, and I think I may be suffering from a &amp;ldquo;more haste, less speed&amp;rdquo; situation.  Well who knows, I just don&amp;rsquo;t know what the key is.  Pour your energy and effort into something and you can easily burn out, spin your wheels, miss the wood for the trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did work Tuesday last week, in-between trips away to get a few things done, such as pushing out the week 1 MOOC materials, pay some bills and stuff I can&amp;rsquo;t now remember.  I had a few people phoning me while I was away - I need to talk to them about switching to email.  My wife suggested there are two sorts of people - the ones who prefer to commmunicate in writing and the others who prefer to just talk.  I love both, but I really don&amp;rsquo;t like being called out of the blue.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve really got to upgrade to gandi&amp;rsquo;s premium mail plan, or move to a different provider, in order to get proper &amp;ldquo;on annual leave&amp;rdquo; messages from my sam@agileventures.org email address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back at the keyboard again. Listened to another podcast during my morning jog and tweeted and slacked that, without getting too distracted by email and Slack.  Whenever I come back from these little breaks I seem to spend most of the day working through the communications backlog.  I&amp;rsquo;m still nervous about cashflow to support my kids, but there are green shoots.  Next week we&amp;rsquo;ve got our AgileVentures online design sprint.  There&amp;rsquo;s a famous quote about how if you want to get people to build ships, that rather than teach them ship building, that you should inspire them to crave the experience of the wide open sea.  I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the design sprint can be something of a vision quest where the community comes together over a vision that can drive itself forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then two weeks after that I&amp;rsquo;m running an in-person design sprint for a closed source educational project.  Fingers crossed that&amp;rsquo;ll pay for my kids extra-curricular music, sports and travel for when I&amp;rsquo;m taking my seventh week breaks to spend time with them.  As I was saying to a couple of relatives over the weekend, I start to see the appeal of a straightforward job with a job description and a reliable, regular salary; although maybe those don&amp;rsquo;t exist anymore?   Feels like some people must have them.  The difficult with being my own boss (of my private company and the AgileVentures charity) is that every day I&amp;rsquo;ve got to be weighing up the pros and cons of how I spend each minute of each hour.  Will this activity generate value?  Will that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a very in the moment &amp;ldquo;mindful&amp;rdquo; way to be.  I&amp;rsquo;ve just read &amp;ldquo;Leap&amp;rdquo; by Steve Taylor, which suggests that Eckhart Tolle-esque spiritual awakenings are not that rare.  Those are enlightenment moments where future and past disappear and you become totally engrossed in the moment, combined with the dissolution of any sense of separation between yourself and the rest of the world.  There are also overtones of everything (plants, rocks, inanimate objects) all being infused with a benign consciousness or aliveness.  Just typing it out I remember this concept of &amp;ldquo;flow&amp;rdquo; from the gaming and education/skills literature which has some of the first, and maybe second, aspects where you become totally engrossed in a task.  Another thing I did yesterday was write out a list of the different competing narratives that struggle for supremacy in my head - quite a few of them being anxiety strains.  I&amp;rsquo;d love to have an awakening moment.  I managed to sit in a deck chair looking at the sky for half an hour on Saturday.  I&amp;rsquo;d love to have a mechanism to just shut down all the trains of thought when they&amp;rsquo;re not necessary, but I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m a long way from achieving any kind of awakening that&amp;rsquo;s described in these books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the absence of some spontaneous awakening, the key appears to be observing your thoughts rather than getting swept away by them.  I&amp;rsquo;m forever getting swept away in my thoughts and reactions.  Be the mountain, they say. Let the thoughts pass by as clouds.  Easier said than done.  That said, before the break, I did manage to &amp;ldquo;wake up&amp;rdquo; in some conversations and group meetings.  For some reason it&amp;rsquo;s group interaction that&amp;rsquo;s the hardest to stay &amp;ldquo;present&amp;rdquo; in.  People say things, you react, they react; it&amp;rsquo;s almost like running on auto-pilot.  To be able to stop and really consciously respond from a place of consideration &amp;hellip; if there&amp;rsquo;s some other trick, it eludes me.  Till then it&amp;rsquo;s back in the saddle.  Keep observing those thoughts, keep trying to &amp;ldquo;awake&amp;rdquo; in conversations and meetings, try not to let the minute by minute evaluation of the &amp;ldquo;worth&amp;rdquo; of an activity get in the way of mindfulness of the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
