<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-03-30T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>NHS Design Sprint Day Four</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/30/nhs-design-sprint-day-four/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/30/nhs-design-sprint-day-four/</id>
    <published>2017-03-30T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-10T21:55:39+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m getting a bit punch drunk keeping up with all the different AgileVentures projects and driving the NHS design sprint forward at the same time, as well as doing all the admin and legal stuff to get the NHS contracts all sorted before the end of the financial year, which is tomorrow.  I&amp;rsquo;ve just about managed to stay on top of the LocalSupport project, but my check ins on the AsyncVoter and Redeemify projects did little more than serve to remind me of the places we are blocked, or I am blocking things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Redeemify we&amp;rsquo;re stuck with CodeClimate not working on our pull requests, and no production environment setup.  On AsyncVoter we need to complete the move from Digital Ocean to Azure hosting.  I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to empower some new project managers with greater devops rights to move those projects forward.  On the NHS project we&amp;rsquo;d wrapped up Tuesday starting to work through with the change manager on some of the different hosted wiki platforms.  The idea is that this was part of the design sprint day two &amp;ldquo;lightning demos&amp;rdquo; where we look at great solutions from a range of companies.  Ideally every member of the sprint team would be bringing examples from a wide range of sources and industries.  I can ask the change manager to prepare some going forward, but here&amp;rsquo;s where the lack of members in our sprint team is a real handicap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least over the remainder of Tuesday and then during Wednesday morning on Skype we managed to review a good 10 or so hosted wiki solutions.  We paused briefly Wednesday morning to get the timeline straight for the project and the next few days.  The original &amp;ldquo;tender&amp;rdquo; had included an aggressive timeline, but our selection as vendor had been delayed.  The change manager and I came up with this adjusted timeline based on that delay and the upcoming public holidays:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;27th March - Work begins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5th April - Prototype developed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6th-7th; 18th April - Prototype tested&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;19th-27th April - User feedback incorporated into wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4th May - wiki is live with moderation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not clear what the outside constraints are that are driving this timetable.  Talking with the decider it seems there is a need to deliver something fast to help the folks on the ground (commissioners, GPs, patients, carers).  I&amp;rsquo;m concerned that if one wants to grow a successful community around a technological solution like a wiki then one needs to grow it slowly.  Rushing forward to a public launch of something increases the risk of long-term failure, but these are apparently the time/resource constraints, and we are a &amp;ldquo;can-do&amp;rdquo; bunch of folks, so we will do our best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked at eleven different wiki hosting services including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikispaces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikidot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tettra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Socialtext&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PBWorks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ourproject.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nuclino&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eXoCloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confluence Hosted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked through the first few with the change manager driving.  We were able to create a wikispaces wiki, but for some reason our posted comments would not show up.   As we moved through the different solutions, I started to see a pattern emerging in terms of a kind of activity script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit the page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a heading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add (and resize) an image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a comment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discussions so far had made it clear to me that HLP staff were also key end-users of the imagined solution, so seeing the change manager (an HLP staff member) trying to navigate these wiki environments was very interesting.  We were getting blocked from signing up to some of the solutions as I couldn&amp;rsquo;t receive my email over the NHS wireless, but we were able to try Tettra, which had a really nice clean interface, reminiscent of the medium blogging tool:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tettra's interface, reminiscent of the medium blogging tool" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/88nk1nwpyvdc4lm/Screenshot%202017-03-30%2010.23.22.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we continued with me remote at my home office over Skype with the change manager at NHS headquarters.  We tried wikidot where we found that the process of adding an image was somewhat laborious:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Trying to add images with wikidot" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/fe5pw87f6bbf2ca/Screenshot%202017-03-31%2009.16.00.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went back to Tettra to see how adding an image was there and it was pretty straightforward.  Next we tried PbWorks, where the interface was a little busier than Tettra, but there was good support for re-sizing an image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Resized image with PbWorks" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/74xnvyany1dzhxm/Screenshot%202017-03-31%2009.22.30.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moved on to Atlassian&amp;rsquo;s wiki confluence, which I was familiar with from my programming background.  I quite liked it, but I sensed that the interface might be a bit busy, given its usual target audience of tech specialists and programmers.  The problem here was also that I was interacting with the interfaces, and the change manager was just watching over Skype, unlike the day before when I&amp;rsquo;d been seeing him trying to manage the interfaces himself.  I consoled myself that this was all still really just us doing lightning demos.  We were trying to bring some of the possible alternatives into our minds, rather than conducting usability tests per se:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Atlassian's Confluence wiki" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/pbauj6vdnw45jy9/Screenshot%202017-03-31%2009.19.54.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also tried Nuclino which had a nice interface following the approach popularised by the Medium blog that Tettra also seemed to follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="the Nuclino wiki" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/9wzt2ogq6xdqlpl/Screenshot%202017-03-31%2009.19.14.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the ExoPlatform system we got quite lost in the interface and couldn&amp;rsquo;t work out how to even make an editable wiki.  We tried iMeet and Wikia.  On iMeet we didn&amp;rsquo;t get past creating a workspace (I note they&amp;rsquo;ve been pinging me every couple of days since, with their best shots at drip emails).  And the sign up process in Wikia took a while and ended up getting left in the background. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s more we could be looking at.  It was frustrating that we lost half an hour to trying Skype and Hangouts at the beginning of my remote day.  The NHS firewall appears to block Skype and maybe hangouts.  When I saw Brendan&amp;rsquo;s laptop the next day, it seemed like it might just have been wifi connectivity issues that could have been solved by plugging into a hard LAN cable.  The setup at NHS headquarters is interesting.  Open plan offices with flat screen tvs showing the BBC news channel.  Lots of meeting rooms with no computers in.  Staff work at their computers in the open plan office, but then generally seem to leave their computers to go meet in rooms where they can have discucssions without disturbing their co-workers.  Or make phone calls where they can only talk, but not show.  I would find it extraordinarily frustratingto be in meetings and discussions in the absence of the digital tools (the laptops) where you can really show each other things or collaborate on specifics.  Some meeting rooms appear to have sophisticated remote meeting systems in them, which is ironic when they could be using Skype or Hangouts, although of course there will be security and support constraints that the the NHS must adhere to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see that a large government organisation would be inclined to pay for a &amp;ldquo;it just works&amp;rdquo; secure remote meeting system, when Skype and Hangouts require a fair amount of technical know how and support.  Naturally NHS England will be very concerned about the security of all their systems.  It&amp;rsquo;s just a funnily different world than I&amp;rsquo;m used to where the computer is the primary conduit for both work and conversation.  The HLP team had been interested when I&amp;rsquo;d shown them Slack the previous day.  Perhaps through working together there can be some side-benefits via me introducing the team to some digital tools and practices that they aren&amp;rsquo;t yet familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big question now of course is how to continue the Sprint?  We were getting out lightning demos done, which was supposed to by the morning of day two, but we hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen the majority of our experts, and we needed to make time for sketching possible solutions; although I was questioning whether that made sense since the budget constraints required us to pick from existing solutions &amp;hellip; find out how we handled it all in tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s blog!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NHS Design Sprint Day Three</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/29/nhs-design-sprint-day-three/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/29/nhs-design-sprint-day-three/</id>
    <published>2017-03-29T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-10T21:42:21+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I realise that the sequencing on these sprint blogs is kind of off kilter, since I&amp;rsquo;m writing the blog on the morning of a given design sprint day, and actually talking about what happened the previous day :-/  Also, the normal five day design sprint schedule is being mashed into the available time, so let&amp;rsquo;s relax and go with the flow :-) Yesterday was Tuesday and I was down at NHS headquarters again.  In the last blog we&amp;rsquo;d left it with me trying to work out whether to continue the day 1 sprint activities into day 2 in order to complete them, or just drop them and move onto the official day 2 activities.  Remaining from day one were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Ask the experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Generate &amp;ldquo;How Might We &amp;hellip;?&amp;rdquo; notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Organise notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Vote on notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Pick target&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a meeting room from 10:30am-2:00pm, and I was just pondering what to do, when we were joined by two other members of the Healthy London Partnership team.  Serendipitously this seemed to match perfectly with continuing the day one agenda of asking the experts.  It would have been great to have all of these folks involved in the entire Sprint, but since that wasn&amp;rsquo;t possible, getting their input on the Goal, Risks and Maps that the change manager and I had generated the previous day would be critical.  We had time for our experts to introduce themselves and explain their roles in the organisation, when the &amp;ldquo;Decider&amp;rdquo; joined us and we flowed into showing the full team what we had generated the previous day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change manager and I had struggled with a good summary sentence of the overall goal the previous day, but the decider nailed it immediately with &amp;ldquo;Empowering people and enabling communities to take control&amp;rdquo;.  We seemed to be on the same page as far as the high level goal was concerned.  We talked the group through the risks, which they concurred with, and they added some more, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience of system is poor or too cluttered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Policy fatigue on the part of the Comissioners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of future enthusiasm from government on SP/SC initiatives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential contributors put off by concerns about legal status of contributions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and another from the change manager having reflected overnight that politics with a small &amp;ldquo;p&amp;rdquo; might be a problem, e.g. if contributors used any system we developed as a platform for excessive criticism of existing solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we took the group through the diagrams we had generated the previous day, which was particularly revealing.  As I explained the way that a commissioner who had been convinced to implement SP/SC might put out a tender to get bids from multiple SP service providers, the decider indicated that maybe it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a competitive process.  Maybe it would work better if it was collaborative.  He also pointed out that G.P.s and Patients/Carers could be ambassadors for the programs.  Patients and Carers could be petitioning G.P.s to use social prescribing in their areas, leading to G.P.s to petition Commissioners. And indeed it could be the Service Providers and Community Resource Providers who were collaborating to petition the commissioners, along with the G.P.s.  I added in arrows for these potential interactions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Social Prescription Implementation Map Updated with more input" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ikj26czyg78kf2r/updated_map.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly I got even more feedback on different models showing the diagram to Steve of Capable Communities that evening.  He&amp;rsquo;s managed to draw down money from central government to implement a Social Prescribing system in my local area (Harrow) without having to go through the process of convincing the commissioners at the CCG to release funds for the program.  He&amp;rsquo;s now working with the CCG and the local G.P.s, but brought the funds in by collaborating with the local authority.  Fascinating how these box and arrow diagrams can draw out the different perspectives on a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The diagram focusing on how the commissioner interacts with the materials and information drew out more from the decider on what makes up a commissioner&amp;rsquo;s day and when they might get a chance to actually use a wiki.  In addition, while commissioners might be the gatekeepers to unlocking funding, participation from the G.P.s was essential, and so ultimately any system would have to be meeting the needs of a much wider range of stakeholders to help SP/SC become a long term success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the team had to go on to other work, so that left the change manager and I, and I pushed us through the remaining activities.  Again it would have been great for more of the team to be involved, but we did our best; generating &amp;ldquo;How Might We &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; questions on post it notes, arranging them in categories on the wall, and then voting on them and placing them on the maps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Categorised &amp;quot;How Might We&amp;quot; post-it notes" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/j5yn7r0l78vnovc/hmw_notes_on_wall_portrait.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="&amp;quot;How Might We&amp;quot; notes added to implementation map" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/htsfa2h1zy7sy9x/hmw_on_maps_portrait.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was slightly artificial and I was realising that ideally we&amp;rsquo;d have had the input of a lot more experts (G.P.s, Patient Champions, Commissioners etc.) before doing this &amp;ldquo;HMW&amp;rdquo; phase, but we were working within the constraints we had.  Either way it seemed clear we were targetting a system that had to be transparent in terms of usability of finding relevant information and editing it.  It also seemed to me that part of the problem we were solving was just creating a framework for the HLP organisation itself to manage its information and resources in collaboration with a wider group of stakeholders.  If we could start with something that worked for HLP, we&amp;rsquo;d be half the way there, so I sat down with the change manager and started looking at different online wiki solutions together, recording the process using a quicktime screen recording.  More on those in tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s blog!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NHS Design Sprint Day Two</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/28/nhs-design-sprint-day-two/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/28/nhs-design-sprint-day-two/</id>
    <published>2017-03-28T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-08T22:31:57+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I was heading into London for the second day in a row to continue our impromptu design sprint with the Healthy London Partnership (HLP).  According to the Google Ventures book on the subject, &amp;ldquo;Day One&amp;rdquo; of a design sprint consists of the following elements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Set long term goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] List sprint questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Make a map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Ask the experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Generate &amp;ldquo;How Might We &amp;hellip;?&amp;rdquo; notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Organise notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Vote on notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Pick target&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sequence of events is designed to fit in a period from 10:00am to 4:30pm on a single day with a few breaks and an hour for lunch.  Actually there&amp;rsquo;s a fair bit of preparation before you can get started on day one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Choose a big challenge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Get a Decider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Recruit a Sprint Team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Schedule extra Experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Pick a facilitator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Block off five calendar days for whole team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Book a room with two whiteboards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge had already been set, of trying to increase the chances that Social Prescription and Self Care programs would be rolled out in many locations in London to benefit the health of individuals and communities while helping to control the rising cost of healthcare.  The team lead, who I&amp;rsquo;d met on Friday was the decider, but he was extraordinarily busy, and so had appointed his change manager as his delegate.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t realistic to grab a full week of anyone else&amp;rsquo;s time, so the sprint team was going to be the change manager and myself, as facilitator.  If we were doing a Sprint by the book, we&amp;rsquo;d have more people involved for the week and would have scheduled extra experts to be available to talk to on the Monday, but this was all at short notice and we were planning and doing in quick succession.  The change manager had reached out to people via email on Friday, and already had interest from 8 different people, but they were going to be a mixed bag of people who could talk either only on the phone or people who could come to the HLP offices in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggested that we try and split folks into experts and testers, and those who were only available electronically would give expert input at the beginning of the week, while those who could come in person could test the prototypes that we would generate by the end of the week.  We had a room with two whiteboards, but there was information we couldn&amp;rsquo;t rub off on one, and the wrong kinds of pens, so ultimately we ended up going with sheets of A3 paper as we tried to knock off as much of day one as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Long Term Goal" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/4tkxujc3bd75w25/long_term_goal_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our long term goal didn&amp;rsquo;t boil down into a wonderfully pithy statement, but the change manager and I seemed to be speaking the same language about what the project might want to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We generated two pages of &amp;ldquo;how might we fail&amp;rdquo; notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="How we might fail (1)" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/iaty72ys9211fe2/how_might_we_fail_one_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="How we might fail (2)" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/wen8yxuct4wq5tw/how_might_we_fail_two_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was doing a lot of writing, and the change manager was throwing out lots of ideas - I was adding mine in too.  We had the cart a little before the horse in the sense that we were already stacked towards thinking about a wiki solution that was proposed in the project tender, but either way I was definitely improving my understanding of how Clinical Commissioning Groups (CCGs) worked within the NHS in order to allocate resources for healthcare.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moved on to map-making, identifying key stakeholders.  The first map had a lot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patient (&amp;amp; Carer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commissioner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HLP Researcher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HLP Implementor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patient Champion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community Resource Provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Prescription Service provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;G.P.s (General Practitioners &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; U.K. doctors)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="First Stakeholder Map" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/dgicpsrce70xfze/map_one_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which we pruned back in a second version:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Second Stakeholder Map" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/62v1nl8vjb7ktva/map_two_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We identified the key component of the point of influencing the commissioners, and dove in deeper on that in another map that focused on just an HLP researcher and the commissioner as stakeholders, and what it would take to have the commissioner become aware of the material, absorb information from it and then actually take action:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="HLP Researcher and Commissioner Map" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/pslia27srgxazwg/map_three_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we ended up with a fourth diagram assuming that other stakeholders could participate in the creation of the materials, which pulled in another Stakeholder - a moderator:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Extended Commissioner influence Map" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/fjvqqyqb906v5q9/map_four_image.jpg?dl=1" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brendan and I seemed to be making good progress, at least in terms of me better understanding the complexities of the interactions between the different stakeholders.  Given a stronger sprint structure we would now have our experts on tap to come in and be interviewed, talked through our high level goals, notes on how we might fail and associated maps.  However we were still in the process of booking our experts, and our time in the room had ended, so we called that a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the rest of the afternoon catching up with email, and putting out feelers for legal advice on the project&amp;rsquo;s terms &amp;amp; conditions.  I&amp;rsquo;d like to have digitalised all the notes and maps, but there wasn&amp;rsquo;t time, and the big question going in for day two was how were we going to fit the different components of the design sprint into the rest of the week.  Should we split day one over two days? Jump straight to day two?  Find out what we did in tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s blog! :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NHS Design Sprint Day One</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/27/nhs-design-sprint-day-one/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/27/nhs-design-sprint-day-one/</id>
    <published>2017-03-27T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-08T22:17:23+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m heading in to central London again to work on this new UK National Health Service (NHS) wiki contract.  I&amp;rsquo;d already taken the train south of the river to meet with &amp;ldquo;Healthy London Partnership&amp;rdquo; (HLP) staff at NHS headquarters on Friday.  The AgileVentures charity (with support from AV Trustee Steve of Capable Communities and Mina of Enterprise Wellness) put in a proposal on an NHS &amp;ldquo;invitation to tender&amp;rdquo; a couple of weeks ago, and we&amp;rsquo;ve been awarded the contract.  The NHS headquarters is an imposing building just outside Elephant &amp;amp; Castle underground station, and the work comes from HLP itself which is is a collaborative enterprise of the 32 &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clinical_commissioning_group"&gt;Clinical Commissioning Groups (CCGs)&lt;/a&gt; in London and NHS England (London region), tasked with improving the health of Londoners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I had to ask on Friday was what a &amp;ldquo;Clinical Commissioning Group&amp;rdquo; (or CCG) was, and apparently they are the management teams in charge of healthcare provision (and budget allocation) for a particular geographical region.  So, for example, if a new hospital was being built, or a new mental health care support framework was being rolled out, the local CCG would be choosing how to spend the money, and perhaps more importantly, what kind of services are being made available in a particular area. According to Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CCGs are clinically led groups that include all of the GP groups in their geographical area. The aim of this is to give GPs and other clinicians the power to influence commissioning decisions for their patients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CCGs can be of different sizes, but usually (always?) have a director of commissioning who is the key decision maker.  The director receives recommendations from individual commissioners, of whom there might be 15-20.  In a given CCG one commissioner will have a brief that covers the self-care (SC) and social-prescribing (SP) that HLP believe can lead to better health and well-being for Londoners while avoiding rising costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HLP are trying to support the local CCG&amp;rsquo;s to make effective choices for improving Londoners&amp;rsquo; health care.  In the context of the current project they&amp;rsquo;ve produced two documents to help NHS commissioners develop social-prescribing and self-care in their local areas.  The &lt;a href="https://www.healthylondon.org/latest/publications/steps-towards-implementing-self-care"&gt;first document&lt;/a&gt; is already available online.  Social prescribing is about doctors providing patients with &amp;ldquo;prescriptions&amp;rdquo; for things other than drugs and medical treatment, such as activities with local volunteer groups; while self-care is all about empowering individuals to go out and take part in community activities.  There&amp;rsquo;s some evidence to suggest that volunteering and connection to the community are good for individual&amp;rsquo;s health and can lead to big cost savings for the health service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HLP&amp;rsquo;s concern is that while they are getting good feedback on the documents they have produced, they are likely to go out of date quickly.  They have a vision for living documents that will be updated by the commissioners themselves and other stakeholders in the voluntary sector.  For example, they imagine one commissioner having developed their own model and sharing that back so that all commissioners can learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commissioners who might recommend (and/or implement) SC and SP in their local areas may be working alone, or with a small team, and will recommend service provisions and changes to the director of commissioning who will make the ultimate decision.  HLP works with a number of NHS public champions, who are people with long term experience as a patient or a carer.  One of the public champions suggested a wiki as a possible way of managing all the documents.  HLP are excited about the idea of &amp;ldquo;open sourcing&amp;rdquo; their materials to allow for collaborative development of living documents.   They have a small amount of money for developing and hosting a wiki system and also for moderating it for the next couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are concerned about possible legal issues around who can post to the wiki, and so it seems we need a careful process to tease out their needs, and to work out what kind of system could achieve the outcomes they are looking for.  In discussion on Friday we came up with this very rough timeline of outcomes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 weeks: live with collaborative solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 months: can see people are using the system - see that people are contributing - see that it works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;6 months: starting to see online community - people are responding to each other&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;12 months: understand the broader impact this is having - and we&amp;rsquo;re seeing more SP and SC in London &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;36 months: see positive health and finance impacts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve proposed doing a design sprint to try and ensure we pick a solution that will give them the outcomes they are looking for.  There isn&amp;rsquo;t sufficient money to build a custom solution, so we will need to go with an existing hosted wiki service, or an existing open source wiki that we can host for them.  It turns out that everyone on the HLP team is extraordinarily busy, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be working with their outgoing change officer this week for the design sprint.  He&amp;rsquo;s going to be the decider delegate and I&amp;rsquo;m going to be the facilitator, and while ideally we&amp;rsquo;d have many more people involved and more time in both our schedules, we&amp;rsquo;re going to do the best we can.  The change officer has already reached out to various stakeholders to participate as experts or test users during the course of the week.  Design sprints are organised along these approximate lines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monday: Frame and understand the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday: Diverge and consider multiple solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday: Converge on specific solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday: Prototype a solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday: Test with real users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I&amp;rsquo;m taking components of Google and Thoughtbot&amp;rsquo;s approaches to Design Sprints to create a week long process that handles the various constraints imposed by the context of the project.  Stay tuned to find out how it goes :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clinical_commissioning_group"&gt;Wikipedia on Clinical Commissioning Groups (CCGs)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.healthylondon.org/latest/publications/steps-towards-implementing-self-care"&gt;HLPs document on Social Prescribing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gv.com/sprint/"&gt;Google Design Sprints&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://thoughtbot.com/product-design-sprint/guide"&gt;ThoughtBot Design Sprints&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Conflicted</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/24/conflicted/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/24/conflicted/</id>
    <published>2017-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-03T21:40:59+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="conflicted" src="/images/conflicted.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a week!  So many developments and me so internally conflicted.  Let me summarise some of the developments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The UK Health Service (NHS) awards the AgileVentures charity a small grant to develop, host and moderate a &amp;ldquo;Social Prescribing&amp;rdquo; wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I land a medium sized private closed-source contract for an educational site through my company NeuroGrid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;edX gives us the all clear to start another run of the MOOC in April&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With some success I used my last two blogging sessions to grapple with some sticky issues on the LocalSupport codebase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So having the UK&amp;rsquo;s NHS as a client of the AgileVentures charity could be a big step forward.  It&amp;rsquo;s a small grant and I&amp;rsquo;m going into town today to get more details, but combine it with the small grant from WikiMedia EDU and we start to look like a respectable organisation that should be taken seriously :-)  I should be overjoyed, but I find myself conflicted because while it&amp;rsquo;s great news, I need to take better paying gigs now to pay the bills.  To that end, landing this medium-sized closed source contract is another fantastic breakthrough.  It&amp;rsquo;s a really interesting project, but the closed-source part of it makes me feel crestfallen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just love not having to be secretive about things.  I love the potential for everyone learning when we do all our coding out in the open.  Of course when people are putting money on the line for a business proposition they are not incentivized to share - they want to minimise the chance that others can capitalize on their breakthroughs.  And sometimes, at least superficially, closed-source is needed to close the deal, so to speak.  I feel crestfallen because I&amp;rsquo;d prefer to have 100% of my time spent on open-source code, open-access pairing with the AgileVentures community.  The new private project won&amp;rsquo;t stop that completely, but it&amp;rsquo;ll probably take up 50% of my time for a few months.  Of course that may be just what the community needs, me stepping back a bit in order to allow other community members to take the lead.  And based on my personality I know I&amp;rsquo;d carry on doing some things exactly the same way till I drove myself into the ground, so it&amp;rsquo;s good to mix things up a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In parallel I&amp;rsquo;m caught slightly off guard by the MOOC being able to go live.  The pressure is on me to come up with start dates and my quandry at the moment is working out if/how we run the TA training course in advance of it.  Running the MOOC takes me away from what I love the most, which is just coding and pairing, and we still don&amp;rsquo;t have a great scalable framework for everyone doing that through the MOOC, or even via AgileVentures.  I managed to force myself to focus on unblocking some issues on the LocalSupport project this week by blogging about them, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t really wrapped up other jobs that I&amp;rsquo;m only part way through on WebsiteOne, AsyncVoter and Redeemify.  Managing too many projects? Me? Argh, we need some mechanism to scaffold folks into project management roles or something &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could the combination of ongoing work by the marketing team and the start up of the MOOC take AgileVentures Premium subscriptions to the next level? At least I&amp;rsquo;m not going to be completely distracted by a new full time job.  I&amp;rsquo;m also doing remote pairing on toy-kata and other folks&amp;rsquo; personal projects just to mix things up, which is fun, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t move forward the devops blocks on our Agile projects for non-profits.  I just wish we had a seemless framework in place to let folks pair online.  Google have split Hangouts into separate chat and meetup which seems insanity to me in terms of the gamified pairing experience I keep imagining.  Of course Google has their eye on other things.  Maybe once I&amp;rsquo;ve finished this private project we can do a design sprint on how to build (and fund) such a thing &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/QqMTSqux9Gs"&gt;Pairing on Tennis Kata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pull Request Feedback by Blog</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/23/pullrequest-feedback-by-blog/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/23/pullrequest-feedback-by-blog/</id>
    <published>2017-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-02T21:38:27+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="feedback" src="/images/feedback2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the blogs over the last two days I managed to get to the bottom of the problems on one LocalSupport pull request from a Premium member (Zmago).  It&amp;rsquo;s clear from that experience that I&amp;rsquo;ve got to adjust the develop branch so that VCR/PuffingBilly caches are all up to date and correct, or no other developers are going to get a correct read on what&amp;rsquo;s going on with network connections.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also got another pull request on a complex three point feature, that I need to spend some concentrated review time on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should have been opening another PR to fix up precisely that issue but I started by pulling down Marouen&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Post Volunteer Opportunities to DoIt&amp;rdquo; branch locally and re-running it with the caches in place - I opened a PR on that basis - but it went to my old tansaku fork. I really need to disconnect that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got down to reviewing Marouen&amp;rsquo;s PR, file by file, using the &amp;ldquo;compare with develop branch&amp;rdquo; feature in RubyMine, which is maybe a funny way to review, but well - start at the beginning.  I made the following notes as I worked through:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doit&lt;em&gt;volunteer&lt;/em&gt;ops.js file being loaded on every page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doit&lt;em&gt;volunteer&lt;/em&gt;ops.js hits local &lt;code&gt;/doit_organisations&lt;/code&gt; end point but does nothing with result?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bootstrap datepicker being incorporated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DoitOrganisationsController providing us local? endpoint to new service &lt;code&gt;Doit::GetManagedOrganisations.call&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new DoitVolunteerOpsController to handle creation of new op on DoIt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VolunteerOpsController has check for whether to display publish button (could be in helper or separate method)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;long running job PostToDoitJob&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new model DoitTrace to store DoIt publication status (VolunteerOp has_one) (in db)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new model DoitVolunteerOp to store more data about doit op? (not in db - stored temporarily)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doit::PostToDoit service to do posting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dropdown_list partial to allow for selection of doit orgs &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doit_orgs index.js.erb - not sure how this fits in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new form for creating DoitVolunteerOps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;volunteer ops show page broken up into more partials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sucker punch async job handling added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doit_volunteer ops nested in volop URL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marouen had a good summary in his PR description:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add new model for tracing published vol ops to Doit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add 2 services to interact with Doit API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add form object to manage posting to Doit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;implement active&lt;em&gt;job with sucker&lt;/em&gt;punch as backend to avoid extra cost from Heroku&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but it took me going through the code, making my own notes, to really work out what was going on.  Then I ran the system locally to review how the UI looked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="submitting a DoIt Volop" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/90viie9yi9r7knu/Screenshot%202017-03-23%2014.20.56.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was great to see a complete solution from Marouen, but we hadn&amp;rsquo;t done a UI mockup of how this should all work in advance.  Marouen was pushing up the code and driving from tests, but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t given him wireframes, which should have been the first step.  I had just assumed that publishing a doit opportunity would be done through the existing volunteer op form with a checkbox.  A checkbox that when checked might reveal the other possible fields. Zmago had done something like that in the past, but of course Marouen hadn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily seen that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I notice that we&amp;rsquo;ve lost some of the layout on the forms, presumably as a consequence of the bootstrap upgrade.  Gah!  I think the user experience would probably make more sense if we just had a single form.  I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about a user wanting to update the description at the point that they are published to DoIt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="existing form" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/g9rj5plfli4zz2o/Screenshot%202017-03-23%2014.28.05.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made this scrappy mockup to show Marouen what I mean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="mockup for merging two forms" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/9a02yw28ypm7qte/Screenshot%202017-03-23%2018.24.47.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I should get input from the client on this, but my intuition is that this will be simpler in terms of our URLs and the workflow for the end user.  The risk is that I&amp;rsquo;m pushing for changes that will just exhaust Marouen.  The buck stops with me here of course - I should have ensured we provided a mockup earlier, or made sure to check out the PR earlier.  So many PRs, so little time &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. we won the nhs-wiki contract!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
