<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Client Project Focus</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/13/av-ecosystem-review-client-project-focus/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/13/av-ecosystem-review-client-project-focus/</id>
    <published>2017-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-27T21:23:50+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="focus" src="/images/focus.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So despite pushing out fresh code all the dokku/azure bots still appear to be offline.  Would love to fix that, but yet I feel I should prioritize the client work.  I guess I can restart the dokku containers.   Has something in azure changed, blocking a new port?  Has rolling out metplus into dokku had some knock on impact?  Ah, I&amp;rsquo;m wrong; it looks like the main greeting bot did work overnight.  So I go back and post the welcome message manually to the few new slack folk.  Not sure about the greeter bots, but I&amp;rsquo;ve posted all the active project links in &lt;code&gt;#new\_members&lt;/code&gt; channel, so maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll see a few folks join channels and then we can tell if the project greeter bot is working again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I found the little widget that allows me to embed a spreadsheet view of another table in a LibreOffice Base form.  Now I need to be able to embed list boxes in it (which is relatively easy) and maybe have them point to other tables, which perhaps needs a sub-form in the table widget, hmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the background someone has answered my &lt;a href="https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/140501/base-dropdown-country-list/"&gt;question about countries in list boxes on ask libreoffice&lt;/a&gt; pointing to a countries table that comes with MySQL. Not sure if LibreOffice has MySQL installed, or that&amp;rsquo;s just a suggestion about where to get the data from, but they also point out that the SQL query needs to return the name of the country twice, so I try that, but the program locks up on me.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s something about list boxes in LibreOffice that I haven&amp;rsquo;t got quite down yet.  In the table widget I&amp;rsquo;ve got listboxes that are giving drop downs from the table data, but aren&amp;rsquo;t showing the relevant field itself &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a funny thing here - should I be trying to read the documentation about how to get it to work - I keep falling asleep whenever I try to read almost any documentation.  I generally make more progress just bashing on the interface and posting to help forums.  But perhaps I should just be getting mockups of the last two forms and sending them to the client, for what I will assume is reams of feedback that I could easily get distracted by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I force quit LibreOffice on the PC and re-start and adjust the query to return &amp;ldquo;Name&amp;rdquo; twice, but that leads to no particular change to the countries list box.  I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll need to re-import the data, since the countries column got wiped out last time around.  There&amp;rsquo;s also the issue that the country names in the existing data don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily match the spelling/abbreviations in the list that I added.  Need to leave that for now; does the double name return help in the subscriptions payment form? &amp;hellip; it does, but needed to be combined with intelligence from another answer on &lt;a href="https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/65146/a-dropdown-list-inside-a-control-grid-table-with-sql-consult-in-base/?answer=65195#post-id-65195"&gt;ask libre office&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so maybe now I can bash out the other two forms &amp;hellip;?  Urgh, but it&amp;rsquo;s locking up on the PC again &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Old School</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/12/av-ecosystem-review-old-school/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/12/av-ecosystem-review-old-school/</id>
    <published>2017-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-26T22:08:15+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bug" src="/images/old_school.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in the second week of a cold - I think it&amp;rsquo;s getting better, but I suspect that not resting properly last week is causing it to drag out for a second.  Totally distracted by Slack and Email this AM, but there we go. At least I have my PC set up with LibreOffice so that I can develop on a similar machine to that of the client.  What I also notice is that the project greeter bots seem to have stopped.   Would like to be working on them, but have to prioritise client work (I think).  Maybe I can just push an empty commit to see if they start up &amp;hellip; so I merge the outstanding pull request:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/project_greeter_bot/pull/26"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/project_greeter_bot/pull/26&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and push that out to production.  And then I get sucked in, shaving several yaks, I update the installation docs for project greeter bot and asyncvoter so that I can link them into greeting bot messages for those channels, and then I push that out from a branch.  Okay, totally distracted; might as well go on twitter and tweet the podcasts I just listened to.  Okay procrastination explosion; now I need to get to the list of follow up items I had from yesterday&amp;rsquo;s client work &amp;hellip; the outstanding issues were that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all dates should have 4 digit years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explain the significance of white vs grey boxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first line of address in top box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;country drop down should be full list of countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adjust DB schema?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add second email address to schema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Last Update”, “Date Joined” and “Member#” should be automatically generated and not keyable – these should have a grey background; other fields a white background. All other fields are potentially changeable although some will default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also notice that the mobile phone text is the wrong font &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to make these changes on the PC and see how they transfer back to the mac.  I start by fixing up the mobile phone text field.  The 4 digit year thing is interesting in that the data that we&amp;rsquo;ve imported has two digit years, although that might be an artifact of the import process.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if we have the date fields in the right format &amp;hellip; ah, it appears we do, so then there&amp;rsquo;s a question about how they are presented in the form.  There&amp;rsquo;s a section on date formats in the docs, but as with many things in LibreOffice it&amp;rsquo;s not clear if it&amp;rsquo;s specific to the base component:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://help.libreoffice.org/Common/Number_Format_Codes#Date_Formats"&gt;https://help.libreoffice.org/Common/Number&lt;em&gt;Format&lt;/em&gt;Codes#Date_Formats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not very googleable, this issue, but when I edit the database table itself, I see an option to set a default format, so that sorts that.  The other non-trivial one is the list of countries for a dropdown menu, so I ask a question about that on the libreoffice forum:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/140501/base-dropdown-country-list/"&gt;https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/140501/base-dropdown-country-list/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but I get side-tracked into that when what I should probably be doing is mocking up the other interface screens &amp;hellip; and now I&amp;rsquo;ve got the country thing working, but I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow blown away a load of country data.  Frustrating; I&amp;rsquo;m getting distracted by additional work requested when I should be focused on the core &amp;hellip; at least I will force myself to copy the existing form and make it into the &amp;ldquo;Subscription Payment&amp;rdquo; form.  However now the software has locked up on the PC &amp;hellip; so I killed it and now I have it giving me a copy of the form which I&amp;rsquo;m working up to be the Subscription Payments form.  I&amp;rsquo;ve added a subform and I can see that migrating to new membership IDs is going to be non-trivial, given they are the primary keys for relating all these tables.  And then I&amp;rsquo;m sort of stuck on displaying a sort of spreadsheet view of all the subscription payments in the new form.  I can create tables, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that&amp;rsquo;s the right thing, but aha, I have found the &amp;ldquo;table control&amp;rdquo; form element that I think we need, and that looks about right.  Phew, so looks like we can probably get all the functionality we need, although the migration feels like it will be painful &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/dm3liajv1l0lflh/Screenshot%202017-12-12%2011.40.52.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Client Feedback</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/11/av-ecosystem-review-client-feedback/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/11/av-ecosystem-review-client-feedback/</id>
    <published>2017-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-22T20:54:02+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="client feedback" src="/images/client_feedback.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got out a screenshot of the main APSoc LibreOffice Base Member Information form to the client late Friday, and over the weekend they&amp;rsquo;ve given me very detailed feedback on changes they want to the form.  Agile is all about providing working software as early as possible, but this seems like a nice shortcut to increase the chances that the resulting system will be what the client wants.  I&amp;rsquo;ve ordered a new HDMI cable so I can start developing on my windows machine (although will that just be a distraction?), and so I&amp;rsquo;m going to have a go at making all the changes requested on my mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjust label font (Liberation Sans &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Tahoma)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have membership number be numeric only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align last updated field with Member Information title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align all field names with left edge of inputs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce size of date fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All dates should have 4 digit years  &amp;lt;&amp;mdash; not sure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce size of &amp;ldquo;Known as&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Salutation&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wants to know signficance of white vs grey boxes &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; can explain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First line of address in top box &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; data issue - some addresses in odd places&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move &amp;ldquo;Local Group&amp;rdquo; up to address along with &amp;ldquo;N/L&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move up &amp;ldquo;NM N/L&amp;rdquo; also&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove KCM only text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move &amp;ldquo;City &amp;hellip; Country&amp;rdquo; row up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align Country field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Country drop down should be full list of countries &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; will need to investigate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Mobile Phone font&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove Fax field (and data from DB) &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; we don&amp;rsquo;t have final DB - am I supposed to provide a new schema?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove &amp;ldquo;Dietary Requirements&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace with &amp;ldquo;Email Address 2&amp;rdquo; &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; need to add this to DB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove “Gift Membership &amp;hellip;” from screen and DB (again the info can be moved to “Notes” by me after migration).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand “Notes” top full width of screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align check boxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Last Update”, “Date Joined” and “Member#” should be automatically generated and not keyable – these should have a grey background; other fields a white background. All other fields are potentially changeable although some will default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Work Phone&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Mobile Phone&amp;rdquo; fields should align with the fields in the row above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve done most of the cosmetic changes and some of the data ones:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/oz1u6wksr1c40mw/Screenshot%202017-12-11%2010.25.27.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In about 30 minutes, but that leaves me with a set of things I need to check &amp;hellip; over the course of the day I also got LibreOffice installed on my Windows machine where it seems to run a little faster, and I can confirm that it looks sensible on Windows; and seems to have all the right basic functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feedback from the client is very specific.  Some of the items are just tiny ones that I would have fixed in a subsequent pass.  Others are micro-changes for alignment and so on that I would have got to eventually.  It feels like many of these changes are ones that they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to make themselves when they are all set up with the software.  Others are more substantive.  Great to keep them in the loop.  For some reason I bristled at the font change suggestions; I think partly because I was having such trouble setting a default font, but as I familiarise myself further with the software I was able to make the requisite changes in short order.  It is great when one is able to show clients/users that you respond to their requests.  I think it builds a really positive relationship, but of course one needs to be able to say no when the amount of work explodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m optimisitic I can get the majority of the work done over the course of the next week without having to break stride, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see.  The interesting question is whether we want to start paying for Chatlio since this work was generated through that system, or if there&amp;rsquo;ll be any kind of similar work generated if we complete well on this.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got other people asking for quotes on website refreshes, so that&amp;rsquo;s probably the place to start before re-opening the web-chat deluge &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Paid Project on Schedule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/08/av-ecosystem-review-paid-project-on-schedule/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/08/av-ecosystem-review-paid-project-on-schedule/</id>
    <published>2017-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-20T21:14:58+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="project management" src="/images/project-management.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve told the APSoc that I&amp;rsquo;d send them mockups of the interfaces today.  I&amp;rsquo;m getting used to LibreOffice, e.g. leave the control panel open to more easily edit labels etc. It&amp;rsquo;s still painfully slow, and I&amp;rsquo;ve now realised that to speed up I need to keep the control panel closed when I want to move things around.  The copy and paste seems to work only intermittently, but I&amp;rsquo;m getting there &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/7sc51p52z5saxkg/Screenshot%202017-12-08%2017.59.55.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few more crashes, and I had the above.  Haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to get all the different interfaces setup, but I realised that each of them was basically a clone of the first with some different sub forms, so better get the first one completed before moving on.  I need to get the checkboxes functioning, and see if there&amp;rsquo;s a way to make the dropdowns choose only unique items when we&amp;rsquo;re offering options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also ordered a new HDMI cable which should allow me to use my Windows PC for development.  Given that the clients will be working on Windows, it would be good to be testing there, and I wonder if actually LibreOffice might work more consistenly there.  It would be a big step forward if the copy and paste would work on Windows &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Old School Progress</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/07/av-ecosystem-review-old-school-progress/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/07/av-ecosystem-review-old-school-progress/</id>
    <published>2017-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-19T21:27:32+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bug" src="/images/old_school.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m pretty far from reviewing the AV ecosystem here.  I&amp;rsquo;m devoting my blog driven development this week to making progress on the Anthony Powell Society membership database.  It&amp;rsquo;s old school in that I&amp;rsquo;m using LibreOffice Base, which is an open source version of MS Access.  I used to teach a course on MS Access and Excel back at HPU and it&amp;rsquo;s that experience that puts me in a position to deliver on the Anthony Powell Society project.  The APSoc have eschewed a cloud based membership database as they don&amp;rsquo;t believe their members would make use of an online offering, and don&amp;rsquo;t want to get locked in to some particular cloud offering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;d been managing their membership database using Lotus Approach for many years, and one of the big advantages there was the WYSIWYG interface that allowed the secretary to tinker with the forms and relationships in the system without having to be a hard core programmer.  Lotus Approach has been sunsetted and so I&amp;rsquo;m currently replicating the entire system for them in LibreOffice Base.  I had a reply to &lt;a href="https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/140023/base-list-box-dropdown-breaks-when-any-formatting-added/"&gt;my query on the ask.libreoffice.org site&lt;/a&gt; about formatting breaking the list box dropdown. Although it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fix the issue it is good to see that the community is responsive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one seems to know &lt;a href="https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/27384/how-to-change-the-default-font-in-libreoffice-base-form-wizard/"&gt;how to change the default font in Base&lt;/a&gt; but I need to kick on since I&amp;rsquo;ve promised mock ups of the forms for the APSoc for tomorrow.  What&amp;rsquo;s annoying is how slowly Base runs on my computer - I did do a restart the other day, hmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So LibreOffice crashes a couple of times and I lose 10 minutes of work, although I do work out how to change the background color and so make the Member Information form look more and more like the original from Lotus Approach:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ph3redhshw4p0cm/Screenshot%202017-12-07%2011.48.14.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also accidentally disconnect the form from the data source and have a few frantic moments getting it connected back up.  I&amp;rsquo;m thinking that I need to email the client to work out some of the more esoteric elements in the form that I haven&amp;rsquo;t added yet, but actually I see their detailed documentation includes exactly what we need there, so hopefully a good 90 minutes tomorrow and I can have mockups of at least the main form, if not the &amp;ldquo;Subscription Paid&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Gift Aid Declarations&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Standing Order Details&amp;rdquo; pages, which are simpler, but do include table embedding that I haven&amp;rsquo;t done yet &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So slow going, and it&amp;rsquo;s frustrating that most Premium members probably won&amp;rsquo;t be interested in this project as it&amp;rsquo;s not really using the latest tech.  I think it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful example of adapting to the needs of the client, and it&amp;rsquo;s good food for thought for our own membership/subscription model, but not many other synergies emerging here &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Crawling Along</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/06/av-ecosystem-review-crawling-along/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/06/av-ecosystem-review-crawling-along/</id>
    <published>2017-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-19T21:23:59+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bug" src="/images/bug.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I think I&amp;rsquo;ve forged a reasonable anxiety management strategy with the following schedule for the Anthony Powell Membership database:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Dec 8th - screenshots of membership database interface for you to approve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Dec 15th - alpha version of membership database for you to approve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 5th - beta version of membership database adjusted as per feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 31st - release version of membership database adjusted as per feedback, including full migration &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which the client says they are happy with, and I&amp;rsquo;ve queried about how the Membership Types table doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be used in the interface.  After yesterday&amp;rsquo;s blog I was fiddling with the system on the train and once I had the fields in the right data format, subforms linking in related tables was all working.  Ironically it seems we don&amp;rsquo;t immediately need that, but good to know that all works.  The form designer is not dissimilar from Keynote or PowerPoint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/eqeny8wkgv225x0/Screenshot%202017-12-06%2011.53.53.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m slowly pulling the fields around, trying to work out how to set the default font.  One thing I need to do is to be able to switch Member Grade to a drop down with different options &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve got that working using the list box wizard, but as soon as I try to add any formatting to the list box, the drop down functionality stops working:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/tlrx6xodqs4fw1p/Screenshot%202017-12-06%2013.46.39.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve asked on a forum:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/140023/base-list-box-dropdown-breaks-when-any-formatting-added/"&gt;https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/140023/base-list-box-dropdown-breaks-when-any-formatting-added/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but in the short term, unformatted should be fine.  Better work through the rest of the interfaces quick to see if I find any other sticking points &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
