<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-05-02T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Distracted Operations</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/02/distracted-operations/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/02/distracted-operations/</id>
    <published>2017-05-02T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-12T22:28:45+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="distractions" src="/images/Distractions.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m getting to the blog phase late today.  I had a backlog of a couple of podcasts to tweet, but one of them seemed particularly relevant to the discussion going on in #av&lt;em&gt;community&lt;/em&gt;talk.  I&amp;rsquo;d been keeping myself away from the discussion in order to focus on preparation for the NHS Wiki project training and updating the online courses.  I thought I could get away with just posting the podcast into the AV community talk, but I ended up reading, and then replying to lots of little elements.  I was definitely being reactive, and reading on, it was clear that others were doing a good job of making many of the points I was making, so I probably didn&amp;rsquo;t achieve much more than blocking and overloading folks, which I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be getting better at not doing, oh well :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a promiment member of AgileVentures the danger is that my input ends up quashing debate (and problem-solving) rather than encouraging it.  We&amp;rsquo;ll see.  There&amp;rsquo;s at least one member whose assertions always seem to get my goat, and I just can&amp;rsquo;t help getting into a debate.  On reflection I think I would have been better off reading the full discussion tomorrow and perhaps writing a blog post about it. At least with the new threaded reply system, maybe my input will not be as intrusive as it otherwise would. Either way, I&amp;rsquo;m now behind on my day&amp;rsquo;s schedule and have yet to write up what I did yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was the May day bank holiday in the UK and I stayed off Slack and Hangouts and spent the full day getting all the moderation and visual editor components set up on the NHS wiki, ready for a training session with NHS staff later today.  It took a good two hours to get the visual editor system working, which involved setting up a node service called &amp;ldquo;Parsoid&amp;rdquo; and opening up an additional port in the Azure system we&amp;rsquo;re hosting on.  Ultimately the &lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Parsoid/Troubleshooting"&gt;Parsoid troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; was really helpful, and I&amp;rsquo;m getting a stronger sense of the MediaWiki extension ecosystem, with some projects on GitHub and some not (MediaWiki has their own code review thing called Gerrit) and the wiki talk pages on individual extension pages seems to be the place to find out tips &amp;amp; tricks, and also the place to report bugs and receive help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the day I had a 30 page keynote with step by step screen shots of the following for the wiki:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Basics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where to go to access the wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to request an account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to search to find a page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to create a page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to edit a page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to add a link to another wiki page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to upload an image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Approving account requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Receiving change notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Approving changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rejecting changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moderation List&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Banning repeat offenders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;d managed to tweak the wiki to change the name of the homepage, get references working and add a fair bit of additional content.  Basically ready for today&amp;rsquo;s hour long training session with a few core NHS HLP staff.  There are a set of other things I&amp;rsquo;d like to do, such as getting the whole thing on SSL (will that play well with VisualEditor/Parsoid?), installing Wikipedia moderation templates and replicating more of the HLP website look and feel.  MyWiki&amp;rsquo;s set up a VisualEditor enabled instance for us and said they&amp;rsquo;d look at getting the Moderation and ConfirmAccount extensions set up.  Maybe they&amp;rsquo;re ultimately going to be faster and easier, but if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t set up our own system I wounldn&amp;rsquo;t have been able to work through and generate training documentation on the moderation process, so I think that&amp;rsquo;s time well spent :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I spent an hour updating the pair programming functionality in the AV102 and first part of the MOOC to switch back to our older optional style and start to work through some of the accessibility issues.  There&amp;rsquo;s still more to do, but that&amp;rsquo;s progress there.  The critical thing today is to record some new videos about the way that hangouts and events are working on AV.  Need to get that done before I head off for this training event.  More on that in tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s blog :-)  Unless I get distracted by Slack &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bringing It All Together</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/04/28/bringing-it-all-together/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/04/28/bringing-it-all-together/</id>
    <published>2017-04-28T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-08T22:26:33+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="wave" src="/images/wave.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last two days have been blog driven NHS wiki flurries in the morning followed by mobbing and AgileVenturing in the afternoon.  In the Elixir mob on Wednesday we made further headway into Phoenix and I really start to question whether we&amp;rsquo;ve all been suffering through an instance variable nightmare.  Yesterday I caught up with the marketing team, the Ruby mob (where we got confident with some of our legacy code) and then spent an hour bashing away at AsyncVoter&amp;rsquo;s Azure/Dokku setup with Matt and Raphael.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there are certain critical things that I need to do upfront this morning, i.e. as part of the blogging process, and some others that need to be done before lunch.  At the end of yesterday I was starting to feel calmer that we were bringing together all the things we needed for the NHS wiki project.  I&amp;rsquo;d emailed all the remaining stakeholders for additional meetings, the HLP team was getting the training dates set, I&amp;rsquo;d made an outline of the training materials, and we&amp;rsquo;d made contact with the Communications team.  Furthermore we&amp;rsquo;d also worked with the trustees to get the paperwork done for me to be paid this month, so that&amp;rsquo;s a relief.  The key things that need to happen before lunch today are then:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Process my payment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reach out to the HLP communication team (as main contact is off sick)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reply to NHS/Voluntary Sector stakeholder emails to confirm meetings for the week after next&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reach out to enterprise wellness related to moderation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m thinking that the first two have to be knocked off quickly. However in even trying to reach out to the HLP communications team I got lost in LinkedIn for 10 minutes reviewing the HLP organistaion there and connecting up to the NHS staff I&amp;rsquo;ve already met.  That was helpful, but (reality check) I&amp;rsquo;ve got to process this payment for my own personal finances.  It should be simple, but anything done for the first time can encounter issues, so let me just pause the blog to get that done &amp;hellip; done - had to do a text authorisation on my mobile, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t have taken more than a minute in total.  I also see that the NHS payment for the first part of our work came through, so that&amp;rsquo;s a relief to have that all sorted.  I think my heart-rate has slowed slightly :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have to think about how best to communicate with the communications team &amp;hellip; an email to all the contacts, or a separate email to each one &amp;hellip;?  I demurred from emailing the three contact emails I had separately, and decided to email all three, cc-ing my existing contacts.  There&amp;rsquo;s a danger that asking a group of people that everyone assumes that someone else can deal with it.  Here&amp;rsquo;s a draft of the email I sent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sorry to email you out of the blue, but I'm working with NAME and NAME in HLP, and our charity AgileVentures is developing the new HLP Social Prescription wiki.

I met with NAME to discuss last week and everything is looking good.

This week I was following up with NAME about a URL subdomain for our wiki, but unfortunately NAME is off sick and I was wondering if you, or someone else on your team might be able to help us out. We're planning for a soft launch on May 4th and a hard launch on May 12th so we're on a bit of a short fuse.

One piece of feedback we've had from many stakeholders is that any new wiki system should not be a "new" location, so we were hoping to set up a subdomain under the http://healthylondon.org domain, e.g.

http://wiki.healthylondon.org

We assume that someone in your communications team, or some of your sub-contracted developers, will control the domain name records for healthylondon.org, and would be able to set up the "wiki" subdomain to point to our system.

Please let me know if any of you might be able to help with this, or if you could put us in touch with whichever controls the domain name.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did add delivery tracking and a return receipt.  Some might consider a return receipt a little aggressive, but there&amp;rsquo;s a time crunch here and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to quickly get to the person who can help us with this sub-domain, or discover that we can&amp;rsquo;t have a sub-domain ASAP.  So sending a group email with a &amp;ldquo;return receipt&amp;rdquo; request was my middle ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with that done I should double check that the funds got transfered from before &amp;hellip; and it has. Yay! So while I&amp;rsquo;m in that bank interface I should update things for the new tax year &amp;hellip; and &amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s all done. Phew.  So that let&amp;rsquo;s me check a few more outstanding things off my todo lists.  So now I need to send out an email to Enterprise Wellness to find a good time for a phone call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It pains me that blogs about what we did in the Elixir and Ruby mobs this week might be more interesting to the coders among this blogs readership, and to you I apologise, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got to feed my kids, and that&amp;rsquo;s what the NHS contract is enabling at the moment.  If you&amp;rsquo;re really, really keen to have more blogs about how Elixir is changing the programming world, and how Ruby gets confident, then vote with your wallet.  Sign up for AgileVentures Premium Mob membership (if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already) and get your friends, family and neighbours to do so as well! :-)  In the meantime it&amp;rsquo;ll probably be more blogs about communication and mediawiki. Sorry &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=BW21_enHixI"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=nH0wPOZ9Ryk"&gt;Marketing meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=tU7lTV99tYY"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>More MediaWiki</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/04/27/more-mediawiki/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/04/27/more-mediawiki/</id>
    <published>2017-04-27T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-07T21:55:06+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="mediawiki" src="/images/MediaWiki.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the zone file propagated and we can now access our bitnami/azure instance at http://hlp-wiki.agileventures.org.  MyWikis support got back to me having fixed their VisualEditor which is now working for me on my Mac.  That means that MyWikis might actually be a good option for us.  I&amp;rsquo;m agonizing about whether I burn time on setting up SSL, VisualEditor and other things on our Bitnami/Azure system, against the other less technical things I need to do such as work out a training plan for the NHS staff, a communications/marketing strategy for the wiki release and a moderation plan.  I guess I&amp;rsquo;ve got to look carefully at the time that&amp;rsquo;s available over the next 10 days or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 2nd Tues 2:30pm - HLP Staff training (editing and moderating)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 4th Thu - Soft Launch of wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 8th Mon - Meeting voluntary sector group to talk about wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 12th Fri - Hard Launch of wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MyWiki&amp;rsquo;s pricing seems pretty reasonable, and under the circumstances it seems like we should at least sign up for one of their solutions and pay $15 or $35 for the first month to see if we can get the feature set that we need.  Things that I need to fit into the schedule include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reaching out to 8 other stakeholders that the NHS has recommended I speak to (arrange for week of May 8th?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going back to earlier stakeholders who said they were interested to see what we&amp;rsquo;d created&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinating with Enterprise Wellness on the moderation (invite Mina to HLP staff training)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinating with HLP communications on the URL and the launch of the wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updating the content in the wiki itself &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gap that I&amp;rsquo;m really feeling at the moment is knowing whether we need a separate moderation package that the moderators will need extra instruction in, or if the basic elements of MediaWiki will be sufficient.  There appears to be a &lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Extension:Moderation"&gt;moderation extension&lt;/a&gt;, but will it be more complex than we need?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After being distracted by Slack station-keeping for half an hour, I&amp;rsquo;ve texted the communications manager to see if she can make the training, and asked about getting wiki.healthylondon.org set up. I&amp;rsquo;ve emailed all the remaining stakeholders to ask what their availability is during the week of May 8th, and so I think the critical thing for me to work on now is a training script for Tuesday, and from that I can drive the sets of technical requirements we&amp;rsquo;ll need by each stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the training will need to consist of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where to go to access the wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to create (request?) an account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to search to find a page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to edit a page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to add a link to another wiki page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to upload an image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big decision is whether we require an approval process for people requesting accounts.  There does appear to be a &lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Extension:ConfirmAccount"&gt;stable extension for confirming accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;ve requested on Miraheze to see how it works.  For the purposes of the Tuesday training, simple creating of accounts is sufficient to have people practicing editing, but if the moderators are going to be approving requests for accounts, then we need that set up for them to see the process.  There&amp;rsquo;s also the moderation part of the training which will include at least some of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Approving account requests?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Receiving change notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Approving changes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reverting inappropriate changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blocking/Banning repeat offenders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable MediaWiki training video https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F8irbbwNo2E that talks about the basics and setting up categories and talk pages, but making the above list makes it seem like a critical thing to check for is the email notification support.  I set &lt;code&gt;$wgUsersNotifiedOnAllChanges&lt;/code&gt; to an array with my email address on our Bitnami/Azure instance but didn&amp;rsquo;t yet receive an update.  I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll request the same from miraheze and maybe ask them how they did it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in summary there&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of little details to work out, both in technical and policy terms.  I really wish I could parallelize all this - I guess making lists is the first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Kp6RPci8pM"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MediaWiki</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/04/26/mediawiki/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/04/26/mediawiki/</id>
    <published>2017-04-26T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-25T22:10:38+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="mediawiki" src="/images/MediaWiki.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having estsablished that MediaWiki&amp;rsquo;s default and visual editors both worked smoothly on the NHS laptops on the NHS intranet, it seemed pretty much wrapped up that we&amp;rsquo;d be using MediaWiki for the NHS Social Prescribing project.  The question then became whether we should host it ourselves or use a third party hosting service.  The main MediaWiki site provides a &lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Hosting_services"&gt;list of hosting services&lt;/a&gt; which are sortable in terms of different features.  I pulled out all the offerings that included visual editor support:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://meta.miraheze.org/"&gt;Miraheze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mywikis.com/"&gt;MyWikis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://wiki-valley.com/"&gt;Wiki Valley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wikibase.nl/Diensten/Managed_hosting"&gt;Wikibase solutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list also included Wikia and Gamepedia, both free with advertising and both targeting the video-game/entertainment market.  Possible, but long shots I thought; for healthcare we&amp;rsquo;d want a more serious tone.  I contacted all four of the above organisations to try and get set up with a test wiki with a visual editor installed.  Miraheze&amp;rsquo;s site didn&amp;rsquo;t immediately load so I got on to the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MyWikis gave me access to their testing wiki sandbox which had the visual editor; but it got stuck loading on all the browsers I tried and although they responded to my help request reasonably promptly, their suggestion that I should try browser refreshes until it worked was not very helpful.  Wiki Valley responded to my request to say they would create a dedicated demo wiki for us as well as giving us access to a sandbox, but I still haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to edit a page anywhere despite several attempts.  The notification emails and the site are in French and they&amp;rsquo;re not filling me with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikibase didn&amp;rsquo;t want to provide a demo environment and said that they only minimally support the visual editor. Instead they focus on semantic wiki and page forms as that&amp;rsquo;s what they&amp;rsquo;re saying their users want.  Sounds like an interesting future possibility (submitting data to wikis via forms) but not the best short term option.  Conversely, Miraheze is a volunteer-run system receiving donations to pay for hosting and have no guarantees of service in their terms and conditions, but they have actually been the fastest to set up a working test site for us and the only MediaWiki hosting service to get us a working visual editor so far.  I had to log into a separate feature requesting system (Phabricator) to get the visual editor enabled, and their site has been responsive all week since that outage I experienced the first time I went to their main site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In parallel I used &lt;a href="https://bitnami.com/stack/mediawiki"&gt;Bitnami&lt;/a&gt; which allowed a very simple deploy to our own MediaWiki instance on Azure where we can config the MediaWiki directly, and I was able to adjust the main logo and do some preliminary testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m honing in on a set of technical features we need to support the higher level project requirements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WYSIWYG editor (optional initially, but might be crucial down the line &amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can disable anonymous edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File upload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom domain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we insert custom HLP header to make it look like part of HLP site &amp;hellip;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTTPS &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;moderation support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think my next priority must be to request all the additional features enabled we need in the hlptest.miraheze.org MediaWiki, and then see how quickly I can set them up in parallel on our own server.  I started by &lt;a href="https://phabricator.miraheze.org/T1720"&gt;requesting the disabling of anonymous edits&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="requesting disabling of anonymous edits on miraheze via phabricator" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ecfs2s49des8xmj/Screenshot%202017-04-26%2009.46.45.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s see how quickly I can do this on our Bitnami/Azure system.  First I need to log in to azure.bitnami.com, which gives me a screen showing both the link to our running instance, and the ssh credentials I need to ssh directly into the box where I can edit the mediawiki settings.  I&amp;rsquo;d previously updated the logo by editing &lt;code&gt;/apps/mediawiki/htdocs/LocalSettings.php&lt;/code&gt;.  So I went back there to try to disable anonymous edits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Manual:Preventing&lt;em&gt;access#Restrict&lt;/em&gt;anonymous_editing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time I needed to go to &lt;code&gt;includes/DefaultSettings.php&lt;/code&gt; and set the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$wgGroupPermissions['*']['edit'] = false;
$wgGroupPermissions['*']['createpage'] = false;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and I had successfully disabled the ability of anonymous users to edit existing pages or create new pages.  Meanwhile I&amp;rsquo;m waiting for Miraheze to process my request.  I might rue the day since it may well be a total pain to set up the visual editor or SSL on our Bitnami/Azure hosted system, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think we can use Miraheze for anything other than testing purposes, since we&amp;rsquo;ll need server side access to fix things ourselves in a hurry if we have a specific request from the NHS team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe ideally I&amp;rsquo;d now spend the rest of the day working through all the other features in turn.  In the first instance I think I&amp;rsquo;ll just request them all from Miraheze and then see if I can knock off a couple of other low hanging fruit.  Although as I look I see that file upload appears to be enabled by default, and there are just restrictions about which sorts of files can be uploaded.  HLP is asking about uploading Excel files, which sounds like something we can easily add later as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miraheze has a &lt;a href="https://meta.miraheze.org/wiki/Custom_domains"&gt;whole page on how to request custom domains&lt;/a&gt;.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know when an HLP subdomain will be created for us, so it&amp;rsquo;s expedient to see if we can set up subdomains on av.org and see if we can get our Bitnami/Azure box hooked up like that.  That reminds me we will really need SSL (something Miraheze has out of the box), and in general we need to improve our Azure admin skills.  If only AWS or DO had given us similar nonprofit credit schemes &amp;hellip; guess I could try a Bitnami deploy to AWS and taking the financial hit, but we do need to skill up in Azure admin for the AsyncVoter project and to take advantage of the credits from MicroSoft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve set up http://hlp-wiki.agileventures.org to point to our Azure/Bitnami system, and we&amp;rsquo;ll see if that works, but we&amp;rsquo;ll have to wait for the zone file to propagate.  For stability we&amp;rsquo;ll need to reserve the IP address which requires powershell installation.  I also see an article for &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cloud-services/cloud-services-configure-ssl-certificate"&gt;ssl setup&lt;/a&gt;.  It might be painful but I think we can get all that done.  The other things to impale ourselves on are setting up the WYSIWYG editor, working out the moderation strategy and whether/how we can have an HLP banner across the top of the wiki &amp;hellip; stay tuned for all those fun and frolics in the coming days.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End of the Line</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/04/25/end-of-the-line/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/04/25/end-of-the-line/</id>
    <published>2017-04-25T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-25T22:12:07+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="end of the line" src="/images/end_of_the_line.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is April 25th, the day that Google shuts down its Hangout API.  We&amp;rsquo;ve been watching this coming for several months, with Google enterprise support hinting at a replacement.  Yesterday (April 24th) all the hangout apps stopped functioning and our scrum hosts were forced back to taking the hangout URLs and pasting them into the site to update the site link and notify Slack (as we had done during a previous Google Hangout API outage).  The &amp;ldquo;Start a Hangout on Air&amp;rdquo; buttons were still working, but are now mainly serving to cause the disabled hangout apps to load into the hangout, which requires (all?) users to click &amp;ldquo;cancel&amp;rdquo; a couple of times before the hangout will start sharing video or screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve been derelict in my duty by failing to spend the last three months thoroughly researching and implementing an alternate solution.  The approach I&amp;rsquo;ve taken is to wait and see what&amp;rsquo;s left after the Hangout API is retired.  It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating.  We&amp;rsquo;ve poured hundreds of hours into the Google Hangout plugins, and the data we get from them underpins a lot of our site&amp;rsquo;s Karma metric and our ability to analyse and track pairing and scrumming in the AgileVentures site and the edX MOOC.  The MOOC is just about to start again and realistically we&amp;rsquo;ll have no telemetry on any pairing.  That said, I&amp;rsquo;ve just got an email saying that the whole AgileVentures site will have to be overhauled for accessibility if it&amp;rsquo;s going to be linked to the edX MOOC.  Maybe going forward we just won&amp;rsquo;t be able to have a direct link pointing our MOOC students to pair using our system.  Early days - lots to review and work out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the purpose of continuing the day to day business of AgileVentures: scrums, meetings and the occasional pairing session, we are still in principle able to use the hangouts.  It&amp;rsquo;s a usability pain, but regular members will be able to learn how to update the events in the AV site manually.  It generates a series of action items:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Inform members individually&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Update documentation in AV to indicate new approach to taking hangouts live&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Update documentation in edX MOOC about new strategy (or remove entirely)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot of the interface element that allows anyone to update an event hangout link:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="interface element that allows anyone to update an event hangout link" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/m6soei7ibumpmym/Screenshot%202017-04-24%2016.16.49.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment we don&amp;rsquo;t support a manual function for distributing the video link, which is something we might want to add.  That and the manual mechanism might make sharing the meeting links less arduous, but they don&amp;rsquo;t address the tracking/telemetry elements that we&amp;rsquo;re losing, or the awareness components that show who is in a meeting and whether it is still live. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google appears to be splitting Hangouts into two separate products, &amp;ldquo;meet&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;chat&amp;rdquo;.  I can now start Google &amp;ldquo;meets&amp;rdquo; through my enterprise account.  They appear to be hangouts with all the apps and chat removed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Google Meet" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/xd8bp268seota88/Screenshot%202017-04-25%2009.50.08.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As yet I can find no mention of an API.   I&amp;rsquo;ve applied for the Early Adopter Program (EAP) for chat, but haven&amp;rsquo;t gained access yet.  I can guess some of Google&amp;rsquo;s motivation for splitting the two products in terms of simpler offerings, but it goes in a completely different direction from what we want.  We&amp;rsquo;d like more tightly integrated chat and videoconferencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we need to back up and work out what&amp;rsquo;s really mission critical for AgileVentures.  What&amp;rsquo;s mission critical for me is delivering on the NHS project so I can feed my kids.  My intuition is that being able to start video events from Slack would be much more convenient and comprehensible for everyone.  It&amp;rsquo;s possible and the de-motivator for me in the past is that those hangouts haven&amp;rsquo;t been recordable; but maybe we need to drop that recording aspect?  The pros are that it&amp;rsquo;s great for learning, openneess, accessibilty, catching up etc., but knowing you&amp;rsquo;ll be recorded is a big barrier for some folks.  We&amp;rsquo;ve got some different technology options to pursue such as seeing whether we could use Zoom, or a hand-rolled WebRTC solution, but we&amp;rsquo;ve got limited development resources.  Before we start spending them I&amp;rsquo;d like to do a full week design sprint to prototype and test the next solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels a bit like the end of the line for the moment.  The AgileVentures events page &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1635"&gt;wasn&amp;rsquo;t loading at all yesterday&lt;/a&gt; due to a 500 error we couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand (some 3rd party service timing out perhaps?), but seems to be working today.  I guess change is the only certainty.  We&amp;rsquo;ve built a community using the free offerings that companies like Slack and Google have provided us, but it was always without guarantees.  Relationships with partners change, and everyone will have mixed feelings when those relationships change, but change they must.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4pS97UiieBg"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=vomDvVEfw_k"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Big Push</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/04/24/big-push/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/04/24/big-push/</id>
    <published>2017-04-24T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-23T21:54:47+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="big push" src="/images/big_push.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend I spent a good couple of hours shutting down all the different browser tabs I had open (about 70) and adding relevant links to my action plan.  I got briefly distracted updating the Wikipedia pages for Social Prescribing, but that felt good to get done, and ultimately I was able to reboot my computer before doing a Premium pairing on EventManager with Marian, where we managed to tinker with the existing pull request. We had to change the styling on the event when it went live.  We managed to use an html data-attribute so that the styling and display of the event live status was always managed by JavaScript &amp;hellip; Would love to pull the code into the blog, but in the meantime check out the &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/EventManager/pull/27"&gt;PR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was an early Monday start to get down to NHS head offices to meet up with new and outgoing change managers.  It was the outgoing change manager&amp;rsquo;s last day, so important to catch them to say goodbye and thank them for the work they&amp;rsquo;d done so far.  On the way in on the train I sketched an agenda for the meeting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asking how things were going&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Double checking on what success looked like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting approval for my plan going forward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting the content from the PDFs into the wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarifying the communication plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it happened we jumped in in the middle and I ended up telling them the outcome of my testing with the NHS laptop on Friday, and how I&amp;rsquo;d landed on MediaWiki as a solution to our problems there.  I also ended up showing them the Bitnami hosted MediaWiki I&amp;rsquo;d set up and the Social Prescribing page on Wikipedia.  They seemed pleased to see the progress and a Social Prescribing page, and I talked them through how moderation works on Wikipedia.  In mentioning the Wikipedia page on the doctor, Michael Dixon, we discovered that there is an NHS wikiproject group within Wikipedia.  That seems like an important lead - folks that we might be able to reach out to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked about the timeline, the communication strategy options, and setting up editing and moderation training for HLP staff and others to fit in with the idea of a soft launch on May 4th and hard launch on May 12th.  We also had a chance to double check that the Bitnami/Azure hosted MediaWiki worked on the NHS laptops.  I was pretty sure there wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be any problems, but after the icon issue the previous week I wanted to double check.  The icons all loaded.  I note that I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually check a successful edit operation - will follow up with the new change manager to make double sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also sat down with team lead, to check in that everything was solid.  Sounds like the conference they wants to present the system at, on May 18th, is a big deal, with VIPs etc. and they&amp;rsquo;ll want to do a live demo if possible &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was glad that I asked the new change manager about how things were going generally as I heard about some of the other HLP activities, including that they were tendering for a social prescribing service to be set up in collaboration with a CCG.  I had assumed that HLP&amp;rsquo;s activities were limited to researching social prescribing, rather than taking an active lead on setting it up, so that was good to know. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all left me with a good set of action items:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting the legal review of the terms &amp;amp; conditions signed and sealed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;double check with the new change manager that they can complete a mediawiki edit on their laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arranging meetings with the remaining stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reviewing all the MediaWiki hosting options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ensuring we have the right kind of moderation options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;creating editing and moderation training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get us a URL &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote these up on the train home, where I saw an interesting health care related advertisement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="UNISON tube advert" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/xkam0b5hthm8hu8/unison-advert.JPG?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is everything connected?  I&amp;rsquo;m steeling myself for the big push to get this all live &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
