<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>All Good Things ...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/</id>
    <published>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-10T21:54:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="good things" src="/images/good_things.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been daily blogging for a year now.  Working day blogs that is.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging on weekends, or national holidays, or during my vacations.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty consistent.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of days where work was super busy due to the tail end of a design sprint or something, but I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to retro-actively blog and keep it one per work day.  I started blogging in June last year doing a blog on a different platform each day of the week, but fairly soon I fell into a pattern of blogging to our AgileVentures middleman site, and then re-releasing to Medium after I&amp;rsquo;d got a little distance from the blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the purpose of this blog frenzy?  My memory is that it was about trying to communicate more effectively.  I often end up assuming that people understand my thoughts and intentions and it turns out that actually they don&amp;rsquo;t.  Of course why would they?  There are few telepaths around.  I&amp;rsquo;m also a bit of a gabbler and my sense is that it&amp;rsquo;s not super easy to understand what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to communicate.  So blogging, get all the thoughts down in text, provide them in an accessible form for everyone to read, and maybe reduce my need to gabble on and on about things.  Win win, no?  There&amp;rsquo;s also the motivation that blogging at the start of each day is a kind of &amp;ldquo;morning pages&amp;rdquo; activity such as writers use to start off their days and clear their heads.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think writers usually publish their morning brain dump, but I have certainly found the process of starting each day with writing out my thoughts to be reassuring and relaxing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year when I was doing a lot more coding, the blogs tended to be all about the previous day&amp;rsquo;s coding.  As AgileVentures became an official charity and my admin load increased, they have tended to be about prioritization.  Starting the day with a blog is certainly less stressful than starting the day with a review of email and Slack conversations, which will generally lead to many adds to my ever-increasing todo list.  Has the time been well spent?  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had positive reactions to some blogs, but my sense is that the blogs are too long, too stream-of-consciousness, too un-focused to gain much traction.  I think I may have even alienated some with my uncensored and unedited thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was 17 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had trouble just generating text, and from even earlier I was always a talker.  It&amp;rsquo;s like my internal thought wheel is hooked up directly to my mouth, and at will I can hook it up to a pen or a keyboard and just dump my thoughts straight out, for better or for worse.  So I rarely have writer&amp;rsquo;s block, but it leaves me with a different problem.  How to edit the thicket of thoughts and ideas, so as to more effectively communicate them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to the end of a year of blogging prompts thoughts of changing things going forward.  There&amp;rsquo;ve been times in the past when rising early I&amp;rsquo;ve done 3 hours of programming before breakfast.  After recent design sprints I think about doing coding sprints, or other activities that fill the week in different ways.  Should it be one blog a week with the blog being edited and revised each day, so that a single polished blog can be released on Friday?  I guess it all depends on what one wants to achieve, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t the Buddhist in me been trying to follow a path of consecrated action, where one is totally unattached to the outcomes of activities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d have loved my blogs to have provoked more positive responses of &amp;ldquo;yes, let&amp;rsquo;s build a solution to that together &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, although there has been some of that.  What I really would like is for AgileVentures to be a healthy thriving community providing great learning experiences for many, while also helping charitable causes around the world.  The process of reflection over the last year does make me think that we&amp;rsquo;re far too text heavy in many, many parts of our interface with the world.  One of the most attractive ideas for me going forward is that I&amp;rsquo;d spend my blogging time each day focused on a part of the main AgileVentures site, converting it from text heavy to text light and adding images.  I have a hunch that, by doing this in strategic places throughout the site, we could improve the sign up rates, the number of members joining projects and the numbers signing up for Premium subscriptions, the source of our financial sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a feeling I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to shake the blogging habit.  The process has become too solidly part of my daily routine.  The thing that actually gets me started and ready to work in the mornings.  So, anyhow, starting tomorrow, blogs that focus on parts of the main AgileVentures site.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to work through it one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog released early for inclusion in our July newsletter, earlier blogs are all in draft form in GitHub and will be on this site soon&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Prioritization Motivation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/23/prioritization-motivation/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/23/prioritization-motivation/</id>
    <published>2017-06-23T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-18T20:53:58+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="prioritization" src="/images/prioritization.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prioritization and motivation is complicated.  Each day I&amp;rsquo;m sitting down and trying to have myself focus on the things that will actually generate revenue.  That said there are things that I&amp;rsquo;m motivated to do (or have fallen into a pattern of doing) that are several steps removed from any revenue generation.  Some things are a pattern that I at least partially enjoy, e.g. blogging, publishing blogs, jogging, listening to podcasts, preparing Japanese language tests for my kids.  Doing them makes me feel centered and organised, but none of them are likely to lead to any revenue generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The late night on Wednesday put paid to any jogging and podcast-listening on Thursday morning.  I thought I&amp;rsquo;d recover for Friday, but then I ended up staying up late after my regular late night blog publishing.  The thing that caught me was fixing up the InVision app that we&amp;rsquo;d created as part of the design sprint so that it would run on GitHub pages.  You can see it there now at &lt;a href="http://why.agileventures.org"&gt;http://why.agileventures.org&lt;/a&gt;.  We&amp;rsquo;d been redirecting the URL to the InvisionApp itself, but in the marketing meeting yesterday Lara raised the issue that Google Adwords might have a problem with the redirection and it might raise an issue of trust with our users.  She asked if we couldn&amp;rsquo;t export the app, but over lunch I googled and discovered that we could export a zip of the app in order to run it offline.  I&amp;rsquo;d quickly uploaded the app into the GitHub pages site &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/why"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/why&lt;/a&gt; and saw that we could host it directly, so no need to redirect away from the &lt;a href="http://why.agileventures.org"&gt;http://why.agileventures.org&lt;/a&gt; domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great, but a half an hour of kicking things about at the end of the day hadn&amp;rsquo;t resolved one part of the app that didn&amp;rsquo;t work.  The final &amp;ldquo;sign up&amp;rdquo; button external link to the main AgileVentures sign up page at &lt;a href="https://www.agileventures.org/users/sign_up"&gt;https://www.agileventures.org/users/sign_up&lt;/a&gt; was attempting to load the following URL &lt;code&gt;/redirect?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.agileventures.org%2Fusers%2Fsign_up&lt;/code&gt;, which is presumably an endpoint on the InVision app, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist in our GitHub Pages app.  I tried a few tricks to get round this, such as just adding a file called &lt;code&gt;redirect&lt;/code&gt; with the contents &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&amp;quot;refresh&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;0; url=https://www.agileventures.org/users/sign_up&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.  That didn&amp;rsquo;t quite work, with clicking the sign up link leading to the browser downloading a file rather than redirecting.  The problem was that GitHub pages (Jekyll) wasn&amp;rsquo;t serving the file with the correct media type.  I tried using &lt;code&gt;redirect.html&lt;/code&gt; and some under the hood jekyll redirection, but it still suffered from the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I emailed InVision support and GitHub support, and InVision came back saying that the downloaded app didn&amp;rsquo;t support the full functionality, and GitHub were asking for clarification on what I was trying to achieve.  I tried MarvelApp (an Invision competitor) and saw that I could quickly recreate the app there, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t download without upgrading.  So I&amp;rsquo;d kind of given up for the time being, but after my late night blog publishing session I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help tinkering.  The late night blog publishing session is also a strange prioritization/motivation conundrum.  In days gone by I used to try and publish the previous days blog after having just written the new days one, i.e. in the morning each day.  That had the advantage of keeping all the blog action within my working day, but I was finding that having written one blog I was struggling to do another blog related activity, and the blog publishing was being put off and forgotten.  Then I started doing the publishing component late in the evening, often in parallel with giving my eldest son a little time on his iPad before I read him a story.  Then I decided it wasn&amp;rsquo;t so good for my eldest boy to be getting that iPad stimulation before bed (all the boys get 20 minutes iPad in the morning if they&amp;rsquo;ve finished getting completely ready), and so I ended up shifting to doing the blog publishing after all the boys were asleep, i.e. in my own winding time before going to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reasonably efficient, but sometimes I am too tired to get to it, and on occasion I get distracted because I&amp;rsquo;ve opened up Slack to post my blog, or like last night where just thinking about work brings me back to a problem like this redirection issue.  As it happens, another thirty minutes of fiddling fixed things up.  The problem seems to be an issue in the Jekyll redirection syntax.  I&amp;rsquo;d been experimenting with Jekyll syntax in &lt;code&gt;redirect.html&lt;/code&gt; like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight yaml"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nn"&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;redirect_from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="pi"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;/redirect&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;redirect_to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="pi"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;https://www.agileventures.org/users/sign_up&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nn"&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but it seems that trailing slashes are necessary to ensure that Jekyll serves things in the right media type, so the following worked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight yaml"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nn"&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;redirect_from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="pi"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;/redirect/&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;redirect_to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="pi"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;https://www.agileventures.org/users/sign_up/&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nn"&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was finding issues like &lt;a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-redirect-from/issues/37"&gt;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-redirect-from/issues/37&lt;/a&gt; that helped me fix things up.  So now, whatever the shortcomings of the prototype app, we have all the functionality working at &lt;a href="http://why.agileventures.org"&gt;http://why.agileventures.org&lt;/a&gt;.  The question now was whether this was good enough to start testing, which prompted a little discussion on Slack:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam Joseph:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;question is whether this is good enough to start testing (@joaopereira @mtc2013 @mlindsey @lara-t)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federico:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@tansaku by “this” you mean what’s up now at http://why.agileventures.org ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam Joseph:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;right - I downloaded the invisionapp and hosted it on github pages so the user stays on why.agileventures.org the whole time - that was the concern that @lara-t raised in the meeting - clearly the app could still be improved in many ways - I know you don&amp;rsquo;t like the font, the buttons could be more clickable etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federico:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the button colors, all the tester feedback. :grimacing:
It’s good enough to test, but it’s serving one purpose: a larger sample size &lt;em&gt;test&lt;/em&gt; of the prototype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam Joseph: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally the design sprint prototype is supposed to be thrown away, and a better one rebuilt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we are operating on a shoestring and in principle the content test could redirect 10% of our clickthroughs to why.av.org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we can increase as we improve it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at the moment our clickthroughs are not driving any revenue so in principle there&amp;rsquo;s nothing too much to lose &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federico:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’ll just be additional data to reinforce the verbal feedback from the testers. &lt;em&gt;That’s obviously appealing. I’m not opposed to it.&lt;/em&gt; I’m excited, however, to help build a &lt;em&gt;slick coded version, that takes into account the tester feedback. Please let me know when that starts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think why.av.org looks pretty good now and we should start 50/50 A/B test whenever @lara-t is able to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lara:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@here great job, I will get everything setup this weekend for AdWords A/B Testing. Well done everyone I really love the new page :slightly&lt;em&gt;smiling&lt;/em&gt;face:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there we go.  I failed to get up for my jog or podcast listening this morning :-( I got my kids Japanese tests written up, and I&amp;rsquo;m over time on my blogging.  Funny thing is about the moment that motivation seizes you.  It seized me several times yesterday trying to get this fixed up.  It&amp;rsquo;s slowly running out now as I spend too long on this blog and my motivation to make all the points I was originally thinking about gradually drains away.  I stopped to email GitHub to tell them how I solved the issue and how their redirection documentation needs updating.  I was trying to make a point about motivation and prioritization.  There are at least two items I should get to, now, that directly relate to getting paid and there&amp;rsquo;s the MOOV/AV102 emails I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting off all week.  I used to be motivated to do them and now &amp;hellip; I guess I&amp;rsquo;ve got sick of the little dance I do to get the old updates from the previous MOOC and put them into the new one.  There&amp;rsquo;s a fiddly updating of the links and no particular positive feedback - as opposed to the likes I get when I tweet about other people&amp;rsquo;s podcasts &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the thing I&amp;rsquo;m stuck on is that, given that I can&amp;rsquo;t automate these MOOC postings (due to the way that edX works), I should delegate them off to someone, but I recoil at the process of trying to get someone to understand how to do it, and that it will probably be screwed up a couple of times before it&amp;rsquo;s done right.  And then there&amp;rsquo;s the thought that we won&amp;rsquo;t even have the need for these emailings once the course goes self paced (from fall?).  Or maybe we will - or maybe no one cares if these things get sent or not.  We&amp;rsquo;re not measuring the impact of doing them or not - I&amp;rsquo;m just sending them because if I was doing a course I&amp;rsquo;d like to get a reminder when new material and assignments are released &amp;hellip; In previous runs I was in a solid pattern of getting the emails out and now I&amp;rsquo;m all over the place &amp;hellip; partly it&amp;rsquo;s my faltering motivation and also trying to prioritize things that have a more direct connection to revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motivation and prioritization.  Right, must finish up blog, leave the A/B testing to Lara and make sure that I get they key revenue generating work done this AM (mainly paperwork), get those MOOC posts out, and keep going with balancing what I have motivation for in the moment, and what really has to get done to pay the bills &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Summer Soltice</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/22/summer-solstice/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/22/summer-solstice/</id>
    <published>2017-06-22T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-15T20:35:32+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Summer Soltice" src="/images/summer_solstice.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve reached the mid-point of the year.  It&amp;rsquo;s been super hot in London for the last few days, although it seems like it&amp;rsquo;s calming down today.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with runaway CPU processes on my main development laptop, and conversations with Apple are now leading me to suspect the Adobe CreativeCloud/Illustrator install I did last Thursday as part of the design sprint.  I&amp;rsquo;ve just uninstalled and re-installed now, on top of the Sierra OS, so if I&amp;rsquo;m lucky that might resolve the issue.  We&amp;rsquo;ll soon tell in today&amp;rsquo;s hangouts.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to skip yesterday&amp;rsquo;s Kent Beck scrum and AsyncVoter kickoff in order to give a talk to a group of coding bootcamp students in Detroit and head into a sweltering central London for an NHS event.  I&amp;rsquo;d managed to talk AsyncVoter with Matt and Raphael during the Martin Fowler scrum.  I have this nagging feeling that the inconsistency of event occurrence combined with the usability issues in our event system is a major drag on AgileVentures.  That sparked a big conversation about WebRTC in the #event_manager channel and caused me to sketch some UI images in keynote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="active projects" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/d31fmx2j304155k/Screenshot%202017-06-22%2009.25.06.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="run event" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ochv7kd9j89mqck/Screenshot%202017-06-22%2009.25.29.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That I&amp;rsquo;m not completely thrilled with.  However the design sprint has definitely left me feeling revved up about prototyping and designing interfaces.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely I&amp;rsquo;m still a little uneasy with the AsyncVoter project.  We&amp;rsquo;d been talking about Raphael becoming project manager, and then we had a period where his pull requests were hanging around for a long time while we were focused on trying to sort out infrastructure issues.  He appeared to get rather frustrated that he was being &amp;ldquo;ignored&amp;rdquo;.  We also had some tense interactions about the possibility that he might sign up for Premium membership in order to get priority code reviews.  Ultimately he said he felt insulted to be asked for money to have his code reviewed, which is very useful feedback but was also quite shocking.  It&amp;rsquo;s not dissimilar to the things that freeranger has said about, why should I pay when I&amp;rsquo;m volunteering my time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is the concept of priority code reviews via Premium membership ultimately anathema? Raphael was apparently so frustrated and insulted that he said he was leaving the project and AgileVentures.  As it happened we also managed to get over the infrastructure hurdles and merge in his PRs and now he seems to be continuing to work on the project.  Yesterday we discussed the need to get a contributions document in place and to work out a project flow.  Raphael says he wants nothing to do with the money and infrastructure side of things.  That&amp;rsquo;s fair enough, but I do feel somewhat aggrieved by the whole interaction. I&amp;rsquo;m nervous that there will be frustrated outbursts in future.  I guess the sensible approach going forward will be to avoid responding to them, and not engage in trying to explain how desparately unfair that feels. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess people have lots of different ideas of how open source &amp;ldquo;should&amp;rdquo; work.  I&amp;rsquo;m trying to introduce elements that connect open source projects more strongly to clients with needs, and include a mechanism whereby the work of the infrastructure folks and projects managers can be compensated.  I totally understand wanting to focus purely on the code, but if that&amp;rsquo;s the case it seems unreasonable to demand attention from those who are struggling to ensure that hosting costs are met.  Of course people should be able to express how they feel, and I&amp;rsquo;m really grateful to Raphael for the insight into his thought processes, as alien as they seem to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all gets stranger and stranger - the combination of the NHS contract and the steady Premium subscriptions mean that we might be on the cusp of making AgileVentures sustainable for me; although it&amp;rsquo;s up in the air if we can sort out the governance issues on that to allow me to cover this month&amp;rsquo;s bills.  At the same time I met lots of new people talking about possible digital projects at the NHS networking event.  Sounds great - we&amp;rsquo;ll see if they come to anything.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also now got the contract for the private design sprint and development work that I&amp;rsquo;m starting next week.  Something that really should cover my expenses, but will take a good portion of my time away from AgileVentures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m super confused about how to better craft the Premium member package to make it less insulting to those who feel they don&amp;rsquo;t need anything other than voluntary support in their professional development process.  At least I&amp;rsquo;ve made it to another summer solstice and I have blogs running from six months before AgileVentures became a registered UK charity, and six months after.  At the very least that makes an interesting set of material for a book of some kind.  But I&amp;rsquo;d still rather crack the Premium member package conundrum before I write one :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Design Sprint Aftermath</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/21/av-design-sprint-aftermath/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/21/av-design-sprint-aftermath/</id>
    <published>2017-06-21T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-14T21:49:56+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been looking forward to a normal week following the AV design sprint, getting back to having standups and project meetings.  Frustratingly Monday was scattered with problems with hangouts that seemed to be specific to me.  The &amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum went okay, but I was unable to participate in the Monday marketing meeting due to my computer slowing to a crawl when I was running hangouts.  There was so much to discuss in the marketing meeting and I was effectively excluded on technology grounds.  Matt, Federico and Michael all tried to help me get to the bottom of it later in the day.  We thought we&amp;rsquo;d tracked it down to either the LAN cable or thunderbolt monitor as things seemed to improve when I switched to Wifi on my backup laptop.  However, broadband speed tests were showing the same results on both computers.  I managed normal participation in the AV community meeting using my backup laptop on the Wifi. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I swapped out one LAN cable and it seemed like my main laptop improved in hangouts, but then they got worse and Wifi didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to help.  The following day I phoned Apple and got advice to upgrade to OSX Sierra, which I reluctantly did.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been frustrated with Apple upgrades before, particularly since you can&amp;rsquo;t back out of them.  I upgraded to Sierra over lunch yesterday and the computer seems to be working okay, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried some of the trickier coding things that involve libraries installed via brew.   The &amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum was just about manageable, but I was carefully monitoring my CPU&amp;rsquo;s and noticing that things went a bit nuts occasionally with all eight cores maxing out.  I tried to switch to my backup computer with Wifi (that had worked for the AV community meeting) but the hangout wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even finish loading.  I switched off my video on the main computer and watched the CPUs come back under control, and was able to complete the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s super frustrating that when a hangout related CPU max out occurs that I can hardly do anything else.  I can&amp;rsquo;t navigate in Slack, can&amp;rsquo;t get other web pages to load.  My ability to function resolves around the ability to paste people links about things they are talking about in the hangout.  Following the scrum I ran a couple of NHS HLP hangouts.  Michael was in both.  We managed okay, but I definitely noticed illustrator being sluggish in the second one.  It really makes me thing we need an open source alternative to hangouts to be able to get to the bottom of these kinds of problems.  If I had the spare cash I&amp;rsquo;d love to just buy a new MacBookPro and exlude exotic hardware failures from the equation, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really have that luxury at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling my own mental CPUs thrashing trying to work out what to focus on each day.  My mood had been dipping but I found myself buoyed yesterday as we managed to identify the font that had been used in the AgileVentures logo, import that and create a &amp;ldquo;customized by AgileVentures&amp;rdquo; logo for the NHS HLP wiki site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="customized by AgileVentures" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/1kekg96rkndea64/customized-by-agileventures-176wide.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d been putting off working on this, but as part of the design sprint we&amp;rsquo;d been using an &lt;a href="https://www.fontsquirrel.com/matcherator"&gt;online font matching tool&lt;/a&gt; and we used the same technique to identify the AgileVentures logo font as &lt;a href="https://www.fontsquirrel.com/fonts/bree-serif"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bree Serif Regular&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.  It&amp;rsquo;s available for free, so I downloaded and installed on my newly upgrade OSX Sierra running mac, and the font became available in Illustrator.  A bit of playing around the gradients made it look similar enough to the existing &amp;ldquo;powered by MediaWiki&amp;rdquo; button to have it not look too out of place, and I found that adding these footer icons is a &lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Manual:$wgFooterIcons#Site_customization"&gt;trivial config operation&lt;/a&gt; in MediaWiki.  Still frustraing that the hangout that allowed me to share and record all of this was slowing the process of experimenting with Illustrator.  I really prefer to just bang on things and look stuff up on Google rather than taking courses and reading documentation &amp;hellip; is that bad?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s more I could keep tweaking, but diminishing returns?  At least with the gradients created for that &amp;ldquo;customized by agileventures&amp;rdquo; logo could be used to make the rounded rectangles in the Design Sprint&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Agile Journey&amp;rdquo; prototype more &amp;ldquo;clickable&amp;rdquo; looking.  That feels like nice cross-fertilization.  Moving forward I guess I just keep monitoring my CPU loads and see if we can&amp;rsquo;t use things like &lt;a href="https://github.com/muaz-khan/WebRTC-Experiment"&gt;https://github.com/muaz-khan/WebRTC-Experiment&lt;/a&gt; to create some transparent open source pairing/meeting solution where anyone who&amp;rsquo;s interested can work on fixing issues with performance rather than closed source Google offerings.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Design Sprint Day Five</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/20/av-design-sprint-day-five/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/20/av-design-sprint-day-five/</id>
    <published>2017-06-20T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-13T22:01:16+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Friday morning was fairly frantic.  I&amp;rsquo;d gone to sleep thinking that the last day testing of the design sprint had been postponed, and woke to find we were &amp;ldquo;game on&amp;rdquo; with testers booked into slots and a half-finished prototype that needed completing by noon my time.  Quick AgileVentures trustee meeting out of the way and I was working away in illustrator to finish the rest of the interactive popups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was getting the hang of illustrator layers and didn&amp;rsquo;t have too much trouble extracting the rest of the images we had downloaded from ShutterStock and getting things set up.  What was immediately clear was that we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get away with a background image with popups being displayed over the top.  There was a noticeable delay in that background loading so what we had was a sequence of main images like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="all screens from the prototype" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/uglnko00ybpwalu/Screenshot%202017-06-20%2009.25.02.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and used InVision hotspots to link them together so that it appeared that you got a popup when you clicked on the relevant part of the image.  We were ready with time to spare and I was able to review the videos of the GV test sessions and re-read the sections of the design sprint book that outline a five-act interview, which we modified ever so slightly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Friendly welcome: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Welcome the customer and put him or her at ease. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain that you’re looking for candid feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Context questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start with easy small talk, then transition to questions about the topic you’re trying to learn about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduce the prototype:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remind the customer that some things might not work, and that you’re not testing him or her. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask the customer to think aloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tasks and nudges: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch the customer figure out the prototype on his or her own. Start with a simple nudge. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask follow-up questions to help the customer think aloud.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Debrief:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask questions that prompt the customer to summarize. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thank the customer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ask about sharing video for training and education purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;say gift card will be taken care of by colleague&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d been volunteered as the interviewer, and while Matt ran a separate hangout for the rest of the team, I set up individual hangouts for the testers so we could record and stream separately.  Federico was working furiously in the background managing the screening spreadsheet to identify individuals in the target demographic.  Basically it all went off pretty well.  One individual tester was a no show, and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get any backups in time, so we only had four sessions.  The second tester found the cursor key navigation was still on so we turned that off.  Testers one and three were from a very similar background, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t ideal from the point of view of getting a diverse range of input on the prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had quite a long chat with each individual about their background, goals, hopes and dreams; before ultimately segueing into introducing the prototype.  Although, by the end I was getting tired and not filling the full hour.  The patterns that emerged from these sessions was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Negatives&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some terminology was confusing, e.g. MOOC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AV&amp;rsquo;s purpose somewhat unclear. NGO? Learning/mentoring?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prototype sections not obviously clickable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too much text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unclear who owns code - is this open source?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unclear if meetings online or in person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Neutrals&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testers wanted to know how to share with friends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Positives&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concept and social aspect appreciated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images and roadmap appreciated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the really solid takeaways were how people seemed to really appreciate the visualization of the journey and the images and how the text needed to be both shortened and tightened up.  We were pretty shattered after over 30 hours in hangouts for this online design sprint, and ended up reviewing the next steps in our AV Community meeting the following Monday.  Some possible follow up actions included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Releasing a static site with the interactive infographic that points to our main site on the sign up link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjust the landing page of our site to better reflect the journey concept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start creating a new main site perhaps in new tech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the community meeting I asked everyone to suggest what they thought was the highest priority.  Michael&amp;rsquo;s was that we get a static site up (even just the InVision site) and A/B test the impact on signups via Google AdWords.  The measurement component of this really appealed to me, and so this morning I snapped to it by setting up a GitHub Pages account and having that redirect to the InVision app.  I set up http://why.agileventures.org to point to that and the sign up button now goes to our main site.  The annoying things are the InVision URL showing as well as their loading screen.  In principle we could put image maps directly into our GitHub pages site &amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think either way the design sprint has weened me off large amounts of text and addicted me to small amounts of text with images.  Will be interesting to see if we can get any substantive change in signups - stay tuned to this blog to find out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vVwO94ae96w"&gt;Day five video, part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BM7A-SBiFqk"&gt;Day five video, part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/Uao3p4k6qs0"&gt;AV community meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Design Sprint Day Four</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/19/av-design-sprint-day-four/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/19/av-design-sprint-day-four/</id>
    <published>2017-06-19T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-12T21:56:06+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I was about to write up the events of our day four design sprint on Friday morning, when it was suddenly all hands on deck.  Actually I had been anticipating a busy morning.  When we had finished the design sprint regular hours on Thursday we had a partially working prototype and I was the person with illustrator installed that could get the rest of the components working.  In the background Federico had put together an advert and screening questionnaire that he put out on Craigslist in a number of cities in order recruit testers for Friday.  However, late Thursday it was looking like we didn&amp;rsquo;t have anyone from the target demographic in those that were applying to be testers.  As I went to sleep on Thursday Federico and I were agreeing we might need to put the testing off to the following week; however, when I woke up we&amp;rsquo;d had another 150 applications from posting the ad on the Indeed network and we had a handful of people in the target demographic.  Overnight Michael had made the decision to push ahead with testing to complete the design sprint within the week as intended.  It was a good call, but it was also relying on my completing the prototype in my Friday early hours.  I had said that I&amp;rsquo;d be able to do that, and I still was, but it meant blogging and other station keeping went out the window, particularly since I&amp;rsquo;d scheduled an important trustee meeting.  That meeting out of the way, I got down to finishing the prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having had the full day of testing on Friday and a camp over the weekend I&amp;rsquo;m struggling to remember how we got to where we did on the end of Thursday.  Fortunately our Google doc for the day reminds me; we started off comparing prototyping tools, specifically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SquareSpace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keynote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Middleman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we discussed, it became clear that Keynote wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to work since we were testing remotely and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t assume that we could get keynote running on the user&amp;rsquo;s remote system in the fashion necessary.  Middleman was an option if we had form heavy interactions, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t, and if possible we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to burn time coding.  Matt and I had some experience with InVision, and I had installed Adobe Illustrator and checked that we could use it to take apart eps files that were available for sale on Shutterstock and others.  I&amp;rsquo;d tried Sketch and Inkscape and a few others and hadn&amp;rsquo;t quite got the ability to take apart stock graphics in the way that we&amp;rsquo;d need.  Michael had some limited experience with SquareSpace and Lokesh even more limited with Wix.  I suggested that they look at those two respectively while Matt looked at InVision and I focused on Illustrator.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael made some progress with SquareSpace, but it was unclear if we could easily get an image map set up.  Lokesh made good progress with Wix, but it seemed like he couldn&amp;rsquo;t immediately lock click-through elements to part of a background image.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure we could have achieved some version of our imagined infographic with each system, but it was a question of how quickly we could get a relatively professional looking system into place.  We decided to go with Illustrator/Invision and Lokesh/Michael switched to image search.  Michael found another image on ShutterStock that he felt captured more of the ethos of his original design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="infographic ecology concept design landscape" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/vg8oncdpeez1af9/Screenshot%202017-06-19%2009.41.51.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d managed to wrangle it into illustrator, and get some alternate text in there that we could get to go operate like a popup in InVision using their hotspot tool.  We pretty much failed to follow the later script of the Thursday in that we didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to do a trial run or work up an interview script.  As the day drew to a close Michael and Matt had found other &amp;ldquo;flat style&amp;rdquo; images to illustrate different parts of the journey, and I&amp;rsquo;d got the first one in a pop up that could be &amp;ldquo;clicked and closed&amp;rdquo; using screens in InVision:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="&amp;quot;you are here&amp;quot; popup" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/iryq4hah16np3ip/Screenshot%202017-06-19%2009.45.05.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a mechanism for constructing a professional looking interactive infographic, and it was now just a question of putting the rest together.  Michael and Matt had selected text and images for the other popups.  I called it a day and promised to complete the work with illustrator the following morning.  Lokesh also did some great follow up work in Wix, making it look like we could make a pretty professional looking website there quicky - good to know for a future design sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned at the start, later in the evening I was on Slack hearing about the trouble recruiting testers and I drifted off thinking I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have such a rushed day on Friday &amp;hellip; how wrong I was.  Stay tuned to this blog for more about how it all went down on Friday :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rnyzabQkoAQ"&gt;Day four Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
