<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Client Feedback</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/11/av-ecosystem-review-client-feedback/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/11/av-ecosystem-review-client-feedback/</id>
    <published>2017-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-22T20:54:02+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="client feedback" src="/images/client_feedback.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got out a screenshot of the main APSoc LibreOffice Base Member Information form to the client late Friday, and over the weekend they&amp;rsquo;ve given me very detailed feedback on changes they want to the form.  Agile is all about providing working software as early as possible, but this seems like a nice shortcut to increase the chances that the resulting system will be what the client wants.  I&amp;rsquo;ve ordered a new HDMI cable so I can start developing on my windows machine (although will that just be a distraction?), and so I&amp;rsquo;m going to have a go at making all the changes requested on my mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjust label font (Liberation Sans &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Tahoma)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have membership number be numeric only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align last updated field with Member Information title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align all field names with left edge of inputs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce size of date fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All dates should have 4 digit years  &amp;lt;&amp;mdash; not sure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce size of &amp;ldquo;Known as&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Salutation&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wants to know signficance of white vs grey boxes &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; can explain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First line of address in top box &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; data issue - some addresses in odd places&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move &amp;ldquo;Local Group&amp;rdquo; up to address along with &amp;ldquo;N/L&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move up &amp;ldquo;NM N/L&amp;rdquo; also&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove KCM only text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move &amp;ldquo;City &amp;hellip; Country&amp;rdquo; row up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align Country field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Country drop down should be full list of countries &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; will need to investigate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Mobile Phone font&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove Fax field (and data from DB) &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; we don&amp;rsquo;t have final DB - am I supposed to provide a new schema?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove &amp;ldquo;Dietary Requirements&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace with &amp;ldquo;Email Address 2&amp;rdquo; &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; need to add this to DB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove “Gift Membership &amp;hellip;” from screen and DB (again the info can be moved to “Notes” by me after migration).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand “Notes” top full width of screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align check boxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Last Update”, “Date Joined” and “Member#” should be automatically generated and not keyable – these should have a grey background; other fields a white background. All other fields are potentially changeable although some will default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Work Phone&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Mobile Phone&amp;rdquo; fields should align with the fields in the row above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve done most of the cosmetic changes and some of the data ones:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/oz1u6wksr1c40mw/Screenshot%202017-12-11%2010.25.27.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In about 30 minutes, but that leaves me with a set of things I need to check &amp;hellip; over the course of the day I also got LibreOffice installed on my Windows machine where it seems to run a little faster, and I can confirm that it looks sensible on Windows; and seems to have all the right basic functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feedback from the client is very specific.  Some of the items are just tiny ones that I would have fixed in a subsequent pass.  Others are micro-changes for alignment and so on that I would have got to eventually.  It feels like many of these changes are ones that they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to make themselves when they are all set up with the software.  Others are more substantive.  Great to keep them in the loop.  For some reason I bristled at the font change suggestions; I think partly because I was having such trouble setting a default font, but as I familiarise myself further with the software I was able to make the requisite changes in short order.  It is great when one is able to show clients/users that you respond to their requests.  I think it builds a really positive relationship, but of course one needs to be able to say no when the amount of work explodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m optimisitic I can get the majority of the work done over the course of the next week without having to break stride, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see.  The interesting question is whether we want to start paying for Chatlio since this work was generated through that system, or if there&amp;rsquo;ll be any kind of similar work generated if we complete well on this.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got other people asking for quotes on website refreshes, so that&amp;rsquo;s probably the place to start before re-opening the web-chat deluge &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Paid Project on Schedule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/08/av-ecosystem-review-paid-project-on-schedule/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/08/av-ecosystem-review-paid-project-on-schedule/</id>
    <published>2017-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-20T21:14:58+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="project management" src="/images/project-management.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve told the APSoc that I&amp;rsquo;d send them mockups of the interfaces today.  I&amp;rsquo;m getting used to LibreOffice, e.g. leave the control panel open to more easily edit labels etc. It&amp;rsquo;s still painfully slow, and I&amp;rsquo;ve now realised that to speed up I need to keep the control panel closed when I want to move things around.  The copy and paste seems to work only intermittently, but I&amp;rsquo;m getting there &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/7sc51p52z5saxkg/Screenshot%202017-12-08%2017.59.55.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few more crashes, and I had the above.  Haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to get all the different interfaces setup, but I realised that each of them was basically a clone of the first with some different sub forms, so better get the first one completed before moving on.  I need to get the checkboxes functioning, and see if there&amp;rsquo;s a way to make the dropdowns choose only unique items when we&amp;rsquo;re offering options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also ordered a new HDMI cable which should allow me to use my Windows PC for development.  Given that the clients will be working on Windows, it would be good to be testing there, and I wonder if actually LibreOffice might work more consistenly there.  It would be a big step forward if the copy and paste would work on Windows &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Old School Progress</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/07/av-ecosystem-review-old-school-progress/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/07/av-ecosystem-review-old-school-progress/</id>
    <published>2017-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-19T21:27:32+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bug" src="/images/old_school.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m pretty far from reviewing the AV ecosystem here.  I&amp;rsquo;m devoting my blog driven development this week to making progress on the Anthony Powell Society membership database.  It&amp;rsquo;s old school in that I&amp;rsquo;m using LibreOffice Base, which is an open source version of MS Access.  I used to teach a course on MS Access and Excel back at HPU and it&amp;rsquo;s that experience that puts me in a position to deliver on the Anthony Powell Society project.  The APSoc have eschewed a cloud based membership database as they don&amp;rsquo;t believe their members would make use of an online offering, and don&amp;rsquo;t want to get locked in to some particular cloud offering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;d been managing their membership database using Lotus Approach for many years, and one of the big advantages there was the WYSIWYG interface that allowed the secretary to tinker with the forms and relationships in the system without having to be a hard core programmer.  Lotus Approach has been sunsetted and so I&amp;rsquo;m currently replicating the entire system for them in LibreOffice Base.  I had a reply to &lt;a href="https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/140023/base-list-box-dropdown-breaks-when-any-formatting-added/"&gt;my query on the ask.libreoffice.org site&lt;/a&gt; about formatting breaking the list box dropdown. Although it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fix the issue it is good to see that the community is responsive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one seems to know &lt;a href="https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/27384/how-to-change-the-default-font-in-libreoffice-base-form-wizard/"&gt;how to change the default font in Base&lt;/a&gt; but I need to kick on since I&amp;rsquo;ve promised mock ups of the forms for the APSoc for tomorrow.  What&amp;rsquo;s annoying is how slowly Base runs on my computer - I did do a restart the other day, hmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So LibreOffice crashes a couple of times and I lose 10 minutes of work, although I do work out how to change the background color and so make the Member Information form look more and more like the original from Lotus Approach:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ph3redhshw4p0cm/Screenshot%202017-12-07%2011.48.14.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also accidentally disconnect the form from the data source and have a few frantic moments getting it connected back up.  I&amp;rsquo;m thinking that I need to email the client to work out some of the more esoteric elements in the form that I haven&amp;rsquo;t added yet, but actually I see their detailed documentation includes exactly what we need there, so hopefully a good 90 minutes tomorrow and I can have mockups of at least the main form, if not the &amp;ldquo;Subscription Paid&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Gift Aid Declarations&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Standing Order Details&amp;rdquo; pages, which are simpler, but do include table embedding that I haven&amp;rsquo;t done yet &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So slow going, and it&amp;rsquo;s frustrating that most Premium members probably won&amp;rsquo;t be interested in this project as it&amp;rsquo;s not really using the latest tech.  I think it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful example of adapting to the needs of the client, and it&amp;rsquo;s good food for thought for our own membership/subscription model, but not many other synergies emerging here &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Crawling Along</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/06/av-ecosystem-review-crawling-along/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/06/av-ecosystem-review-crawling-along/</id>
    <published>2017-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-19T21:23:59+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bug" src="/images/bug.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I think I&amp;rsquo;ve forged a reasonable anxiety management strategy with the following schedule for the Anthony Powell Membership database:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Dec 8th - screenshots of membership database interface for you to approve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Dec 15th - alpha version of membership database for you to approve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 5th - beta version of membership database adjusted as per feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 31st - release version of membership database adjusted as per feedback, including full migration &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which the client says they are happy with, and I&amp;rsquo;ve queried about how the Membership Types table doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be used in the interface.  After yesterday&amp;rsquo;s blog I was fiddling with the system on the train and once I had the fields in the right data format, subforms linking in related tables was all working.  Ironically it seems we don&amp;rsquo;t immediately need that, but good to know that all works.  The form designer is not dissimilar from Keynote or PowerPoint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/eqeny8wkgv225x0/Screenshot%202017-12-06%2011.53.53.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m slowly pulling the fields around, trying to work out how to set the default font.  One thing I need to do is to be able to switch Member Grade to a drop down with different options &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve got that working using the list box wizard, but as soon as I try to add any formatting to the list box, the drop down functionality stops working:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/tlrx6xodqs4fw1p/Screenshot%202017-12-06%2013.46.39.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve asked on a forum:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/140023/base-list-box-dropdown-breaks-when-any-formatting-added/"&gt;https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/140023/base-list-box-dropdown-breaks-when-any-formatting-added/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but in the short term, unformatted should be fine.  Better work through the rest of the interfaces quick to see if I find any other sticking points &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Easily Distracted When Sick</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/05/av-ecosystem-review-easily-distracted-when-sick/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/05/av-ecosystem-review-easily-distracted-when-sick/</id>
    <published>2017-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-19T21:23:59+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="sneeze" src="/images/sneeze.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I didn&amp;rsquo;t get far with the Anthony Powell work yesterday, but I did at least get all the software running and get my head back into the problem space.  That was enough to take the edge off my anxiety about getting it started early.  I&amp;rsquo;m also onboarding a few new developers to WSO which ameliorates my worries about bleeds there.  This morning I got totally distracted by email and Slack, but in the procrastination wheel picture of things I did get a few things done.  Now let&amp;rsquo;s focus.  I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to see if I can bash the auto-generated form in LibreOffice Base to look like the exising Lotus Approach one.  The voice in my head worries that I should be writing out user stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can enter new member information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can browse member information in same form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The database dump we have from Lotus Approach appears to have five tables:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gift Aid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recurring Subs (transactional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and we have a dump of each with the addresses randomized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LibreOffice Base (like Lotus Approach and MS Access) provides a form interface where we can page through the rows in the database, and add new information.  I guess the key things to do are to make the forms look usable and ensure that the different tables have the right relationships set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also already imported three of the tables into the system.  I can&amp;rsquo;t remember how I did first time around.  I&amp;rsquo;ve previously referred to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://help.libreoffice.org/Common/Importing_and_Exporting_Data_in_Base"&gt;https://help.libreoffice.org/Common/Importing&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt;Exporting&lt;em&gt;Data&lt;/em&gt;in_Base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which basically involves opening the existing dbf files and copying and pasting all the existing rows into the tables section of a LOB database, and then using the import wizard.  I had a go at trying to match up the datatypes, which reminds me that I&amp;rsquo;ll probably need to start this over from scratch to get all the datatypes working properly &amp;hellip; as well as ensuring that I&amp;rsquo;m updated to the very latest LibreOffice version.   Hmm, I wonder if a Trello board or Pivotal Tracker is in order to track all the tasks?  I&amp;rsquo;m leaning towards Pivotal since being able to accept/reject by default will be a good match for this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got the form design system working so that I start manipulating the auto-generated form to look more like the existing Lotus Approach form:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/5grezldftymxi4z/Screenshot%202017-12-05%2010.52.43.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but now a key feature is being able to have a form field that refers to another table.  There are some videos online:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thefrugalcomputerguy.com/libreoffice-base/Base17.php"&gt;http://thefrugalcomputerguy.com/libreoffice-base/Base17.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but I browse around and read a few help forums, and then I&amp;rsquo;ve pretty much worked out how to put sub-forms into a form that link to a different table and slave certain fields to the record being shown in the main form.  It&amp;rsquo;s not working at the moment, but I guess that might be due to different field data types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/xi07mk1ckua2tgq/Screenshot%202017-12-05%2011.17.34.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think the sensible thing to do is to re-import the data.  What I should also do is give our clients a sensible timeline, such as showing them mockups of the new interfaces by the end of the week, and a first version to play with by the end of the following week &amp;hellip; hopefully that should put a lid on both my anxiety and theirs :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review No Good Choices</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/04/av-ecosystem-review-no-good-choices/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/04/av-ecosystem-review-no-good-choices/</id>
    <published>2017-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-14T20:11:58+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Urgh, so I&amp;rsquo;ve got a mild cold, but I desparately want to clear up and fix a few things with the Slack notifications.  Also the Google login and signup is broken.  However in addition I think I must use my morning blogs this week to work on the Anthony Powell Society database that we just got the contract for.  Of course between the cold and rebooting my computer and getting distracted by Slack I&amp;rsquo;m now out of time for really getting anything done before the WebDev Mob.  I guess maybe the thing to do is cancel the other meetings later in the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really not sure what the right choice is.  Maybe I should just be sleeping the whole day &amp;hellip; I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll at least start by opening LibreOffice Base &amp;hellip;, although the LibreOffice starts up with a document rather than a database.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to need to remember how to run the Base software itself.  Ah, okay, it looks like it is all one package.  I think LibreOffice accidentally opened a text file and so re-started in document mode.  Now restarting it I get a view of the recent files that includes the charity database components I was testing beforehand:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/1yk586ws45z9hcr/Screenshot%202017-12-04%2010.23.48.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opening libre-test.odb I get the familiar database design interfaces and the sample form I created for the membership database:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/1vbjqqs6y5qvid7/Screenshot%202017-12-04%2010.25.12.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we want it to look like is something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/y3xtz17fge1lm90/Screenshot%202017-12-04%2010.26.39.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is how the AP folks have their current Lotus Approach set up.  It would be nice to have a set of specific user stories, where I can ensure each one works.  I think I can infer the user stories from the forms and what the secretary showed me previously.  I could probably triple or quadruple the whole time spent on the system trying to set up some kind of automated acceptance testing &amp;hellip; although I have found a related blog on the subject:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://mmohrhard.wordpress.com/2016/09/07/ui-testing-in-libreoffice/"&gt;https://mmohrhard.wordpress.com/2016/09/07/ui-testing-in-libreoffice/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but now it&amp;rsquo;s time for the webdev mob &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
