<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2018-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Distracted By The Real Thing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/09/av-ecosystem-review-distracted-by-the-real-thing/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/09/av-ecosystem-review-distracted-by-the-real-thing/</id>
    <published>2018-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-14T21:17:47+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="distraction" src="/images/distraction.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically after getting more sleep last night I feel groggier this morning.  Sunday night I couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep re-hashing my 9-year old twins lost football (soccer) match (I&amp;rsquo;m the coach).  Don&amp;rsquo;t want to be strung out thinking about it, but I am every pretty much every time they lose; although it&amp;rsquo;s particularly bad when I think the opposing coach is not setting a good example.  Despite the lack of sleep on Sunday, yesterday was a solid day.  I slept properly last night, but is this a cold coming on?  Urgh.  Been distracted this morning, but maybe by the right stuff?  I&amp;rsquo;ve done a quick Slack/Email review and edited the &lt;a href="https://www.agileventures.org/premium-f2f-offer"&gt;AV Premium F2F offer page&lt;/a&gt; to include connecting to me on LinkedIn.  I keep wondering what to do with the random folks connecting to me there - might as well be offering them a free hour of pairing on a charity project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now I want to just quickly follow through with Will&amp;rsquo;s advice on changes to the Premium Sponsorship form, and get the revised version out to a few folks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay. This is only a side note, but I read this interesting article about names: &lt;a href="http://www.kalzumeus.com/2010/06/17/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-names/"&gt;http://www.kalzumeus.com/2010/06/17/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-names/&lt;/a&gt; TLDR: have a single &amp;ldquo;name&amp;rdquo; field&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each question should have a reason. I want to know why you need to know what country I live in, for a premium membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resume could be a lot of work. Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t the questions ask everything you want to know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re working remotely, where is the company based? *&amp;rdquo; shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have an asterisk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edited-down mob programming videos might get more folks applying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Please upload a cover letter indicating how you think you would benefit from the Premium membership you are applying for&amp;rdquo; could become just &amp;ldquo;How do you think you would benefit from the Premium membership you are applying for?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now it&amp;rsquo;s much shorter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/m29aa7wl36fiuw5/Screenshot%202018-01-09%2010.32.39.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but I must jump back to the APSoc membership database, and my new backup ritual which involves copying the previous days file in dropbox and relabelling it with the day I&amp;rsquo;m starting on.  Giving LibreOffice Base an extra 2GB of Java memory does not appear to have helped with the lock up issues.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;rsquo;s start with correctly populating the Local Group field in the membership form.  I create and populate a new table, and in short order I have the Local Group dropdown as requested:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/w93hp5cyr700a9i/Screenshot%202018-01-09%2010.45.43.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I duplicate the version and restart LibreOffice.  And then I work on a new dropdown for pay method on the subscription payment form.  I create the table, but then trying to set up the relation we get stuck again.  I go make coffee, come back, still stuck.  I kill the app, and re-start.  I&amp;rsquo;m lucky - this time we&amp;rsquo;re able to recover the corrupted file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/cms13nfe5rtu8nd/Screenshot%202018-01-09%2011.09.14.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ac9vdcxbhwlfpkk/Screenshot%202018-01-09%2011.10.30.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but I&amp;rsquo;ve got no basis to diagnose the issue &amp;hellip; I make a quick extra backup and continue, and I get it working:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/anclrh7bi983wpb/Screenshot%202018-01-09%2011.13.11.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no particular pattern - although sense problems come when I double up on things, e.g. add a table in the SQL view by double clicking, but then also click the add button &amp;hellip; okay, enough for today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to pass this version on to the client, as I said I would do that daily this week.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Tight Corner</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/08/av-ecosystem-review-tight-corner/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/08/av-ecosystem-review-tight-corner/</id>
    <published>2018-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-10T21:59:40+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="tight corner" src="/images/tight_corner.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my estimates were all wrong.  I had hoped to complete the membership database beta for APSoc in two mornings last week, and then be able to move back to things that were arguably more core AV ecosystem.  The task itself was no harder than expected, but the repeatedly crashing LibreOffice Base lost two mornings&amp;rsquo; work and then slowed me to a crawl as I instituted a variety of different (and increasingly extreme) backup options.  Having missed the deadline for Friday, I&amp;rsquo;ve pushed back to the following Friday, and now potentially I lose another week of mornings that I would like to have devoted to the AV ecosystem.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m now weighing up whether I try and combine the dropbox backups I have with git, and I see there&amp;rsquo;s some interesting SO posts about this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/1960799/using-git-and-dropbox-together-effectively"&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/1960799/using-git-and-dropbox-together-effectively&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it looks like it could work.  But I think I&amp;rsquo;ll burn time with set up for potentially not much gain.  I think the key is doing the LibreOffice double save and restarting it each time I make any progress.  It feels late in the day to try and switch to another piece of software such as MSAccess.  Interacting in read/write mode with LibreOffice feels fairly stable.  It&amp;rsquo;s the occasional random lockups, when actually editing the interface, that cause me headaches.  Hopefully for the client it will be solid, but if not I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll have to pay for MSAccess and re-do it all there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with is boosting the allocated memory for the app.  Let&amp;rsquo;s see if that helps today.  Maybe I can sort out the Countries DB to have USA and UK at the top &amp;hellip; I try to create a countries table from scratch, but I have trouble setting the primary key.  And almost immediately I have the spinning beachball of death.  Is this something about the size and structure of the system I&amp;rsquo;ve created here within LibreOffice DB?  That I&amp;rsquo;m using it on Mac? Although I do get similar issues on PC.  Or is it that both my computers are too old and slow?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway I managed to create the adjusted countries table by just allowing the db to create its own primary key, and then finally pasting in data from Google sheets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/rkw7tt19t85jtqu/Screenshot%202018-01-08%2009.54.07.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now I can&amp;rsquo;t insert any records.  Seems like we lost all the auto-value settings on all the table IDs somewhere last week.  I&amp;rsquo;d better send this revised version off to the client, before they start testing the buggy one I sent on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you had a good weekend and apologies again for the deadline slippage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve just been working on the system and if you do run any more tests I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to work against this version (rather than the one sent on Friday):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LINK TO BETA VERSION 2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one has the the UK and USA at the top of the countries list, and another insert bug fixed (or rather refixed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that we&amp;rsquo;re behind schedule we&amp;rsquo;ll try and give you daily updates this week.  However - please don&amp;rsquo;t feel obliged to test things daily.  We just want to make sure that when you do get a chance to test that you&amp;rsquo;re working against the latest and greatest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, we plan to have all your items of feedback addressed by Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best, Sam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tight corner indeed - can I bank effectively and avoid coming a cropper?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Beta Release Deadline</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/05/av-ecosystem-review-beta-release-deadline/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/05/av-ecosystem-review-beta-release-deadline/</id>
    <published>2018-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-15T21:34:33+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="distraction" src="/images/../images/dealine.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I&amp;rsquo;m up against the deadline for the beta release of the APSoc membership database.  The timeline I gave them at the beginning of the project was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Dec 8th - screenshots of membership database interface for you to approve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Dec 15th - alpha version of membership database for you to approve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 5th - beta version of membership database adjusted as per feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 31st - release version of membership database adjusted as per feedback, including full migration &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to avoid losing any work yesterday, let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can do the same today with appropriate dropbox backups.  What I need to do now is work through their list of fixes again, re-fixing the stuff I lost from Tuesday and Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Fixes (membership form)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring all text entry fields to front and labels to back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete junk at bottom of form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start renaming the elements that still have default names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And already I&amp;rsquo;ve got the spinning beachball - okay - time to move to the PC - I duplicate the latest system and add a &amp;ldquo;-pc&amp;rdquo; tag on it, but it&amp;rsquo;s reporting as a corrupted file and I can&amp;rsquo;t open it on the PC.  A little dance and I restore the previous version from dropbox and get it opened on the PC.  Tense moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Fixes (membership form) (cont. on PC)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;swapped NL and NML checkboxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and after merely 60 seconds of normal function on the PC the software has locked up again.  Gosh, am I going to have to tell the client that we&amp;rsquo;ll have to switch to Microsoft Access &amp;hellip;?  I had another go with the recovered version on Mac, and I used the advice in &lt;a href="http://lowendmac.com/2014/speed-up-libreoffice-on-your-mac/"&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; to increase the amount of memory being made available to the LibreOffice on Mac, and I&amp;rsquo;ve made some progress, finishing up the tab sequence changes on the membership form, and now putting through a series of changes to the Subscription Payment form.  I&amp;rsquo;ve saved and backed those up, but now onto the Gift Aid form, where a series of small formatting changes leads the system to lock up again!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Regular Backups</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/04/av-ecosystem-review-regular-backups/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/04/av-ecosystem-review-regular-backups/</id>
    <published>2018-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-08T21:06:45+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="backup" src="/images/backup.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So leaving it overnight has not magically fixed the corrupted database file, and it seems I&amp;rsquo;ve lost several hours work from the last few days, and I can&amp;rsquo;t figure out any easy way to recover it.  Brent was suggesting git, but the annoying thing about this LibreOffice Base (MSOffice/LotusApproach) style system is that the data is stored along with db schema and interface.  I can&amp;rsquo;t really put this in a public git repository.  I could set up a private git account on GitHub through AgileVentures, for which this is a project, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a stab at a dropbox backed up approach.  Cloning the system at critical points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I start by adjusting all the tables so that the autovalue is set on the primary fields, which should clear up the main issue the client experienced in the alpha version, which was an inability to save data.  I&amp;rsquo;m now working with the odb in dropbox and I can see the version history going past:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/4imbyibc39ilidm/Screenshot%202018-01-04%2010.00.23.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d moved off dropbox before because I was worried that the dropbox syncing might be causing problems and a previous attempt to backup from dropbox hadn&amp;rsquo;t worked, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve worked out that there&amp;rsquo;s a double save operation required and I&amp;rsquo;ll keep tracking the dropbox updates to check I&amp;rsquo;m getting proper backups and I don&amp;rsquo;t lose any more work &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now onto trying to fix the Standing Order form that I was sure I did before Xmas, but appears to have been lost (not properly saved), the editing of which caused the main crash yesterday &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I get the form updated (i.e. the subform that connects to the recurring sub table), and it seems okay, but then I try to add a new form field and we get the spinning beach ball of death again.  This was the point yesterday when I killed the system and we lost all the data.  I note now that dropbox is stuck trying to upload the latest version.  Maybe the trick is that I have to create a new subform from scratch rather than modifying the existing one, but this is a silly game of guess what&amp;rsquo;s causing the problem &amp;hellip; hmm, should I switch back to working on the PC?  Should we have just gone with MSAccess, or tried harder to convince the client to go with a cloud based solution?  Personally I&amp;rsquo;m still enamoured with the feature that the client loved about Lotus Approach which was their ability to tweak the forms themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this time I was less hasty about killing the application and in about five minutes, while I looked up the latest version of LibreOffice (I think there&amp;rsquo;s a new version out) and fired up my PC, the libre on my Mac unlocked and I was able to save it &amp;hellip; it locked up again a little time later, so I killed it and was able to recover with the latest version of LibreOffice for mac.  I sorted out the Standing Order Details form.  Here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot to prove it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ve6vacheeuz4a69/Screenshot%202018-01-04%2011.58.33.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carefully saving after each change, and now I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll have to push on the rest tomorrow, after making a backup copy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Task Switching</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/03/av-ecosystem-review-task-switching/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/03/av-ecosystem-review-task-switching/</id>
    <published>2018-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-07T21:24:54+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="task switching" src="/images/taskswitching.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say that task switching is bad for getting things done.  Clearly some tasks require more concentration, but then there&amp;rsquo;s also the issue of getting bored with the task at hand.  There&amp;rsquo;s also the issue of switching between documenting (blogging?) a task and getting that task done.  Yesterday morning after about an hour (?) of blog-driven work on the APSoc membership database I switched to admin tasks and then the rest of the day.  It was about 5pm before I got some more free programming time and was able to punch in some time on WebSiteOne where I think I had more done test-driving the creation of a &lt;code&gt;current_subscription&lt;/code&gt; method on our User model.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given a free choice I&amp;rsquo;d probably carry on with that right now, but I have a 5th Jan deadline that I committed to for the APSoc, so I best get that sorted first.  It was a good feeling to sort the &amp;ldquo;AutoValue&amp;rdquo; fields on the APSoc membership database so that data could be inserted, but there&amp;rsquo;s something about the interplay between tests and code that I love.  The LibreOffice Base system is not really amenable to unit tests, although for all I know they have unit tests under the hood as part of the development suite.  However designing a client application via the graphical interface does not involve me writing any kind of tests and given the sensitivity of the application I&amp;rsquo;m not inspired to check out the acceptance testing frameworks that are available.  I burned a lot of time on a private client coding project trying to get comprehensive acceptance testing set up for Electron, and I&amp;rsquo;m becoming a lot more circumspect about the range of acceptance tests that I&amp;rsquo;ll try to employ these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the WebSiteOne project, I&amp;rsquo;m in a phase of Domain Driven Design, where I&amp;rsquo;m tweaking a relationship in the data model that I believe is needed to accurately replicate the nature of our Premium subscriptions.  I&amp;rsquo;ve started with making the database model change, and I&amp;rsquo;m working out from there - I&amp;rsquo;m in the unit tests for the model, and much as I say I love the interplay, yesterday was tricky where it seemed I had to discard a fast running mocked test for a slower integration test using FactoryGirl. I turned this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class="n"&gt;context&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'look up stripe id from subscription'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:subscription&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mock_model&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;Subscription&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;save: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kp"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;before&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;allow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;subscription&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:[]=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="n"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'asks subscription for identifier'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;subscription&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;:identifier&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="n"&gt;subject&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;subscription&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;subscription&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="n"&gt;subject&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;stripe_customer_id&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;into this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class="n"&gt;context&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'supporting current subscription'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;subject&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;FactoryGirl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;:with_karma&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:premium&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;FactoryGirl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:plan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;name: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Premium'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:premium_mob&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;FactoryGirl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:plan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;name: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Premium Mob'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:payment_source&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;PaymentSource&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;PayPal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;identifier: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'75e'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# presence of type (no longer used) in the Subscriptions model is confusing ...&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# should get rid of all the STI classes ...&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="n"&gt;let!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:subscription1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;FactoryGirl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:subscription&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;user: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;plan: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;premium&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;started_at: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;days&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;ago&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;ended_at: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;ago&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;let!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:subscription2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;FactoryGirl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:subscription&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;user: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;plan: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;premium_mob&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;started_at: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;ago&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;payment_source: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;payment_source&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="n"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'returns subscription that has started and has not ended'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;current_subscription&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;eq&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;subscription2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="n"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'asks subscription for identifier'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;subject&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;stripe_customer_id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;eq&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'75e'&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bit uncomfortable with all this FactoryGirl stuff, but I&amp;rsquo;m exercising the following new method on the user model:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;current_subscription&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_subscriptions&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;where&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;ended_at: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kp"&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;where&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'started_at &amp;lt; :now'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;now: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;DateTime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;now&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kp"&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;nil?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;empty?&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and stubbing it would require a rather long stub chain.  Ironically the APSoc system is also a database running SQL under the hood, and at points I end up writing queries that could be the subject of unit tests, but it&amp;rsquo;s a different beast.  In the WSO code I&amp;rsquo;ve just changed what was a unit test into an integration test, and I&amp;rsquo;m slowly moving up the chain and realising I could have driven this from an acceptance test that ensured the state of subscriptions after an upgrade, although it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a black box test &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night I wasn&amp;rsquo;t blog driving the WSO RoR coding as I wanted to move fast, but now I&amp;rsquo;ve burnt 30 minutes this morning (mixed in with trying to chat with BT about our intermittment business broadband issues).  Partly the blogging is supposed to help me stay focused on a task, but it can also be a distraction or a great way of thinking through a problem, depending on the circumstances.  So anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ve pulled up yesterday&amp;rsquo;s blog with the list of outstanding tasks for the APSoc db.  Let&amp;rsquo;s take a pass over things that might be sticky/tricky:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outstanding items:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completing tab sequence changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local Group sub-table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove various fields from the db&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reformat the content of Member_No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various layout changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Couple of UI interaction issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standing Order Details form appears to be a duplicate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I think the Member&lt;em&gt;No change might be the sticky one.  If I recall the client is suggesting making a change in the format of the membership number which might make for a tricky migration.  I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to just work though the list, making all the changes that are simple, and putting off anything that could take a little longer, specifically the Local Group sub-table and the Member&lt;/em&gt;No thing for the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although as I look at it in more detail I see they want something else from the Member&lt;em&gt;No.  This is not the RecNo that is the &amp;ldquo;primary key&amp;rdquo;.  It&amp;rsquo;s a composite that they want to be built from &amp;ldquo;Member&lt;/em&gt;Types&lt;em&gt;Code&lt;/em&gt;Letter + RecNo&amp;rdquo;.  Hmm, should this be a dynamically constructed field?  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where the Member&lt;em&gt;Types&lt;/em&gt;Code_Letter is coming from &amp;hellip; Didn&amp;rsquo;t they just ask the CodeLetter be deleted from the membership types table?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ve deleted the fields they didn&amp;rsquo;t want in the membership table, so let&amp;rsquo;s make sure that the membership form still works &amp;hellip; so I can view records and edit them after the table changes.  Here&amp;rsquo;s where acceptance tests might save me from needing to exhaustively test all things like adding a new record &amp;hellip; perhaps I can delete the test one and re-add - that worked fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the biggest surprise is that my work creating the Standing Order form appears to have been lost.  I could have sworn I went through creating that, but this bloody double save requirement is my bane.  It&amp;rsquo;s not enough to click save on the form editor - you also have to click save on the main database page in order to ensure everything is actually saved to disk - insane.  I&amp;rsquo;ve just dredged up the memory about how to create the correct subform, and now the app has crashed again.  In my other parallel task BT says they have detected a possible fault on our line and they are looking into it - which is better news.  But LibreOffice is back to the spinning beach ball of death &amp;hellip; time to kill it and restart.  Argh, and now the entire file is corrupted - my entire two days work lost by the look of it &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent 15 minutes kicking things around.  The backup files are all zero size, no go.  I think I&amp;rsquo;ll start again tomorrow &amp;hellip; new process - take a backup each day &amp;mdash; maybe develop in dropbox?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review New Year Same Conflicts</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/02/av-ecosystem-review-new-year-same-conflicts/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/02/av-ecosystem-review-new-year-same-conflicts/</id>
    <published>2018-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-03T21:09:51+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="new year" src="/images/newyear2018.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The start of a new year; some of the same conflicts remaining, though.  Leaving off from the last week of last year, I really want to adjust our Premium membership domain model to more accurately reflect the way in which members upgrade and downgrade.  Perhaps even more critically I want to set up private event functionality that would automate some of the process by which potential members try out premium sessions and get presented with the option to upgrade.  Unfortunately I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can work on either, as I must deliver the beta-version of the membership database to the Anthony Powell society.  The timeframe is entirely of my own making of course, and it will be reasonably interesting and pleasing to get the membership database done, but I&amp;rsquo;ve not got much interest from many Premium members in my LibreOffice development work &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept behind AgileVentures is that folks can skill up by working/observing real projects with real customers as they progress.  The problem seems to be that in many cases it&amp;rsquo;s not the latest new tech that&amp;rsquo;s needed to get the job done.  Or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s that the process of learning through client work is just too traumatic?  Anyway, if I want to make time to add new features to WebSiteOne I&amp;rsquo;ll need to crack on with the APSoc database &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the list of issues with the alpha version that the client identified:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;MembershipTypes DB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t need &amp;ldquo;Code Letter&amp;rdquo; field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Countries DB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we have UK and USA as the top two please as they&amp;rsquo;re the most used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Member Information Form&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unable to add/save a new member record – see error below! – probably applies to all forms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cannot key into &amp;ldquo;Mobile Phone&amp;rdquo; – cursor won&amp;rsquo;t go there!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Local Group&amp;rdquo; needs to be correctly populated – maybe we need a table of the groups?  The groups should be: London, Baltic, Germany, Great Lakes, Toronto, NE USA, Australia, California, Texas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch positions of &amp;ldquo;N/L&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;NM N/L&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tab sequence should be – see Member&lt;em&gt;Form&lt;/em&gt;Tab_Seq.pdf – similar sequences for other forms.  Unnumbered keyable fields do not need to appear in the tab sequence (but could after numbered fields)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Membership DB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can remove the fields: “Gift&lt;em&gt;Donor”, “Fax”, “Diet&lt;/em&gt;Rqts”, “Address”, “Crap”, “C_N” – see comments to the DB specification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the field “Address4”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reformat the content of “Member_No” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Subscription Payment Form&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t need &amp;ldquo;Member Card&amp;rdquo; field as we don&amp;rsquo;t use membership cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Amount Paid&amp;rdquo;, please can it display with a £ sign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pay Method&amp;rdquo; dropdown needs populating; options should be: PayPal, Credit Card, Cheque, Bank Transfer, Standing Order, Cash, Other.  Worth putting this in a new table so it can be changed easily?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;CC No&amp;rdquo; and CC&amp;quot;Expiry&amp;quot; fields can be removed as we don&amp;rsquo;t store this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Rate Paid&amp;rdquo;, please can the items in the dropdown be sequenced as&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whenever try adding a record of new subscription I get:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/fleeiuezj046z4b/image003.jpg?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removal of fields means &amp;ldquo;Notes&amp;rdquo; could be positioned to the right of the payments lines to reduce the size of the form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keying say &amp;ldquo;15&amp;rdquo; in a date field adds the date from the field above or is it the last date enetered?), unless the field above is blank&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subs DB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remove &amp;ldquo;Member Card&amp;rdquo; field as we don&amp;rsquo;t use membership cards&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remove &amp;ldquo;CC No&amp;rdquo; and CC&amp;quot;Expiry&amp;quot; fields as we don&amp;rsquo;t store this&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Form doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to show &amp;ldquo;Letters&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Known As&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Salutation&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gift Aid Declaration Form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If there is a completed record of a declaration, with a blank &amp;ldquo;To Date&amp;rdquo; then the &amp;ldquo;Gift Aid&amp;rdquo; checkbox should be checked&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Declaration line items, can the fields be less wide, and then again &amp;ldquo;Notes&amp;rdquo; can go to right of the line items and form size reduces&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Same error as in Subscription Payment Form when adding a record&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standing Order Details Form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a duplicate of the Gift Aid Declaration Form&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots to do here - I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with the section on the Membership information form:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member Information Form

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unable to add/save a new member record – see error below! – probably applies to all forms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cannot key into &amp;ldquo;Mobile Phone&amp;rdquo; – cursor won&amp;rsquo;t go there!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Local Group&amp;rdquo; needs to be correctly populated – maybe we need a table of the groups?  The groups should be: London, Baltic, Germany, Great Lakes, Toronto, NE USA, Australia, California, Texas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch positions of &amp;ldquo;N/L&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;NM N/L&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tab sequence should be – see Member&lt;em&gt;Form&lt;/em&gt;Tab_Seq.pdf – similar sequences for other forms.  Unnumbered keyable fields do not need to appear in the tab sequence (but could after numbered fields)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knock off some low hanging fruit by switching the positions of &amp;ldquo;N/L&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;NM N/L&amp;rdquo;.  I confirm that the &amp;ldquo;Mobile Phone&amp;rdquo; can&amp;rsquo;t be entered - can&amp;rsquo;t see anything in the settings about why it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work, so I delete it and copy over the &amp;ldquo;Work Phone&amp;rdquo; text box.  That doesn&amp;rsquo;t fix it, hmm.  I realise the problem is that the text label above it is too large and preventing cursor selection, so I resize that and we have two minor issues fixed.  I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to work on other less threatening issues like the tab sequence but this inability to save is likely to be the big blocker, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to hit that next.  I replicate the error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/yi6szspyshvrmgl/Screenshot%202018-01-02%2010.29.22.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the problems seems to be that our automatically added ID columns from the data import are not set up as primary keys that will get an autoincremented ID added with new records.  That&amp;rsquo;s a simple fix thanks to &lt;a href="https://forum.openoffice.org/en/forum/viewtopic.php?f=61&amp;amp;t=64324"&gt;this forum post&lt;/a&gt;, and that now works fine, although I can see all sorts of little niggly issues now that I start entering data rather than just focusing on the form layout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, just adding UK and USA at the top of the countries field turns out to be non-trivial, but I can clearly do it if I re-import the countries data.  Let&amp;rsquo;s check the process of adjusting the tab sequence to flush out anything else that could turn out to be harder than I expect.  The client has sent this diagram of the tab sequence they want:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/gw06wl2inhioh69/Screenshot%202018-01-02%2010.50.01.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and sorting that isn&amp;rsquo;t too hard once I find &lt;a href="https://forum.openoffice.org/en/forum/viewtopic.php?f=39&amp;amp;t=9484"&gt;this forum post&lt;/a&gt; that helps me navigate to the tab ordering tool.  Of course now LibreOffice is gradually slowing, and I&amp;rsquo;m worried it&amp;rsquo;s going to crash again.   I think I&amp;rsquo;ve worked out the trick, to avoid losing too much work, of saving not just in the form view, but also in the main database page.  Now it&amp;rsquo;s spinning beachballs on each screen.  Guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to grab a coffee &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still stuck - I kill it, recover the db and lose only a tiny bit of work.  I make changes to the tab order, save, and that seems to work.  There&amp;rsquo;s a chunk more to do, but with a run up I could maybe get it all done tomorrow &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
