<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-10-02T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>The pilot+copilot organizational pattern</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/10/02/pilot-copilot-organizational-pattern/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/10/02/pilot-copilot-organizational-pattern/</id>
    <published>2017-10-02T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-04T21:52:30+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="pair flying" src="/images/pairflying.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2002, I graduated a distance-learning masters in applied mathematics. Every month, the university mailed me an A4 enveloppe containing the course support. I was supposed to learn from the course material and returned the completed assignments within a month. A month later, I would receive an answer key. Should I have a question, I could mail it to the professor and wait for his reply. The whole process was cumbersome. I was often behind schedule. Interactivity was near to zero. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on, I participated in the MOOC endeavour. The video of the instructor gave a feeling of a one-to-one training session. Discussion forums, deadlines, follow-up mails, peer-reviews grounded the learning process. There were meetups too. And a MOOC about Agile Development using Ruby On Rails offered remote pair-programming sessions between participants. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pair-programmming reuses the rather old organizational pattern of pilot+copilot : double-check, higher focusing, external view, and stronger engagement. You may object that programming is very different from flying. Yes, it is! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But programming requires a strong level of accuracy too. Your pairing fellow is both a watch dog that tells you not to call a library without checking how it works, not to cut and paste code across your work, and an inspiration to experiment with new ways of coding. As some aerobatic aircrafts don&amp;rsquo;t include a copilot seat, some programs are implemented by lone wolves in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools like teamviewer, logmein, skype, hangout or joinme have been instrumental to the success of remote pair working. There is still room for improvement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) In a face-to-face meeting, there is a desk between the two interlocutors. Webcams should recreate this confortable spacing. I&amp;rsquo;m neither a barber nor a dental professional!
2) Remote working platforms lack of interoperability. Some only run on Windows, some require to install a software, others are more suitable for mobile use&amp;hellip; and don&amp;rsquo;t try to connect to hangout with skype
3) Security is a weak point for all of these platforms. Choosing which window you share, which you don&amp;rsquo;t, masking your passwords or your personal information are not intuitive. In my earlier days, I remembered displaying my passwords on a recorded session. Not so good a security practice!
4) Optimizing the screen definition so that everybody can watch comfortably is not supported either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every desktop application from IDE to word processors will probably include some kind of remote pair working feature sooner or later. C9 already includes some simple pair-programming features, for instance.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bugs in the code? Don&amp;rsquo;t blame me, it&amp;rsquo;s my pair programming partner who fooled around!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Another free refill?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/22/another-free-refill/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/22/another-free-refill/</id>
    <published>2017-09-22T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-27T21:07:18+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="free refill" src="/images/freerefill.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I undertook a training session targeting small business manager to teach them how to improve profitability of business projects. The course instructor showed us a rather clear way to deal with profitabiliy. First, you estimate your break-even hourly rate, based on your history. Then, you don&amp;rsquo;t sell any project under the bottom line. After that, you prioritize your work to put the highest priority on the most profitable projects. Finally, you keep any accepted project above the bottom line. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is quite simple. It&amp;rsquo;s all down to the execution. I began to schedule my workday according to business priorities preferably to a sense of urgency that overcame me before. Then, everytime I felt I was at risk to hit the bottom line, I shifted my attention towards what I really sold to the client annd I reduced my objectives accordingly. Finally, I was trying to become a project reviewer for a well known MOOC platform. But the hourly rate was much too low. I felt relief to drop my candidature. Paid projects management improved greatly. But, a significant part of my workday, dedicated to volunteer projects, was out of the scope of this effort.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many commitments, workaholism, things we begin and we never achieve, any freelance worker faces these contradictions. The inherent contradiction is even stronger when you work on non-paid project. How to prioritize your volunteer works?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten working hours a day is my upper limit, considering that I&amp;rsquo;m not a computer nerd, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a family, hobbies, and a social life &amp;hellip; I was already busy ten hours a day. Adding anything to my schedule implied removing something else. I have been more or less active on professional social networks for three years. I first thought this commitment would improve my reputation and fuel my prospect pipeline. But in three years, the return was not very encouraging. I felt that my social network activity was fueled by bitterness or anxiety or ego or the three rather than by a clear sense of business opportunity! I decided to forget social networks. Two to three hours a week were freed thanks to this good resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to devote these hours to Agile Venture mob programming sessions. It&amp;rsquo;s a real community, with real developers. You can both learn by observing how skilled developers work and by doing things by yourself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still in the midstream of my prioritization effort. I&amp;rsquo;ve been very actively participating in MOOCs for five years. My skills greatly improved as a result of this effort.  But choosing which courses to invest on is not easy. Knowledge is a bit like indirects costs. You don&amp;rsquo;t really know how to assign it to your achievements. During the first years, the offer flourished. I tried many courses, from Economy to Computer Sciences. I progressively focused on Computer Science and left courses as they switched to paid offers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was giving up, a prominent MOOC platform offers me to beta-test courses for free. Free refill is the end of resolution and the beginning of passive hyperactivity! You may begin your training week with a course on Embedded systems and end, on friday, with a course on PythonML on friday, without completing any. Does it make sense to participate in a mob programming session about RSPEC on monday, another one about phoenix on wednesday, on the last one about React on friday, when you only need to develop a small web app with React?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AgileVenture Premium Mob includes some kind of Professional Development Planning Support. I may ask the team to help me clean my training plan. But I&amp;rsquo;m still afraid they will tell me to stop learning Tensor Flow or the nitty gritty of Intel Parallel Architecture if I don&amp;rsquo;t have any prospect to work in these fields in the next year! &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Email What Next</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/12/av-ecosystem-review-what-next/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/12/av-ecosystem-review-what-next/</id>
    <published>2017-09-12T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-08T20:05:01+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve looked back at my list from yesterday as I tried to work out how to start the week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) review the process of people coming in from adwords
2) fix the email SPF setting
3) more work on greeter bots
4) search for other areas of ecosystem that are blocked up
5) preparing that video for dropbox to debug github image embeds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s looking like we&amp;rsquo;ve fixed the email SPF setting (thanks Federico!) and I&amp;rsquo;ve submitted the video to dropbox about their links not working in Github and Pivotal markdown, but they&amp;rsquo;ve not replied yet (checking the email sidetracked me while I unsubscribed from five things), so no joy on that getting fixed yet.  It might be procrastination, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ll put off reviewing people flowing into the site for a week to see if I can get my easy  &amp;ldquo;insert-screenshot&amp;rdquo; functionality back.  I really want to put the new community-wide code of conduct into the website and the greeter bots, but the community is discussing it and so it might be good to leave that a couple of days (but no longer).  Thinking about important areas of the ecosystem, I&amp;rsquo;ve got hanging items in terms of WebSiteOne.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got a slew of content tickets relating to Premium that have been hanging around for ages, and I said in last Friday&amp;rsquo;s WSO meeting that I&amp;rsquo;d take on the multiple source repository task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our project maintainers had dropped in the WSO channel to mention this was an issue - that&amp;rsquo;s a faily solid prod.  There&amp;rsquo;s no direct revenue growth attached to it, but the health of the community relies on active healthy projects.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also got to get the board cleared up - every hanging ticket is extra noise that I (and others) have to process every time we look at it &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just looking at the board, I got distracted by other tickets - checking that LocalSupport deployed to production correctly and that the latest code on WSO staging is making sense &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve kicked off the karma calculator there and should ask Praveen to check his features there &amp;hellip; but back to the board.   I&amp;rsquo;ve got one ticket for making the Premium page questions pop-out to reduce the amount of text on the page overall &amp;hellip; and that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to do this morning. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://staging.agileventures.org/premium"&gt;https://staging.agileventures.org/premium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least edit that page on the staging server.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also saved an HTML copy into the staticpages view directory that will move the ticket from ready to in progress on the waffle board:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/pull/1816"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/pull/1816&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also thinking that ultimately we may need to make these pages slightly less editable, and more generated.  We&amp;rsquo;ll see.  I think other devs also need to have copies of them locally.  Either way I&amp;rsquo;ll get feedback on the staging server from the Marketing team before pushing live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. did a &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/tansaku/6450f322f7505880872eb287c0ca36b0"&gt;node rep and included standardjs&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Email Fixes and Directions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/11/av-ecosystem-review-email-fixes-and-directions/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/11/av-ecosystem-review-email-fixes-and-directions/</id>
    <published>2017-09-11T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-07T22:07:17+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="directions" src="/images/directions.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m conflicted - what direction next?  On the table are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) review the process of people coming in from adwords
2) fix the email SPF setting
3) more work on greeter bots
4) search for other areas of ecosystem that are blocked up
5) preparing that video for dropbox to debug github image embeds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally managed to see one of our adverts that Lara shared:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-09-11%2009.00.27.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I&amp;rsquo;m still concerned about the message we&amp;rsquo;re sending, i.e. the absence of any mention of team skills or agile in that ad.  It&amp;rsquo;s so frustrating that I can&amp;rsquo;t immediately get a simple view of our actual ads from the Google Analytics interface.  We also got the concern that our ads seem to be showing up particularly heavily in India, and we&amp;rsquo;re not sure why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend I got the following from Elastic Email:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Account sam@agileventures.org has one or more domains that were validated at one time but are no longer for some reason. How the domains became invalidated is not known but it is likely a configuration issue on your DNS for the domain(s) in question. It is important to take this step to ensure your emails are sending directly from your domain. Below is the list of domains that are not currently validated anymore: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;agileventures.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it seems like that the recent SPF change in the Gandi settings is the issue here.  I passed that on to Federico, who suggested the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ 600 IN TXT "v=spf1 include:_mailcust.gandi.net include:_spf.elasticemail.com ~all”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice the change of Time To Live to 10 minutes instead of 3 hours, and the switch back to “~all”—the recommended policy statement. &amp;ldquo;?all&amp;rdquo; means neutral policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I replaced the current:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ 10800 IN TXT "v=spf1 include:_mailcust.gandi.net ?all"
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with the suggested change, but I got this error&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Line 5: Error while parsing rdata: newline in quoted string&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which was due to a non-ascii quote - switching that out and the DNS file saved.  Federico had shortened the TTL, so in principle we could check sooner if it was having the effect we wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I wait for that the frustration of wanting to embed an image made me want to record the video for dropbox.  I did that using the preview tab for creating this blog.  Here&amp;rsquo;s what I sent them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Marco,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for this - here&amp;rsquo;s a video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.dropbox.com/s/2rjda5vuqaj1b0g/DropboxLinksNotWorkingForImagesOnGithub.mov?dl=0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It shows me trying to preview an image embed from the following dropbox link:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.dropbox.com/s/nmurrdqxj76oq07/Screenshot%202017-09-11%2009.00.27.png?dl=1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see that the image does not show up in preview - also note that for the last year links like these were showing up fine as images, so something somewhere changed recently.  As you&amp;#39;lls ee from the video GitHub grabs the image from you at dropbox and stores it on their own servers.  Here&amp;rsquo;s what Steve Guntrip at GitHub said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When ?dl=1 is specified, we get redirected to the image file with a non-image Content-Type header, Content-Type: application/binary. For your image to load, this Content-Type should be an image, like Content-Type: image/png.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, I would suggest reaching out to Dropbox&amp;rsquo;s support to see if they can maybe support embedding images if the user agent is github-camo (our service that downloads these images to githubusercontent.com), or if they have another solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks in advance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best, Sam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s almost time to test the email, but maybe time for a &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/tansaku/c311c996cc1521dceea0c0852849e9ca"&gt;quick node test rep&lt;/a&gt; and then I can check the email stuff by going to http://tools.wordtothewise.com/spf/check/AgileVentures.org and clicking on the DNS tab (as Federico suggested), where I see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-09-11%2009.25.55.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which I guess is telling me it&amp;rsquo;s working?  I can also send an email from my account that was previously marked as spam &amp;hellip; and that&amp;rsquo;s still coming through normally, so I guess that&amp;rsquo;s sorted?  We&amp;rsquo;ll see what happens with Elastic Email &amp;hellip; I guess that&amp;rsquo;s enough progress for one day.  If I&amp;rsquo;m super lucky, I&amp;rsquo;ll get back the easy image embed functionality from dropbox/GitHub that&amp;rsquo;ll make reviewing everything else a lot easier &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Email Fix</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/08/av-ecosystem-review-email-fix/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/08/av-ecosystem-review-email-fix/</id>
    <published>2017-09-08T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-06T21:51:29+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="fix" src="/images/fix.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, following my blog and email of yesterday I got the following response from Gandi:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally, it is the recipient&amp;rsquo;s email server rules that play to deliver the message to the recipient&amp;rsquo;s box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To decrease the chance to be considered as spam by the recipient mail server, you can add the SPF record in your zone file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this, you can refer to the instructions page here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://doc.gandi.net/en/dns/zone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please delete the current SPF record below :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ 10799 IN TXT "v=spf1 a mx include:_spf.elasticemail.com ~all"
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SPF records to be added is as below (please use edit mode : EXPERT):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ 10800 IN TXT "v=spf1 include:_mailcust.gandi.net ?all"
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above records indicate when mail is sent from the email server Gandi, normally, it is not spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that changes to your zone file will take around 3 hours to propagate on the Internet. Please wait for this propagation time before doing test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about the SPF record, please see the online documentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://wiki.gandi.net/en/dns/zone/spf-record&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I had the following from Federico&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the step-by-step video tutorial that Zoho Mail provides: https://docs.zoho.com/embed/28z4w99ee43ded3f14b3182bf0041c35042b7&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok. That one was purely SPF. This one is for DKIM &lt;em&gt;(3-min):&lt;/em&gt; https://docs.zoho.com/embed/281y6174f134d5f244817a38c7d32e4cd4c41&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d rather scan text (DKIM): https://www.zoho.com/mail/help/adminconsole/dkim-configuration.html
SPF: https://www.zoho.com/mail/help/adminconsole/spf-configuration.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to review here, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to calm myself with an &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/tansaku/8e2ee25a007d9b706390513d53bbe191"&gt;athletic node test rep&lt;/a&gt;.  Ah, calming and I think 3 minutes to complete the rep.  So what&amp;rsquo;s the deal with this email?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gandi is asking me to delete the spf1 record for elasticemail. Now this might have a negative impact on our newsletter sending but I guess I should just go ahead since we won&amp;rsquo;t be sending a newsletter for a while &amp;hellip; I scanned the text information on SPF and DKIM from Federico.  Not sure if we also need a DKIM but in the first instance I&amp;rsquo;ll do what Gandi instructs, removing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ 10800 IN TXT "v=spf1 a mx include:_spf.elasticemail.com ~all"
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and replacing it with &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ 10800 IN TXT "v=spf1 include:_mailcust.gandi.net ?all"
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so this will take up to 3 hours to propagate, and I should try a test of email sending after that.  Ah delayed feedback debugging, how I loathe thee :-)  And in the meantime I could try and follow Gandi&amp;rsquo;s other instructions to try and fix sending from sam@agileventures.org from my iPhone &amp;hellip; and that&amp;rsquo;s fixed now too, yay!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Email Failings</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/07/av-ecosystem-review-email-failings/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/07/av-ecosystem-review-email-failings/</id>
    <published>2017-09-07T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-03T21:23:40+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I think the main bleed in the AV ecosystem may now be some of the problems we are having with sending emails and them ending up in spam filters.  Hold that thought for a moment and I&amp;rsquo;ll just do my node/mocha/chai &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/tansaku/718547c89be1ef216dda4e973ea67075"&gt;athletic rep for the morning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I can afford to do that for a few mornings in a row and start exploring where I can speed up &amp;hellip;, but back to our email issues.  So we sent out 10 emails with a special offer (from support@agileventures.org) last week and as far as I can tell, every single one ended up in spam.  Annoyingly I have to go to slack to grab some info about it, but there&amp;rsquo;s not too much to distract me there today, phew.  So one person who got the email in their spam filter reported that they saw this message from Google:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot_2017-09-05-16-59-32.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The message is &amp;ldquo;Why is this message in Spam? It is in violation of Google&amp;rsquo;s recommended email sender guidelines.&amp;rdquo;.  This week we had a new Premium Mob member sign up and so far none of the emails from me via sam@agileventures.org appears to have arrived with them.  I also get warnings of authentication failures from hotmail for several emails I&amp;rsquo;ve sent over the last 6 months.  We need to get to the bottom of this.  Can I replicate the failure above (from gmail) and get more info on what&amp;rsquo;s failing &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I re-send one of the free trial emails and I find it in my gmail spam folder.  I thought I sent a test of this email and it got through to my sam@neurogrid.com account.  It did.  Anyway, I can now click through to &amp;ldquo;learn more&amp;rdquo; on the email to see why the message got marked as spam.  It links to https://support.google.com/mail/answer/81126?hl=en#authentication&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Why is it important to authenticate your messages?

Authentication ensures that your messages can be correctly classified. Emails that lack authentication are likely to be rejected or placed in the spam folder, given the high likelihood that they are forged messages used for phishing scams.

In addition, unauthenticated emails with attachments may be outrightly rejected, for security reasons.

To ensure that Gmail can identify you:

* Use a consistent IP address to send bulk mail.
* Keep valid reverse DNS records for the IP address(es) from which you send mail, pointing to your domain.
* Use the same address in the 'From:' header on every bulk mail you send.

We also recommend the following:

* Sign messages with DKIM. We do not authenticate messages signed with keys using fewer than 1024 bits.
* Publish an SPF record.
* Publish a DMARC policy.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now one thing I did do with these 10 message was adjust the From address to be &lt;code&gt;support@agileventures.org&lt;/code&gt; which Thunderbird allows me to do, but maybe that triggered Gmail&amp;rsquo;s spam filter.  That said, I&amp;rsquo;ve had problems just sending from sam@agileventures.org as well, so can that be the whole story? &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hotmail failures I have had are like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Feedback-Type: auth-failure
User-Agent: XMR/2.2
Version: 1.0
Original-Mail-From: &amp;lt;sam@agileventures.org&amp;gt;
Arrival-Date: Fri, 23 Jun 2017 10:02:07 -0700
Message-ID: &amp;lt;b6a7803d-c6ff-16cd-ed5f-e37569ef4ba5@agileventures.org&amp;gt;
Authentication-Results: hotmail.com; spf=softfail (sender IP is 217.70.183.196; identity alignment result is pass and alignment mode is relaxed) smtp.mailfrom=sam@agileventures.org; dkim=none (identity alignment result is pass and alignment mode is relaxed) header.d=agileventures.org; x-hmca=fail header.id=sam@agileventures.org
Source-IP: 217.70.183.196
Auth-Failure: spf
Reported-Domain: agileventures.org
DKIM-Domain: agileventures.org
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve sent off an email to Gandi:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hi Gandi,

We've been having trouble sending email from our domain agileventures.org, specifically from sam@agileventures.org which is a gandi mail account.  We are getting reports from hotmail (see below).  These are not bulk or spam email, but messages being sent to individual members of our charity from my Thunderbird email client.

I also note that I cannot send email from sam@agileventures.org from my iPhone, although I can receive.

Are there settings on Gandi's site, or even mail settings that we control that could be used to address these issues to ensure that email gets through?

Many thanks in advance

Best, Sam
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and I guess I will take another pass on this tomorrow, bring it up in the marketing meeting etc.  the funny thing is that hotmail failure messages have often been accompanied by delivery of the message as evidenced by sequences of replies and responses that I&amp;rsquo;m having with the people emailed &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
