<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Passing a Threshold</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/01/23/passing_a_threshold/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/01/23/passing_a_threshold/</id>
    <published>2017-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-08T12:02:21+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I collapsed with my cold after lunch on Friday and didn&amp;rsquo;t wake up until after the &amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum time.  I cancelled the remaining meetings for the day and took it easy; doing a little light devops work on WebsiteOne and LocalSupport later in the evening.  I continued chewing the ginger and got a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep.  Sensibly I would have done nothing all weekend, but that often doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like an option as a parent.  If I just stayed in my bed all weekend my kids would tear the house and each other up, and my wife would be driven to distraction.  I pulled myself out of bed to run my boys football (soccer) training session and then take my eldest to guitar and do the food shopping for the week.  I replaced the 2pm &amp;ldquo;Bob Martin&amp;rdquo; scrum with a text version and got another good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep before driving my kids across town for their league match on Sunday and got a good Premium session in with Michael on Sunday afternoon.  Weekend accomplished!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cold is still dragging on, and I&amp;rsquo;m working from bed today, and fingers crossed all the zinc from the ginger is shortening its duration.  Am I completely crazy?  Or just a workaholic father?  If I was salaried and could take a paid sick day I would, but I passed a threshold this weekend.  I went ahead and booked our summer trip to Japan, and came face to face with the depleted state of our finances.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been gradually working through our savings over the course of the last year, and although AgileVentures is bringing in around £1000 a month that&amp;rsquo;s nowhere near enough to cover my time and money investment.  If we could double that I could just about cover our living expenses.  Realistically I need four times that to be fixing up the problems with our house and putting something by for retirement.  Not that AgileVentures is my sole source of income - even though I haven&amp;rsquo;t actualy taken any income from AV yet - just putting everything in the bank for the moment.  I get dribs and drabs from other bits of consulting work, but there&amp;rsquo;s nothing regular at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a great year.  We&amp;rsquo;ve got AgileVentures to a new level of activity.  We&amp;rsquo;ve got recognized as an official charity.  We&amp;rsquo;ve been on Ruby Rogues, and we&amp;rsquo;ve got a corporate sponsor, as well as a chunk of income from Premium memberships.  Still, something has to change now, at least as far as my personal finances are going.  We had only one additional Premium signup in January, and a couple of downgrades.  Most people are tightening their belts in January and February after festive binges, so it isn&amp;rsquo;t too surprising if things will be slow till Spring hits us, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to start devoting increasing amounts of time to non-AgileVentures consulting work.  It&amp;rsquo;s not the end of the road.  There are some important meetings today.  There&amp;rsquo;s the possibility of some paid-work from our corporate sponsor, and a meeting with UCBerkeley/edX which will determine the flow of the MOOC this year, and there&amp;rsquo;s potential profit share there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a traditional corporate job maybe I could just take a sick day today, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got online meetings with people in several different timezones, some of which have taken months to arrange.  I guess one choice would be to just pack it all in, say it was nice while it lasted, but from today I devote myself full time to getting some closed-source corporate job for whatever.  That&amp;rsquo;s difficult to do when I love doing what I do for AgileVentures (blogging, coding, helping, reviewing, supporting folks).  Maybe that $10,000 a month AdWords grant from Google will make all the difference, but I&amp;rsquo;ve just had an email about technical issues with my account for the third time in a row!  So frustrating!  Here&amp;rsquo;s the email:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for submitting your AdWords Express account for review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The account you submitted is affected by a technical issue and cannot be activated for Ad Grants. In order to become a Grantee, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to create a new account and submit it for review. Please read the directions below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;***PLEASE NOTE: When you create a new AdWords/AdWords Express  account, you must choose a different email address than you used for your initial account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please create a new account, by following the relevant account creation guides below:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AdWords Express Account Creation Guide: https://support.google.com/grants/answer/6077396?hl=en&amp;amp;ref_topic=6077566&amp;amp;rd=1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the submission process for your country and reapply here: https://support.google.com/grants/answer/46115 - Select your country in the drop-down menu and follow the directions. Once you submit your new AdWords Express account for review, our team will re-review it and send you a follow up email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Google Ad Grants Team &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had this email for my tansaku@gmail.com account, then again for a new marketing@agileventures.org account, and then now a second time for marketing@agileventures.org where I started completely from scratch, re-applying for Google non-profit status from the beginning with marketing@agileventures.org.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the phone with Google support twice.  I want to be spending time with marketing, and fixing up the site to help get more Premium users.  But first I guess I will have to do this dance with Google again.  How many more hours will it be navigating their system before it&amp;rsquo;s not worth it?  Difficult to say.  $10,000 AdWords budget a month sounds great - the ad draft I put in predicted it would generate 100,000 or so impressions a month and 1000 click throughs.  That sounds good, but how many of those will we convert to Premium members or sponsors?  I&amp;rsquo;ll keep bashing away and let you know &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pxYvATQy2lo"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Under the Weather</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/01/20/under-the-weather/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/01/20/under-the-weather/</id>
    <published>2017-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-07T13:28:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I have mixed feelings.  I&amp;rsquo;m frustrated to be &amp;ldquo;under the weather&amp;rdquo;; my throat has swollen up and I feel exhausted.  A cold I guess.  I&amp;rsquo;m chewing my way through a ton of raw ginger.  I keep chunks in a little plastic pot so that I can pretty much chew it continuously.  Chewing the ginger releases a kind of juice that runs down my throat and takes the sting out of the soreness.  I have half a theory that the Zinc in the ginger also gives the cold virus a hard time, but perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s just my imagination :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt the sore throat coming on last night as I sat hacking away at a couple of WebSiteOne pull requests on my laptop while my kids were doing their Karate class.  I&amp;rsquo;d finished a couple of days of talk prep for the remote DevOps conference, and it was nice to get back to some coding. The DevOps talk was at 9:15pm that evening.  I managed to get the kids to bed, and gave the talk despite starting to lose my voice.  It seemed to go off reasonably well - some good questions and a nice chat with some attendees in Slack afterwards.  Such a relief to have it all done, particularly given that I&amp;rsquo;m now propped up in bed, chewing more ginger; a scarf wrapped around my neck.  I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to postpone the one real world meeting I have today, so in principle I can take it easy and give my body a chance to fight the cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suck pretty badly at &amp;ldquo;taking it easy&amp;rdquo;.  Given the laptop I can work from my sick bed, as I&amp;rsquo;ve done many times in the past.  A logical part of my brain might be reasoning that if I just rest and do no work all day then I might get back to full health sooner, but I find it really difficult to let go of my personal commitments, such as writing a blog post like this every work day.  In my experience it pretty much takes me a week to get over a cold, once I&amp;rsquo;ve been hit by that wall of lethargy.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t had a really nasty cold this last year if memory serves, and the last couple in early Autumn were pretty mild, so all in all I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t complain too much :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I seem to remember reading something about how sometimes your immune system will tip over and force the body to rest by flooding it with certain chemicals.  I can&amp;rsquo;t find the reference right now, but that seems to explain my experience of colds.  Sometimes I just have a blocked nose and a scratchy throat, but I can basically keep going; unpleasant as I find the symptoms.  Other times I just feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve been knocked down.  I&amp;rsquo;ve always found those latter types of colds and flus frustrating, as there&amp;rsquo;s always plenty I want to get done.  I could have given my DevOps talk a miss last night in order to get to bed earlier, but after all the work I&amp;rsquo;d done to push myself to get the slides sorted, and videos of draft runs of the talk circulated so I could get feedback; I couldn&amp;rsquo;t bear the thought of putting that off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll take a little longer for me to recover from the cold as a result, difficult to tell.  More frustrating in some ways will be if I&amp;rsquo;m not well enough to run the football coaching session I have for my Under 8 soccer team tomorrow.  My hope is that by getting some rest today, I&amp;rsquo;ll be up for that tomorrow.  I&amp;rsquo;ve managed those on a cold before, if I have a sufficient supply of ginger.  I&amp;rsquo;m also struggling with my supposed healthy left knee i.e. not the one that was operated on. The new physio exercises I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing seemed to first put my back out and then my left knee.  Hopefully they did do some good to my right knee, recovering as it is from ACL surgery;  I&amp;rsquo;m probably doing the physio too vigorously as usual.  However listening to &lt;a href="https://www.greaterthancode.com/podcast/episode-009-travis-b-hartwell/"&gt;GreaterThanCode&lt;/a&gt; this morning put all my minor troubles into perspective as Travis Hartell talked about his coding career and managing his chronic kidney condition with ongoing dialysis.  In the podcast they mentioned &lt;a href="https://butyoudontlooksick.com/articles/written-by-christine/the-spoon-theory/"&gt;Spoon Theory&lt;/a&gt; as a metaphor for explaining how people living with disabilities or chronic conditions might have less spoonfuls of energy to get through their day.  There was further talk about the appropriateness of other groups using the same term to talk about their experience of energy in daily life independently of any chronic conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all seems pretty tricky to work out what might and might not cause offence.  I certainly have days where I have more and less energy. It feels really tricky to compare how difficult life is for different people on a daily basis.  There are so many different types of struggle; mental health issues, diseases, chronic conditions, trying to pay the rent, prejudice, trying to raise a family.  Might someone be offended by one of the items in that list?  Is an economic struggle harder or easier than a mental health struggle?  Is that comparing apples and oranges?  For some reason I&amp;rsquo;m often thinking about how in London the rents are so expensive that for many people the majority of their salary goes on their accomodation costs and how hard that must be for those commuting into the center each day to keep a roof over their heads.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On reflection I think we all have privileged insight into our own pain.  It&amp;rsquo;s maybe generally true that we are much more closely acquainted with how difficult our own struggle is, compared to the struggles of others.  It&amp;rsquo;s probably a good step to admit that others may well be struggling harder than ourselves.  Ironically, while we may acknowledge that intellectually, day to day we still have special access into the intensity of our own struggle.  I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of this quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be kind because everyone is fighting a great battle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attributed to the Scottish thelogian &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ian_Maclaren"&gt;Ian Mclaren&lt;/a&gt;.  It&amp;rsquo;s often quite unpleasant when a conversation tips into a struggle to demonstrate who is struggling most.  However hard we feel that our own struggle is, I think we need to keep bringing ourselves back to acknowledging that ultimately we don&amp;rsquo;t know, and will never truely know, just how hard a struggle others are facing.  We can imagine, speculate, guess, but things that are hard for some people are a joy for others and vice versa.  Maybe there are some things like bereavement, illness etc. that would be universally acknowledged as unpleasant but this brings me back to the parable of &amp;ldquo;Maybe &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a Taoist story of an old farmer who had worked his crops for many years. One day his horse ran away. Upon hearing the news, his neighbors came to visit. &amp;ldquo;Such bad luck,&amp;rdquo; they said sympathetically. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe,&amp;rdquo; the farmer replied. The next morning the horse returned, bringing with it three other wild horses. &amp;ldquo;How wonderful,&amp;rdquo; the neighbors exclaimed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe,&amp;rdquo; replied the old man. The following day, his son tried to ride one of the untamed horses, was thrown, and broke his leg. The neighbors again came to offer their sympathy on his misfortune.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe,&amp;rdquo; answered the farmer.The day after, military officials came to the village to draft young men into the army. Seeing that the son&amp;rsquo;s leg was broken, they passed him by. The neighbors congratulated the farmer on how well things had turned out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe,&amp;rdquo; said the farmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;from &lt;a href="http://www.katinkahesselink.net/tibet/zen.html"&gt;http://www.katinkahesselink.net/tibet/zen.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the question Steve Hagen (author of &amp;ldquo;Buddhism Plain and Simple&amp;rdquo;) asks is when do we think the story ends &amp;hellip; &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Punch Drunk</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/01/19/punch-drunk/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/01/19/punch-drunk/</id>
    <published>2017-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-07T13:28:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Feeling pretty rough today, like someone&amp;rsquo;s been punching me in the head for a while.  Reasonably productive day yesterday.  Got to bed at 10:30pm, but my &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; knee was starting to ache from the new physio exercises I&amp;rsquo;m doing for my &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; knee.  I couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep - eventually I was listening to Todd Barry standup on Spotify to get me off to sleep.  Ideally of course I&amp;rsquo;d be using my powers of meditation to effortlessly drift off to sleep, but when my mind gets stuck on money worries, or re-hashing the complexities of past social interactions that haven&amp;rsquo;t gone so well, I run out of patience and reach for audio comedy.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the background the remote DevOps conference started, and since I was trying to multi-task with all the usual family and AgileVentures activities I only managed to attend one talk.  That was in the waiting room in a leisure centre while my boys did an academy football (soccer) class.  I love the concept of remote conferences.  This one would be easier for me if the schedule was in UTC; DevOps RemoteConf is running seven hours behind me in US mountain time.  It also makes me reflect on the value of a physical face to face conference in that it takes you out of your day to day routine and clears some space to focus on other stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was really pleased to see Chuck had set up a Slack instance for the conference, and I joined all the channels for each talk.  The activity in the Slack instance so far hasn&amp;rsquo;t been high - it&amp;rsquo;s frustrating that Slack isn&amp;rsquo;t also the chat used in the sessions themselves.  I think that if everyone watching the talk was automatically in the Slack channel it would help connect people, and then there&amp;rsquo;d be a stored history of any questions that got asked in the session themselves.  I was pleased to be able to use the Slack channel to ask Arthur Hicken about his talk &amp;ldquo;Evolving from Automated to Continuous Testing for Agile and DevOps&amp;rdquo;.  I asked him if he had any thoughts on how we can make sure that tests are really testing the right thing, rather than being tests that would pass even if the functionality was removed.  Having the slack meant that I continue to have the transcript of the conversation to refer back to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="chat with Arthur" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/r1mqm9j3crvdmtl/Screenshot%202017-01-19%2009.59.39.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arthur was suggesting having comments like @PR12345 to associate bits of code with a requirement.  I felt that might introduce a linkage between test and code that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t give us the implementation flexibility we might want, but even just having the conversation I found some Ruby mutation apps that might be interesting to use.   The round-table discussion that I would really like to have joined was taking place at midnight my time, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really practical given my schedule and how badly I perform on little sleep :-/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got my talk coming up later today at 9:15pm my time.  Hopefully I can stay awake for it :-)  I&amp;rsquo;ve had some good feedback on the draft version.  Giving the talk into a YouTube live stream and then sharing the video link really makes so much sense.  One suggestion was to write out the transcript and then read it back.  That has been the way I have slowed myself down and made myself comprehensible in the past.  Not sure that I have the luxury of doing that today.  I have done it with the half hour chunks of stuff in the AV102 course.  Reading my own edited monologue back from a teleprompter really is the way to make myself understandble to a wider range of folks, let&amp;rsquo;s see &amp;hellip; maybe some coffee can get me over this punch-drunk feeling &amp;hellip;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J7EycNcfH3A"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HMcU42Jy8X4"&gt;Draft talk on DevOps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kqTSgFLLaEw"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog took 21 minutes to write&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Coding vs. Admin</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/01/18/coding-vs-admin/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/01/18/coding-vs-admin/</id>
    <published>2017-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-07T13:28:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pat was commenting that my recent blogs don&amp;rsquo;t have so many technical deep dives and are more admin focused.  That&amp;rsquo;s probably a reflection that I&amp;rsquo;m doing less coding and more admin recently.  I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a couple of hours over the last few days trying to hook up the Google NonProfits AdWords grant, which will apparently give us up to $10,000 a month in AdWords funding.  An exciting prospect, but it&amp;rsquo;s taken me several admin hours to file the application on the right email address - go round the houses with Google online help suppport etc.  This week I&amp;rsquo;m also trying to get ready for a presentation at the DevOps conference, which sucks up time, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s enabled me to get the NewRelic monitoring setup on WebSiteOne correctly, and identify the source of strange health check activity on the LocalSupport servers.  The latter seems to be an artifact of using legacy NewRelic monitoring tools - time to upgrade!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did however manage to snatch a chunk of time to do WebSiteOne devops.  The bug fix to prevent un-recorded YouTube links being tweeted was stuck on staging since we had stubbed the mock incorrectly.  While we waited for that fix some other PRs had piled up and I&amp;rsquo;d merged in our refactoring the Premium plans to support easier creation of new plans.  I rebased all the latest code from develop into staging, which finally worked smoothly since I&amp;rsquo;d previously merged the production fixes from last year back down to develop.  All the new functionality worked as expected on staging with me running the set of rake tasks that went along with the various new bits of code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ heroku run rake fetch_github_commits -r production
$ heroku run rake db:create_plans -r production
$ heroku run rake db:migrate_plans -r production
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still had to manually test the Hangouts/Twitter interaction.  It occurs to me that we might be better off with things that are being merged into develop following a faster cycle into staging and production, rather than allowing them to bunch up.  I guess the difficulty is the complexity of setting up individual developers to be able to manually test all the 3rd party hookups.  Perhaps with automated deploy from drie that will change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I did immediately notice was that the language in the tweets coming from the staging server was odd:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="odd language in tweets" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/6s33zipjbpj1e8o/Screenshot%202017-01-17%2015.34.10.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of the latest changes we now only tweeted a link to the YouTube once the host had clicked the &amp;ldquo;start broadcast&amp;rdquo; button in the hangout and the YouTube video was reporting a non-nil &lt;code&gt;actual_start_time&lt;/code&gt; via the API.  However the language in the tweet said that the session had finished, when clearly it was potentially still ongoing.  I groaned as I thought about needing to make another change before we could push this out, but talking it over with Michael in the scrum I realised that this was an existing bug.  That&amp;rsquo;s not to say we don&amp;rsquo;t need to fix it, just that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to hold things up to get the original bug fix out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original setup (as had been running for the last year or so) is that as soon as the server receives a notification from the Hangout plugin that the hangout has successfully started, the server automatically tweets both a link to the hangout (with text saying the session has started) and a link to the YouTube video saying the session has finished.  The original bug-report from Thomas was that some of the YouTube links were duds.  We&amp;rsquo;re pretty sure that this is due either to those situations where no one starts the broadcast/recording, or there&amp;rsquo;s a technical fail on YouTube.  So we have fixed the bug where we would tweet unrecorded sessions, but in the process highlighted other inconsistencies in the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;rsquo;s not such a big deal, because as soon as the recordings do finish the wording will be correct for the rest of the lifetime of the tweets.  Not that anyone is necessarily paying attention to our Twitter feed (although I do notice more and more followers stacking up recently), but anyone paying close attention would think that all scrums and pairing sessions shut down pretty soon after they start.  At least with our latest fix, anyone reviewing the tweets a few hours after the fact will encounter fewer dead YouTube links so that&amp;rsquo;s probably a good thing.  Having said that we&amp;rsquo;ve got no evidence that our Twitter feed is a source of any value for our organisation, specifically we only get a couple of click throughs to the site and from Twitter a month (that said, perhaps we should more closely check out YouTube referrals, and maybe auto add a shortened AV link to all our tweets - maybe rather than redirecting to YouTube we should post links to the videos embedded in our site?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on this bug has been an interesting learning experience.  It&amp;rsquo;s included myself, Sasha, Matt, and Michael and we&amp;rsquo;ve covered all sorts of interesting topics related to BDD, 3rd party APIs, mocking, caching, testing etc.  However since we may lose the entire Hangout plugin in April, it does make me wonder if we&amp;rsquo;ve just been rearranging the deckchairs on a tiny portion of the system that&amp;rsquo;s unlikely to have any significant impact on our sustainability.  My mind leans towards adjusting the site to have a stronger call to action on the front page, e.g. to sign up as a member and then ultimately upgrade to Premium, as being something that might have stronger chance of impacting our sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Matt started looking at a new feature the other day I suggested that maybe we should look at some bug-fixes first.  Together we managed to get to the bottom of the Slack invite bug, which strangely seemed to be just a missing setting on production, which in principle saves me a few minutes each week spent inviting new users into Slack.  Anyhow, given that we&amp;rsquo;ve got all this tweeting code adjusted through strenuous effort, the priority must be to get these latest changes to out onto production.  There&amp;rsquo;s one other minor fix that could be done first, but I&amp;rsquo;ve created a ticket for it.  I think we need to experience any pain from the collection of new changes rather than holding off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s smoothing the upgrade process to the different levels of Premium that&amp;rsquo;s really going to make the difference to sustainability?  Or the next admin task that will unlock some more funding?  I guess I just keep swapping between coding and admin-ing in turn until it all becomes sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V2KfoeCcp-o"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yc4c0QL8Efg"&gt;WSO DevOps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h3b5Og-umnU"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog took 20 minutes to write&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Server Monitoring</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/01/17/server-monitoring/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/01/17/server-monitoring/</id>
    <published>2017-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-07T13:28:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m still forcing myself to think about DevOps in preparation for my talk on Thursday.  Other things being equal I&amp;rsquo;d be blogging about our new marketing activities and how Google will potentially give us $10,000 a month of AdWords, and how there might be similar, if less generous, offers from other social media sites.  However, it felt great yesterday when I managed to complete a first draft of the slides for the talk.  There&amp;rsquo;s still a little something missing though; the performance requirements for the different systems.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I do know from the metrics we get from Heroku on WebSiteOne is that we regularly exceed our 500MB memory allowance, although the site performance doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem too horrible.  We&amp;rsquo;ve gone in and fixed particularly slow loads on the users, projects and event pages, as well as had a stab at removing gems that seem to be eating up a lot of memory.  We&amp;rsquo;ve improved page load times, but not managed to get the memory usage down.  We could pay to upgrade to the next Heroku tier to get 1GB of memory, but the site performance seems superficially okay - and no one is explicitly complaining about it.  We know that pages need to load as fast as possible in order for people to spend any time on the site. Greater than 4 seconds is likely a big turnoff these days.  The front page appears in about 1.2 seconds when I refresh in Chrome.  Of course it would be slower if not cached.  In incognito mode the entire front page loads in about 2.6 seconds.  That seems acceptable, but I do have a reasonably fast mac.  It might be the case that other folks around the world are experiencing poor performance and we&amp;rsquo;re not aware of it &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like NewRelic wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually enabled on WebSiteOne production.  The code was all set up, but the NEW RELIC key wasn&amp;rsquo;t in the production settings.  I&amp;rsquo;ve added that now so perhaps we&amp;rsquo;ll see some interesting data.  NewRelic is all set up for LocalSupport, where we can see an overview of the web transaction times:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="NewRelic data from HarrowCN production" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/myb72nmofhmm7lg/Screenshot%202017-01-17%2010.22.04.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ping requests haven&amp;rsquo;t been working for the last 12 days, and aren&amp;rsquo;t working from the command line either, but the site is up and it looks like pages are being served okay.  I can see a couple of page loads that failed in the last seven days, which is probably acceptable for this low traffic site.  Even if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to go from that failure to a fix.  Superficially it would just mean provisioning more dyno or more memory.  At the moment LocalSupport is on a legacy dyno from Heroku, meaning we aren&amp;rsquo;t getting metrics on memory usage as we are for WebSiteOne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing this, the NewRelic data on WebSiteOne has started coming in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="NewRelic data from WSO production" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/s5x799dlbdx4l7z/Screenshot%202017-01-17%2010.28.42.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes it look like there was at least one frustrated request in the last half an hour at least.  That makes me think fixing our memory issues on WSO might be higher priority.  Looks like some kind of active record lookup was getting stuck &amp;hellip; Going back to HarrowCN, it seems like I can embed a &lt;a href="https://rpm.newrelic.com/public/charts/7odyrRrzsqR"&gt;feed of the throughput&lt;/a&gt; in an iframe:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="HarrowCN throughput" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/zzyev88mr4orwbn/Screenshot%202017-01-17%2010.33.07.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baseline requests look like some sort of healthcheck is going on, rather than it being representative of human users &amp;hellip; more investigation required.  I wonder if that&amp;rsquo;s a side effect of NewRelic or some other pinging service we&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten about?  Anyhow, I want to get deeper into this for both WSO and HarrowCN (and AutoGraders/MetPlus) to flesh out what I can say about the usage of our systems in my talk on Thursday.  Let&amp;rsquo;s see how far I get &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hosting Costs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/01/16/hosting-costs/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/01/16/hosting-costs/</id>
    <published>2017-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-07T13:28:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s lots I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about.  Premium pairing on new non-profit IT support plans, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P66oJafqqng"&gt;helping Kenyan students get started with LocalSupport&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zrz6ct9wIUs"&gt;meeting with the LocalSupport client&lt;/a&gt;, deploying LocalSupport via the new drie push Github interface, mob programming on the Hash#fetch method, but I&amp;rsquo;m presenting my talk on &amp;ldquo;DevOps on a Budget&amp;rdquo; on Thursday, so things have got to be DevOps pricing focused :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m torn between focusing the presentation on the costings and the actual process of DevOps I&amp;rsquo;m doing on AV projects that I blogged about last week.  The talk summary is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover how we&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping our hosting costs down at the AgileVentures online IT and Education charity over the last 4 years, touching on how we&amp;rsquo;ve been using Heroku, AWS and other less well known services like NineFold and drie. In particular we&amp;rsquo;ll look at how we manage DevOps in an ever changing team of volunteer participants. We&amp;rsquo;ll also cover our migration from Heroku to Ninefold and back again when Ninefold went bust, and our most recent ongoing migration from Heroku to drie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the key thing is to get down some of that narrative about how our longest running project has been managed from a DevOps point of view over the years.  A quick trip to to Google Analytics showed me a slightly perplexing view of the traffic to the site over the last 2 years that we&amp;rsquo;ve been tracking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Harrow Community Network users" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/zrhi3tit04i44s0/Screenshot%202017-01-16%2009.42.25.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site traffic was an order of magnitude heavier in 2015, and I can&amp;rsquo;t really think of an explanation other than some sort of error relating to analytics of some service pinging the site that shut down.  Throughout 2016 we&amp;rsquo;ve had about 300 visitors a month, which seems about right.  I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine why 2015 would have seen such high traffic.  In contrast WebSiteOne has been much more consistent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="AgileVentures site users" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/p5inkiun3j1993r/Screenshot%202017-01-16%2009.45.43.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extra challenge with the Harrow Community Network site has generally stemmed from needing https for logins to ensure they are secure.  Arguably this is an issue for every site, but the AgileVentures site handles login via GitHub and G+ which have their own security.  As a cash strapped NonProfit with clients who also have limited resources we were looking at ways of affording the extra fees for setting up SSL certificates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Slack archive and meeting notes shows me that we had got prototypes of the main site on Heroku in early February 2014.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before we&amp;rsquo;d realised that Heroku SSL suport would lead to a recurring monthly fee, and so the site was only very briefly on Heroku (3 months) before we&amp;rsquo;d switched to NineFold. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started investigating &lt;a href="http://ninefold.com/"&gt;NineFold&lt;/a&gt; as an alternative to Heroku in April 2014, when a member of our community working for NineFold indicated we might be able to get a grant from NineFold to cover the hosting costs.  We went live on NineFold in May 2014, but it was less than a year before we were forced to switch back to Heroku due to NineFold sunsetted their Rails hosting solution in March 2015.  We&amp;rsquo;d gotten almost a years free SSL support from NineFold, although that did inadvertently charge my credit card a couple of times.  Talking it through with them I got a refund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have emails from April 2015 about moving our data back from NineFold to Heroku, and getting SSL certificates set up.  At that point Heroku gave us a $100 grant towards the costs of the SSL certificates.  Importing the data back was problematic, and ultimately fixed by using a binary dump with schema AND data and reseting the db before doing the restore operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NineFold&amp;rsquo;s command line interface had been slightly different to Heroku&amp;rsquo;s and had taken a little getting used to.  The deployment was not too difficult, and we had a NineFold person giving us technical support directly in our Slack instance. There had been a fair amount of fiddling around to create valid SSL certificates through a third party provider. Overall it was an interesting experience to have migrated a site from one provider to another; which mainly involved being familiar with PostGres import and export tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving back to Heroku, the free SSL certificate provider I&amp;rsquo;d used for NineFold was no longer operating, and the client was now willing to take on some hosting costs.  At the time I was also just contributing to AgileVentures part time and so the Heroku Expedited SSL solution was very attractive, so we went for that and have been billing the client $35 a month since then.  Ironically SSL is now free on custom domains on Heroku, but to get off the limited hours free tier we need to pay $7 a month, and we need to keep the staging and develop instances running so we could switch over to the new dynos and take the costs down to $21 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re also looking seriously at moving to drie, who have a low cost hosting service called &amp;ldquo;drie push&amp;rdquo;.  One of the advantages of drie is automatic availability of hosted versions of all the branches in ones&amp;rsquo; git repo.  Early on we linked things up for HarrowCN like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;master branch &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; https://www.harrowcn.org.uk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;staging branch &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; http://staging.harrowcn.org.uk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop branch &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; http://develop.harrowcn.org.uk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having that kind of mapping automatically available from the start of the project is very appealing, but after the experience with NineFold we are cautious about moving to a new service provider.  However drie also has a tighter GitHub integration than Heroku allowing us to add drie as a GitHub integration and deploy directly by pushing to any repo branch.  Heroku can be set up to do this, but their &amp;ldquo;build on PRs&amp;rdquo; functionality creates more instances that we have to pay for.  drie has a different model that sleeps apps more aggressively and so their free tier goes further than that of Heroku.  We&amp;rsquo;re also excited about being able to use GitHub&amp;rsquo;s team interface system rather than Heroku&amp;rsquo;s; since Heroku is also charging extra for the use of the team interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NiXjhjaTTCk"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zrz6ct9wIUs"&gt;LocalSupport Client Meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ToV8wt9sr8w"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VOnol6QAaeg"&gt;Saturday &amp;ldquo;Bob Martin&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P66oJafqqng"&gt;Sunday &amp;ldquo;Bob Martin&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. Full disclosure, AgileVentures has received financial grants from Heroku and NineFold in the past, and drie is an ongoing sponsor of the AgileVentures charity. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
