<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>All Good Things ...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/</id>
    <published>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-10T21:54:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="good things" src="/images/good_things.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been daily blogging for a year now.  Working day blogs that is.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging on weekends, or national holidays, or during my vacations.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty consistent.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of days where work was super busy due to the tail end of a design sprint or something, but I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to retro-actively blog and keep it one per work day.  I started blogging in June last year doing a blog on a different platform each day of the week, but fairly soon I fell into a pattern of blogging to our AgileVentures middleman site, and then re-releasing to Medium after I&amp;rsquo;d got a little distance from the blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the purpose of this blog frenzy?  My memory is that it was about trying to communicate more effectively.  I often end up assuming that people understand my thoughts and intentions and it turns out that actually they don&amp;rsquo;t.  Of course why would they?  There are few telepaths around.  I&amp;rsquo;m also a bit of a gabbler and my sense is that it&amp;rsquo;s not super easy to understand what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to communicate.  So blogging, get all the thoughts down in text, provide them in an accessible form for everyone to read, and maybe reduce my need to gabble on and on about things.  Win win, no?  There&amp;rsquo;s also the motivation that blogging at the start of each day is a kind of &amp;ldquo;morning pages&amp;rdquo; activity such as writers use to start off their days and clear their heads.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think writers usually publish their morning brain dump, but I have certainly found the process of starting each day with writing out my thoughts to be reassuring and relaxing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year when I was doing a lot more coding, the blogs tended to be all about the previous day&amp;rsquo;s coding.  As AgileVentures became an official charity and my admin load increased, they have tended to be about prioritization.  Starting the day with a blog is certainly less stressful than starting the day with a review of email and Slack conversations, which will generally lead to many adds to my ever-increasing todo list.  Has the time been well spent?  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had positive reactions to some blogs, but my sense is that the blogs are too long, too stream-of-consciousness, too un-focused to gain much traction.  I think I may have even alienated some with my uncensored and unedited thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was 17 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had trouble just generating text, and from even earlier I was always a talker.  It&amp;rsquo;s like my internal thought wheel is hooked up directly to my mouth, and at will I can hook it up to a pen or a keyboard and just dump my thoughts straight out, for better or for worse.  So I rarely have writer&amp;rsquo;s block, but it leaves me with a different problem.  How to edit the thicket of thoughts and ideas, so as to more effectively communicate them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to the end of a year of blogging prompts thoughts of changing things going forward.  There&amp;rsquo;ve been times in the past when rising early I&amp;rsquo;ve done 3 hours of programming before breakfast.  After recent design sprints I think about doing coding sprints, or other activities that fill the week in different ways.  Should it be one blog a week with the blog being edited and revised each day, so that a single polished blog can be released on Friday?  I guess it all depends on what one wants to achieve, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t the Buddhist in me been trying to follow a path of consecrated action, where one is totally unattached to the outcomes of activities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d have loved my blogs to have provoked more positive responses of &amp;ldquo;yes, let&amp;rsquo;s build a solution to that together &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, although there has been some of that.  What I really would like is for AgileVentures to be a healthy thriving community providing great learning experiences for many, while also helping charitable causes around the world.  The process of reflection over the last year does make me think that we&amp;rsquo;re far too text heavy in many, many parts of our interface with the world.  One of the most attractive ideas for me going forward is that I&amp;rsquo;d spend my blogging time each day focused on a part of the main AgileVentures site, converting it from text heavy to text light and adding images.  I have a hunch that, by doing this in strategic places throughout the site, we could improve the sign up rates, the number of members joining projects and the numbers signing up for Premium subscriptions, the source of our financial sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a feeling I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to shake the blogging habit.  The process has become too solidly part of my daily routine.  The thing that actually gets me started and ready to work in the mornings.  So, anyhow, starting tomorrow, blogs that focus on parts of the main AgileVentures site.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to work through it one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog released early for inclusion in our July newsletter, earlier blogs are all in draft form in GitHub and will be on this site soon&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Private Design Sprint Day Five</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/03/private-design-sprint-day-five/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/03/private-design-sprint-day-five/</id>
    <published>2017-07-03T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-26T21:48:06+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a frenetic last day but we managed to run usability tests with five different people.  I had to reach out to my personal network to fill all the slots, as well as stretching out of the precise demographic range that we had targeted, but I think we managed to conduct five really meaningful sessions.  The tech setup also worked pretty well with FaceTime and YouTube streams from hangouts, although probably it would have been better to have the observers joining the hangouts - then again that could have just made things that little more complicated.  We started the interviews from 10am, and we definitely needed that 9am-10am period to get settled in.  In the book they suggest starting the interviews from 9am, but for that to work I think one really has to have had a run through session on the Thursday, and in my experience so far the tail end of Thursday is spent frantically working on the demo app itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe even greater proficiency with the prototyping tools might address that, but there&amp;rsquo;s so much room for something not to work on the Thursday.  Maybe larger sprint teams are the key.  The sprints I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in have had small teams.  There&amp;rsquo;s also the location issue.  I can see the whole thing really working best when you have a company that has a dedicated physical space that they&amp;rsquo;re comfortable working in and there aren&amp;rsquo;t a load of logistical issues to get sorted.  Starting the interviews at 10am meant that they ran back to back with 30 minute breaks.  Also most of the team needed to leave soon afterwards so we didn&amp;rsquo;t get time for the sort of review that I&amp;rsquo;d have liked.  There was lots of interesting discussion during the breaks, and the reactions to the demo system were pretty solidly positive.  The decider wasn&amp;rsquo;t so happy with the final design that emerged, but ultimately I think we all agreed that we&amp;rsquo;d been able to get good positive feedback on some of the key conceptual elements that we were planning for the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a relief to get it all done.  I was exhausted, running all this while under the weather.  I had cancelled some of my Saturday activities (soccer coaching) to try and recover.  I fell asleep in a deck chair in the garden for two hours in the afternoon.  Even doing that is so slippery when you have a family.  It meant we ate supper late, I got indigestion and into a battle with my two youngest about completing their homework before playing computer games.  Sunday followed a somewhat similar pattern, with a dose of me stressing about online interactions with folks in AgileVentures.  I had hoped to start back into getting everything sorted out on Monday, but I woke up feeling like my cold had taken a retrograde step and ended up having to go back to bed for an hour; and even now am just easing myself back into the saddle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In principle it&amp;rsquo;s time to end my year of blogging and focus on upgrades to the AV site, as well as getting on with the various administrative and paperwork tasks that are needed to get a grip on the financial situation.  One step at a time I guess.  I have to pay back the health debt from last week for having pushed on with the design sprint when my body was arguing for a time out &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Private Design Sprint Day Four</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/30/private-design-sprint-day-four/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/30/private-design-sprint-day-four/</id>
    <published>2017-06-30T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-25T20:57:53+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m heading in to London on the train for day 5 following a frenetic day in London yesterday.  We got access to our space a little late, but proceeded to make good progress on the prototype with the designer cranking out a landscape, logo and background; and I got MarvelApp going through the gears to auto-play videos and provide the interactivity we needed.  The main snag was that the audio quality in the room we were in was not great and we needed to record of the order of ten short videos to make the prototype work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately we had to give up and head off to a different part of London where we could film quietly.  I was working illustrator in the back of a cab at one point.  There was debate about a change of approach, but ultimately we got it all done.  The editor got all the videos sorted out, and I linked them all in to the prototype.  I was up late, but woke early.  I&amp;rsquo;d also phoned and confirmed all the testers for the Friday, and knowing that we had real people showing up to use the app kept me going despite exhaustion and the tail end of my cold.  Design sprint Thursdays do seem to be the most frenetic and least pleasant.  The one in which tempers fray.  I wonder if the prototyping would be better off starting on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Private Design Sprint Day Three</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/29/private-design-sprint-day-three/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/29/private-design-sprint-day-three/</id>
    <published>2017-06-29T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-22T21:21:28+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m heading into London on the train for day 4 as we have a location switch for the last two days.  The last three days we&amp;rsquo;ve been in a somewhat remote location which would be difficult for testers to reach, so the last two days are in central London.  Yesterday (day 3) involved the usual art museum, heat maps and speed critiques of our three different prototype designs.  Given there were only three of us, there was plenty of time to discuss them, reflect on them and vote on them.  By lunch we&amp;rsquo;d ended up with most of the votes on my own design, and there seemed agreement that we were all pretty much on the same page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch we started storyboarding and it was clear that there was some confusion.  There was the issue of the extent to which our small prototype would reflect the operation of the rest of the site.  It had seemed that we had agreed on a particular prototyping approach by selecting a particular prototype, but there was concern from one member that what we prototyped wouldn&amp;rsquo;t reflect the overall site experience.  As we went back and forth, the terms &amp;ldquo;press-pack&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;trailer&amp;rdquo; floated out.  It came down to distinguishing between sites where the experience before you signed in reflected what you got once you were signed up, and those where that wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case.  Both valid approaches and their effectiveness dependent on the nature of your target demographic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a fairly long debate, but ultimately we settled on the prototype that was largely as I had envisioned.  Offering the user a small sense of one particular aspect of the site experience and seeing how they would react to that and to the idea that they&amp;rsquo;d need to sign up (and pay) to access more.  Ultimately we had our storyboard and agreement on our storyboard, and hopefully a shared understanding about what we would be achieving over the next two days.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Private Design Sprint Day Two</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/28/private-design-sprint-day-two/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/28/private-design-sprint-day-two/</id>
    <published>2017-06-28T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-21T21:31:32+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day two of our design sprint was a slightly calmer affair.  One member had left us since they couldn&amp;rsquo;t stay the whole week, so we were down to three on the sprint team.  I&amp;rsquo;d also come down with a head cold that was making me move and talk slower; probably a good thing for all concerned, but not very pleasant for me.  We spent the morning doing lightning demos, and then the afternoon sketching interface designs, &amp;ldquo;working alone together&amp;rdquo; as they say in the sprint book.  I got my interface sketch done fairly quickly and decided to move on to sorting out the screening survey and putting up an ad on Craigslist and Indeed to recruit testers for Friday.  I&amp;rsquo;ve woken up this morning to see that four people have applied so far, and probably there&amp;rsquo;s only one that meets our testing criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It occurs to me that recruiting people who have an hour free during the middle of a work day on Friday creates its own bias, in that one is unlikely to get lots of people who are in full time employment.  Challenging if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to test that demographic.  That&amp;rsquo;s not particularly the demographic we are looking for in this design sprint, but it seems inevitable that there&amp;rsquo;s some degree of skew there.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll have to supplement this week by distributing the ad through some of my personal networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to judge day two of the sprint, as we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen each other&amp;rsquo;s sketches yet; we&amp;rsquo;ll have to see if three is too small a number.  Certainly we had no shortage of lightning demos, and there was lots to learn from looking through all the different sites that the team members suggested.  Today we&amp;rsquo;ll be reviewing those sketch ideas and coming up with a storyboard for the prototype that we need to build on Thursday.  I wonder if I got into problem solving mode too early on day one, as my sketch is not wildly dissimilar from some of the components I was sketching on the map on Monday.  I guess rather than interface elements it would have been better to map interactions, drawing the person interacting with the computer, or talking to another person.  We&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, we&amp;rsquo;re changing location after today.  For logistical reasons we&amp;rsquo;re in one location Mon/Tues/Wed and then a different location Thu/Fri.  I&amp;rsquo;m quite pleased as Thu/Fri I&amp;rsquo;ll be closer to home, and I&amp;rsquo;m not particularly enjoying my current hotel-bound cold.  The cold is also making it difficult for me to focus on administrative matters that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to juggle around the design sprint, which pretty much blocks out the sun while it is running.  The nice thing about having a physical space and these table top flip charts is you can draw out large and then take them off and stick them on the wall, so we have the different sketches from our lightning demos etc. covering the walls of the room that we&amp;rsquo;re working in.  Perhaps ideally we&amp;rsquo;d still have these up on Thursday as we work on our prototype, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem completely critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing the AV design sprint online I think it&amp;rsquo;s quite important to have multiple monitors so that one can put up the different digital documents in multiple locations and use one&amp;rsquo;s physical space management skills, but so many people don&amp;rsquo;t seem to have a second or third monitor &amp;hellip; anyway, fascinating to contrast the online and in-person sprint.  There&amp;rsquo;s certainly an aspect of this that feels very marketing orientated, but I guess for any organisation to be successful it has to have the right communication &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Private Design Sprint Day One</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/27/private-design-sprint-day-one/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/27/private-design-sprint-day-one/</id>
    <published>2017-06-27T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-20T20:01:45+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in the Premier Inn restaurant again after day one of the sprint.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also come down with a cold which is not much fun.  Don&amp;rsquo;t really have time to write a blog, as I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be updating part 2 of the MOOC, but I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just take a few minutes to get down some reflections on yesterday&amp;rsquo;s day one of the design sprint.  We had four of us in person in a lovely room with an ocean view, and we used a couple of flipboard markers and whiteboard rolls (that stick on windows and walls and allow you to draw on them).  It seemed to go pretty well.  This was probably the closest I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten so far to a day one of Design Sprint as intended, with the exception that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have any expert interviews joining us, for one logistic reason and another.  We improvised there by taking turns to be experts and have each of us present the concepts to the rest of the group, and then all ask questions of the &amp;ldquo;expert&amp;rdquo;.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think we got the full benefit of outside input, but there was definitely some benefit derived from re-articulation of the idea from different perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first map we made was maybe too detailed.  I was almost drawing interface elements, and one of the other team members did a revised simpler map.  The maps in the book are really simple, but they look simplified for the purpose of the book compared with the whiteboards I&amp;rsquo;ve glimpsed in the videos from Google, but Pat did seem to criticise our overly complex map from the AV design sprint; so perhaps this is a pattern of poor behaviour on my part.  Looking back I think it might have been more effective to avoid interface elements completely and focus on interactions; drawing person at computer, person talking to other person as the elements of the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the slide deck from the GV site to introduce the sprint in the morning and that seemed to work quite well.  Everyone seemed happy with me as the facilitator and the main client being the decider.  My handwriting for the sprint questions was not outstanding, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how powerful they were for the rest of the sprint.  I guess they were re-articulated by the presenters in the afternoon.  Interestingly people started writing &amp;ldquo;how we might fail&amp;rdquo; questions on post-it notes and there was a process of integration as I re-wrote them.  The others didn&amp;rsquo;t join in the initial map drawing in the way that the AV folks did, collaborating in the drawing of the online map.  I did my best to map out what they were talking about, and it was great that they re-drew the map in simpler form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was interesting to see outbreaks of what might be called &amp;ldquo;argumentative&amp;rdquo; behaviour during the day.  Not in a negative sense, but more in a point and counterpoint, and point and counterpoint, that goes round and round.  I know I&amp;rsquo;ve been super guilty of this in the past, and it&amp;rsquo;s interesting being a facilitator and working out how to move on from those areas.  From one perspective when both people have made their points, the key thing is to record the positions and allow the process to move on to generate more ideas.  That can be derailed when both parties feel the need to explain their position further, falling into a kind of &amp;ldquo;No, but &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; where effectively the same point (with minor nuances) gets repeated.  Is it partly about having the last word.  Why do I (and many others) want that last word so much?  I&amp;rsquo;ve often felt that if someone makes a statement that I feel is incorrect, that if I don&amp;rsquo;t make the counterpoint then that&amp;rsquo;s the statement that&amp;rsquo;s being accepted by the room.  I guess I should trust people better that they won&amp;rsquo;t think just because someone said something last that it&amp;rsquo;s being accepted as truth.  Still it&amp;rsquo;s a difficult character flaw to let go of.  If someone makes a point and you have no comeback then it can seem like you are conceding the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fascinating to look at it from a third person point of view.  I can see how others can get frustrated with the debate where they feel they&amp;rsquo;ve heard both points of view in painful detail and just want to move on.   And it&amp;rsquo;s clear how a debate can block the floor and prevent other issues being raised, other ideas being heard &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
