<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Hangouts Filling Up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/14/hangouts-filling-up/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/14/hangouts-filling-up/</id>
    <published>2017-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-04-05T22:22:19+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="sprinting" src="/images/full.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday saw full hangouts for the &amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrums.  It was at least partly because SUNY Binghamton students were coming in to vote as part of their class assignment, but also the return of previous regulars such as Tong Wei and Raphael.  Also contributing was the running of the LocalSupport kick off in the latter scrum, which brought in three Kenyan developers.  Great to be having busy hangouts - allowing lots of new folks to see aspects of the Agile scrum process and planning poker with Arreche&amp;rsquo;s great Slack voting app. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s great to be able to support the students but it does come with a cost, and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty rare that university students who participate as part of an assignment will come back to contribute further, although perhaps I&amp;rsquo;m seeing the world without rose-tinted glasses today.  I feel a negative haze on my vision at the moment.  Nasty cough almost gone but dragging into a third week, beating myself up about subbing decisions when coaching the weekend football game, feeling like I should be able to awaken to the moment and drop the illusion on the self.  Scrabbling for grants for tiny amounts of money.  Working really hard but not earning any money.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least I&amp;rsquo;m feeling calmer - I&amp;rsquo;m not expecting AgileVentures to generate enough funds to support my family and I think we&amp;rsquo;re doing some great work.  The under-populated &amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrums are filling up as I associated a different project kick-off with each.  Also affecting my mood is rejection from Pragmatic Programmers on my book draft on &amp;ldquo;Agile Methods for Open Source Projects&amp;rdquo;.  I put a fair amount of effort to get what was originally a short chapter up to 5000 words.  I know that publishing a book is no ticket to financial stability, but it&amp;rsquo;s one additional route to push out the AgileVentures methodology.  There&amp;rsquo;s a model of how a loose and flexible Agile Scrum process can help Open Source projects grow and maintain quality, and for a while I was thinking a book on the subject might be the way to get it across, but perhaps we just need to bake it in to the user experience of AgileVentures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graghh!  I just want to code and scrum and generate systems for clients and work with them to understand if it&amp;rsquo;s really helping fix their problems, and I want to do it in an open fashion that allows everyone else in the world to see the process and join in.  I get to do that a little in AgileVentures, but increasingly my time is spent scrabbling for funding, and if we don&amp;rsquo;t land something soon I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to kick my paid job/contract search into a much higher gear.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bringing this back round to scrums, it was interesting that some new folks had difficulty even getting into Slack to vote on the stories with us.  They were using Slack via the web.  It&amp;rsquo;s funny for me with the desktop app installed, navigating to a Slack channel is trivial, but there&amp;rsquo;s a learning curve.  Even with a direct link to the relevant Slack channel in the chat in the hangout, one person got all tangled up trying to type out that link rather than clicking it, and several folks were stymied trying to work out how to join the channel on the spur of the moment.  The voting interface was present, but they had to click the green &amp;ldquo;join channel&amp;rdquo; button that Slack adds to take you from the preview mode to really entering the channel and the voting interace coming live.  That old beginner vs expert UX divide.   We got everyone voting in the end, but being able to see other folks experience via screen share in Google hangouts is eye opening as always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly voting plugged directly into the Hangout would be better - gosh I wish the hangout could embed the Slack chat itself and those joining the hangout would be automatically in that chat.  Maybe with some new YouTube live interface, or if we switch to Zoom or roll our own after April 25th.  The visions of the interfaces that would work still dance in my head, but I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to command the resources to put them together in the quality that I imagine &amp;hellip; maybe one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/kZ7m9abU0po"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V8EGMGuRSFc"&gt;Marketing meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DyjHlJc_rrw"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum and LocalSupport KickOff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Day by Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/10/day-by-day/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/10/day-by-day/</id>
    <published>2017-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-04-04T22:28:52+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="sprinting" src="/images/day.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day by day I&amp;rsquo;m getting one item off my desk.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why it&amp;rsquo;s so painful.  Over the last 10 days I&amp;rsquo;ve got off new passport applications for myself and my eldest son, sent off tax liability statements for the AgileVentures bank, and put various bank statements and odd pieces of papers in either the bin or my new filing cabinet.  Is it possible to enjoy the process more?  It&amp;rsquo;s a great feeling when one of these administrivia tasks is completed.  A lovely feeling of progress as the surface of my desk slowly re-appears.  Managed to get straight to the blog this morning despite tweeting and slacking a GreaterThanCode episode.  It was almost as if the volume of Slack alerts (25) kept me on the straight and narrow.  Gosh, why is so much of this stuff like pulling teeth! :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My daily routines continue; writing out Kanji tests for my kids while eating breakfast, walking them to school, listening to podcasts on the way back, tweet/slacking them (the podcasts, not the kids), blogging ~ the day ~ getting the kids to bed, reviewing older blogs and pushing to Slack, Medium and LinkedIn.  Looking back at older blogs, I&amp;rsquo;m missing the more intense coding of last year, missing blogs with more code samples; not that I&amp;rsquo;m sure if anyone other than me derives any benefit from them.  I&amp;rsquo;m starting to get a few more likes on Medium and LinkedIn, getting a few interesting conversations on Slack, but my consciousness is changing.  I&amp;rsquo;m watching more, seeing how the experience from my senses interleaves with memories, feelings, short excerpt from movies and tv shows.  What is this extraordinary one mind that can leap from considering the scale of the universe, to the inside of an atom, to the rage at a failing relationship, to the bitter sweet joy of nostalgia, to the peace of satisfaction!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have it (I think), the mind?  Or should we just say the experience of reality?  The ever-runnning flow of experience; attention slipping from sensations in the body, focus on something in the &amp;ldquo;outside&amp;rdquo; world.  If ever anything is truly &amp;ldquo;outside&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;inside&amp;rdquo;.  I&amp;rsquo;m starting to be able to watch as the emotions rise.  Yesterday my eldest son injured his left arm during his evening football training.  It seemed to become more painful as he got closer to bedtime, and there was fair amount of work with painkillers, ice-packs etc. I think it this morning that I was on the stairs calling up to his room to ask him which arm he had injured as I was considering whether he needed the day off school.  I asked him &amp;ldquo;right arm?&amp;rdquo; and he responded indicating that he didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I was talking about.  He was changing in his room, I was on the stairs, and irritation welled up overtaking my experience.  The irritation was a sort of disbelief that my 12 year old son couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand the question, couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand the context.  My tone changed and I said with some tension &amp;ldquo;the arm you injured last night, was it the right arm or the left arm&amp;rdquo;.  &amp;ldquo;Left arm&amp;rdquo; came the reply.  Why should I be irritated?  There, at some level, I&amp;rsquo;m sort of expecting my son to be on the same train of thought as me.  But why should he?  Why should anybody?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I can go further.  I&amp;rsquo;m still not quite observing the irritation (or other emotion) just as it rises.  It&amp;rsquo;s still slightly after the fact and then it&amp;rsquo;s kind of damage repair to make myself calm again.  My kids tell me I&amp;rsquo;m less angry than I used to be.  I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m on the edge of grasping something important here.  I&amp;rsquo;d meant to blog about the components of my day; take another look at where I can find some time savings.  Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s time for a little of that.  The blogging process has simplified as a result of reviewing it last year, with me creating a branch in the github UI, navigating to the correct directory, editing in the browser, submitting a PR.  Could be simpler, but still pretty smooth.  What else was in yesterday:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;09:30 - 10:00 - accidental Slack and Email review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10:00 - 10:30 - blogging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10:30 - 11:30 - composing a report about AgileVentures situation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;11:30 - 11:45 - Scrum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;11:45 - 13:30 - working through todo list (pushing out WSO code to staging, phone call with potential funder, phone call with charity trustee, managing new Premiums and sponsorships)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;14:00 - 14:30 - lunch and reviewing &amp;ldquo;Confident Ruby&amp;rdquo; sections for mob programming session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15:00 - 15:45 - Skype with potential sponsor/partner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15:45 - 16:00 - Scrum and Redeemify project code review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16:00 - 17:00 - Ruby Mob&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18:00 - 19:00 - fixing elasticmail/mailchimp settings and writing draft proposal for funder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;21:00 - 21:30 - reviewing old blogs, pushing to medium/linkedin - Slack catch up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure where I can squeeze much more efficiency out of all that.  I guess the difficult thing is that applying for funding and reaching out to sponsors takes up time.  Maybe we can get to the point where the mobs stop being review of book chapters and actually generating new code on community challenges.  We had a new Premium sign up yesterday and got two new folks sponsored.  There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of coding we could do to smooth that process up, but right now I have to switch to coding/working on things that bring in money immediately, not things that might speculatively bring more money in in the future.  I&amp;rsquo;ll still keep taking it day by day, and seeing if I can enjoy the experience, moment by moment &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=70T6fa4Tdck"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MQBHqiJE5B4"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sprinting</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/09/sprinting/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/09/sprinting/</id>
    <published>2017-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-04-03T22:28:30+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="sprinting" src="/images/sprinting.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I totally failed to avoid Slack and Email before blogging this AM.  Again it was posting the update about the podcast that I&amp;rsquo;d listened to.  I&amp;rsquo;d had this idea to post to Twitter and then leave posting it to Slack till after the blog, but going into #techtalk on Slack I see a post by another community member, reply to that, post my podcast update and then I just don&amp;rsquo;t have the self-control not to look through the other channels.  And once I&amp;rsquo;ve done that, hell, I might as well look at my email :-) Perhaps, fortunately there was not too much going on, so I&amp;rsquo;m back at the blog pretty quickly.  I have found a Slack command line interface (&lt;a href="https://github.com/rlister/slackcat"&gt;SlackCat&lt;/a&gt;) that allows me to post an update without looking at the rest of the Slack.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll use that tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course just firing off to #techtalk without going in there to check if there&amp;rsquo;s an ongoing conversation might be a little inconsiderate.  Could I have some mechanism that would hold the update ready to go until the previous update didn&amp;rsquo;t have a question mark on the end?  Gosh, what a convoluted train of thought! :-) The structure I&amp;rsquo;m building to try and deal with a lack of willpower &amp;hellip; Maybe I need the willpower workout, or maybe it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if I don&amp;rsquo;t get straight to the blog &amp;hellip; just why are Slack and Email so addictive?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I was going to try and link this all tangentially to the subject of Sprints, an important part of the Agile Scrum process whereby work is timeboxed into multi-week sprints.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty lax on formal Sprints in the projects I&amp;rsquo;m managing recently.  We used to do them regularly on LocalSupport and WebSiteOne with a weekly meeting that tried to combine retrospective and planning elements.  As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before, it seemed like there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much enthusiasm for the meetings, and it was quite de-motivating to go to the effort of arranging them when not many people would show up.  Or even more so if they would say they would turn up and then cancel at the last minute, or not even send word that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, reading more about Sprint philosophy for the book I&amp;rsquo;m writing on &amp;ldquo;Agile Methods in Open Source Projects&amp;rdquo; and Pat Bolger&amp;rsquo;s effective use of Sprints in the MetPlus and WikiEduDashboard projects, AND Michael&amp;rsquo;s enthusiasm for a new kind of structure to planning meetings in WebSiteOne, has got me all gung-ho for Sprints now.  It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how different areas of Agile, Scrum and XP overlap.  Pair programming is great for keeping focused on a task.  As I&amp;rsquo;ve dialled back the amount of pairing I do, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending less time coding.  There are lots of admin things to do, and that&amp;rsquo;s partly why I&amp;rsquo;ve gone for more solo sessions, since they can be organised more easily at the last minute.  However in absence of pairing and a sprint structure, it&amp;rsquo;s easy for things to just drift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making a committment as part of a Sprint that a certain amount of work will get done during that Sprint is no guarantee that the work will get done.  However we&amp;rsquo;re now in our second week-long Sprint in the new WebSiteOne flow and I&amp;rsquo;m finding that committing to complete a certain number of tickets in a &amp;ldquo;formal&amp;rdquo; meeting is proving reasonably effective at keeping me on task in the absence of pairing.  It&amp;rsquo;s inspired me to start more formal Sprints for the LocalSupport, AsyncVoter and Redeemify projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a AsyncVoter kick off yesterday involving Arreche and myself in which we found ourselves a little early to vote on new features, but we both made commitments to sorting out certain infrastructure issues.  It&amp;rsquo;s too early to say whether this will all have a big long-term impact, but particuarly since the afternoon (UTC) Kent Beck scrums have been relatively slow recently, I&amp;rsquo;m going for making each one a &amp;ldquo;Sprint kick-off&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monday (LocalSupport)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday (AsyncVoter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday (Redeemify)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday (WebSiteOne)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think maybe Redeemify should be on Tuesday.  Perhaps the daily scrums should be renamed after their project focus, instead of &amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo;.  What I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do is give the impression that other project business couldn&amp;rsquo;t be discussed there &amp;hellip; maybe the thing to do is set up a repeating event that takes place after the &amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum of scrums?  Rather than just letting the scrum event bleed over as I&amp;rsquo;m currently doing &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should be going to take Agile and Scrum certification, but I&amp;rsquo;m not inspired by what feels to me like a rubber stamping process.  I feel like true learning comes from doing things in the trenches.  Trying out one technique, tweaking it, reflecting and so forth.  Not that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t learn something from seeing the inside of the &amp;ldquo;corporate&amp;rdquo; Agile/Scrum certification, but at arond £1000 a pop, I&amp;rsquo;ll need to sort my financial situation first.  Then again do you need to speculate to accumulate?  Should we perhaps be using the limited AV funds to pay for Agile certification for people like myself, Pat and Lara, so that we could advertise that projects brought to AV would have a dedicated certified scrum master?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know.  There is infinite flexibility.  I hate having to nail things down and saying we&amp;rsquo;ll do this or that.  I&amp;rsquo;d much rather let things evolve and see what happens; hear what people want then offer it, but I guess it&amp;rsquo;s exhausting for people to explain what they want.  You need to work out what they want through some other mechanism and then communicate to them that you have just what they need, so they can find it there all laid out for them &amp;hellip; maybe &amp;hellip; :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/QP1S5Tp4-TA"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bI5sC-s1-Eo"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum and AsyncVoter kick off&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grants and Prototyping</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/08/grants-and-prototyping/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/08/grants-and-prototyping/</id>
    <published>2017-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-30T21:46:55+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="balance" src="/images/grants.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my taking one thing off my desk a day is at least keeping my desk in a steady state rather than becoming completely overwhelemed with pieces of paper.  I still haven&amp;rsquo;t thrown out my old filing cabinet, and I got caught by Slack/Email before getting down to this blog &amp;hellip; urgh.  One day at a time on the ever present moment path to enlightement :-)  Anyhow, my generally despondent feelings about applying for grants were not buoyed by us failing to get the Nelson Mandela Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Website and Intranet project.  I think I spent about 4 or 5 hours on that last week.  A good learning experience for Pat, Lara and myself, and certainly worth going for, as landing it would have made a huge difference to our community.  Good preparation for subsequent bids, but a bit deflating coming hot on the heels of another bid failure from the previous Thursday.  I&amp;rsquo;ve now got a couple of other micro-bids on my plate, but I fear they might be distractions from the one larger project that by itself will probably sort my financial worries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to have a proposal for that larger project done by this coming Monday.  No one&amp;rsquo;s jumping out of Slack or Hangouts to make me work on it, so the danger is that I get distracted and fail to generate a good proposal.  I took some steps towards avoiding that last night by sorting a basic set of estimates, and also working with InVision.  I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about a &lt;a href="https://thoughtbot.com/product-design-sprint/guide"&gt;ThoughtBot style Design Sprint&lt;/a&gt; for the client, and I notice that Thoughtbot is now recommending the &lt;a href="https://www.invisionapp.com/"&gt;InVision system&lt;/a&gt; over paper prototyping for quickly preparing UI mockups to get fast feedback from stakeholders.  I spent a little time getting a version of the AV site up in InVision and got comfortable with the system.  The key thing is creating hot spots on images to allow users to click through from one screen mockup to another.  The experience can then be shared with a &lt;a href="https://invis.io/B7ARISKJV#/222386846_Home_Screen"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not necessarily a quantum leap over doing the same sort of thing with PowerPoint or KeyNote, but the ability to drag and drop hotspots makes the InVision something that one can more quickly mock things up in.  Here you can see a few hotspots in green and the fixed nav bar that I made after just taking a few screenshots of the AV site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="mockup of AV site" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/t3b3l3q0z5poqfo/Screenshot%202017-03-08%2010.18.00.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoughtbot&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/proteus-middleman"&gt;Proteus Middleman&lt;/a&gt; also looks like fun for things that need more complex interactions.  Having satisfied myself that I&amp;rsquo;ve got some good tools to work with for a Design Sprint, I think I pretty much have my proposal for next week.  Not sure if I need to write out a load more text - what I really want to do is pull a load more information out about the stakeholders and participants and so on.  What I will be needing to do is make a decision about CSS and JavaScript frameworks, and probably in the short term that will be Bootstrap and React, since those are the ones that I&amp;rsquo;m most comfortable with at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m left with is the focus today, which I&amp;rsquo;d love to spend just kicking around more prototypes and exploring, or second best, just responding to the PRs and comments in my GitHub notifications, relating to the various AgileVentures projects.  However there&amp;rsquo;s another small bid that I could be focused on.  Apparently today is the last day I can phone to ask questions about it, and it needs to be submitted for Friday.  It&amp;rsquo;s small change, and feels a bit like a setup for more effort to be followed by a rejection, but even a single paid project now could serve as a great incentive to sign up more AgileVentures Premium members with the benefit of being eligible for such paid projects; which may be one of those things that can keep the community growing.  Okay, I&amp;rsquo;ve talked myself into it - I&amp;rsquo;ll just make a coffee and get started.  Well, &amp;hellip;, after I&amp;rsquo;ve looked at one or two pull requests :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Uqs3P_-sWfY"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zg9s5KCFlU8"&gt;Marketing Meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o-Z8uK2H-Sk"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Analytics Visualization</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/07/analytics-visualization/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/07/analytics-visualization/</id>
    <published>2017-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-29T22:04:14+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="balance" src="/images/visualization.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pushed out some changes to the main AgileVentures landing page last night.  I&amp;rsquo;d had a set ready from last week&amp;rsquo;s sprint on Friday, but rather than push them straight out I&amp;rsquo;d held them on staging and posted an image of them to the #websiteone channel on Slack:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="reworked home page" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/1em05z5kzqdk0ln/Screenshot%202017-03-06%2013.13.56.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I did, as I got lots of great feedback.  I&amp;rsquo;d got a round of feedback in the &amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum on Friday, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling entirely comfortable with the result, and the reaction from several in the #websiteone channel was that it didn&amp;rsquo;t look great and was a bit too wordy, so I held off to review things in Monday&amp;rsquo;s marketing meeting.  Lara asked, why move the button when it was already &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo;. Marufa concurred there was too much text, and I was thinking maybe reduce the font size and add more whitespace padding/margin around it to make it all less busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However Lara also recommended an analytics plugin for Chrome which made me think rather differently.  The &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/page-analytics-by-google/fnbdnhhicmebfgdgglcdacdapkcihcoh?hl=en"&gt;Page Analytics&lt;/a&gt; plugin by Google annotates a site with information about where users are clicking based on Google Analytics tracking.  It looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="page analytics plugin on AV.org" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/5huv3vgkftr50wc/Screenshot%202017-03-07%2009.52.42.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a fantastic example of how data visualization can make all the difference.  All the other different displays of data and flow through the site in Google Analytics had so far failed to help me feel I was understanding what was going on as people browsed the site.  The main thing that really popped out of this visualization is that 13% of those arriving at the page did click through on the round &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; banner, followed by ~5% on the &amp;ldquo;learn&amp;rdquo; banner.  We&amp;rsquo;d had feedback from at least one user that they hadn&amp;rsquo;t realised the round banners were clickable, but clearly a non-trivial portion of recent visitors (the graphic above is from the last month&amp;rsquo;s traffic) are clicking through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that might reflect the preponderence of those keywords being used in our AdWords campaigns.  Lara was saying the &amp;ldquo;Get started now to begin coding&amp;rdquo; button was working because we had 23% click through.  Although the way this plugin works, it can&amp;rsquo;t distinguish where a user is clicking; rather it seems it just checks which URL they land on next, as I see the &amp;ldquo;Sign up&amp;rdquo; link in the top right corner is also marked up with a 23%.  Now I assume that people are probably clicking through on the large visible button, but seeing that we clearly did have some non-trivial level of click through on the round banners, and that we had some questions about the proposed text only change, made me roll back the text change and just push out two other minor changes for guest users:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Change main call to action button text from &amp;ldquo;Sign up now to start coding&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Get started now to begin coding&amp;rdquo;
2) Change scrum link from title of scrum to &amp;ldquo;Want to learn more? Listen in. Next projects review meeting in x hours&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are less controversial and I hypothesize that the second might conceivably bring some more folks into hangouts, and we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to tell intuitively over the course of the week if there are any new faces showing up.  Maybe we should be A/B testing the change to the button text, but I can justify that quick fix in terms of making the text consistent with other changes we&amp;rsquo;ve been making on the other pricing and Premium pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m left conflicted about the next steps.  It seems sensible to see how the small changes impact things.  For bigger changes to the landing page it feels like we need 4 or 5 variations which could be kicked around by the various interested teams, and then perhaps we could A/B test a couple of alternatives if we can narrow down to two that we like.  The concern that Pat raised is that the landing page doesn&amp;rsquo;t immediately communicate our value proposition, and I tend to agree with him.  I think there are also a great number of other tweaks that could be made in other places to make the whole site look more pleasing and professional - things like the disabled direct signup component, the excessive and small font size text in several places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on our sprint kick off on Friday I&amp;rsquo;m adjusting the site so that newly signed up users will be redirected to the getting started page.  That feels like a survivable experiment that might deliver some value.  However for all this tweaking I don&amp;rsquo;t have much evidence that any of the AdWords activity will actually lead to revenue generation.  Clearly if we can get the site into the shape where it does act as a funnel for those who might really derive value from AgileVentures, then that would be fantastic.  However I suspect that most who are coming in through our &amp;ldquo;learning to code&amp;rdquo; related keywords might be better served by CodeCademy and FreeCodeCamp.  Presumably if we carefully tweak our AdWords, over time we might be able to hit a seams of developers at junior, mid and senior level who&amp;rsquo;d want to get involved and take out Premium plans &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow it&amp;rsquo;s clear to me that so far the income we have has been generated by me reaching out directly to people via Email and Slack.  Getting people to sign up on our site of course swells the number we can email to, but then again if they are not the ones who&amp;rsquo;ll benefit from AgileVentures then it&amp;rsquo;s effort in vain.  Clearly the email newsletter needs to go out and we need to see what interest it generates.  I&amp;rsquo;m inclined to think that making some mobbing session videos available as examples of the benefits of Premium Mob might have more impact at the moment &amp;hellip; I guess we keep experimenting and analyzing AND visualizing&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/rMgERi4w8W0"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QzR72HpWaQk"&gt;Marketing meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-CMIoFYLuqI"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Balance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/06/balance/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/06/balance/</id>
    <published>2017-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-28T22:05:58+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="balance" src="/images/balance.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any Premium pairing this Sunday, and my twin boys&amp;rsquo; football match was rained off, so I had a relatively calm day, staying completely off Slack and Email.  I collapsed after lunch and slept for three hours - catching up lost sleep from the week where I&amp;rsquo;d been up in the night a few times.  The last couple of weeks haven&amp;rsquo;t been great sleep-wise.  A sudden alertness at 4am and then an inability to get back to sleep without listening to an hour of audio comedy.  Not that I don&amp;rsquo;t try just relaxing back into sleep, but after an hour of the same work and relationship thoughts going round in my head I get sick of it, and find audio comedy is a reasonably pleasant way of changing my internal dialogue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do end up feeling a bit of a failure when Steve Hagen and Eckhart Tolle say that there&amp;rsquo;s a simple step to enlightenment or awakeness available in every moment, and that we&amp;rsquo;re all supposed to be equipped to realise it. I had lots of moments of awareness/self-observation over the weekend, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t stop me from blowing up in a rage at my kids on two or three occasions.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got to balance that against the points when I didn&amp;rsquo;t blow up in a rage, or didn&amp;rsquo;t resist the moment and wrestle it forcefully into something that it currently wasn&amp;rsquo;t.  It&amp;rsquo;s funny, but I see an analogy with the Empire Strikes Back where Yoda tells Luke that he shouldn&amp;rsquo;t go off to help his friends (Han and Leia), because by turning aside from his main task he&amp;rsquo;ll threaten what they fight for.  Ironically Luke rushes to save his friends, but they save themselves and he isn&amp;rsquo;t the one who effects their escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved Star Wars growing up, but with the subsequent movies and a jaundiced adult eye it all seems rather trite and very militaristic; sort of glorifying a sanitised violence where no one actually bleeds.  Still I can&amp;rsquo;t help but notice that when I try to resist my children&amp;rsquo;s moods directly; when I try to prevent one from screaming their displeasure at another, that I seem to make the situation worse and not better.  Far more effective recently is not to resist their upset.  Naturally I still physically intervene if it&amp;rsquo;s actually coming to blows; but what I&amp;rsquo;m reducing is my protestations of &amp;ldquo;of course if you scream at him he&amp;rsquo;s not going to let you have it&amp;rdquo;, and so the reactions that I would get to those statements, e.g. &amp;ldquo;well he&amp;rsquo;s being rude to me and has made me upset!!&amp;rdquo; don&amp;rsquo;t fly back at me.  If I try to control my kids behaviours too strongly what I get is lots of justifications from each child about why their own bad behaviour is inevitable as a result of the poor behaviour of other parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly a lot of adult conversations can go the same way, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been guilty in the past of making justification after justification, when I&amp;rsquo;m starting to realise that &amp;ldquo;defending your corner&amp;rdquo;, so to speak, has a tendency to provoke additional attack.  I still have huge trouble with statements I disagree with.  I really find it difficult not to respond to them.  I feel like not responding is somehow tacit agreement.  That letting a statement stand unopposed is tantamount to conceding that it is the truth.   That&amp;rsquo;s just my perception - is there any truth in it?  Do other people think that the last unopposed statement reflects the group concensus? I&amp;rsquo;d be interested to know &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday we had various meetings, and what I&amp;rsquo;m grudgingly realising more and more is that my tendency to challenge statements I disagree with can make for longer and longer meetings.  I think I actually did a better job than usual.  I stayed in the moment in one meeting, frustrated that someone had said something that contradicted my own assertion, but realising to confront it would be to drag out part of the meeting, when I was judging that actually it was more important to move on to other things.  Who knows if that was the right decision?  Like the foolish(?) neighbour who keeps congratulating the wise(?) farmer in the Zen riddle, when does the story ever end?  When do we find out the true extent of all the consequences of every decision?  Never?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the most important thing is not being taken over by the &amp;ldquo;unconscious&amp;rdquo; reaction to any situation?  Let the situation be; give yourself time to observe your internal mental state and then allow a &amp;ldquo;conscious&amp;rdquo; reaction to emerge?  Will that allow things to get better?  Let&amp;rsquo;s not attach ourselves to outcomes.  Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on being conscious in the current moment.  Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s the way to achieve true balance &amp;hellip; but then life&amp;rsquo;s such a complex puzzle, could managing it really be that simple?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=drjxg5Gc_tQ"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3OZx8NrT2FA"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum and WSO Kick Off&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8tY4Tvew9Xs"&gt;BetaSaaSers AutoGraders meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
