<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>All Good Things ...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/</id>
    <published>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-04T22:27:03+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="good things" src="/images/good_things.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been daily blogging for a year now.  Working day blogs that is.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging on weekends, or national holidays, or during my vacations.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty consistent.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of days where work was super busy due to the tail end of a design sprint or something, but I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to retro-actively blog and keep it one per work day.  I started blogging in June last year doing a blog on a different platform each day of the week, but fairly soon I fell into a pattern of blogging to our AgileVentures middleman site, and then re-releasing to Medium after I&amp;rsquo;d got a little distance from the blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the purpose of this blog frenzy?  My memory is that it was about trying to communicate more effectively.  I often end up assuming that people understand my thoughts and intentions and it turns out that actually they don&amp;rsquo;t.  Of course why would they?  There are few telepaths around.  I&amp;rsquo;m also a bit of a gabbler and my sense is that it&amp;rsquo;s not super easy to understand what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to communicate.  So blogging, get all the thoughts down in text, provide them in an accessible form for everyone to read, and maybe reduce my need to gabble on and on about things.  Win win, no?  There&amp;rsquo;s also the motivation that blogging at the start of each day is a kind of &amp;ldquo;morning pages&amp;rdquo; activity such as writers use to start off their days and clear their heads.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think writers usually publish their morning brain dump, but I have certainly found the process of starting each day with writing out my thoughts to be reassuring and relaxing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year when I was doing a lot more coding, the blogs tended to be all about the previous day&amp;rsquo;s coding.  As AgileVentures became an official charity and my admin load increased, they have tended to be about prioritization.  Starting the day with a blog is certainly less stressful than starting the day with a review of email and Slack conversations, which will generally lead to many adds to my ever-increasing todo list.  Has the time been well spent?  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had positive reactions to some blogs, but my sense is that the blogs are too long, too stream-of-consciousness, too un-focused to gain much traction.  I think I may have even alienated some with my uncensored and unedited thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was 17 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had trouble just generating text, and from even earlier I was always a talker.  It&amp;rsquo;s like my internal thought wheel is hooked up directly to my mouth, and at will I can hook it up to a pen or a keyboard and just dump my thoughts straight out, for better or for worse.  So I rarely have writer&amp;rsquo;s block, but it leaves me with a different problem.  How to edit the thicket of thoughts and ideas, so as to more effectively communicate them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to the end of a year of blogging prompts thoughts of changing things going forward.  There&amp;rsquo;ve been times in the past when rising early I&amp;rsquo;ve done 3 hours of programming before breakfast.  After recent design sprints I think about doing coding sprints, or other activities that fill the week in different ways.  Should it be one blog a week with the blog being edited and revised each day, so that a single polished blog can be released on Friday?  I guess it all depends on what one wants to achieve, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t the Buddhist in me been trying to follow a path of consecrated action, where one is totally unattached to the outcomes of activities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d have loved my blogs to have provoked more positive responses of &amp;ldquo;yes, let&amp;rsquo;s build a solution to that together &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, although there has been some of that.  What I really would like is for AgileVentures to be a healthy thriving community providing great learning experiences for many, while also helping charitable causes around the world.  The process of reflection over the last year does make me think that we&amp;rsquo;re far too text heavy in many, many parts of our interface with the world.  One of the most attractive ideas for me going forward is that I&amp;rsquo;d spend my blogging time each day focused on a part of the main AgileVentures site, converting it from text heavy to text light and adding images.  I have a hunch that, by doing this in strategic places throughout the site, we could improve the sign up rates, the number of members joining projects and the numbers signing up for Premium subscriptions, the source of our financial sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a feeling I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to shake the blogging habit.  The process has become too solidly part of my daily routine.  The thing that actually gets me started and ready to work in the mornings.  So, anyhow, starting tomorrow, blogs that focus on parts of the main AgileVentures site.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to work through it one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog released early for inclusion in our July newsletter, earlier blogs are all in draft form in GitHub and will be on this site soon&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>All in One Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/09/all-in-one-day/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/09/all-in-one-day/</id>
    <published>2017-05-09T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-22T22:12:48+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="four seasons" src="/images/four_seasons_one_day.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m struggling with what each blog should be.  Should it be a focused dive on one thing?  Should I be trying to cover everything that happened since the last blog?  Yesterday was pretty intense.  I could spend the whole blog on the AV community meeting we had at the end of the day yesterday.  There&amp;rsquo;d been a spurt of conversation in the #av&lt;em&gt;community&lt;/em&gt;talk channel triggered by Mikael&amp;rsquo;s reaction to my blog of a month ago about having to switch my focus away from AgileVentures.  The discussion was all around trying to understand how we could make AV sustainable.  It was Joao, Matt and myself in the meeting, which we could probably have publicized better, but then who takes the lead on these things?  I&amp;rsquo;m close to drowning trying to attend to the NHS project, ramping up the new run of the MOOC and keeping AV ticking over.  Perhaps we can repeat weekly &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d really liked all the independent conversation taking place in the #av&lt;em&gt;community&lt;/em&gt;talk channel and had resolved to stay in the background in the meeting.  I started off well and we went round trying to answer Joao&amp;rsquo;s question about what the AV product is.  We had a good chat, but I noticed that by the end it was me doing most of the talking :-( Joao had to go, but Matt and I carried on a little as I evangelised the design sprint concept.  We didn&amp;rsquo;t end up trying the &amp;ldquo;Market and Product Validation Checklist&amp;rdquo; that Matt had mentioned in the chat &amp;hellip; well, anyway, Matt got quite enthused about the idea of doing a design sprint so we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That all came at the end of a full day, where I was just hanging in there to get emails out to move forward on the private contract that will hopefully sustain me for the rest of year, and the communication with the lawyers about the NHS wiki terms &amp;amp; conditions.  The majority of the day had been taken up getting ready for a usability/outreach session with the &lt;a href="https://www.kcsc.org.uk/"&gt;Kensington &amp;amp; Chelsea Social Council&lt;/a&gt;; an umbrella group supporting the non-profit sector in the London borough of Kensington &amp;amp; Chelsea.  I have the feeling they are the equivalent entity to the Voluntary Action Harrow (VAH) group who we&amp;rsquo;ve built the Harrow Community Network for through the LocalSupport project.  I&amp;rsquo;d been put in touch with folks at the Kensington &amp;amp; Chelsea Social Council via NHS HLP as a group that were implementing Self Care in their area and might have interest in the wiki project we&amp;rsquo;ve developed.  Our NHS design sprint has sprawled out from its initial week (a few weeks back), and I&amp;rsquo;ve got a meeting with a different stakeholder each day this week, and I&amp;rsquo;m using those meetings to get further usability feedback on the MediaWiki system we&amp;rsquo;ve deployed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just about hanging on, making the arrangements to meet everyone, fitting in the travel etc.  I say just about because I had to push the marketing meeting back an hour yesterday at the last minute when I realised that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be back in time for it.  Not ideal.  I could have tried to do it in a coffee shop in Kensington &amp;amp; Chelsea, but I felt back at the home office would be more efficient.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got an extra meetup to fit in this week and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where my lunch breaks are going to fit in through the week!  Maybe I need to move the Martin Fowler scrum.  Pat has just said he can&amp;rsquo;t commit to share the hosting of the meeting.  I could move it earlier or even just put it on hold for while &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, we got the marketing meeting done.  At least I&amp;rsquo;m remembering to review the outstanding action items.  I feel like there must be some better meeting management system somewhere in between Trello and the text notes I&amp;rsquo;m pasting into Slack, but then again.  The main technical challenge for the day was seeing if I could get the HLP banner into the wiki.  I was getting stuck on it, and managed to hand off the task briefly to Lara, who played with a few settings and came up with a solution.  I had been adding the MediaWiki vector skin to insert a div for the HLP banner/navigation from their main site; but certain mediawiki elements would not move down.   Thanks to Lara&amp;rsquo;s input we got a great mockup editing the common.css for the site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight css"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;#hlp-banner&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sx"&gt;url('https://www.dropbox.com/s/2yokso0fkd3bivt/Screenshot%202017-05-08%2010.40.18.png?dl=1')&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;100%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;min-height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;123px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nf"&gt;#mw-head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;margin-top&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;123px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nc"&gt;.mw-wiki-logo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;background-image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;none&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had just taken a quick screen shot of the HLP site banner to play with.  I just got this into the main site on the train on the way into meeting Kensington &amp;amp; Chelsea Social Council, and then I also managed to make emails required in the site.  All a bit skin of the teeth, but it allowed me to get valuable feedback at the stakeholders&amp;rsquo; offices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat down with their strategic health lead and the manager of their Self-care program, and we could have easily been continuing the expert interviews of the previous weeks.  I could tell that there would be lots of great stuff to learn about how K&amp;amp;C was implementing self care, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to burn all the time on that.  We had to move on to a more testing footing.  We had our working &amp;ldquo;prototype&amp;rdquo;.  After understanding a bit more about how things worked at KCSC, I convinced them to try out our wiki on their systems.  Simply having them navigate to the site and seeing that it appeared correctly was already useful, particularly given the problems we&amp;rsquo;d had with some wikis on the NHS laptops/network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I encouraged the Self-care manager to navigate through the site, try some searches and then some editing.  It was all rather slap-dash from an academic usability standpoint, but there were some clear knowledge gains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you weren&amp;rsquo;t logged in, searching for things did not suggest page creation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches for multiple terms were not matching anything in our system (not much content in there)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The combination of required email confirmation and the visual editor could lead to a confusing user flow &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two reasonably high priority items are now to see if we can make the banner fully dynamic, and also whether we can drop the email confirmation requirement, since the moderation step still catches anything a user tries to post.  I&amp;rsquo;m definitely leaning towards having almost no requirements for becoming a user and push the burden onto the moderation queue - at least at the beginnning when there are few users.  If the moderation burden becomes too heavy, then we can start imposing additional constraints on user sign up; which makes me think I need to get the moderation plan and budget out of my head and onto paper.  Of course the ongoing interaction testing (training?) is what&amp;rsquo;s helping us understand how the moderation will actually work with this system.   We&amp;rsquo;re doing our hard launch on Friday.  I&amp;rsquo;ll take a deep breath; say to myself that we&amp;rsquo;ll address each issue in turn each day of this week and next week will be calmer :-) Taking it one day at a time &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=_JPjZvDJ2VQ"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4gqu79SLxRc"&gt;AV Community meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rich Tapestry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/08/rich-tapestry/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/08/rich-tapestry/</id>
    <published>2017-05-08T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-20T22:21:36+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="rich_tapestry" src="/images/rich_tapestry.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brain was grabbling at titles for the blog/branch&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;webs we weave&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;elephants all the way down&amp;rdquo;.  After nearly a year of blogging there&amp;rsquo;s a haze about which expressions I&amp;rsquo;ve used already and how well they express what I&amp;rsquo;ll end up blogging about.  Not that titles can&amp;rsquo;t or don&amp;rsquo;t change through the subsequent editing process.  Last week was characterised by a series of edge of the seat devops activities.  Do I mean DevOps?  I guess I just mean installation of different components of the NHS wiki software.  One could characterise them as just part of the MediaWiki install process.  Looking back at them being all done it can be laid out as fairly straightforward, but any one of them could have turned out to be insoluble in the time available; and really I was pulling time out of other activities to sort the Apache, Parsoid and SSL configurations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system is live at &lt;a href="https://wiki.healthylondon.org"&gt;https://wiki.healthylondon.org&lt;/a&gt; and it loaded a bit sluggishly this morning, reloads were pretty prompt, and the Visual Editor is still working with the SSL.  After previous forays to get the Visual Editor working (Monday?) and SSL installed (Thursday?), it turned out that the Visual Editor wouldn&amp;rsquo;t play well with the SSL.  It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to say whether the Visual Editor is a &amp;ldquo;nice to have&amp;rdquo; or a &amp;ldquo;must have&amp;rdquo;, but losing it would have been a shame.  In total it took only about forty minutes to fix the Visual Editor to work with SSL on Friday.  It works with SSL on the main Wikipedia site, so my efforts were heartened by the idea that it was at least in principle possible to get it working.  However, hosting on Azure could have made it arbitrarily difficult to come up with a solution in a reasonable amount of time, and indeed I found several plaintive posts from people getting stuck on this, and those posts had no solution responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again being with MediaWiki means we have an extensive online community and googling error messages gives leads pretty readily, but there was no &amp;ldquo;out of the box&amp;rdquo; solution that I could easily find.  In the end it took a reasoned analysis of the way the Parsoid system works.  The Visual Editor is a plugin that works within MediaWiki, but it needs to be able to translate pages from its own format to the MediaWiki syntax.  This used to be done via PHP script, but is now a stand alone node service (microservice).  Parsoid needs to be able to talk to the MediaWiki API and MediaWiki needs to be able to talk to the Parsoid service when starting up the Visual Editor.  The new SSL endpoints meant that the MediaWiki could no longer reach the Parsoid service.  I&amp;rsquo;d like to give a more detailed walkthrough of the errors encountered etc., but I&amp;rsquo;m feeling pretty run down today and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to get on to.  The executive summary is that I had to configure an additional virtual host in Apache to redirect through the security layer so that the Mediawiki Visual Editor pages could access Parsoid.  It also required opening an additional port in the Azure system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;d really like to do now is spend a full day re-creating the whole installation on a fresh Azure/Bitnami installation - documenting as I go.  However I&amp;rsquo;ve got a meeting today and most days this week, getting together with other stakeholders the NHS has put me in touch with.  This is going to be, sort of, the final section of the design sprint, where I try to observe end user reactions to the &amp;ldquo;prototype&amp;rdquo; we&amp;rsquo;ve created.  On the technical side I need to check on the backup solution we&amp;rsquo;ve implemented, and it occurs to me that we could get the MediaWiki edits we&amp;rsquo;re making into git or some other versioning system.  There&amp;rsquo;s also replying to the lawyers about the updates to the terms &amp;amp; conditions, preparing for a revised training session tomorrow (do we drop the ConfirmAccount plugin?), etc., etc.  From the design sprint perspective I guess I should focus on getting the look and feel finished to see end user reactions to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so the plan is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the backups are working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on the look and feel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start seeing the stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I can follow up with a full documentation of the install process, which might also make me less of a single point of failure if we have an issue with the configuration.  That said, I would ideally be doing the look and feel update on a staging instance; so maybe I can&amp;rsquo;t get out of replicating the setup?  Of course the faster option is to just try design changes on the existing out of step staging instance we currently have.  Gah!  Life&amp;rsquo;s rich tapestry indeed &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m going to make some coffee &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Breathing Room</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/05/breathing-room/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/05/breathing-room/</id>
    <published>2017-05-05T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-19T21:33:54+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="breathe" src="/images/breathe.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt like I was in a bit of pressure cooker yesterday with so many different tasks piling up.  I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to relieve the pressure slighlty by requesting that the start date of the edX MOOC get put back by a week.  UCBerkeley and edX seem just fine with that, and it&amp;rsquo;s done, and it brings the operation of the TA training course AV102 into line so that the TAs can help with the review of the course material.  This was the mistake that I made last year&amp;ndash;that the final assigninment in the main 4 week body of the AV102 course is pair programming and it&amp;rsquo;s in the following week that the learners start getting credit for contributing to supporting learners in the main MOOC and reviewing the course material.  I think part of the key problem, and probably the reason I made the SAME mistake this year (despite trying hard not too) is that my schedule spreadsheet didn&amp;rsquo;t include the fourth assignment and the first level 2 certificate items for the AV102, screwing up my estimates for when that course ends.  So I&amp;rsquo;ve fixed that now, and hopefully I can avoid the same mistake again, although I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how many times we&amp;rsquo;ll be running this course again in this form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been nice to meet learners from the course coming into the AgileVentures hangouts this week.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had them participating in votes on the LocalSupport project, which is probably a good learning experience for them, but other LocalSupport contributors haven&amp;rsquo;t been around.  I think the voting on stories makes a lot more sense for people who are maintaining a certain level of involvement with the project, naturally; which turns me back to thinking that the bootcamp model has a lot going for it in that respect.  Not that I ever saw creating user stories or voting on them in any bootcamp I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with, but the opportunity is there.  I think the difficulty is that both for the individual learner and the project outcomes you need a certain base level of commitment; a certain number of hours a week that are going into the coding and project managment.  That&amp;rsquo;s really difficult to get from a group of volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the recent regulars in LocalSupport don&amp;rsquo;t usually make the kick-offs, which have been quite well attended by Sigu, Cess and Stella, but they weren&amp;rsquo;t around yesterday for kick-off.  Admittedly it was the first time we moved it to Thursday.  Michael showed up and we talked about the direction of the overall project and the apparent low use of the system.  We spent 45 minutes chewing the fat, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how much we achieved, apart from me bringing Michael up to date with how the project has pivoted from being a directory of organisations to focusing on listing volunteer opportunities.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it was a very productive discussion.  Maybe I should have been doing more listening.  I have trouble when I&amp;rsquo;m in the pressure cooker and I think people are telling me things I already know.  Then again, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s more important to allow someone to express what they want to say.  Michael was telling me I had to understand that lots of MOOC participants are just taking MOOCs to blast through 30 MOOCs in a year, just get a taste of things.  Totally.  Lots of people are just looking to get a taster of what&amp;rsquo;s going on in a particular subject area; and I do feel pleased that the AV folks can get to participate in scrums and vote on stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More the difficulty for me is that I&amp;rsquo;m behind on reviewing the PRs for LocalSupport and regular meetings with the client have gone out of the window with my overload on the NHS wiki project.  That could change in a week or two, but realistically I have to work on things that will pay for my time, as I&amp;rsquo;m out of spare cash.  I can see what I think would help the LocalSupport project thrive, i.e. active reviewing and integration of pull requests.  After meeting with Michael I did spend some time reviewing and see to my pleasure that Marouen had been reviewing and giving feedback on several.  That leaves Marouen&amp;rsquo;s Pull Request which needs a detailed review and planning; but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can devote time to that unless there&amp;rsquo;s some sort of funding for it.  I did manage to get Zmago&amp;rsquo;s new ReachSkills volunteer integration out, and we could have that onto production soon.  That&amp;rsquo;s the new vision for the site, that if the site were a one-stop shop for all the different sources of volunteering opportunities in Harrow then that might give people a reason to visit it regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest I think part of the problem is that the project hasn&amp;rsquo;t included us meeting and interacting with the intended end users.  At least in the NHS wiki project I&amp;rsquo;ve been out to talk and interact with lots of different stakeholders.  The LocalSupport client is in contact with lots of different charity groups in Harrow, but it feels like we&amp;rsquo;re just guessing about what the Harrow voluntary sector might actually want.  It&amp;rsquo;s like we&amp;rsquo;ve spent nearly five years doing what design sprints are supposed to help us avoid, i.e. we keep building different versions of a full system, to discover that people aren&amp;rsquo;t so interested.  Not that we haven&amp;rsquo;t had lots of great learning experiences along the way for the client, for me, for the different folks in AgileVentures who are contributing.  That said maybe recently I&amp;rsquo;ve drunk too much design sprint Kool-Aid, and I&amp;rsquo;m starting to see the need for them everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the NHS wiki project we haven&amp;rsquo;t had any money or resources for development, but we&amp;rsquo;ve substituted off-the-shelf platforms, and we&amp;rsquo;re doing high level usability tweaking much faster and getting quick feedback through testing with stakeholders.  I think that&amp;rsquo;s the kind of thing that we need to supercharge our AgileVenture projects.  Of course I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be turning myself from a hero to a host and not driving forward on these things.  The AV community has been coming up with their own ideas and have arranged a meeting for next Monday where I think it&amp;rsquo;s important I take a back seat and allow others to craft ideas, and then help empower them to try them out, fail and reflect and improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gosh, well this blog went off in a different direction.  I was planning to focus on how most of yesterday morning was spent on configuring SSL certificates on Apache in our Bitnami/Azure setup and how I was just about to give up and then it started working after this incantation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;./letsencrypt-auto --apache --apache-server-root /opt/bitnami/apache2 --apache-challenge-location /opt/bitnami/apache2 --apache-handle-sites FALSE --apache-vhost-root /opt/bitnami/apache2/conf/bitnami -d &amp;lt;domain-name&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I did also have to set up &lt;code&gt;sites-enabled&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;sites-available&lt;/code&gt; directories with symlinks like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ln -s /opt/bitnami/apache2/conf/bitnami/bitnami.conf /opt/bitnami/apache2/sites-available/&amp;lt;domain-name&amp;gt;.conf
ln -s /opt/bitnami/apache2/conf/bitnami/bitnami.conf /opt/bitnami/apache2/sites-enabled/&amp;lt;domain-name&amp;gt;.conf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it also involved splitting the VirtualHosts files up, and then merging them back together after the SSL cert was installed, in order to get the redirect from http to https working properly.  That was pretty much the soft launch of https://wiki.healthylondon.org but there are so many other things to tidy up.  I may live to regret that we are hosting the wiki ourselves.  I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m back in the early 2000&amp;rsquo;s managing &lt;code&gt;LocalSettings.php&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;apache.conf&lt;/code&gt;, but it seemed the only way to get the thing set up on schedule.  Go with the flow!  I worry slightly that this will bite me when we need to renew the certificates as I&amp;rsquo;ll have to decompose the VirtualHosts file, but then again, maybe the auto certbot will be able to handle that then.  One thing at a time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least with the MOOC put back a week I feel like I have space to implement some delegation in AgileVentures, finish up this round of the NHS wiki project, and get the MOOC prep done.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got just a little breathing room &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=DeIhzvdGO28"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=Lw79fDuia3Q"&gt;AV Marketing Meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=veCjZQEJLJk"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=h9d0_Cjen6o"&gt;LocalSupport &amp;ldquo;Kick Off&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Harder I Try</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/04/the-harder-I-try/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/04/the-harder-I-try/</id>
    <published>2017-05-04T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-14T21:37:30+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="dream catcher" src="/images/dream-catcher.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it feels like my life is one of those dreams where you&amp;rsquo;re running as hard as you can, but you&amp;rsquo;re not moving forward.  Yesterday I fixed two sticky technical issues that have been bugging us for a while, I got out an updated video for the AV102 course and enjoyed an Elixir mob run by two of our Premium Mob members, but still didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like I&amp;rsquo;d made much of a dent in the old ToDo list.  Let me tell you about the first bug in our AgileVentures WebsiteOne Rails code.  Ideally I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be spending two hours tracking down and fixing that bug, as the impending release of the MOOC next week meant that the final week of the AV102 TA training course needed to go live sharpish.  However one of the videos in the final week was still talking about the Hangout plugins and they&amp;rsquo;ve been discontinued and there really needed to be an explanation of how to take AV events live manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for the past couple of weeks on the odd day here and there we&amp;rsquo;d been getting 500 errors on the main events listing page.  It tended to come and go, and seemed more likely to occur on Mondays and Tuesdays.  Part of re-recording the video involved showing things appearing in the event list, and it seemed to me that not having the events index page working was a block on recording the video which should probably show that event list working.  That&amp;rsquo;s not to say that the events list bug wasn&amp;rsquo;t also a priority fix, but I&amp;rsquo;m kind of drowning in high priority items at the moment.  Anyway, I resolved to have a good stab at getting the bug fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d previously hypothesized that the bug might be related to some third party website we were relying on for timezone conversions, based on some of the different error messages we were seeing in the logs associated with the 500 errors.  We were getting different errors in different parts of the code base, but they all seemed to be related to time conversion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/app/vendor/bundle/ruby/2.3.0/gems/activesupport-4.2.7.1/lib/active_support/core_ext/time/zones.rb:56:in `find_zone!'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/app/vendor/bundle/ruby/2.3.0/gems/activerecord-4.2.7.1/lib/active_record/attribute_methods/time_zone_conversion.rb:24:in `convert_time_to_time_zone'`
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that they were intermittent and changing started to make me think (as Michael had suggested) that this was a resource issue.  I wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting any Google hits for these kinds of errors, so I tried upgrading our plan on Heroku, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t have much impact.   We&amp;rsquo;d just cloned the production data to staging and I saw we were getting similar errors there, but not on develop.  I was considering cloning to develop, when I ran locally against an older version of the production data - things were okay.  I cloned the production data locally and the events page was taking &amp;gt;20 seconds to load.  Whatever the issue was, something about the data was influencing the problem.  We have 20-second timeouts on Heroku, after which web queries are just shut down.  I speculated that some individual events might have corrupt timezones or something, but deleting a few had no impact on the time locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought maybe I should do more to replicate the production setup locally, but I knew that was a pain, and I had basically the same issue locally, although without the error being thrown, since I have longer timeouts for http requests on my local machine.  The Rails logs on my local machine were showing that lots of time was being spent in the request, but actually the time spent constructing the view and doing activerecord queries were relatively small:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Completed 200 OK in 35596ms (Views: 359.4ms | ActiveRecord: 80.0ms)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking more closely I could see that there appeared to be a 2 to 3 second wait after every query on the event instances table, which I traced into this method:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nc"&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;remove_past_events&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;events&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;events&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;delete_if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;event_instances&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;last&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;try&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:live?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;
                           &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;duration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;minutes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;current&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Playing with the query on the console I saw that as the number of &lt;code&gt;event_instances&lt;/code&gt; increased for an individual event, this method would get slower and slower. Some of the scrums had over 400 &lt;code&gt;event_instances&lt;/code&gt;, and the daily scrums appear multiple times in the list so we were repeating many slow operations.  I experimented with replacing &lt;code&gt;delete_if&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;reject&lt;/code&gt; but the method just got slower.  Then, looking more closely at the boolean statement I saw that the db query was in the first portion, and not the second, and actually the time check in the second half of the boolean would probably be false most of the time.  I tried switching the order of the boolean like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nc"&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;remove_past_events&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;events&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;events&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;delete_if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;duration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;minutes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;current&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;
                           &lt;span class="o"&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;event_instances&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;last&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;try&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:live?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and suddenly the problem evaporated.  Now the majority of queries were not checking for event instances at all, and in relatively short order I had the fix deployed and the main site event lists page was loading in just a few seconds.  It&amp;rsquo;s still not as fast as I would like, but it got us out of the woods and unblocked me for re-recording the AV102 video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I was into an Elixir mob, and since two Premium Mobbers had taken the lead on running the session it was less intense effort from me and I&amp;rsquo;d been able to skip preparation the previous day.  We talked about starting a React Mob the following day and the question came up about whether Premium Mob membership covers attending more than one Mob per week.  My response that we&amp;rsquo;ve been somewhat flexible with that perhaps shows that I&amp;rsquo;m not really cut out for being a businessperson.  I just want everyone to have access to all materials :-(  It&amp;rsquo;s weird, because even with payment not every Premium Mob member shows up to the sessions they have in principle paid for.  There seems like a higher level of committment from the Premium Mobbers than overall in the rest of the community, but we have the conundrum that their activity is less visible as we&amp;rsquo;re running the Mobs in private events.  Gosh, just what is the model that will make this all work and be sustainable?  Having Premium Mob events show in our events stream, but only be accessible by those who&amp;rsquo;ve paid, with the stream of every fifth session being available for others to see what goes on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after lunch (and React Mob prep with Stephen Grider&amp;rsquo;s kindly donated React/Redux course) and besides the AV102 pivotal tracker voting sessions (which is another blog post), I was impaling myself on the set up for the Slack slash command for AsyncVoter on Azure/Dokku.  We&amp;rsquo;d spent multiple sessions struggling with this and kept hitting a 503 error with no extra information.  The system was all working fine on Digital Ocean with dokku (where Arreche had set it up), but even after getting SSL working on the Azure/Dokku system we were still stuck.  No one showed up for the AsyncVoter kick off, so I spent the half hour quietly deleting the previous app in Slack and creating a new one.  The whole setup is rather involved, and I think I got it fully documented at &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/asyncvoter-slack-command/wiki"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/asyncvoter-slack-command/wiki&lt;/a&gt; but I think ultimately the sticking point was how many layers you have to dig down to find the key URL for a slack app.  Here&amp;rsquo;s the first screen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Slack App basic information" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/2eveqtmb4waywis/Screenshot%202017-05-04%2010.13.48.png?dl=1" /&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now previously I&amp;rsquo;d worked out that we need to click on things like &amp;ldquo;interactive messages&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;OAuth &amp;amp; Permissions&amp;rdquo; etc. on the left nav bar.  I find it odd that there is configuration hidden behind those links, that look like to me like they would just be descriptions of the &amp;ldquo;features&amp;rdquo;.  I usually expect configuration to be across the vertical nav, or to look more like buttons, but anyway, we&amp;rsquo;d previously ensured all the &amp;ldquo;interactive messages&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;OAuth &amp;amp; Permissions&amp;rdquo; URLs were updated to SSL, but there&amp;rsquo;s another.  Clicking on the &amp;ldquo;Building Apps for Slack&amp;rdquo;, reveals another control panel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="revealed control panel" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/9zqr9ncli5umymu/Screenshot%202017-05-04%2010.17.07.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And all of this is with wording about doing things, not configuring them.  It was through the process of recreating the app from scratch that I discovered the other place that the URL needed to be updated.  Inside the slash command setting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="slash commands" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ay2gjyn4sfvuidg/Screenshot%202017-05-04%2010.18.36.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s the option to edit, which reveals another URL that needed to be edited:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="additional url edit" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/qzbwmqxiprjz2wq/Screenshot%202017-05-04%2010.19.13.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you know it&amp;rsquo;s there, it&amp;rsquo;s not very discoverable.  Just writing this blog I see I can navigate to the top page via the &amp;ldquo;Slash Commands&amp;rdquo; on the left &amp;ldquo;Features&amp;rdquo; navigation links.  In our previous group sessions I think we&amp;rsquo;d been to that page repeatedly, but never realised that by editing the slash command we&amp;rsquo;d reveal another URL that needed updating.  I&amp;rsquo;d say the key usability issue here is that the summary of the slash command, before you edit, does not show that there are another three variables open for editing there, i.e. the RequestURL, ShortDescription and UsageHint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course now I know and I&amp;rsquo;ve blogged about it, but there we go.  The next step is now to ensure we can set up subdomains so that we can have a staging instance and a production instance; I have an idea about how to do that, but it might take 5 minutes, or I might get stuck on it for two hours.  I have to say that, moment to moment, I do prefer coding and debugging to trying to record videos for courses, or even just setting up and organising courses.  Now it&amp;rsquo;s May 4th and soft launch for the NHS wiki and I&amp;rsquo;ve got to work out which of the list of fixes and changes to prioritise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSL setup for Azure with bitnami mediawiki stack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting the Watchlist emails working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting the full banner/logo in there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While fighting for my attention are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting the rest of the MOOC accessibility fixes done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting all the AV102 TA trainees access to the course as betatesters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and further follow up on WebsiteOne, LocalSupport, AsyncVoter; catching up with our sponsor drie etc. etc.  Like I say, the harder I try to run, the more it feels like I&amp;rsquo;m just staying in the same place :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=4DAU-nFUP-U"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=kS3ttK6Wuxw"&gt;Starting Hangouts via AV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=JK9i1NCuHno"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>One Step Forward</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/03/one-step-forward/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/03/one-step-forward/</id>
    <published>2017-05-03T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-13T21:57:44+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="distractions" src="/images/one_step.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I got distracted by Slack and email again this morning.  Wanting to post my last podcast listen into #av&lt;em&gt;community&lt;/em&gt;talk I ended up replying to freerangers last post.  At least today I think I was calmer, and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t so much to catch up with in all the incoming communication channels.  I&amp;rsquo;m definitely struggling with anxiety about getting everything done.  I&amp;rsquo;m less anxious this morning after completing the first round of wiki training with some of the HLP core team yesterday.  The big thing was that the MediaWiki visual editor ultimately loaded on three different NHS laptops and networks, and all the trainees succesfully created edited pages as well as got set up with moderation permissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We never managed to really complete important parts of the design sprint we started a month ago.  The project time and budget wasn&amp;rsquo;t ever going to allow for custom development of a particular solution, so we were reduced to a process of reflecting over the existing solutions.  We&amp;rsquo;ve &amp;ldquo;sneaked&amp;rdquo; in the customer testing phase as part of training everyone in the use of the system.  We&amp;rsquo;ve also failed to &amp;ldquo;prototype&amp;rdquo; in the pure design sprint fashion by using a real software package (MediaWiki) and having that set up and working.  I think the design sprint concept assumes that there&amp;rsquo;s budget and time, following the sprint, to properly deliver the solution to the end users.  A critical part of the overall question for us was whether we could get &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; reasonable solution working on the NHS laptops and networks, and the result from yesterday appears to be yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran an hour long training session and had the trainees try things out for themselves (as we might do in a usability test) before reviewing how things should be done (if they got stuck).  I learned a lot, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;initial sign up confirmation emails were going into some junk mail folders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the sign up process with the ConfirmAccount module was rather burdensome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the visual editor was working in our custom instance on NHS laptops/network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That last element might seem trivial.  One might be tempted to say, well Wikipedia&amp;rsquo;s visual editor worked fine on NHS laptops/network, so of course the same visual editor on our own server will work fine, but if working with computers has taught me anything it&amp;rsquo;s that you really musn&amp;rsquo;t assume that things work as you expect.  Particularly since we moved to MediaWiki after a selection of other high profile enterprise and open source wikis completely failed to load critical icons on the NHS laptops/network, which rendered them completely unusable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve got a series of additional training events to run next week, and in the meantime we&amp;rsquo;ve got a soft launch scheduled for tomorrow.  To support that we need to get a good subset of the following sorted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;backups on our MediaWiki instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ensure we have a fixed IP -&amp;gt; okay because we are CNAMing to the bitnami name &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get SSL set up on our MediaWiki instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;consider whether we remove the ConfirmAccount plugin (is Moderation sufficient?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things we will need to do before next week include&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting the watch list email notifications working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create a training video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;consider whether to add Wikipedia style moderation templates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could easily spend the whole rest of the week completely focused on this, but I&amp;rsquo;ve also got to re-record AV102 videos to reflect the changes to the Google Hangout API, and ensure we&amp;rsquo;ve made all the final accessibility changes on the MOOC which goes live next week.  There&amp;rsquo;s also reviewing all the pull requests for the different AgileVentures projects, and the process of following up with Premiums. I have finally started creating individual private Premium channels to try and distribute the load of supporting the increasing numbers of Premium members.  We can do it, yes we can!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&amp;amp;video_id=4oBrjn-9S3o"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
