<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-09-20T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Clearing the Decks</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/20/clearing-the-decks/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/20/clearing-the-decks/</id>
    <published>2016-09-20T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-20T17:14:36+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Monday involved continuing on two &amp;ldquo;clear the decks&amp;rdquo; tickets that Michael and I had started on the previous Thursday and Friday. The heuristics in my mind thus included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clear the decks before starting on something else big&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finish what you&amp;rsquo;ve started&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deal with things in the &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo; column in your Kanban board to reduce cognitive overload for the team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drive-by coding, i.e. try not to get too bogged down in any one thing, make tickets for additional features, refactorings and so forth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focus on completing one task rather than constantly worrying if it is the right task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and that&amp;rsquo;s forming a nice-ish set, even if some of them aren&amp;rsquo;t that pithy :-) Lots of room for improvement there.  There are parallel collections of heuristics being applied in the actual coding going on, e.g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be confident (don&amp;rsquo;t keep nil checking)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t mock what you don&amp;rsquo;t own; prefer to introduce adapters you control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;follow the testing pyramid (few acceptance, some integration and lots of unit tests)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep methods/classes short&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;try to name methods/classes for understandability and maintainability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start DRYing once it&amp;rsquo;s clear there is a pattern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use Dependency Injection to avoid locking what objects collaborate with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many more could be added to the list, but the above are the set that are more to the forefront of my mind at the moment.  There&amp;rsquo;s a cross-talk between the two levels though, because seeing a place where you could use dependency injection, or introduce an adapter can extend the amount of time on task.  If you&amp;rsquo;re practising &amp;ldquo;drive-by&amp;rdquo; coding, then that&amp;rsquo;s a key place to ask if that refactoring needs to be done now, or if it&amp;rsquo;s something to create a ticket for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might say, you must immediately do any refactoring you think of, and if you put it in a ticket it&amp;rsquo;ll never get done.  However there&amp;rsquo;s a counter-example from the LocalSupport project, where we had a nasty case statement, I created a refactoring ticket, and worked on it with someone later, and we eventually completely removed the case statement and replaced it with a gem using the strategy pattern; so that&amp;rsquo;s at least a proof that it&amp;rsquo;s possible in principle :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing about refactoring is that there&amp;rsquo;s always a little more you could do, but fundamentally we don&amp;rsquo;t know what the future holds.  As needs change maybe that refactoring will have to be undone, or that code thrown out.  That isn&amp;rsquo;t to disregard general code smells, but it is all relative.  Either way you have the interplay of the different heuristics.  Say you notice you could use some dependency injection, and/or some adapters, which do you work on first?  Or put both in a ticket?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the set of heuristics at the higher level there&amp;rsquo;s less conflict for me at the moment.  Focusing on completing one task in a drive-by fashion is all about not getting too distracted, and if the distraction is important, get that distraction into a ticket that you can review later for relative importance and complexity.  Huge ideas about a different direction?  Sure, but let&amp;rsquo;s clear the decks by finishing what we started, especially those things we identified as going in the ready/backlog column in the current sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s all well and good, however the memory leak task that Michael and I started on from the &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo; column &amp;ndash; taking on something another developer didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be progressing on &amp;ndash; was not simple to resolve quickly.  Just investigating the task involves leaving a process running overnight to see what the memory profile is like after 12 hours.  That wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hard to fit into the heuristic since once we had set up a memory profiling experiment we could leave that and move on to something else, but the ticket was still in the &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo; column. Hmm &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mixed shout out to Heroku; positive for their memory profiling beta tools, negative for not getting back to me about the sudden spike in charging us for our group account without warning.  Still I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying seeing memory traces like this one that show the critical memory errors our app is generating in the resting state on develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="memory trace with errors" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/z20m133bcd4b3ph/Screenshot%202016-09-20%2009.09.00.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly those errors are removed from develop by having the setup match production:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="lower trace with from matching production puma workers and threads" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/jqwv7pxtdw41nd0/Screenshot%202016-09-20%2009.09.46.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Production itself still experiences memory errors, but it&amp;rsquo;s under a higher load:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="production memory errors" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/poi23wzp8i0wvg8/Screenshot%202016-09-20%2009.34.00.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re basically following Heroku&amp;rsquo;s tips on getting better &lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/ruby-memory-use"&gt;memory performance from Ruby apps&lt;/a&gt; which has pointed us to the &lt;code&gt;nearest_time_zone&lt;/code&gt; gem as being our biggest memory hog.  Removing it cuts our baseline by about 10% (based on leaving things running overnight):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="reduced baseline profile after removing nearest_timezone" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/8zg6xgvbzz1nn2x/Screenshot%202016-09-20%2009.10.12.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which leaves us with a complicated choice.  Would that 10% reduction actually help us reduce memory errors in production? Can we re-arrange the way the main app works so that we don&amp;rsquo;t use that gem?  Is that worth it?  Following the heuristics, it feels to me we are getting to the end of the &amp;ldquo;investigating the memory errors&amp;rdquo; issue, and into new issues of trying different solutions to the memory errors, as well as needing to consider how serious these memory errors are, in that the app still seems to be running despite them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other task we&amp;rsquo;re bashing away at in parallel is setting up an admin mailer to notify us when the slack invites fail (as they sometimes do).  I&amp;rsquo;d love to drive that with an acceptance test, but the difference in settings in test from production (invites are turned off), and the use of async tasks, means that is a more involved process to create an acceptance test than usual.  We&amp;rsquo;ve gone for a couple of unit tests and pushed the acceptance test into a separate ticket.  This is an example of the higher level heuristics overriding the lower level ones; which makes intuitive sense.  The admin mailer was something we spiked somewhat to get a tracer bullet to see the end to end connection, i.e. see the emails sent.  Although it was ultimately wrapped in a unit test, I berated myself at the end that &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;d written a really clear unit test at the start I&amp;rsquo;d have spent less time in the spike, but then again it was seeing the output from the email spike that helped me understand what I needed to be testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drive with tests?  Sure, but let me spike to understand the problem.  More importantly, please let me drive with an acceptance test.  An architecture that doesn&amp;rsquo;t let me easily add an acceptance test always makes me a little uncomfortable.   More heuristics at the coding level.  My intuition is that it&amp;rsquo;s the higher level heuristics that should over-rule the lower level ones.  So on with clearing the decks.  We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes &amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Videos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qveh4RtiWN4"&gt;Pairing on AV main site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UBo8d0Yebyw"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Business as Usual</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/19/business-as-usual/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/19/business-as-usual/</id>
    <published>2016-09-19T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-19T20:29:13+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Trying to run a business is notoriously hard.  How about a charity?  A volunteer organisation?  I&amp;rsquo;m starting to see some patterns from the last few years.  I notice at the Karate classes that I do with my kids that there&amp;rsquo;s been a huge turnover of participants in the last three years we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing it.  There are people who come once or twice and then you never see them again.  There are people who show up for a period and seem quite committed, like the group of students doing their Duke of Edinburgh award who were saying they wanted to go all the way to black belt, and then there are people who are there every time for a couple of years and then just disappear.  The funny thing, to me, is that pretty much everyone strikes a post of &amp;ldquo;see you next week&amp;rdquo;.  No one says &amp;ldquo;I think I won&amp;rsquo;t come any more&amp;rdquo;.  Maybe they&amp;rsquo;re saying it to the Karate instructor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I speculate that Karate is aspirational, a bit like coding for some people.  I also coach kids football (soccer).  We have a similar sort of pattern with participants coming and going, and generally you&amp;rsquo;re not going to be informed about a change of attendance.   People vary of course.  Sometimes I might get a &amp;ldquo;sorry we&amp;rsquo;ve signed up for another club&amp;rdquo; message on WhatsApp, but it&amp;rsquo;s almost never the kind of thing that&amp;rsquo;s said to you in person.  I&amp;rsquo;ve always found this a little strange.  The other day I mentioned the rough ride I had at 13 telling my music teacher I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to play in the orchestra, while my friends slinked off to avoid any confrontation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of the same thing online sometimes.  One that springs to mind was that I was getting stuck on an issue related to the simplecov gem, and was having an interaction with the gem author in an &lt;a href="https://github.com/colszowka/simplecov-html/issues/41"&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt; and I remember that there were huge currents of work on different things going on at the time, and I just totally failed to respond.  Now I found the issue again I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to go back and at least thank the gem author for their input.  It must be a pretty common experience for open source projects.  You&amp;rsquo;ve potentially got the whole world working on getting something done.  They start a conversation and sometimes it just gets cut off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re unlikely to interact with the person again then you&amp;rsquo;re not strongly incentivised to give them warning about your plans.  I guess the majority of people just want to avoid any conflict and usually won&amp;rsquo;t make the time to say sorry.  In May last year there were lots of people I was meeting daily face to face who were getting my priority attention over open source projects.  Oh yes, and if I remember correctly I did collapse with pneumonia a few days later, so perhaps I can be forgiven :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s something to the scale of our modern civilisation.  In the past I imagine you&amp;rsquo;d have known everyone in your village and it would be much more important to let people know that you were or weren&amp;rsquo;t going to keep on doing something with them.  Maybe not.  Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s always been like this.  If someone asks you if you want to get involved in something, you express an interest, even if really what you&amp;rsquo;re feeling is a no; and then just don&amp;rsquo;t show up on the date.  Of course sometimes people will make the effort to give an explicit no, but most of the time it&amp;rsquo;s easier to say &amp;ldquo;yes/probably/maybe&amp;rdquo; and that keeps your options open.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something we observed when we were using G+ to organise pairing events, and something that is common to most meetup gatherings I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, is that out of the people that sign up to say they will attend, 50% or less will actually turn up.  If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to run a voluntary organisation then people who sound like they are committing but don&amp;rsquo;t show up can be incredibly draining.  I remember when we started AgileVentures, talking to the AirPair founder who said he was just sick of volunteering groups.  He&amp;rsquo;d been trying to organise a voluntary rock-climbing group for people to find rock-climbing partners, and at the time it didn&amp;rsquo;t dissuade me from trying AgileVentures as a purely voluntary organisation.  We had such numbers as a result of the interest in the MOOC that I thought why not give it a try, and we certainly accomplished a lot of cool things, but it is frustrating when you put a lot of effort and energy answering someone&amp;rsquo;s questions, helping them get set up and then they just disappear without so much as a word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an aspect of this in business too.  For every 10 people that you explain your product to, you might be lucky to get one customer; but in a business at least when you get that customer they&amp;rsquo;re paying for all the &amp;ldquo;marketing/sales&amp;rdquo; work (if you&amp;rsquo;ve priced things right).  In a voluntary organisation that&amp;rsquo;s much more draining.  I gave up doing face to face AgileVentures meetups in central London after it seemed that I would spend all my time greeting, being friendly, answering questions, for not much follow up.  Sometimes people would be really intense, asking lots and lots of questions, monopolising the discussion when other people were waiting to ask, or move on; talk about how involved they were going to get, and then totally disappear.  At least by being completely online, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with the logistical overhead of getting into central London, arranging a place for a meet up, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally it would make quite a big difference to me if people emailed or texted to say, thanks for your help the other night, but I think this isn&amp;rsquo;t for me; and then give a little more input on why it&amp;rsquo;s not a match.  However the chances are they will never encounter me again, so there&amp;rsquo;s not much upside for them in doing that, and the downside of risking all that unpleasant confrontation that everyone fears.  Honest feedback would be truly valuable but there isn&amp;rsquo;t much incentive for people to give it.  It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to get that feedback from the people who know you best, such as family, friends and work colleagues, let alone total strangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny, though; we had some people in the last few weeks I&amp;rsquo;d love to have got that feedback from.  We had one person jumping into a scrum (after a series of emails and slacks) who wanted to propose a new project, which sounded really interesting, and the guy was really keen.  We set up a chat room for him, promoted it, got a few people in there, and then nothing.  No communication whatsoever, my follow up emails ignored.  Of course he may have dropped with pneumonia like I did last year, who knows.  However it leads me to question the whole concept of the AgileVentures &amp;ldquo;open to all to make a pitch&amp;rdquo; - I mean I guess we did&amp;rsquo;t lose that much, but it&amp;rsquo;s just strange not to have any follow up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s similarity with onboarding to projects like LocalSupport.  There&amp;rsquo;s some people we&amp;rsquo;ve spent the time to onboard who go on to contribute loads, but others were we spend a fair amount of time trying to get them setup, and then we just don&amp;rsquo;t hear from them again.  I mean fair enough - people work out the project isn&amp;rsquo;t for them, other stuff in their life comes up.  However, it would just be nice to get a text or email saying &amp;ldquo;this isn&amp;rsquo;t for me&amp;rdquo; and maybe a bit of feedback.  I&amp;rsquo;m left confused about whether there&amp;rsquo;s anything we can do to make a difference.  Better onboarding documentation?  More friendly in the chatroom? Our whole site and setup just looking more professional? Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s nothing we can do to make a difference.  The question in my mind is do people realise that when they are asking for help to get setup that they are taking up valuable resources from our voluntary organisation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward I think I have to assume this is just the way people are.  Part of the valuable offering of a bootcamp or university is the filtering mechanism that means that, rather than a random group of people you might get in a MOOC, you get a group of smart, motivated people, who are really committed to studying together.  Having members of a group that are not as committed can be really draining on everybody, particularly in terms of logistics, e.g. team members not showing up etc.  Hence our switch to providing a premium level of AgileVentures.  Those in the premium tier are necessarily more committed.  Similarly for the new &amp;ldquo;Agile Development using Ruby on Rails&amp;rdquo; project course, which will be paid-only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be nice to think that super UX and value proposition by themselves could lead to the critical mass we&amp;rsquo;re looking forward.  That&amp;rsquo;s what FreeCodeCamp is going for, but trying to extract revenue from companies that hire their graduates.  I&amp;rsquo;d be interested to know how that&amp;rsquo;s really going. I&amp;rsquo;m certainly very impressed with their interface.  Still maybe there&amp;rsquo;s something in the saying that if you&amp;rsquo;re NOT paying for something, then YOU are the product.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>DriveBy Coding</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/16/driveby-coding/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/16/driveby-coding/</id>
    <published>2016-09-16T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-16T18:51:40+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Had another day of trying to work quick and light. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of calling it &amp;ldquo;drive-by coding&amp;rdquo;.  The idea is to try and avoid getting stuck for too long on any one thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to be good to my word of yesterday and get to work on some of the static site content issues that I had been putting off.  These were suggestions that had come out of feedback on the site from Charles and Freeranger.  Charles is a Sales specialist and we&amp;rsquo;d been working with him before the summer on the design of the static site.  We&amp;rsquo;d been having regular meetings with Charles and he was pushing for detailed documentation on what we would be offering to charities and non-profits in terms of hourly rates and detailed breakdowns of inception events and so forth. The attempts to pin us down on hourly rates up front, and then add his own hourly-rate to the inception packages made me feel &amp;hellip; strange.  It felt very &amp;ldquo;big design up-front&amp;rdquo; and not very Agile.  I felt like we needed to talk to individual non-profits about their needs; although part of it is that I wanted to focus on coding, and also that as more people signed up for our premium memberships we effectively had &amp;ldquo;customers&amp;rdquo; who we could talk to directly and try and evolve our service to make them happier and bring others on board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course as Michael has pointed out, if we could land a good sizeable charity project, then that would dwarf the amounts coming in from premium memberships.  The difficulty for me is that the approach Charles was taking seemed to involve lots and lots of paperwork up front - trying to make decisions with little data about the market.  Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s the way businesses should run?  Make a detailed business plan before talking to anybody outside, relying on your instinct to put the right kind of plan together.  Charles has lots of experience selling IT related things in the corporate world and some experience of the charity sector, so maybe I should be trusting his intuition, but my instinct told me to go with a softer incremental launch of the static site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;d told Charles we&amp;rsquo;d do that soft launch and get back to him.  We pushed out the site to our internal group on Slack, and got some immediate feedback.  In particular we got very detailed feedback from Freeranger in a set of five issues on Github (see issues 36 through 40 on &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/av-static-website/issues"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/av-static-website/issues&lt;/a&gt;), in which he wrote almost stream of consciousness as he explored the site.  Very valuable stuff, but also quite overwhelming.  I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about overloading before.  I think I do it to people a lot.  Freeranger and I have some things in common there :-)  Anyway, the concerns that Freeranger was raising were valid ones, but I was emotionally knocked back by the thought of what we needed to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s not entirely accurate.  We had made good progress before the summer on trying to address a number of the issues.  Probably the most complex was switching from the ghost blog as a separate site, to an integrated middleman-blog, which was a round about way of addressing a number of the navigation issues that Freeranger raised, and also reduced our need to maintain two separate copies of the CSS design.  Actually we created a summary ticket called &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/av-static-website/issues/42"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tweaking Ready for Release&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; that only had a single thing outstanding on it, adding some more links in the about section.  Trying to pin down my feelings here, I think the concerns raised by Freeranger had knocked my confidence in the site.  Michael and I had done a fair amount of work to get it to a point for a soft launch.  We&amp;rsquo;d set about fixing the issues, but we&amp;rsquo;d done the engineering work and finally there was just content work (more or less) which I was loathe to subject Michael too, so I&amp;rsquo;d been putting it off and other items in my administrative agenda kept seeming to trump it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yesterday I forced it to the top of my morning agenda, at least partly inspired by enthusiasm from Marouen about getting some charity clients in, and I knocked off that immediate content work, and completed our tweaking for release ticket, yay!  I also went back through Freeranger&amp;rsquo;s issues again slowly and carefully.  A lot of the feedback was great UX feedback about buttons vs nav and the consistency of using the back-button etc.  I spent some time responding how I thought some of our changes had now addressed some of the issues, and created other tickets for those we hadn&amp;rsquo;t been able to quickly resolve (see issues 55 through 58 on &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/av-static-website/issues"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/av-static-website/issues&lt;/a&gt;.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to the thing that probably concerns me the most, which is improving the images associated with some of the projects in the case-studies section; and that will have to wait till next week now.  That&amp;rsquo;s more complex as it involves liasing with different project groups &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But so I made progress in the morning with &amp;ldquo;drive-by administration&amp;rdquo; and got down to some coding in the afternoon with Michael.  It didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like we made as much progress as the previous day, but in drive-by coding style we moved through the ProjectScope project where we spiked a time report that would help us assess if the heroku schedule was working as expected, and then on to WebSiteOne where, although I was getting all excited about a new event telemetry, creation flow, karma and premium promotion, I thought that if we were serious about keeping the Waffle board under control we really should address tickets in terms of their position in the board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience a project board can become a kind of dumping ground unless you are ruthless with it.  At least it&amp;rsquo;s easy to leave a ticket hanging in the &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo; column because it hasn&amp;rsquo;t quite been resolved, and/or you&amp;rsquo;re not sure what to do with it.  I&amp;rsquo;m starting to think that it&amp;rsquo;s more dangerous to leave it there, eating up some of everyone&amp;rsquo;s cognitive resources every time they review the board.  There&amp;rsquo;s nothing like some empty columns to give people the motivation to take on new stuff.  Of course this means the process for getting tickets into the right columns and in priority order in the first place has to be good, but that&amp;rsquo;s another story.  My new resolution is to close out old tickets with what we&amp;rsquo;ve learnt and then create new tickets based on more complex or uncertain stuff that arises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Michael and I &amp;ldquo;drove by&amp;rdquo; the WebSiteOne board taking on tickets where we could in the in-progress column. We fixed up some outstanding work on the stripe credit card change sad path, and got the PR ready for review. We jumped on the &amp;ldquo;out of memory&amp;rdquo; issue and got in a quick PR that might help us explore (if not fix) the issue.  Drive on - we started on the issue that the site admin is not alerted when slack invites fail, since we were realising we wanted a similar alert system as an extension to the card change fail for stripe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m liking the narrative that&amp;rsquo;s emerging about sticking to what&amp;rsquo;s organised on the board to help you work with the team, and keep the decks clear for when bigger issues arise.  Avoid things gathering dust.  And then also driving-by tickets, getting a little action, furiously making other tickets so that a sliver of work can be marked closed. Then longer more complex follow-ups can be evaluated on subsequent passes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I really must go sort Heroku who&amp;rsquo;s now charging us to high heaven for our group account.  There&amp;rsquo;s no point in us bringing in loads of new premium members if we can&amp;rsquo;t keep our server costs down.  Heroku might give us leniency as a charity, but I won&amp;rsquo;t hold my breath.  Mustn&amp;rsquo;t let this one slide &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Videos associated with this blog:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gx4mgVQuyzo"&gt;ProjectScope Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GDPrd9ixTAU"&gt;WebSiteOne Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E5bH5F-EaOc"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Feels like Progress</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/15/feels-like-progress/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/15/feels-like-progress/</id>
    <published>2016-09-15T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-15T21:31:38+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wednesday felt good this week.  Son cycling to high school by himself for a second day - those extra 40 minutes really coming in handy to catch up with administrative stuff.  The automation of the thunderbird mailing allowing me to send 20 emails a day and have some nice chats with the AgileVentures members who respond.  Even more pleasing was the afternoon&amp;rsquo;s programming.  Hadn&amp;rsquo;t got to the static site in the morning; although I had got two reasonable clips of good pairing activities to share with TAs and instructors.  So I suggested to Michael we should try and make some progress on some small niggles on the static site.  Part of me was, oh, we should be pushing on with AgileBot, but I also wanted to put that down to settle and clear up some presentation stuff that was bugging me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging daily through the middleman-blog we have on &lt;a href="http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/"&gt;http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/&lt;/a&gt; means I was seeing things like the font-size of html lists &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/av-static-website/issues/48"&gt;feeling too small&lt;/a&gt;. Fixed that in a few minutes, and was straight on to dealing with a &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/av-static-website/issues/46"&gt;presentation issue&lt;/a&gt; identified by another AV member.  They&amp;rsquo;d also submitted a pull request which we reviewed.  It looked pretty good full size, but it seemed to break the mobile view.  Looking back perhaps we should have started debugging why it broke the mobile view, but it felt simpler and faster to just go with the initial suggestion of smaller font sizes from the original ticket, and kicking things around we ended up removing a couple of icons, and switching the text-align to centred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael was saying that we&amp;rsquo;d spent time getting those icons in there, and that we should switch text-alignments from mobile to desktop views, and I think he was right, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend a big chunk of time on that now.  I suggested we put a further refactoring ticket in and just deploy the fix we had, which was a basic improvement, not wonderfully elegant, but I wanted to move fast.  The narrative in my mind was let&amp;rsquo;s move fast; avoid getting bogged down in too much discussion (usually my fault) and if something turns out to be trickier than we anticipate we should do the simple thing and open a new ticket for any more complex work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael concurred and we switched drivers, and he fixed up the pagination for the blog posts.  The great thing about working with a static middleman site like this is that we can get fixes into production pretty much instantaneously.  In under an hour we&amp;rsquo;d fixed up three presentation issues with the static site, and I was already feeling more positive about pushing it out on social media.  There was still a little swathe of content related work that I feel should be fixed before we really start pushing it to non-profits - linking it into the main developer site and so on.  I resolved to work on that during my admin period today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Move fast, quick fix - push things off into other tickets.  What I really wanted to get to was this mobile presentation bug on the main developer site (AgileVentures WebsiteOne).  On the main site on desktop we have these floating call outs promoting different aspects of our mission:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="shout out on main site" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/2e7z3nz6he927w9/Screenshot%202016-09-15%2008.56.23.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which look pretty good to me.  Unfortunately on mobile they end up looking like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="shout out on mobile" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/z5te1eewurcalcq/Screenshot%202016-09-15%2008.57.46.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if they always looked like that on mobile, or if that&amp;rsquo;s how they ended up after some change in the CSS.  That design was all put in place before I took on the project manager role, and to be honest I don&amp;rsquo;t spend that much time looking at web sites on mobile, but hey it&amp;rsquo;s the future, right? :-) We&amp;rsquo;ve got to look good on mobile.  Freeranger had helped us fix up some navigation problems on the mobile view a few months back, which was a great improvement, and it was then that I&amp;rsquo;d noticed the layout issue.  Just me perhaps, but the lack of space around the shout out just feels crowded; looks wrong.  Maybe there are loads of other issues with our mobile view that I&amp;rsquo;m missing &amp;hellip; reminds me we have an issue that you can&amp;rsquo;t click through on individual users on mobile, but anyway, what I wanted the shout outs to look like on mobile was this (more or less):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="shout on on mobile improved" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/2jz1upu2fn34tpp/Screenshot%202016-09-15%2009.02.36.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which turned out to be achievable with a pretty small change; specifically the addition on the &lt;code&gt;margin&lt;/code&gt; elements in the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight css"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nc"&gt;.section-well&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nl"&gt;padding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="m"&gt;1em&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nl"&gt;margin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="m"&gt;1em&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nl"&gt;border-radius&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="m"&gt;10px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nl"&gt;overflow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;hidden&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;@media&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;min-width&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;screen-sm-min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nc"&gt;.section-well&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;padding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="m"&gt;1em&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="m"&gt;2em&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;margin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="m"&gt;0em&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, job done, another micro pull-request pushed up, and I was feeling pretty pleased.  This presentation issue had been bugging me for months; a constant drag on my level of enthusiasm for promoting the site.  Ironically I think casual viewers of the sites tend to be positive.  I guess it&amp;rsquo;s easy to be over-critical of the things we work on; although there&amp;rsquo;s the argument that the cumulative effect of many rough edges is its own drag on everything else you are trying to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then we switched gear and Marcelo joined us from SF to go through a LocalSupport pull-request.  He had less than an hour, so we didn&amp;rsquo;t really have time to get into pairing, but he and I had already async git ponged on a &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/LocalSupport/pull/348"&gt;related refactoring&lt;/a&gt;, and then he had done the same with Marouen on an &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/LocalSupport/pull/359"&gt;alternative approach using a 3rd party gem&lt;/a&gt;.  The full details are maybe worth another blog post on the evolution from hacky case statement fix, to our refactoring of that into something more maintainable, to the realisation that there was a gem that pretty much did what we needed.  In the session with Marcelo we reviewed all that, including the internals of the gem, and how the LocalSupport site used cookies and how the gem could be integrated with Cucumber stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was great to hook up with Marcelo, but he had to dash off to work, and so Michael and I finished up with some clean up related to the Stripe credit card change feature, with Michael popping in a sad path to give the user better information when card update fails, and I dealt with some legacy data migration.  The day finished up for me with the Kent Beck scrum where Michael and I reviewed our possible next steps, which include further work on making premium membership more visible in WebSiteOne, improving the flow of the event pairing mechanism and increasing the resolution of the pairing tracking telemetry so that we can give our users more Karma for the scrums and pairing sessions they are involved in.  Like I say, it was a day where it felt like we were making some progress :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pairing Videos related to this blog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lbcH6Gqr-I0"&gt;Pairing on Static Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e84n_wBP7_c"&gt;LocalSupport PR review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nuyODPgitIk"&gt;Pairing on WebsiteOne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=60EREsMw00o"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Production and Staging Similarity</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/14/production-staging-similarity/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/14/production-staging-similarity/</id>
    <published>2016-09-14T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-14T21:18:16+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So Michael and I finished up an important piece of work on the AgileBot yesterday.  At least we completed something we had started working on a while ago, which was getting the AgileBot legacy code wrapped in tests, and refactoring the config out of the main script file.  It seems like a good heuristic to finish what you start, although of course there&amp;rsquo;s always the danger of throwing good money after bad, or rather time; since time is of course, money.  It&amp;rsquo;s definitely been an interesting process though, and it feels very good to get to this point where we can catch our breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before, AgileBot is a chunk of CoffeeScript that takes incoming requests to send notifications about hangouts from WebSiteOne (our Rails monolith for AgileVentures) and pass them on to Slack and Gitter.  AgileBot&amp;rsquo;s CoffeeScript runs in Hubot (which runs on Node) and is deployed on Heroku.  AgileBot was an experiment from a couple of years ago to see what could be achieved in CoffeeScript (a Ruby flavoured variant of JavaScript) and Hubot.  Hubot has a range of functions and is extendible to allow it to respond to users in chat rooms, which is certainly something I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in in the past.  Chatbots tend to become annoying rather quickly though, and users will often fail to take them seriously, although we do read reports of some &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/innovations/wp/2016/05/11/this-professor-stunned-his-students-when-he-revealed-the-secret-identity-of-his-teaching-assistant/"&gt;chatbots fooling students into thinking they are human&lt;/a&gt; in some online classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to be deploying really effective chatbot tech, but we&amp;rsquo;re a small community and I think we&amp;rsquo;re in the stage where value is being derived from authentic connections between humans, rather than automating 1000&amp;rsquo;s of responses.  We&amp;rsquo;ve totally not played with the range of functions that Hubot can support, and the AgileBot script is taking advantage of Hubot&amp;rsquo;s ability to act like an API endpoint to act as a waypoint between our Rails monolith and the 3rd party endpoints of Gitter and Slack.  We&amp;rsquo;ve been making little changes to the AgileBot script over the months, and the lack of tests was a little nerve-wracking.  After tweaking the Jasmine tests on HangoutConnection we thought, yeah, let&amp;rsquo;s get some tests wrapped around AgileBot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve blogged about parts of that before, and my nagging concern is that we could have completely re-created this micro service as a gem in our Rails monolith, or as a separate Sinatra micro service, faster than we could get the tests working and fix the associated issues.  In the meantime, particularly valiant solo efforts from Michael have got us to the point where the code is wrapped in integration tests, the config is refactored, and yesterday we got the new AgileBot deployed in production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big hurdle that came up at the end was that when we deployed the new code to the staging server we saw a thrashing in the logs.  The logs were dumping what looked like the entire list of our slack instance users in JSON format, and that&amp;rsquo;s so big we couldn&amp;rsquo;t see the actual error message.  It was this issue that we really took apart yesterday.  It was a tricky issue and while speculating about whether we&amp;rsquo;d been hacked, or the upgrade had changed some node modules out from under us, we made some progress by managing to replicate the error locally.  This took us copying the entire staging server config locally and running the hubot locally just as it would run on the Heroku server.  This allowed us to see some error specifics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;node_redis: no callback to send error: OOM command not allowed when used memory &amp;gt; 'maxmemory'.
[Tue Sep 13 2016 14:50:21 GMT+0100 (BST)] ERROR Error: OOM command not allowed when used memory &amp;gt; 'maxmemory'.
  at ReplyParser.&amp;lt;anonymous&amp;gt; (/Users/tansaku/Documents/GitHub/AgileVentures/agile-bot/node_modules/hubot-scripts/node_modules/redis/index.js:279:27)
  at emitOne (events.js:77:13)
  at ReplyParser.emit (events.js:169:7)
  at ReplyParser.send_error (/Users/tansaku/Documents/GitHub/AgileVentures/agile-bot/node_modules/hubot-scripts/node_modules/redis/lib/parser/javascript.js:296:10)
  at ReplyParser.execute (/Users/tansaku/Documents/GitHub/AgileVentures/agile-bot/node_modules/hubot-scripts/node_modules/redis/lib/parser/javascript.js:181:22)
  at RedisClient.on_data (/Users/tansaku/Documents/GitHub/AgileVentures/agile-bot/node_modules/hubot-scripts/node_modules/redis/index.js:504:27)
  at Socket.&amp;lt;anonymous&amp;gt; (/Users/tansaku/Documents/GitHub/AgileVentures/agile-bot/node_modules/hubot-scripts/node_modules/redis/index.js:82:14)
  at emitOne (events.js:77:13)
  at Socket.emit (events.js:169:7)
  at readableAddChunk (_stream_readable.js:146:16)
  at Socket.Readable.push (_stream_readable.js:110:10)
  at TCP.onread (net.js:523:20)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it seemed like we might be having a problem with Redis, the key-value cache that Hubot uses as a memory.  We&amp;rsquo;d copied over the Redis URL in the server config, so our local Hubot was also hitting the same Redis cache as the staging server.  We cycled through various loops of trying to clear out that Redis cache, but to no avail.  Our AgileBot script doesn&amp;rsquo;t use Redis at all.  It&amp;rsquo;s just part of booting up Hubot, which also has its own Slack connections and code.  That we&amp;rsquo;re spending time debugging something that&amp;rsquo;s not really related to our microservice logic is fuel for my thoughts that we would move faster building an express or Sinatra app, but maybe getting distracted by those thoughts are counter-productive &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow we couldn&amp;rsquo;t seem to empty the Redis cache.  Even with resets and flushes and shutting everything down it still seemed to be filling up. We also tried deploying the master branch of the production code to staging and got the same thrashing issue.  This was an important step - we&amp;rsquo;d isolated the problem as not being related to any of the new code changes we&amp;rsquo;d introduced.  That&amp;rsquo;s such a crucial step when debugging.  All our speculations about how all sorts of updates might be influencing this thrashing issue could be thrown out, and we could focus on the problem being either the Redis cache, or some unknown upgrade of a node module.  It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to me that npm doesn&amp;rsquo;t create a lock of the particular versions that get installed.  When we use bundle in the Ruby world we get a Gemfile.lock, and if you check that in the versions of libraries that you&amp;rsquo;re using can&amp;rsquo;t change.  Unless I&amp;rsquo;m missing something npm seems much more permissive.  At least if you don&amp;rsquo;t check in the node_modules directory itself then any time you do a fresh install (say on Heroku) then you&amp;rsquo;re doing the equivalent of Ruby&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;bundle update&lt;/code&gt;.  Maybe the Heroku build pack for node mitigates that somehow, but it feels like the node/npm keeps you more on the bleeding edge of your libraries?  That&amp;rsquo;s both exhilarating and frightening! :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fix for our thrashing problem came when Michael noticed that we had different Redis plugins on the production and staging instances of AgileBot.  HerokuRedis on production and RedisToGo on staging.  We uninstalled RedisToGo and installed HerokuRedis on staging.  The bug was gone locally, and gone from staging too.   A great reminder of how you really really really want staging to be as much like production as possible.  We were now able to proceed with doing manual acceptance tests of staging to check that hits from WebSiteOne would cause AgileBot to ping our Slack instance (but in suitable test channels), and that wasn&amp;rsquo;t working.  We spent some time trying to get live debugging working in the context of Hubot, which was partially successful.  Michael wrote a debug Hubot script, and we got node-inspector running, and finally got the chrome inspector hooked on the debugger, but there was a time out and we lost the connection.  I&amp;rsquo;ve seen that with Rails running on Puma - the web server timeouts killing the debugger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We gave up on that - worked out how to post to the Hubot logs, and then saw that the problem was that our slack token wasn&amp;rsquo;t set correctly.  Fixin that our manual acceptance tests worked.  We deployed to production just in time for a live test running the &amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum - everything worked fine, and over night I can see the PacificRim scrum notified fine, and the days pair notifications came through fine too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Kent Beck scrum Michael and I took stock, comparing the hours spent on getting the bots&amp;rsquo; legacy code wrapped in tests and deployed.  Michael thinks we spent less time getting to this point than we would trying to rebuild.  He might be right, but I think there&amp;rsquo;s a range of rebuilding options including just switching to JavaScript, moving to express, or moving to Sinatra, with each having different pros/cons and likely times to completion.  Undeniably we are much more familiar with the Node/Hubot/CoffeeScript tech stack now, and that information is valuable.  Having got this far it would be silly not to now make a few more refactoring to AgileBot to deliver some noticeable improvements to our users, and see how our regression suite helps us make those changes; that much is clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The itch I still want to scratch though is how fast I could make an express or Sinatra micro service to do the same thing.  Am I delusional that I think I could do the Sinatra one in a couple of days and the express one in half a day?  I won&amp;rsquo;t drag Michael on that whale hunt :-) I think that&amp;rsquo;s just something I need to waste my own spare time on to help in my internal estimation process.  I also worry that my constant questioning of the architecture of the system is kind of draining for people.  I want to work on the things that will deliver the most value to our users, and in turn generate revenue for AgileVentures that makes the whole charity enterprise sustainable.  I have so many thoughts, so many possibilities, but it really isn&amp;rsquo;t clear to me where to focus.  Would it be easier for everyone if I just pretended that I was certain that a particular approach was the best? :-) Maybe that debate is just something that I should be having internally without dumping it on other people through blogs, scrums and pairing sessions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just love that feeling when you can jump up a level and say, right, we don&amp;rsquo;t need to build X, we can achieve our goal by building Y.  I love jumping those levels.  I guess many others like to stay focused on one level, at least for longer than I do.  If one thing is certain it is that I think too much :-) More doing, less thinking/debating perhaps? :-) Still, the whole reason I enjoy working with AV is thinking about the architectural/team/structural decisions and how they can make us more efficient and sustainable.  I&amp;rsquo;ll save the other thoughts I have on that for another micro-services blog.  In the meantime I think we can reflect that pithy sayings and heuristics can often be contradictory, but the take home today is: make sure your production and staging environments are as similar as they can possibly be!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Eye on the Ball</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/13/eye-on-the-ball/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/13/eye-on-the-ball/</id>
    <published>2016-09-13T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-14T13:41:56+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My last few days have been taken up a lot with transferring data between iPhones.  This has been precipitated by the gradually faltering abilities of my 2 year old iPhone 5S:  Trickle charge not working, normal charging intermittent except with specific cables.  Also, my eldest son is starting cycling to a high school that&amp;rsquo;s some distance away.  He wants a phone to stay in touch with his circle of friends, some of whom are starting at other schools even further away.  My wife and I have been &amp;ldquo;technologically conservative&amp;rdquo;.  We&amp;rsquo;ve held off getting a phone for him, while his peer group now all seems to have one and use texting and whatsapp to arrange get togethers etc.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the social pressure has mounted to get him a phone.  The last 10 days I&amp;rsquo;ve been cycling with him to school to check his road safety, and that&amp;rsquo;s great exercise and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to spend the time with him, but it&amp;rsquo;s taking a good 40 minutes plus out of my work day, which is difficult given I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get the new AgileVentures charity enterprise off the ground (burning my savings to do so), and also my increasing commitments to the under eights football team, which has had an explosion of players this season.  Anyhow, so I bought an iPhone SE directly from Apple because I&amp;rsquo;m not interested in a larger phone.  What I should have done was do the immediate sync of data, but as I do recently when I upgrade laptops, I was tempted not to in order to switch items over one at a time.  Have a clear out so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That approach has worked very well for me on laptops.  Going through the re-install process for all the software and projects is a sharp reminder of the install process for people trying to onboard onto our AgileVentures open source projects.  However it turned out to be a bad choice for a quick move to the new phone, or at least, a bad choice when I was trying to quickly decommission the old phone so that my son could use it, take it with him on the commute to school and calm my &amp;ldquo;he&amp;rsquo;ll be knocked off his bike and not be able to phone for help!&amp;rdquo; paranoia sufficiently so I can reclaim the missing 40 minutes of my day that I need to get back on top of the current work avalanche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s rather frustrating is the time I invested in the independent move of data - re-entering all my email data, migrating whatsapp messages through iCloud etc., but the real sticking point was the 1Password app.  I got that on iPhone a couple of years ago. It works really well; allows me to manage complex passwords for things that really should be secure like Stripe on the phone.  However since I got 1password on my iPhone they&amp;rsquo;ve pivoted their approach so that now there are family and business accounts; new approaches to sharing.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also been using LastPass, but they charge for their mobile support, so I was finding myself in a sticky situation.  I&amp;rsquo;d burned a lot of time with a gradual transfer that kind of relied on me having my old phone around as backup.  However I needed to give up the old phone to my son, and although he&amp;rsquo;s pretty responsible, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance he might lose it, and so I really need to wipe all the old data off that phone before giving it to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of time was burnt on that last night that I would have preferred to spend on practising the guitar or working on next Saturday&amp;rsquo;s football training session for the under-eights.  It&amp;rsquo;s all quite stressful, not least because of the memories it brings up of my own high-school days, and this transition involving my eldest son taking/getting more and more independence! :-)  Judgement call on judgement call!  I went for doing the sync after all, throwing out the time I had spent on the step by step, and despite knowing that maybe there would be problems with doing the sync itself.  My old phone was still on iOS7 (I&amp;rsquo;d got conservative. As an iOS dev I knew you couldn&amp;rsquo;t downgrade once you upgrade), the new one is on iOS10, but thank goodness it worked out.  All the old apps including 1Password now work on the new phone; although I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have the heart to do a full test of all the Japanese banking apps yet &amp;hellip;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the other thing is this new &amp;ldquo;Find Friends&amp;rdquo; app - I upgraded what is now my son&amp;rsquo;s phone to iOS10 and it seems I can now track where he is.  So he cycled to high school by himself for the first time this morning and I was able to follow his progress.  He texted me to say he had got to school, and I could see he was there.  Big brother or what!  This really does feel like science fiction, although clearly it&amp;rsquo;s been totally possible for the last 10 years or so; that it was such a relatively simple set up on iOS10 gives me pause for thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so now I&amp;rsquo;m poised to reclaim that 40 minutes, and get on top of the meaty topics of the week.  Yesterday Michael and I added some tests to, and merged in, a PR on ProjectScope that allows us to update all the metrics using a rake task.  I popped that in a Heroku scheduler so that they&amp;rsquo;ll be daily updates of project metrics.  Clearly key for the Berkeley teaching assistants who are each going to be trying to monitor 8 or so different project teams this semester.  With some misgivings I started using Waffle to organise our workflow, but I think we identified the critical path.  The key thing was a new instance for the Berkeley TAs to use.  The client (Armando) wanted every end point secure, which we&amp;rsquo;ll try to get on today, but I wanted to check that deploy process and the scheduler first - that&amp;rsquo;s critical (Make one change at a time).  We&amp;rsquo;re finding the encrypted application.yml file a bit of a handful - probably more on that tomorrow, but the big thing was that we saw that we now couldn&amp;rsquo;t have a free-tier Heroku instance in our AgileVentures team on Heroku, and more catastrophically they&amp;rsquo;d upgraded our legacy apps to paying tiers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Careful review showed that a cluster of apps that were all redundant had each been accumulating charges of $7 a month for the last three months or so.  Not good for a struggling charity startup.  Michael started shutting down the apps, and I contacted Heroku customer support to ask for a refund.  We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes &amp;hellip; frustrating stuff.  I totally understand Heroku changing their plan there.  We were using the team feature of Heroku for free for a long while since we took it up as an early beta.   I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;happy&amp;rdquo; to pay for our key apps to run on the team, but this all feels like a stab out of the blue.  Did I miss an email alerting me about this?  Have I not been keeping my eye on the ball?  Investigation required, but it seems like the key is keep focusing on doing things that will free up time like ensuring the transition of old phone to son; printing and laminating a FAQ for the under eights football team so I can hand them out to parents to avoid spending time trying to explain things to them while running a practise session; and ruthlessly eliminating, simplifying, automating or delegating anything and everything I spend my time doing during the working day.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
