<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-09-22T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Another free refill?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/22/another-free-refill/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/22/another-free-refill/</id>
    <published>2017-09-22T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-27T21:07:18+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="free refill" src="/images/freerefill.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I undertook a training session targeting small business manager to teach them how to improve profitability of business projects. The course instructor showed us a rather clear way to deal with profitabiliy. First, you estimate your break-even hourly rate, based on your history. Then, you don&amp;rsquo;t sell any project under the bottom line. After that, you prioritize your work to put the highest priority on the most profitable projects. Finally, you keep any accepted project above the bottom line. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is quite simple. It&amp;rsquo;s all down to the execution. I began to schedule my workday according to business priorities preferably to a sense of urgency that overcame me before. Then, everytime I felt I was at risk to hit the bottom line, I shifted my attention towards what I really sold to the client annd I reduced my objectives accordingly. Finally, I was trying to become a project reviewer for a well known MOOC platform. But the hourly rate was much too low. I felt relief to drop my candidature. Paid projects management improved greatly. But, a significant part of my workday, dedicated to volunteer projects, was out of the scope of this effort.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many commitments, workaholism, things we begin and we never achieve, any freelance worker faces these contradictions. The inherent contradiction is even stronger when you work on non-paid project. How to prioritize your volunteer works?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten working hours a day is my upper limit, considering that I&amp;rsquo;m not a computer nerd, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a family, hobbies, and a social life &amp;hellip; I was already busy ten hours a day. Adding anything to my schedule implied removing something else. I have been more or less active on professional social networks for three years. I first thought this commitment would improve my reputation and fuel my prospect pipeline. But in three years, the return was not very encouraging. I felt that my social network activity was fueled by bitterness or anxiety or ego or the three rather than by a clear sense of business opportunity! I decided to forget social networks. Two to three hours a week were freed thanks to this good resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to devote these hours to Agile Venture mob programming sessions. It&amp;rsquo;s a real community, with real developers. You can both learn by observing how skilled developers work and by doing things by yourself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still in the midstream of my prioritization effort. I&amp;rsquo;ve been very actively participating in MOOCs for five years. My skills greatly improved as a result of this effort.  But choosing which courses to invest on is not easy. Knowledge is a bit like indirects costs. You don&amp;rsquo;t really know how to assign it to your achievements. During the first years, the offer flourished. I tried many courses, from Economy to Computer Sciences. I progressively focused on Computer Science and left courses as they switched to paid offers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was giving up, a prominent MOOC platform offers me to beta-test courses for free. Free refill is the end of resolution and the beginning of passive hyperactivity! You may begin your training week with a course on Embedded systems and end, on friday, with a course on PythonML on friday, without completing any. Does it make sense to participate in a mob programming session about RSPEC on monday, another one about phoenix on wednesday, on the last one about React on friday, when you only need to develop a small web app with React?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AgileVenture Premium Mob includes some kind of Professional Development Planning Support. I may ask the team to help me clean my training plan. But I&amp;rsquo;m still afraid they will tell me to stop learning Tensor Flow or the nitty gritty of Intel Parallel Architecture if I don&amp;rsquo;t have any prospect to work in these fields in the next year! &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV Website Review Part 2</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/06/av-website-review-part-two/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/06/av-website-review-part-two/</id>
    <published>2017-07-06T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-28T21:23:26+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m deeply tempted to continue with the premium page review.  I think making all the new questions have their explanations in pop-out form would probably be an improvement, but I know that&amp;rsquo;s a sticky hour or so of manipulating HTML.  Very unDRY, something we could, or perhaps should, be doing with a DB backed loop through a template, but setting up (and deploying that) would be another few hours and days.  I&amp;rsquo;m leaning towards further review of the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page, although we did make a change to that on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s too early to tell if those changes have had any impact.  We can look for changes via Google Analytics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/yyyf9ykhy0tc68u/Screenshot%202017-07-06%2009.17.13.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and compare Monday to Wednesday last week, with Monday to Wednesday this week.  The number of clicks through WebSiteOne has gone down, although we can see it went up for some other projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/39tiao9ajhshqib/Screenshot%202017-07-06%2009.18.11.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far too early to discern any trend.  I guess the question is whether to leave that single change (of removing the first two administrative steps) or to keep on &amp;ldquo;improving&amp;rdquo; the page.  Same quandry with the Premium page, I guess.  Just reviewing that now, I made some minor changes to the top of the page to remove the seemingly redundant link to &amp;ldquo;AgileVentures Premium&amp;rdquo; and an explanation text saying &amp;ldquo;the benefits are as follows&amp;rdquo; that seem to make no sense now that we have a list of questions.  Let&amp;rsquo;s at least do a sanity check on what we have in the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page.  So, step 1 currently says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browse the list of AgileVentures projects on agileventures.org, or the active projects listed in the table below, and learn more about the projects that interest you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can always set-up your own project, but we would recommend joining an existing one at first. This way you can meet other members, learn about our culture, principles and tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the odd thing is that we say browse the list of projects, but we don&amp;rsquo;t link there, and I could impulsively link that up, but would we rather the user focuses on the list of projects shown below?  The key thing we have in this list is the technologies used by the projects, the current maintainers and direct links to the relevant slack channels.  Of course it would be great if the main projects page showed all these things.  I&amp;rsquo;m thinking that a slimmed down more focused version of the above text would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find a project that interests you from the table below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the table, and then notes on &amp;ldquo;can&amp;rsquo;t find a project you like, see our complete list&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;want to set up your own project&amp;rdquo; after the table itself and also we could improve the table formatting somehow &amp;hellip; so I pushed the width out to 100%, increased the font size, bolded the headings and added a couple of other active projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/66ss4bwklwf5may/Screenshot%202017-07-06%2009.52.21.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as well as further cleaning up the text a little.  Reading through the rest of the getting started I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m reading a decsription of how some of the original developers intended the entire site to work.  There are cryptic references to WSO and other things that I think will make little sense.  Even after a few tidy ups what we have in step 2 is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how we communicate and coordinate projects:
* source code is kept in Github repos
* user stories (feature descriptions) are kept in project&amp;rsquo;s Pivotal Tracker (or other tracking systems)
* other documentation and detailed feature descriptions are kept in project&amp;rsquo;s section on agileventures.org
* real time discussion are done in Slack channels, in the specific channel for the project
* long-term discussions (where it is important to preserve history) are done on Pivotal Tracker, or in Github pull requests/issues or by commenting under specific documents in project&amp;rsquo;s section on agileventures.org 
* optionally recordings of PairProgramming sessions and standups are stored on YouTube. The list of videos for a specific project is under project&amp;rsquo;s section on agileventures.org
* technical information on the project is kept in documents under project&amp;rsquo;s section on agileventures.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all information that we want new members to absorb, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that many people will read and absorb.  We probably need to break this up into multiple steps (just like FreeCodeCamp) and have an activity associated with each.  Again it would be lovely to track people&amp;rsquo;s progress through this - I recall FreeCodeCamp has a separate page with an animated gif for each action, so they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to track with Google Analytics how far people are getting through the process.  Giving the user themselves a sense of progress through the task would also be great, as would having buttons that made it trivial to post a question to a project maintainer in the relevant slack channel (a bit like LinkedIn does to make it easy to send messages of a particular format).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course with all these different ideas there&amp;rsquo;s the question of which are the ones that are really worth pursuing.  I did get set up a few months back with being able to make nice animated gifs.   A nice animated gif of reaching out to a project maintainer and having them respond in a friendly fashion would probably be much more asorbable by lots of people than the current text of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Contacts&amp;rdquo; column contains the &amp;ldquo;Slack name&amp;rdquo; of one or more people that can help orient you to the project.&lt;br&gt;
Use this name to alert that person to a specific message when you post to the project slack channel.  For example, say you want to post a message to the MetPlus project channel, and make sure that &amp;ldquo;patrick&amp;rdquo; is aware of that message.  Here, you would go to the channel (and join the channel), and send a message like this:
&amp;ldquo;@patrick - hi, I am new to agile ventures and I would like to learn more about this project.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;patrick&amp;rdquo; will then be alerted to your message and respond back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;rsquo;s all question of where to expend the effort &amp;hellip;?  Once people have left the getting started page will they come back to follow through the steps?  Perhaps not, unless they are marking off progress.  It makes me want to split the getting-started pages into Step 1 (of 5), Step 2 (of 5), &amp;hellip; Step 5 (of 5) so that there&amp;rsquo;s much less text per individual page, and so that we can see the flow of people from page to page.  Of course a lot of this points to the need for a re-design of the project page, which we&amp;rsquo;ve thought we&amp;rsquo;ve needed for a long time.  There&amp;rsquo;s also the automated greeter bot in Slack, which I need to move to Azure, and make sure others can deploy to and change.  That greeter bot would ideally point people back to the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page, rather than off to GitHub as it does currently &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I think that&amp;rsquo;s the course I wanted to be on with these blogs.  Careful review of various pages in the site.  Set up an experiment on each, come back and review in a month to see what impact there&amp;rsquo;s been.  There&amp;rsquo;s certainly a good few other pages I can review over the course of the next month, e.g. the home page, the about page, the projects page, the event page, the opportunities page, the past scrums page, all the individual project pages &amp;hellip; the list goes on &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV Website Review Part 1</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/05/av-website-review-part-one/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/05/av-website-review-part-one/</id>
    <published>2017-07-05T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-27T21:12:10+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="new dawn" src="/images/new_dawn.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, new dawn.  I could be blogging about all the conversations we had about testing yesterday, but my new resolution is to get the AV website sorted out in terms of usability, readability and user flow one day at a time.  Immediately I&amp;rsquo;m torn between two sections.  There&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page that people either browse to, or get redirected to after sign in.  After discussions in the AV community meeting on Monday I removed the first two sections of that document:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-05%2009.29.00.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two sections are all things we&amp;rsquo;d like users to do, i.e. get set up with GitHub and Slack (and other things), but the danger is that the very first thing we are doing is directing folks away from our site.  The likelihood is that they signed up via GitHub and they&amp;rsquo;ve received a Slack invite.  It&amp;rsquo;s all very well asking folks to work through a set of administrative tasks when they are a &amp;ldquo;captive&amp;rdquo; audience, such as having already paid to take a class, but, really, we need to get people as quickly as possible to the higher engagement, fun activities, such as looking through the different active projects.  Anyway, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t belabour the point, but it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to look at the flow through from Google Analytics for this page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-04%2012.01.38.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we see there is a lot of drop offs and not many people clicking through on individual project pages.  The text associated with the first two &amp;ldquo;administrative&amp;rdquo; sections was forcing the table of active projects &amp;ldquo;below the fold&amp;rdquo;, i.e. making it something that people would have to scroll to get to.  Even so, the Google Analytics plugin for Chrome shows us what percentage of people are clicking through on which projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-05%2009.35.10.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So anyway, I removed the first two sections and we&amp;rsquo;ll see if there is any change.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s still room to reduce the amount of text, improve the layout and add graphics through this document, and so I&amp;rsquo;m torn about making more significant changes.  Particularly since it will take some weeks before we can really tell if there&amp;rsquo;s a difference.  We had 168 visits to the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page in the last month.  In addition I also want to make progress on the Premium page.  Previously Matt and I had worked on things so that when signed in users clicked on &amp;ldquo;Upgrade to Premium for additional support&amp;rdquo; on the home page, that instead of going to the payment page (with no information about Premium), it went to the description page for Premium, which made a lot more sense to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s functionality in the Google Analytics Chrome plugin to compare a period with the previous month, and I can see that there&amp;rsquo;s been a small increase in people clicking on the &amp;ldquo;Upgrade to Premium for additional support&amp;rdquo;.  We just redesigned the banner, but that only just went live, so we don&amp;rsquo;t have a clear indication for that increase:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-05%2009.48.57.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking through at the Premium description page we can now see some changes.  We adjusted the flow on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/commit/1af6bfe440133e4ade2b08e6fc7b8703825ec2b6"&gt;18th of May&lt;/a&gt;, and we can now see that the click through on &amp;ldquo;Get Started with Premium&amp;rdquo; has increased from 11% to 15% compared with the same period previously:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-05%2009.55.37.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the difficulty is that that change could just be due to a trend that we would have seen anyway, and also we don&amp;rsquo;t know that all those clicks are coming in via the new flow.  Users can reach this page by coming in through the pricing page, but having more people click on &amp;ldquo;Getting started with Premium&amp;rdquo; certainly feels like we are going in the right direction.  What&amp;rsquo;s frustrating is that we don&amp;rsquo;t have more info about what&amp;rsquo;s happening on this page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-05%2009.59.16.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Google analytics plugin is silent on the numbers of folks clicking on the subscribe buttons.  PayPal redirects to another site, while Stripe uses JavaScript to popup a credit card form.  I spent a chunk of time trying to see if I could see the flow around that page in the main Google Analytics site, but this was as close as I got:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Screenshot%202017-07-05%2010.15.30.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the exits could be people going to the PayPal page, but it&amp;rsquo;s unclear.  It makes me want to put the Chatlio &amp;ldquo;any questions&amp;rdquo; element in the site so that there&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity for people to tell us what they&amp;rsquo;re thinking as they browse the page.  Hmm, well I&amp;rsquo;ve burnt a lot of time reviewing the analytics and not a lot of time getting on to what I thought was my main thrust today, which is this rewording of the Premium description &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d posted some thoughts on that into a &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1583#issuecomment-310992734"&gt;WSO issue&lt;/a&gt; where Ashley had made a great point about how these new re-wordings didn&amp;rsquo;t include the term &amp;ldquo;Agile&amp;rdquo;.  What&amp;rsquo;s interesting is that in breaking out separate items to give support on, we lose sight of the bigger Agile picture.  Michael had mentioned that getting quick feedback on pull requests is crucial for Agile, but it&amp;rsquo;s also the case that the main &amp;ldquo;Agile&amp;rdquo; things that we offer, such as working with a team, doing scrums, retros, kick-offs, sprints etc. are not something that the Premium offering particularly supports - or at least not in its current form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes me think about things like having specific features like Sprint or retrospective support.  Of course that&amp;rsquo;s not as easy to break out as something that can be offered to Premium&amp;rsquo;s on a 121 basis without the associated selection of a project, introduction to the team etc. etc.  I have ideas about people signing up for a one off &amp;ldquo;sprint support package&amp;rdquo; at some higher price point, but there&amp;rsquo;s a ways to go there for that to make sense &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So anyhow, here&amp;rsquo;s another pass at questions for the Premium page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to find great developer jobs? Get help on the job search process?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to ace technical tests required to get interviews?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to accelerate your professional development?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to improve your coding and development skills?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to really understand Agile software development?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to put paid coding projects on your resume?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to make the world the better place?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to feel confident asking technical questions online?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to get discounts on important software and services for developers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I&amp;rsquo;ve now gone ahead and updated the Premium page using them and reworded the descriptions to make sense.  I think I could also be adjusting the full details to be popping up like we have in the FAQ, but I think this is enough for today.  The interesting thing will be to see if this has any noticeable impact on the click through rates or the number of people signing up &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. Side note, since shortening the text in the &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; page and adding a call to action &amp;ldquo;get started now&amp;rdquo; button, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen a good third of the people landing on the page clicking through on the &amp;ldquo;get started now&amp;rdquo; button.  Not that that says very much - what would be good to be seeing is month by month stats of footfall and percentage of people on the site actually signing up &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>All Good Things ...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/</id>
    <published>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-27T21:07:14+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="good things" src="/images/good_things.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been daily blogging for a year now.  Working day blogs that is.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging on weekends, or national holidays, or during my vacations.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty consistent.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of days where work was super busy due to the tail end of a design sprint or something, but I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to retro-actively blog and keep it one per work day.  I started blogging in June last year doing a blog on a different platform each day of the week, but fairly soon I fell into a pattern of blogging to our AgileVentures middleman site, and then re-releasing to Medium after I&amp;rsquo;d got a little distance from the blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the purpose of this blog frenzy?  My memory is that it was about trying to communicate more effectively.  I often end up assuming that people understand my thoughts and intentions and it turns out that actually they don&amp;rsquo;t.  Of course why would they?  There are few telepaths around.  I&amp;rsquo;m also a bit of a gabbler and my sense is that it&amp;rsquo;s not super easy to understand what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to communicate.  So blogging, get all the thoughts down in text, provide them in an accessible form for everyone to read, and maybe reduce my need to gabble on and on about things.  Win win, no?  There&amp;rsquo;s also the motivation that blogging at the start of each day is a kind of &amp;ldquo;morning pages&amp;rdquo; activity such as writers use to start off their days and clear their heads.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think writers usually publish their morning brain dump, but I have certainly found the process of starting each day with writing out my thoughts to be reassuring and relaxing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year when I was doing a lot more coding, the blogs tended to be all about the previous day&amp;rsquo;s coding.  As AgileVentures became an official charity and my admin load increased, they have tended to be about prioritization.  Starting the day with a blog is certainly less stressful than starting the day with a review of email and Slack conversations, which will generally lead to many adds to my ever-increasing todo list.  Has the time been well spent?  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had positive reactions to some blogs, but my sense is that the blogs are too long, too stream-of-consciousness, too un-focused to gain much traction.  I think I may have even alienated some with my uncensored and unedited thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was 17 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had trouble just generating text, and from even earlier I was always a talker.  It&amp;rsquo;s like my internal thought wheel is hooked up directly to my mouth, and at will I can hook it up to a pen or a keyboard and just dump my thoughts straight out, for better or for worse.  So I rarely have writer&amp;rsquo;s block, but it leaves me with a different problem.  How to edit the thicket of thoughts and ideas, so as to more effectively communicate them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to the end of a year of blogging prompts thoughts of changing things going forward.  There&amp;rsquo;ve been times in the past when rising early I&amp;rsquo;ve done 3 hours of programming before breakfast.  After recent design sprints I think about doing coding sprints, or other activities that fill the week in different ways.  Should it be one blog a week with the blog being edited and revised each day, so that a single polished blog can be released on Friday?  I guess it all depends on what one wants to achieve, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t the Buddhist in me been trying to follow a path of consecrated action, where one is totally unattached to the outcomes of activities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d have loved my blogs to have provoked more positive responses of &amp;ldquo;yes, let&amp;rsquo;s build a solution to that together &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, although there has been some of that.  What I really would like is for AgileVentures to be a healthy thriving community providing great learning experiences for many, while also helping charitable causes around the world.  The process of reflection over the last year does make me think that we&amp;rsquo;re far too text heavy in many, many parts of our interface with the world.  One of the most attractive ideas for me going forward is that I&amp;rsquo;d spend my blogging time each day focused on a part of the main AgileVentures site, converting it from text heavy to text light and adding images.  I have a hunch that, by doing this in strategic places throughout the site, we could improve the sign up rates, the number of members joining projects and the numbers signing up for Premium subscriptions, the source of our financial sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a feeling I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to shake the blogging habit.  The process has become too solidly part of my daily routine.  The thing that actually gets me started and ready to work in the mornings.  So, anyhow, starting tomorrow, blogs that focus on parts of the main AgileVentures site.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to work through it one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog released early for inclusion in our July newsletter, earlier blogs are all in draft form in GitHub and will be on this site soon&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Private Design Sprint Day Five</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/03/private-design-sprint-day-five/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/03/private-design-sprint-day-five/</id>
    <published>2017-07-03T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-27T21:07:14+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a frenetic last day but we managed to run usability tests with five different people.  I had to reach out to my personal network to fill all the slots, as well as stretching out of the precise demographic range that we had targeted, but I think we managed to conduct five really meaningful sessions.  The tech setup also worked pretty well with FaceTime and YouTube streams from hangouts, although probably it would have been better to have the observers joining the hangouts - then again that could have just made things that little more complicated.  We started the interviews from 10am, and we definitely needed that 9am-10am period to get settled in.  In the book they suggest starting the interviews from 9am, but for that to work I think one really has to have had a run through session on the Thursday, and in my experience so far the tail end of Thursday is spent frantically working on the demo app itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe even greater proficiency with the prototyping tools might address that, but there&amp;rsquo;s so much room for something not to work on the Thursday.  Maybe larger sprint teams are the key.  The sprints I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in have had small teams.  There&amp;rsquo;s also the location issue.  I can see the whole thing really working best when you have a company that has a dedicated physical space that they&amp;rsquo;re comfortable working in and there aren&amp;rsquo;t a load of logistical issues to get sorted.  Starting the interviews at 10am meant that they ran back to back with 30 minute breaks.  Also most of the team needed to leave soon afterwards so we didn&amp;rsquo;t get time for the sort of review that I&amp;rsquo;d have liked.  There was lots of interesting discussion during the breaks, and the reactions to the demo system were pretty solidly positive.  The decider wasn&amp;rsquo;t so happy with the final design that emerged, but ultimately I think we all agreed that we&amp;rsquo;d been able to get good positive feedback on some of the key conceptual elements that we were planning for the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a relief to get it all done.  I was exhausted, running all this while under the weather.  I had cancelled some of my Saturday activities (soccer coaching) to try and recover.  I fell asleep in a deck chair in the garden for two hours in the afternoon.  Even doing that is so slippery when you have a family.  It meant we ate supper late, I got indigestion and into a battle with my two youngest about completing their homework before playing computer games.  Sunday followed a somewhat similar pattern, with a dose of me stressing about online interactions with folks in AgileVentures.  I had hoped to start back into getting everything sorted out on Monday, but I woke up feeling like my cold had taken a retrograde step and ended up having to go back to bed for an hour; and even now am just easing myself back into the saddle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In principle it&amp;rsquo;s time to end my year of blogging and focus on upgrades to the AV site, as well as getting on with the various administrative and paperwork tasks that are needed to get a grip on the financial situation.  One step at a time I guess.  I have to pay back the health debt from last week for having pushed on with the design sprint when my body was arguing for a time out &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Private Design Sprint Day Four</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/30/private-design-sprint-day-four/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/30/private-design-sprint-day-four/</id>
    <published>2017-06-30T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-27T21:07:14+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m heading in to London on the train for day 5 following a frenetic day in London yesterday.  We got access to our space a little late, but proceeded to make good progress on the prototype with the designer cranking out a landscape, logo and background; and I got MarvelApp going through the gears to auto-play videos and provide the interactivity we needed.  The main snag was that the audio quality in the room we were in was not great and we needed to record of the order of ten short videos to make the prototype work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately we had to give up and head off to a different part of London where we could film quietly.  I was working illustrator in the back of a cab at one point.  There was debate about a change of approach, but ultimately we got it all done.  The editor got all the videos sorted out, and I linked them all in to the prototype.  I was up late, but woke early.  I&amp;rsquo;d also phoned and confirmed all the testers for the Friday, and knowing that we had real people showing up to use the app kept me going despite exhaustion and the tail end of my cold.  Design sprint Thursdays do seem to be the most frenetic and least pleasant.  The one in which tempers fray.  I wonder if the prototyping would be better off starting on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
