<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>All Good Things ...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/</id>
    <published>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-10T21:54:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="good things" src="/images/good_things.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been daily blogging for a year now.  Working day blogs that is.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging on weekends, or national holidays, or during my vacations.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty consistent.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of days where work was super busy due to the tail end of a design sprint or something, but I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to retro-actively blog and keep it one per work day.  I started blogging in June last year doing a blog on a different platform each day of the week, but fairly soon I fell into a pattern of blogging to our AgileVentures middleman site, and then re-releasing to Medium after I&amp;rsquo;d got a little distance from the blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the purpose of this blog frenzy?  My memory is that it was about trying to communicate more effectively.  I often end up assuming that people understand my thoughts and intentions and it turns out that actually they don&amp;rsquo;t.  Of course why would they?  There are few telepaths around.  I&amp;rsquo;m also a bit of a gabbler and my sense is that it&amp;rsquo;s not super easy to understand what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to communicate.  So blogging, get all the thoughts down in text, provide them in an accessible form for everyone to read, and maybe reduce my need to gabble on and on about things.  Win win, no?  There&amp;rsquo;s also the motivation that blogging at the start of each day is a kind of &amp;ldquo;morning pages&amp;rdquo; activity such as writers use to start off their days and clear their heads.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think writers usually publish their morning brain dump, but I have certainly found the process of starting each day with writing out my thoughts to be reassuring and relaxing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year when I was doing a lot more coding, the blogs tended to be all about the previous day&amp;rsquo;s coding.  As AgileVentures became an official charity and my admin load increased, they have tended to be about prioritization.  Starting the day with a blog is certainly less stressful than starting the day with a review of email and Slack conversations, which will generally lead to many adds to my ever-increasing todo list.  Has the time been well spent?  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had positive reactions to some blogs, but my sense is that the blogs are too long, too stream-of-consciousness, too un-focused to gain much traction.  I think I may have even alienated some with my uncensored and unedited thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was 17 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had trouble just generating text, and from even earlier I was always a talker.  It&amp;rsquo;s like my internal thought wheel is hooked up directly to my mouth, and at will I can hook it up to a pen or a keyboard and just dump my thoughts straight out, for better or for worse.  So I rarely have writer&amp;rsquo;s block, but it leaves me with a different problem.  How to edit the thicket of thoughts and ideas, so as to more effectively communicate them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to the end of a year of blogging prompts thoughts of changing things going forward.  There&amp;rsquo;ve been times in the past when rising early I&amp;rsquo;ve done 3 hours of programming before breakfast.  After recent design sprints I think about doing coding sprints, or other activities that fill the week in different ways.  Should it be one blog a week with the blog being edited and revised each day, so that a single polished blog can be released on Friday?  I guess it all depends on what one wants to achieve, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t the Buddhist in me been trying to follow a path of consecrated action, where one is totally unattached to the outcomes of activities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d have loved my blogs to have provoked more positive responses of &amp;ldquo;yes, let&amp;rsquo;s build a solution to that together &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, although there has been some of that.  What I really would like is for AgileVentures to be a healthy thriving community providing great learning experiences for many, while also helping charitable causes around the world.  The process of reflection over the last year does make me think that we&amp;rsquo;re far too text heavy in many, many parts of our interface with the world.  One of the most attractive ideas for me going forward is that I&amp;rsquo;d spend my blogging time each day focused on a part of the main AgileVentures site, converting it from text heavy to text light and adding images.  I have a hunch that, by doing this in strategic places throughout the site, we could improve the sign up rates, the number of members joining projects and the numbers signing up for Premium subscriptions, the source of our financial sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a feeling I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to shake the blogging habit.  The process has become too solidly part of my daily routine.  The thing that actually gets me started and ready to work in the mornings.  So, anyhow, starting tomorrow, blogs that focus on parts of the main AgileVentures site.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to work through it one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog released early for inclusion in our July newsletter, earlier blogs are all in draft form in GitHub and will be on this site soon&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Design Sprint Day Three</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/15/av-design-sprint-day-three/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/15/av-design-sprint-day-three/</id>
    <published>2017-06-15T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-11T21:38:01+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Thursday and I&amp;rsquo;m looking back at day three of our design sprint that we did on Wednesday.  I think all of our energy was down after having done two full days in a single hangout.  I&amp;rsquo;d been out in the morning to attend an NHS meeting and I think that was pushing it.  Hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll all have got a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep last night and be somewhat refreshed for day four.  But so what did we actually do in day three?  We started by taking a look at the four different prototypes that we had designed independently on day two.  We did heat map stickers to highlight aspects of the designs we liked, and then Matt nominated me to talk through each in speed critique mode while he took notes on the standout ideas:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1. Journey to Agile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;first image&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Journey to Agile first image" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/inga2yiyziy6a4v/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.19.33.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* You are Here 
* Benefits hilight list
* Job Seeking Network
* Scrum Bridge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;second image&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="How long does it take" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/8fc33tpapiec120/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.21.36.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* Start the journey (clickable)
* The AV journey (graph showing faster progress)
* Premium benefits indicated on graph (graph goes faster)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2. Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First image&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/nwgr50a8fudg61m/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.22.50.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* Badges/Milestones
* Profile rating (ambiguous)
* Project rating&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second Image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ek4ctr1uzjlvf58/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.23.54.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* Link to verified Certificate
* Certificate details right on certificate (appeals to companies) = Value to customer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third Image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/n8vv8wbgohxjruv/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.24.38.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* Project performance 
* Most influential contributor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3. Seeker on the Path&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/nsf052ds1usaqg3/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.25.57.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* Video Pitch (maybe put on top)
* Different Paths (depending on …)
* Guided Navigation with SubTasks
* List of Projects
* Badges/Certificates on the Path&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4. Guided Interactive Map&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/hk6o0hjcti7s7k5/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.28.14.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* Diagram (clickable) perhaps cold lacking motivation, needs video(?)
* Description of value
* Time per week, updates map focus
* Popup of values
* Value proposition
* Multi-select of tech&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was relatively straightforward to allow us to put heat map stickers in the Google doc once all the images had been added to drawings where we could overlay dots.   Here&amp;rsquo;s the full sequence we were following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Art museum. Tape the solution sketches to the wall in one long row.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat map. Have each person review the sketches silently and put one to three small dot stickers beside every part he or she likes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speed critique. Three minutes per sketch. As a group, discuss the highlights of each solution. Capture standout ideas and important objections. At the end, ask the sketcher if the group missed anything. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Straw poll. Each person silently chooses a favorite idea. All at once, each person places one large dot sticker to register his or her (nonbinding) vote.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supervote. Give the Decider three large dot stickers and write her initials on the sticker. Explain that you’ll prototype and test the solutions the Decider chooses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above images you can also see some of the straw poll votes.  We were divided pretty evenly between the first and third. That&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Journey to Agile&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Seeker on the Path&amp;rdquo;.  So there was a decision to make, go with one or the other, or combine them in some fashion.  After some debate we narrowed it down to the following options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rumble (building two prototypes and two fake brand names)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge where click through on Agile Journey has pathways (multiple steps) (single prototype)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge where Seeker on the path has video or infographic of Agile Journey (single prototype)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just do Agile Journey (single prototype) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just do Seeker on path (single protoype)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took another poll on this, but as the decider the final decision was up to me.  We had votes for items 1 and 2, but I thought with a sprint team of four we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the resources to make two prototypes, and I thought that we needed a single clear idea to make most effective use of the time and energy we were putting in.  In the background Federico was sorting out the advert for testers, the screening form, and getting the ads up onto craigslist around the world.  This was outstandingly helpful as I think our whole sprint team was exhausted and the logistics of managing the testers just seemed beyond us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federico joined the hangout on a couple of occasions to get input and decisions.  We decided to go for remote usability testing, and the full $100 Amazon gift card as compensation.  That&amp;rsquo;s $500 which is a lot of money for our non-profit charity, but I thought we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t skimp here and that we should be trying to get outside, unbiased input on the AgileVentures concept that we were trying to get across.  Our sprint focus was on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure that developers understand how they will benefit from AgileVentures (before looking for projects)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having made the decision, we moved on to making a storyboard to help structure the prototype we would build on Thursday.  I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed my computer getting slower and slower as these long hangouts run on with multiple large google doc windows open.  I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to quitting Slack and having that on another machine (if I need it) and even after a Chrome restart yesterday it was tough going trying to make the storyboard in a Google doc.  We got as far as this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/qoukd7h052vpko0/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.41.16.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;before I gave up, rebooted Chrome and started sketching on paper.  My memory is that shared editing of the Google drawing on day one had been a pretty efficient group operation.   I hadn&amp;rsquo;t rebooted my computer since then and I think we were all mentally flagging.  As the computer starts to lag it becomes increasingly frustrating.  I thought that, based on the concept we were working on, the storyboard was pretty straightforward.  I uploaded what I had drawn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ay5i33jehioui5m/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.44.23.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either others were reasonably happy with it, or too tired to argue.  Matt said there weren&amp;rsquo;t many &amp;ldquo;call to actions&amp;rdquo; and I pointed out the four &amp;ldquo;Learn More&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Sign me up&amp;rdquo; buttons.  I started pushing to say that we should do a little work on what goes into the map, so we moved the diagram into a fresh location and I went round each person asking if there were items they wanted to add or remove:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ukgpl9zhv6bewm6/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.45.34.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and wrote up this list of tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding Themed clipart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What goes in the map (ordering)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making individual subtopic info sites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does info popup (scroll, new page, popup)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keynote vs Invision vs Middleman?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt was telling us he was getting to the point that he could only do simple tasks.  I thought I might be able to write up some subtopic text, at least if I did it locally in Keynote.  We spent twenty minutes more with me going to each person and trying to ask what they would like to work on the list.  Maybe that was the wrong way to go.  It felt like we were moving in treacle.  Michael was talking through what each task involved.  I think there was confusion about whether we could work on things in parallel.  Ultimately Matt left, Lokesh started working on finding themed clipart, which Michael was doing in parallel.  I started on a Keynote with subtopics, but got distracted searching for clipart.  The remaining time was spent looking at Shutterstock and other images like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/623cie39vefg6p9/stock-vector-mountain-hiking-infographic-template-design-in-flat-style-386934532.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think any of us thought much of our artistic skills so the idea of having a pre-designed map showing a journey that we could put our own text into seemed pretty appealing.  The question was whether we had the software to edit the EPS files.  I played around with Sketch and Inkscape but ultimately made more progress downloading a free trial of illustrator.  Then we called it a day.  Now it&amp;rsquo;s Thursday and the Friday tests are looming.  Big day today to turn actually create our interactive infographic so that we can learn as much as possible from our randomly selected testers on Friday.  Stay tuned to this blog to find out how it all goes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/0TKPezdmui0"&gt;Day Three Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Design Sprint Day Two</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/14/av-design-sprint-day-two/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/14/av-design-sprint-day-two/</id>
    <published>2017-06-14T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-08T20:23:35+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Squeezing in too much? Me? I&amp;rsquo;m just on the train coming back from a NorthWest London CCG meeting, where I had been invited to present the HLP Social Prescribing and Self Care wiki.  It was an all morning meeting and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stay for the second half as I had to get back to my home office for day three of the design sprint.  It could have been useful to stay for the second half of the meeting where they were going to be talking about a digital health app, and giving me the chance to network with people after the meeting, but I&amp;rsquo;m committed to completing this design sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a face to face design sprint there&amp;rsquo;d be no time for me to squeeze in additional meetings (I&amp;rsquo;ve scheduled a Trustee meeting for Friday morning as well), but because we are running the meetings noon-6pm so that the East coast participants can join, there is in principle time, but whether it&amp;rsquo;s sensible is another question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back at day 2 we fairly quickly polished off the remaining agenda items that were left out on Monday afternoon due to our plethora of expert interviews.  Tuesday started with further organising of our &amp;ldquo;how might we&amp;rdquo; notes and voting on them.  At the end of that process the board looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="HMW notes voted on" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/0e4c2nc3lw39zah/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.04.39.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bit of negotiation we had four notes with at least 2 votes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ensure that developers understand how they will benefit from AgileVentures (before looking for projects)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get sustaining revenue?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better activate new signups into active community members?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make it clearer what project opportunities exist in terms of languages/frameworks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We added those to the appropriate places on our map, and as the decider I chose what the focus would be for the remainder of the sprint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="map with HMW notes added" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/lniu3rnvs2vgexw/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.07.36.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose &amp;ldquo;ensure that developers understand how they will benefit from AgileVentures (before looking for projects)&amp;rdquo; at least partly swayed by what Michael said that if you can&amp;rsquo;t get people in the door then it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to build anything further.  After a quick break we went into a series of lightning demos.  Here&amp;rsquo;s what we each showed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sam&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.headspace.com/"&gt;Headspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=502ILHjX9EE"&gt;Agile Product Ownership Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://freecodecamp.com/"&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=eisenhower+matrix"&gt;Priority Matrix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lokesh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showcase achievements(Github)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel prideful and helpful (StackOverflow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promote we are for good cause (https://campus.mozilla.community/)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michael&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon Prime Benefits Sell Page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile Ventures Signup Page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we doodled design components while each other presented, which either went on paper or into our shared Google doc.  When we finished presenting to each other we spent some more time trying to write up the components. Here are some:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="components" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ifohrjqhs3vso6m/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.12.26.png?dl=1" /&gt;
&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/v9j18l28ahvmwwp/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.12.45.png?dl=1" /&gt;
&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/f8o39mvquwu61xo/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.13.01.png?dl=1" /&gt;
&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/m1ym4qygf8h1f99/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.13.15.png?dl=1" /&gt;
&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/wrmdjrusjfxuypx/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.13.26.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we moved on to the group (but alone) interface/storyboard sketching activity where we each worked on making notes, doodling more components, crazy 8 doodle variation generation with time constraints, and then finally a big chunk designing an interface/storyboard.  We were all in the hangout coming and going.  There was nothing much happening for the outside viewer as we were all trying to avoid showing what we were working on to each other.  Some of us were sketching on paper, and we had a debate about whether the final versions should all be in google doc format, or just scans from the paper, and ultimately I proposed that everyone should just use whatever medium allowed them to work most efficiently and we would worry later about anonymity of design.  At the end of the day we had four different storyboard prototypes that we put on the shelf to review in day three!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/mvv2GPivSGo"&gt;Day Two Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Design Sprint Day One</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/13/av-design-sprint-day-one/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/13/av-design-sprint-day-one/</id>
    <published>2017-06-13T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-07T21:44:26+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I learned one thing from the NHS design sprint it&amp;rsquo;s get the sprint day blog numbering sorted! :-) I think I&amp;rsquo;m on top of it this time.  I started yesterday with a minus-one blog and so today&amp;rsquo;s day one blog looks back at day one that we had yesterday as we get set for day two coming up later today.  We did an intense six hours yesterday, all online, with Matt, Michael and myself in the same hangout for the whole time.  We did start off with Lokesh, but he suffered a power cut and had to drop out which was a shame.  A couple of others who might have been going to join us couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it, so we were down to a pretty bare sprint team of three, but that was more than we had for the NHS design sprint, so my personal design sprint trend is up.   We also had five experts give their input and opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We operated out of this &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1-58E54GHIg8OrZdsPe55O9-mEVcNmGFa7roe9ya-mzw/edit#"&gt;Day 1 document&lt;/a&gt;, getting the schedule in there and recording the long term goal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Significant number of people having authentic learning experiences on real projects helping good causes around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real projects should be receiving real support that leads to satisfied clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole process should be sustainable, by which we mean can we generate enough income to pay for services necessary to run the organisation (e.g. server costs, software costs, staff costs, contractor costs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and listing up a set of sprint questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will clients ever be satisfied with work from group of volunteers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will large numbers of developers ever get over the idea of &amp;ldquo;paying&amp;rdquo; for volunteering?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will we be able to present projects in such a way so that developers can find ones they will be a good fit for?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will we be able to present meeting time schedules so developers and clients can be available at the right time to coordinate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will we be able to provide good online communication (chat, real-time) mechanisms that enough people will find easy to use?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will we be able to communicate the benefits of additional (Premium?) support so that we can increase the numbers willing to pay for it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will we be able to provide the right level of structure so that developers and clients feel supported, but are also free to make the decisions that are part of learning?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will we have enough income so that we can compensate those who want to put in additional time, or more generally pay for the services needed to sustain the overall operation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will we work out how to allocate funds effectively?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will some customers be willing to pay for support and development?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will learners be enticed to pay for our services?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will Sam be overwhelmed and without significant assistance or automation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will learners have a clear path to progress?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will we allocate funds to maintain AV as a venture?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will turnover of volunteers make projects suffer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will customers, especially paying ones, trust a group of volunteers with their project?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will learners really pay to learn if there isn’t a &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; credential?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will staff time be taken up with increasing amounts of administrivia?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will existing key technological infrastructure fall into disrepair?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will there be enough people in the world who really want to learn through authentic volunteer experiences to make this all worthwhile?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will we attract a critical mass of volunteers so people can find each other when they want and have time to volunteer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and generated the following map of the interaction between different stakeholders moving towards our goal state:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="stakeholder interaction map" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/dl5c5zta66137kr/Screenshot%202017-06-13%2009.16.41.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d say that the Google docs were pretty efficient for doing all this online.  Being able to put questions and thoughts about long term goals directly into the same document that we could all see seemed to allow us to move pretty fast.  Similarly for the generation of the interaction map, although I did notice my computer lagging as we went on, perhaps from having the hangout running for so long.  Still, for what we lost in time in generating the diagram we sort of made up for in the greater legibility of the result and the fact that we can move boxes around (refactoring?) and the arrows all stay connected.  I think one of the key benefits is from making this map together so that we&amp;rsquo;re all undestanding it from the inside out.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how useful it is for conveying our ideas to others, but anyhow &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the sprint Matt took the lead as facilitator and I was the decider, which seemed to work pretty well for day one.  The main difficulty we had was that the availability of our experts were spread out over a larger time frame than we would have liked, so that rather than talking to all our experts we had a couple of interviews followed by a 30 minute break, then one more, then another break etc.  There wasn&amp;rsquo;t much we could do about that, so we put together a &amp;ldquo;how might we&amp;rdquo; notes in another google doc in the breaks, and made reasonable progress.  We started organising them into categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="HMW notes" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/m9huy92cclkz2n2/Screenshot%202017-06-13%2009.23.16.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to finish promptly to go for family supper while Matt and Michael finished up the last interview.  I noticed that those experts who&amp;rsquo;d been following our video feed or looking at our documents in advance were able to hit the ground running and give us more detailed feedback, as we each took turns talking the experts through the goal, questions and interaction map.  What we didn&amp;rsquo;t do was the final component where we vote on the HMW notes and then attach them to the interaction map and make a decision on which part of the process to focus on for the rest of the sprint.  We weighed the pros and cons of cancelling the last couple of interviews versus sacrificing some of the competitor product review the following day and went with completing interviews with all the experts we had scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though we were bending the sprint rules, I felt that we did better at sticking to the overall sprint philosophy than we did with the NHS sprint.  That&amp;rsquo;s understandable given the wider sets of constraints for the NHS wiki project, and either way I&amp;rsquo;m very much looking forward to the rest of the week.  One of things it makes me think is that going forward I would really like to be doing focused sprints on just one project or another, e.g. spend a week (two weeks?) purely focused on the AsyncVoter project, or the LocalSupport project, or what have you.  I wonder if there could even be a different kind of AgileVentures Premium product.  For those people less interested in a monthly subscription, perhaps they&amp;rsquo;d be more interested in an intense week or two working on a project?  People could take time off work for it? To get accelerated to the next level.  The trick is in the communication, I think.  It&amp;rsquo;s about getting across the value proposition.  Independently of any particular product, I&amp;rsquo;d love to generate that intense focus on particular projects.  I sense the constant switching from different project, day to day, is meaning it takes longer to break through certain tricky issues, get coherent shared understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, design sprint onward ho!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/A5d5VCGb1lE"&gt;Design Sprint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Design Sprint Day Minus One</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/12/av-design-sprint-day-minus-one/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/12/av-design-sprint-day-minus-one/</id>
    <published>2017-06-12T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-07T20:28:10+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just back from a weekend wild camping in North Wales with by brother-in-law (who&amp;rsquo;s training as a mountain leader) and my eldest son.  We had a great wet and windy time climbing mountains and camping in the wild by lakes.  It was great to get away and also to see my eldest son able to keep up with (and on occasion race ahead) of us.  He put up with some nasty weather, but was calm and made good decisions.  We got back late last night and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty shattered.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to need a couple of cups of coffee to wake myself up for the AgileVentures design sprint we are running this week.  We&amp;rsquo;ve got people from several time zones involved and we&amp;rsquo;ve set it to run from noon to 6pm to make it practical for myself in the UK and various east coast US folks to attend.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means I&amp;rsquo;m going to need to re-arrange various kid evening activities this week, but the US east coast folks will be getting up extra early, especially one who&amp;rsquo;s on central time (?)  We&amp;rsquo;re all committing a big chunk of time this week.  We&amp;rsquo;ve also got interns based in France and India joining in.  That it starts at noon for me means that I&amp;rsquo;ve got the morning to prepare and catch up with other things, although I&amp;rsquo;m not going to make much progress today until I&amp;rsquo;ve got some coffee in me.  We&amp;rsquo;re departing in various ways from the classic Google Ventures design sprint.  We&amp;rsquo;re trying to do it remotely (rather than co-located).  The GV sprint is supposed to be 10:30am to 5 or 6pm each day in a co-located venue, with a decent lunch break in between.  I&amp;rsquo;d been thinking that I&amp;rsquo;d have lunch early and push on through our 6 hour chunk, but now I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve bought TimeTimer software to display the countdown timers we should need for the sessions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/u0hmuwqfpxxdct2/Screenshot%202017-06-12%2009.52.58.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which will float on my desktop, but I suspect we might suffer from other people not having multiple screens to display both timer (via hangout) and the google docs they&amp;rsquo;ll need to be working in.  We&amp;rsquo;ll see.  I need to get going and clear out the admin activities in the morning to get set up for this sprint, which is starting in just two hours.  Despite being away in dramatic scenery over the weekend, I still found myself repeatedley mulling over the sticky emotional interactions I had with some members of AgileVentures last week.  One of them is being particularly persistent in coming up over and over again.  Is that my ego being ridiculous, or is that my subconscious trying to tell me something?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also an odd synchronicity with a section in the book on &amp;ldquo;Parenting with Presence&amp;rdquo;, by Susan Stiffleman that I&amp;rsquo;m reading, about apologizing, which was in a section on modelling behaviours to serve as an example for your children.  The four steps to deliver an apology are apparently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry&amp;rdquo; spoken from the heart and without any explanations, which might be seen as an attempt to justify or defend what happened&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I imagine you felt _________,&amp;rdquo; showing that you have stepped into the other person&amp;rsquo;s shoes with empathy and concern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the future &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;  Here is where you announce your intention to do better making it clear that the hurtful behaviour is not something you want to repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is there anything you need from me?&amp;rdquo; You are inviting the other person to share whatever might be preventing him from forgiving you and moving on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s the suggestion also that trying to force children to say the words &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry&amp;rdquo; is not very meaningful and that apologies should be delivered with genuine remorse and involve the above four steps.  I am forever trying to stop my children from justifying and defending their actions, and get them to just apologise and focus on connecting with the other person.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think I model the behaviour very well&amp;ndash;pretty much always trying to explain and justify&amp;ndash;and I&amp;rsquo;m starting to suspect that that gets me into a lot of trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course work relationships are different from relationships with children.  I think the above pattern of four is for when you really feel you&amp;rsquo;ve done something wrong.  I&amp;rsquo;m also thinking about what Erin Flynn said in the Freelancers podcast and saying that you are sorry to hear that someone is upset, but that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to immediately apologise for having done something wrong.  I think that makes sense too, because people are often upset about their perception of circumstances and you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t just admit culpability because someone accuses you of something, but it certainy costs nothing to say that you feel sorry they feel that way.  I guess the trick is in the timing about when you can explore the issue without making the person even more upset.  There&amp;rsquo;s an argument that in many situations you just can&amp;rsquo;t get into the whys and wherefores without provoking further argument and upset and in those situations you just have to disengage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My understanding of how to most effectively interact with people &amp;hellip; definitely a work in progress.  Just hearing what people say and offering no resistance or judgement whatsoever, versus academic debate about what caused what.  Is the latter ever appropriate?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sticky Feelings</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/09/sticky-feelings/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/09/sticky-feelings/</id>
    <published>2017-06-09T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-06T21:47:15+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="sticky" src="/images/sticky.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m heading south of the river again for an NHS meeting - I&amp;rsquo;ve just typed up my draft marketing/moderation report and got it into a PDF format that I can share with the NHS folks.  I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten the bloody dongle I need for the old style projectors - will have to order a spare one of those to leave in my bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with this week is my own reactions to two emotionally charged interactions on Slack. I have always found difficult social interactions terribly sticky in my mind, i.e. I keep reviewing the same thing over and over again.  I particularly remember working at the University of Hawaii when my eldest son was about two years old and lying awake at midnight reliving interactions with the head of department over and over in my head.  There&amp;rsquo;s also been a partial pattern of coming into conflict with people when I join new organisations, at least I have a memory of a pattern and difficult (and mentally sticky) interactions with people when I started work at Toshiba; at an internet startup in Tokyo, when starting at the University of Hawaii.  I think I recognised that pattern and learnt from it, although it&amp;rsquo;s longer ago now and as we go back twenty years or so I can&amp;rsquo;t remember whether the particular interactions were quite so sticky before I moved to Hawaii over ten years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least for me, whenever I have an emotionally charged disagreement with someone I find myself dwelling on it repeatedly.  I think I&amp;rsquo;ve slowly improved in my handling of these things, but I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure that I&amp;rsquo;m being as effective as I might.  The two particularly emotionally charged interactions this week were with two AgileVentures members on Slack.  One is a premium member and the other is a free-tier member.  The Premium member got rather angry about a meeting cancelled at the last minute.  I think I reacted in reasonably apologetic tones, but I think my attempt at an explanation lead to more anger.  A follow up post from that individual (I&amp;rsquo;m worried to mention names for fear of further inflaming things) left me reeling in a very highly charged emotional state.  In the past I might have responded directly in Slack, but in a hopefully more sensible approach I wrote out my feelings in a text document, and responded later to the individual that I had heard what they said, and let them know I had written a long response and offered to share that, or possibly to meet in order to talk face to face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that&amp;rsquo;s a better way to go and as it happened a podcast with Erin Flynn the next day gave similar advice.  Still I was frustrated at the strength of my feelings and I spent an hour on writing them up.  In the process I think I definitely did understand the person&amp;rsquo;s point of view better, but also strengthened my own feelings that they are over-reacting to a degree.  While writing that out may have addressed my immediate highly intense feelings it has not stopped me from visiting and re-visiting the interaction repeatedly over the subsequent days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On reflection it feels that my attempt at an explanation did not help and merely fanned the flames.  In deep irony that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m always telling my children - get that apology in, and wait for the person to calm down before trying to explain.  Erin Flynn was saying focus on saying that you are sorry the person feels the way they do, but do not apologise for your actions, per se.  At least (I assume) that you are in a place where you can decide that&amp;rsquo;s appropriate, rather than just doing it reactively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have more examples of how the apology/reaction can backfire.  The most difficult thing for me however is the unpleasant sensation that it all creates for me repeatedly over the next few days;  waking up in the morning, last thing at night.  A mental movie plays in my head of the interaction.  How can I describe it? I re-experience the interaction over again and the same strong emotions come up.  What are those emotions?  A feeling of embarrassment of not having handled the interaction correctly.  A feeling of anger towards the person for directing anger at me.  There&amp;rsquo;s a kind of revulsion, a desire to just stop thinking about this thing that appears to have me re-living unpleasant emotions again and again when I would rather be focusing on other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the Buddhist/awakening stuff seems to suggest that it is helpful to simply observe the emotions; to try and be present in the body. I try to do that but often get caught up again in the unpleasant emotions and find myself overwhelmed with a desire that the unpleasant emotions would stop.  That can often lead to more feelings of anger towards the person involved in the initial interaction, and so the cycle continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At HPU it tended to be the students who I would occasionally have challenging interactions with, more than the staff, but that was possibly due to me working remotely from the other side of the world.  At MakersAcademy there were some tricky interactions with students, but it was ultimately the staff interactions that were hardest.  I can remember being overwhelmed with frustration at the actions of one individual and being repeatedley consumed by reliving my feelings about my interaction with them all through a family weekend. I ended up writing a short essay on it all.  Sharing that with the person then seemed to end up backfiring as they said they had felt be-littled by it.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t find that out till much later though.  I was busy trying to honestly share my feelings on our interaction and when they suggested sharing with the rest of the team I happily did so.  The team&amp;rsquo;s reaction seemed to be that I was attacking this one individual.  There it all seemed to be complicated by the fact that I was in a position of some authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back at that situation it seems like I should have shared my short essay with some of the other senior team members before going to the individual in question.  I&amp;rsquo;m still shocked by how it all seemed to blow up in my face.  I&amp;rsquo;m now on good terms with the individual in question, but I still regret how it all turned out.  The individual in question had come across as a very confident assertive individual.  However the interaction with the essay was a traumatic one because I was someone in a position of authority.  I was approaching the situation as one where equals would be discussing how they interacted with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was another occasion when I had a prolonged interaction on Slack with a student about their decision to leave MakersAcademy.  They were being very critical of our course in what I felt was a logically incoherent fashion.  I&amp;rsquo;d been working hard to reach out and try and help the student stay on the course.  I shared my Slack interaction with the team in the interests of transparency and ultimately I don&amp;rsquo;t think it was too my benefit.  There&amp;rsquo;s a convincing argument to be made that I was just continuing an academic debate with the student far past the point that it was constructive.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.  I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t feel very good about it.  It was very mentally sticky, and my openness and transparency about the interaction didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have any positive consequences that I can see, other than to garner the feedback that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a very productive conversation, which I kind of knew already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsequently I have occasionally had very mentally sticky interactions at AgileVentures.  One of the key senior people appeared to get very angry and withdrew themselves from interaction with the organisation.  That particular individual often expressed themselves in what I found as very aggressive terms.  The final straw that broke the camel&amp;rsquo;s back appeared to be me not responding in Slack. I had made a somewhat reactive comment to something they said, but then didn&amp;rsquo;t want to engage in further discussion.  I relive that over and over again.  The individual subsequently wrote up a long list of their grievances, and I avoided responding to it directly.  Learning from my Makers Academy experience I wrote up my responses separately and shared them with two other senior team members, got feedback, polished etc., but by the time I was ready to post the individual in question had archived the discussion and it seemed like my input wasn&amp;rsquo;t being waited for, or necessarily needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should be digging out that response and sending it over to put my own demons to bed?  The timing seems wrong.  My sense is that individual is calmer as a result of having been able to write out how they felt.  I strongly disagree with many of their assertions and feel they were being unreasonable, demanding and unfair.  I relive those emotions with what I hope is gradually decreasing frequency.  More recently I have been writing up separate responses to someone who regularly engages in intense debate on the AgileVentures Slack, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted them back and in that case I don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be reliving things so much.  I still think their logic is deeply flawed, but I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped believing that trying to convince them of my point of view has much merit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that brings us back to this week.  I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about the first interaction where I&amp;rsquo;ve written up my response and have held off posting it.  The stickiness and unpleasantness of that interaction is vying for time in my head with another unpleasant interaction that came up later in the same day, this time with a non-premium member.  This individual had been upset on several occasions about their code (pull requests) being ignored.  I had said (as I often do on those occasions) that one option was to upgrade to Premium membership to get priority code reviews.  There was also a long running infrastructure issue on that project that I felt needed addressing first.  The individual had said they couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford the Premium membership and I had mentioned the possibility of sponsorship.  A week later and seemingly out of the blue (to me) the individual expressed that they were insulted by being asked for money to review their code and the offer of sponsorship and wanted to leave the project and AgileVentures.  I said that I was sorry that they felt that way, but that was great feedback and thanked them for it.  I also mentioned that I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I had asked them for money to review their code, but I guess I was splitting hairs; but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself.  It felt like a nasty accusation and I needed to defend myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more immediate consequence was that we engaged in a repeated back and forth in which we told each other a lot more about each other&amp;rsquo;s feelings.  It felt like quite a heated argument.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure neither of us felt very good.  Ironically it&amp;rsquo;s the former interaction with the Premium member that&amp;rsquo;s proving much stickier.  The non-premium member then surprised me by turning up in the planning meeting for the project, being very civil, taking on tasks etc. when I just thought they&amp;rsquo;d said they were leaving.  So confusing.  I really give up. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what the right thing is to do with all this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it really the case that you just shouldn&amp;rsquo;t respond to anyone&amp;rsquo;s assertions about yourself?  Is defending yourself just a way to get into an unpleasant fight?  Should one listen and not respond and always take a week before responding, even if that means you give no response?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
