<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>All Good Things ...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/</id>
    <published>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-10T21:54:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="good things" src="/images/good_things.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been daily blogging for a year now.  Working day blogs that is.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging on weekends, or national holidays, or during my vacations.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty consistent.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of days where work was super busy due to the tail end of a design sprint or something, but I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to retro-actively blog and keep it one per work day.  I started blogging in June last year doing a blog on a different platform each day of the week, but fairly soon I fell into a pattern of blogging to our AgileVentures middleman site, and then re-releasing to Medium after I&amp;rsquo;d got a little distance from the blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the purpose of this blog frenzy?  My memory is that it was about trying to communicate more effectively.  I often end up assuming that people understand my thoughts and intentions and it turns out that actually they don&amp;rsquo;t.  Of course why would they?  There are few telepaths around.  I&amp;rsquo;m also a bit of a gabbler and my sense is that it&amp;rsquo;s not super easy to understand what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to communicate.  So blogging, get all the thoughts down in text, provide them in an accessible form for everyone to read, and maybe reduce my need to gabble on and on about things.  Win win, no?  There&amp;rsquo;s also the motivation that blogging at the start of each day is a kind of &amp;ldquo;morning pages&amp;rdquo; activity such as writers use to start off their days and clear their heads.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think writers usually publish their morning brain dump, but I have certainly found the process of starting each day with writing out my thoughts to be reassuring and relaxing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year when I was doing a lot more coding, the blogs tended to be all about the previous day&amp;rsquo;s coding.  As AgileVentures became an official charity and my admin load increased, they have tended to be about prioritization.  Starting the day with a blog is certainly less stressful than starting the day with a review of email and Slack conversations, which will generally lead to many adds to my ever-increasing todo list.  Has the time been well spent?  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had positive reactions to some blogs, but my sense is that the blogs are too long, too stream-of-consciousness, too un-focused to gain much traction.  I think I may have even alienated some with my uncensored and unedited thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was 17 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had trouble just generating text, and from even earlier I was always a talker.  It&amp;rsquo;s like my internal thought wheel is hooked up directly to my mouth, and at will I can hook it up to a pen or a keyboard and just dump my thoughts straight out, for better or for worse.  So I rarely have writer&amp;rsquo;s block, but it leaves me with a different problem.  How to edit the thicket of thoughts and ideas, so as to more effectively communicate them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to the end of a year of blogging prompts thoughts of changing things going forward.  There&amp;rsquo;ve been times in the past when rising early I&amp;rsquo;ve done 3 hours of programming before breakfast.  After recent design sprints I think about doing coding sprints, or other activities that fill the week in different ways.  Should it be one blog a week with the blog being edited and revised each day, so that a single polished blog can be released on Friday?  I guess it all depends on what one wants to achieve, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t the Buddhist in me been trying to follow a path of consecrated action, where one is totally unattached to the outcomes of activities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d have loved my blogs to have provoked more positive responses of &amp;ldquo;yes, let&amp;rsquo;s build a solution to that together &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, although there has been some of that.  What I really would like is for AgileVentures to be a healthy thriving community providing great learning experiences for many, while also helping charitable causes around the world.  The process of reflection over the last year does make me think that we&amp;rsquo;re far too text heavy in many, many parts of our interface with the world.  One of the most attractive ideas for me going forward is that I&amp;rsquo;d spend my blogging time each day focused on a part of the main AgileVentures site, converting it from text heavy to text light and adding images.  I have a hunch that, by doing this in strategic places throughout the site, we could improve the sign up rates, the number of members joining projects and the numbers signing up for Premium subscriptions, the source of our financial sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a feeling I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to shake the blogging habit.  The process has become too solidly part of my daily routine.  The thing that actually gets me started and ready to work in the mornings.  So, anyhow, starting tomorrow, blogs that focus on parts of the main AgileVentures site.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to work through it one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog released early for inclusion in our July newsletter, earlier blogs are all in draft form in GitHub and will be on this site soon&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bayesian Decision Making</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/19/bayesian-decision-making-blog/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/19/bayesian-decision-making-blog/</id>
    <published>2017-05-19T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-17T21:25:11+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bayesian" src="/images/bayesian.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my blog from yesterday isn&amp;rsquo;t finished.  I got stuck halfway trying to document the mediawiki setup process, and then loads of other things fell on me.  I can feel my decision making process creaking.  I got caught for twenty minutes in Slack and email before starting this blog.  I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of the Bayesian approach to making decisions which seems eminently sensible and is all about working out prior probabilities.  It&amp;rsquo;s been a while and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m mangling it, and anyway it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to get accurate probabilities, but there&amp;rsquo;s so many things I could work on, and it&amp;rsquo;s so difficult to work out the actual rewards that come from each thing.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got to just start listing them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Generate case studies of recent paid NHS and Wikimedia EDU projects (possibly even LocalSupport) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time to complete: 2 hours?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potential benefit: could help unlock funding from new Myanmar project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create bid for Capable Communities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time to complete: 1 hour?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potential benefit: might unlock funding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Review new first MOOC assignment proposal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time to complete: 1 hour?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potential benefit: unclear, but MOOC does drive traffic to our site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Respond to email from &amp;ldquo;Code for Kindness&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time to complete: 20 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potential benefit: unclear, but could be good for collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Respond to email from Safecast&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time to complete: 20 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potential benefit: unclear, but could be good for collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attending marketing meeting  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time to complete: ~1hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potential benefit: unlocks other folks trying to collaborate on marketing strategy &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Releasing latest WSO updates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time to complete: ~1hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potential benefit: releases changes to flow that might have more people understanding benefits of Premium and then signing up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Further investigating AsyncVoter routing issues&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time to complete: unknown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potential benefit: clarity about Azure routing, unblocks developers to focus on code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sorting LocalSupport repo relations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time to complete: 15 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potential benefit: makes AgileVentures clear owner; and opens route to testing drie deploy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Completing MediaWiki install and config as clone of HLP wiki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time to complete: &amp;gt;2 hours?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potential benefit: gives us a much safer testing area for upgrades and changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s a slew of other things.  I can&amp;rsquo;t get everything done, and each thing I have mentioned above only includes guesses of the time it takes and what the potential benefits will be.  It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be such a big deal if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t relying on opening the right doors to bring in enough money to feed my kids.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kicked off the WebSiteOne deployment in the background as that requires a few background steps for CI to run on each of the develop, staging and production instances.  The Bayesian approach calls for prior probabilities to be assessed.  The likelihood that each thing was successful in the past, to help weigh which item to choose &amp;hellip; if I was calm I&amp;rsquo;d go and look up the formula, but I&amp;rsquo;m just too stressed at the moment.  I feel like the critical thing is to get the case-studies of our paid projects written up.  Even if they don&amp;rsquo;t unlock fudning for this Myanmar project it&amp;rsquo;s the kind of thing that&amp;rsquo;s going to be useful to trot out when people ask, and the write up should contribute to one of my highest priority items, which is a plan for the AgileVentures charity to regularly pay for my family and I to eat.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Full Monty</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/17/full-monty/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/17/full-monty/</id>
    <published>2017-05-17T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-13T20:53:38+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="full monty" src="/images/full_monty.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;d made a plan for this morning.  I was going to quickly check if we had progress on our IE11 VisualEditor/Moderation problems, get the final report written up for the NHS folks, and then try to get into rebuilding our complete wiki stack on a staging instance to have it all documented and somewhere to test changes before they go into production.  I&amp;rsquo;m still hoping that&amp;rsquo;ll all get done.  There was an &lt;a href="https://github.com/edwardspec/mediawiki-moderation/issues/9#issuecomment-301893840"&gt;update on our IE11 VisualEditor/Moderation problem&lt;/a&gt; which seemed like it could be the final fix, so I pushed it into production to find it was a partial fix.  The moderation messages now shows up on IE11, but the visual editor still wouldn&amp;rsquo;t fully load, argh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took 30 minutes or so of fiddling on my Windows machine to get all the errors recorded and noted in the GitHub issue, and now I&amp;rsquo;m finally at my blog, and the plan basically seems sound.  It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating that it&amp;rsquo;s not the &amp;lsquo;final&amp;rsquo; fix, because if the VisualEditor had just loaded, then that would have been our last major technical hurdle out of the way, and it would have made it easy to make decisions about which editor to default to.  Actually for all the effort to get the moderation messages to show up on IE11, it&amp;rsquo;s clear from the lastest round of usability-testing/training at the NHS, that even when the moderation message is present, users just don&amp;rsquo;t read it.  I&amp;rsquo;m guessing that the addition of some kind of icon might be helpful and I opened an &lt;a href="https://github.com/edwardspec/mediawiki-moderation/issues/12"&gt;issue on the moderation extension&lt;/a&gt; to discuss that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final NHS training session went well yesterday, and it turned out that part of this was because the trainee was using Chrome.  Still it&amp;rsquo;s clear to me that most users will just think their edit is lost, or the system is somehow broken, because just going in to edit they won&amp;rsquo;t have any mental model of the moderation process and they won&amp;rsquo;t read the moderation message, which has a green tick next to it and so they will just assume their edit has been saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="popup" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/6o6w0elykokw0zh/Screenshot%202017-05-11%2017.46.02.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What continues to shock me is that more people aren&amp;rsquo;t more interested in these usability issues.  Maybe being in a community that is all about learning to code, learning to be Agile is the wrong place.  There was a point a few years ago where I was trying to help start a community around Scott Klemmer&amp;rsquo;s HCI usability course.  There clearly are people really interested in usability, but so often the coding conversations go towards code beauty, or database consistency, and those critical steps of building something that people can fit into their existing workflow and derive value from get lost in the cracks.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m delusional but we all seem to be labouring under the assumption that other people basically understand what we understand.  I&amp;rsquo;m often going on about how that is such a hard assumption to break, so I guess I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is exciting is the enthusiasm for design sprints that we&amp;rsquo;re starting to have in the AV community.  I&amp;rsquo;m starting to see the design sprint as a tool for lasering in on breaking down those assumptions.  Let&amp;rsquo;s see.  Right, a little less conversation, a little more action; sort of.  Do my Email/Slack check, get final draft of final report for NHS and get that staging stack set up before I end up breaking something on the production system.  Again, why aren&amp;rsquo;t more of the community interested in the devops for this paid NHS project?  It&amp;rsquo;s the usability and the devops that&amp;rsquo;s key. Can&amp;rsquo;t deliver the system in the fashion intended and fit it into the user&amp;rsquo;s daily workflow and you might as well be throwing all your code in a dumpster.  Great if you&amp;rsquo;re into abstract art - insane if your intention is to help people or change anything.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m failing to communicate the value, or perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s just that people won&amp;rsquo;t want to get more involved until we&amp;rsquo;re paying them bigger bucks &amp;hellip;?  In the meantime I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep focusing on what I call the &amp;ldquo;Full Monty&amp;rdquo; - trying to build things that people can fit into their working life to get things done more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Debugging MediaWiki</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/16/debugging-mediawiki/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/16/debugging-mediawiki/</id>
    <published>2017-05-16T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-12T21:01:40+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="mediawiki" src="/images/MediaWiki.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I finally got a clear shot at resolving some of our MediaWiki technical issues.  A key one was users getting loggged out after they create new accounts.  I had had some feedback from MediaWiki support that our cookies weren&amp;rsquo;t being set correctly on production.  So I created a new account for mediawiki on our staging box.  It created the following cookies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cookies created for new user account" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/f73wmvq1g31uh6o/Screenshot%202017-05-15%2010.56.38.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three of these were reported created on the main wiki: cpPosTime, UseDC, UseCDNCache. I navigated to the main page and was logged out, although now there was just one cookie:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="single cookie after redirect" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/mha525jx20y2yow/Screenshot%202017-05-15%2011.00.21.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigating around I stayed logged out, and then tried logging on, which worked and generated a couple more cookies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="more cookies after login" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/h68yx9n2tz9jpv5/Screenshot%202017-05-15%2011.01.59.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the fact that this was happening on our staging box made it seem like this was a Bitnami MediaWiki issue, or possibly something to do with the extensions we had configured on both.  So far the only extensions configured on the staging site are the moderation extension and the wikieditor.  I could try disabling these two to see if we get the same effect, or I could even try a completely fresh Bitnami MediaWiki deploy &amp;hellip; but faster might be to search the Bitnami forums.  A few searches didn&amp;rsquo;t reveal anything:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki%20logged%20out"&gt;https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki%20logged%20out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki%20create%20account"&gt;https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki%20create%20account&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki%20cookies"&gt;https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki%20cookies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki_session"&gt;https://community.bitnami.com/search?q=mediawiki_session&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was about to post to the Bitnami forum, when I tried disabling the wikieditor and the Moderation extension, and then create account maintained a login.  I re-enabled the wikieditor appearing to confirm that the Moderation extension was the culprit.  I did a few extra tests and opened a &lt;a href="https://github.com/edwardspec/mediawiki-moderation/issues/11"&gt;ticket on the mediawiki-moderation github repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That kicked off a variety of interactions with the Moderation extension maintainer over the course of the day.  First up they asked me to try out a fix involving disabling a php function called &lt;code&gt;onLocalUserCreated&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;hooks/ModerationPreload.php&lt;/code&gt;.  That fixed the issue and the maintainer almost immediately released a fix, which I pulled into staging which now worked fine. The master branch of the extension now included that fix, and another fix that was supposed to resolve another key issue we were having; the failure of the moderation notice to display.  The set up we have is the Moderation extension sitting in an extensions directory within MediaWiki on the Azure/Bitnami instance, and we got it there via git.  So upgrading it involves just pulling down the latest code from GitHub.  This makes me a little nervous.  I&amp;rsquo;m more comfortable with upgrading libraries via something like rubygems and having a full test suite to run to check that everything is still working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually this is not so different from what I do with the autograders on AWS, where we update from git; although there at least we have staging and master branches.  I see that we do have some tests associated with both MediaWiki and the Moderation extension.  I&amp;rsquo;d like to have these running, ideally in CI.  At the moment everything is relying on time-consuming manual tests.  Argh! I&amp;rsquo;d love to have space to re-create a box from scratch, checking what tests we can run on the way and also do a step by step performance review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the moment I upgraded the Moderation extension via git and things seemed to be fine.  Two important bugs fixed, but then I noticed that although the Moderation notice was showing up on staging, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t there on production where we had SSL and the VisualEditor installed.  I added notes to the GitHub issue, and also reviewed all my comments to the VisualEditor team.  Nothing back on the IE, iPad and usability issues there and it had been a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Topic:Tqcoy1d9m5sbtf1e"&gt;Asking about iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Topic:Tql1dw7a2muih6ma"&gt;Usability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Topic:Tqcpj4g11oe3b2ht"&gt;graceful failures on IE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve still had no responses there, but I managed to track down the VisualEditor team on IRC, where I got some great feedback.  Looking at our production site MatmaRex was able to identify the Moderation extension as the culprit for the IE fails, and it looked like several related issues could be solved in one go if the Moderation extension could be adjusted to work with VisualEditor and IE11 in combination.  I got this input on trying to fail gracefully:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19:05] &lt;tansaku&gt; on a more general note, is there a way to have things fail more gracefully? so that if something like this happens the editor switches over to basic?
[19:07] &amp;lt;+MatmaRex&amp;gt; tansaku: no. if you have a syntax error in your script (and effectively, that&amp;rsquo;s how IE11 treats this), the whole MediaWiki script loading system goes out of whack. we really assume you don&amp;rsquo;t have syntax errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got a lead about how to work better on mobile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19:15] &amp;lt;+MatmaRex&amp;gt; tansaku: Wikimedia wikis use https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Extension:MobileFrontend to display a different skin for mobile views, and it has slightly different VisualEditor integration than normal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s something we can look at later.  Right now we&amp;rsquo;re stuck on getting VisualEditor and the Moderation extension to play well on IE11.  The moderator is telling me that IE11 doesn&amp;rsquo;t support the JavaScript &lt;code&gt;for ( A of B )&lt;/code&gt; syntax and more importantly that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support &lt;code&gt;FormData.entries()&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This looks bad. In IE11, there is no way to read the contents of FormData at all.
https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/Hh772723#methods&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the current implementation, reading FormData is essential for ajaxhook (VisualEditor support in Moderation) to work. Need to think of some way to workaround that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but they&amp;rsquo;ve had an idea:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we currently get from FormData, can be obtained by wrapping around mw.Api.prototype.api(). This should work in IE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the maintainer is investigating that, and in the meantime I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll try and complete adding our training materials to the wiki.  I think I also found the &lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Extension:VisualEditor#Complete_list_of_configuration_options"&gt;settings&lt;/a&gt; to remove some of the annoying VisualEditor popups in.  Back to the grindstone &amp;hellip; at least I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to document some of the process of debugging a MediaWiki bug.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Never Enough</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/15/never-enough/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/15/never-enough/</id>
    <published>2017-05-15T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-11T22:38:29+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="never enough" src="/images/never_enough.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However hard I work, it never seems like I&amp;rsquo;ve done enough.  We got the NHS Social Prescribing wiki &amp;ldquo;live&amp;rdquo; on Friday, and I also managed to do a round of updates and fixes on the MOOC.  Superficially I should be pleased at having gotten all that &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo;, but there are a set of usability issues on the wiki that are bothering me.  Maybe the ultimate solution is the philosophical one of not being attached to any future outcome so that one can enjoy every moments inner peace and stillness.  More often that not I am agonizing about the things not done, or whether the things I am doing are having the effects I intend, e.g. blogging supposedly centering me in the morning, but potentially being wasteful navel gazing &amp;hellip; :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s put this blog to work, and look at the issues that are bothering me about the wiki.  I had been hoping to work on them on Friday morning, but time seemed to get sucked into getting them into a trello board:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="HLP wiki trello board" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/4nqawtimebrqe43/Screenshot%202017-05-15%2009.53.52.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and then in a Skype call with the new HLP change manager.  That in itself was a major breakthrough and involved getting one of the NHS tech staff to provide a separate laptop with Skype enabled.  Huge relief as I could now show the change manager various aspects of the wiki operation without having to commute across town.  As we were Skyping, the updated version of the terms &amp;amp; conditions and privacy policy came in, and by the time I&amp;rsquo;d gotten that approved by the communications manager, I added that to the website, sorted out some very basic help guides etc. I&amp;rsquo;d used up my allotted time in the day for work on the wiki.  On reflection I think it was the right focus.  While part of me yearned to be working on the technical issues, having the correct legal cover was crucial.  Also, connecting with the change manager was unblocking them to finish putting all the content from the HLP PDF document into the wiki, and the first (and possibly only) experience that most people were likely to have of the wiki were going to be the content and the viewable portions.  One thing that was clear from the previous week of testing was that we needed a lot more content in there for this to be of any use to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So going back to the Trello board I could move the legal work into the &amp;ldquo;completed&amp;rdquo; column.  Another &amp;lsquo;view&amp;rsquo; item I had created was about improving the landing page.  I&amp;rsquo;d put two items in that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linking all the key topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making all the useful links at the bottom go to our own internal pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change manager had been able to do the former after I&amp;rsquo;d reviewed the process of making links with them.  There were however another set relating to Self-Care that would be linked to pages created from the second HLP PDF document, but that hadn&amp;rsquo;t been signed off by the &amp;ldquo;decider&amp;rdquo; so I&amp;rsquo;m stuck here not being able to click the relevant checkbox.  Pedant?  I know from Friday&amp;rsquo;s experience that I could easily burn a lot of time just editing things around, so I decided to leave this ticket &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo;.  It&amp;rsquo;s odd because there are lots of simple editing tasks, e.g. creating multiple new pages, that are relatively straightforward for me, particularly with my multi-monitor setup, that are quite time consuming for novice users.  At the same time, there are lots of more technical issues that those novice users can&amp;rsquo;t make progress on, so I must drag myself over to the more serious technical issues. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the particularly niggling ones is that creating an account seems to log folks in temporarily, but then they get logged out when they move off the page.  I had opened a &lt;a href="https://trello.com/invite/b/5J4lZIaT/53a4831a8f2f8dc0de936756c66e10d3/hlp-wiki"&gt;support ticket&lt;/a&gt; on the main mediawiki site about this, and got a response:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;definitively it&amp;rsquo;s not something I can reproduce on a local instance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On your wiki, after creating account, I see those cookies being set: cpPosTime, UseDC, UseCDNCache&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On next page I&amp;rsquo;m logged out, and when logging in again, those cookies are being set: bitnami&lt;em&gt;mediawiki&lt;/em&gt;session, bitnami&lt;em&gt;mediawikiUserID, bitnami&lt;/em&gt;mediawikiUserName&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, on a local 1.28, I get all cookies set after creating the account. the _session cookie is set when loading the createaccount page, but then replaced with another after the account gets created. However it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get replaced on your wiki on creating an account, and I have no idea why&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m so tempted to dive in here.  My first action might be to replicate what the MediaWiki person is indicating.  I&amp;rsquo;m also tempted to do the complete setup and install of the whole system on a clean machine.  Although that smells slightly of procrastinating.  I could just start checking the behaviour on our staging instance that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the visual editor and SSL as a way to attack this problem faster, but then again I have two more &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo; tickets.  One is the side navigtation issue which I&amp;rsquo;ve got done, so stick that in completed.  However, the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Help&amp;rdquo; pages that I&amp;rsquo;ve created are still just basic stubs, and it has to be a priority to fill those out further &amp;hellip; and there might be other things to add to that side navigation.  Close the ticket, make a new one on help &amp;hellip; wait - I have a ticket on making the help pages and uploading my training materials there &amp;hellip; I added another ticket on the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page, and spent a few moments moving that into the backlog and moving more important items to the top of the backlog; closing out some other tickets that I&amp;rsquo;ve dealt with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to the crux of my stalled decision-making process.  Filling out the help pages with my training materials feels like super high priority, but the training materials include the sign up process, which has this niggling bug, which if I can fix will change the way we document the site.  To cut this Gordian knot I think I&amp;rsquo;ll upload the training materials, documenting the current issue &amp;hellip; using that as a way to explore the issue, in the way that I sometimes work blog - so wiki work if you will.   I&amp;rsquo;ll hedge against being unable to fix the issue by documenting it.  In the same process I&amp;rsquo;ll be getting wiki usage documentation up.  Two birds, one stone?  Although I might be tempted just to check if we have the same issue on our staging wiki first &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I have a plan, and the Trello board is updated.  I have a niggling doubt that I haven&amp;rsquo;t reviewed all the meetings from last week and that I&amp;rsquo;m missing some other critical issues that need fixing.  Other annoying ones that I do have in the Trello &amp;ldquo;icebox&amp;rdquo; include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create pages defaults to the basic editor which many find confusing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moderation notices fail in some cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The visual editor doesn&amp;rsquo;t fail gracefully&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another knot in that if we can&amp;rsquo;t rely on the visual editor failing gracefully then it might not be such a good idea to make it the default for create pages &amp;hellip;  Anyway.  One knot at a time.  Plan is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get coffee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on first knot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on second knot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure once I&amp;rsquo;ve worked hard through these knots it will be more than enough :-) See you tomorrow :-) &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hard Launch</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/12/hard-launch/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/12/hard-launch/</id>
    <published>2017-05-12T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-10T21:54:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="launch" src="/images/launch.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s May 12th, the hard launch date for the wiki.  We talked about a soft launch on May 4th, and we had the basic system up for then.  The hard launch is now to have everything in place.  I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the week getting usability feedback from different stakeholders across London and now we&amp;rsquo;ve got to knuckle down and make sure everything is in place.  My personal action plan document has sprouted a whole section of stuff for the wiki:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] wiki launch 

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] adding t&amp;amp;c, privacy policy into the system &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] moderation notification to more than one user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] usability issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] default to visual editor on creating pages (or wikieditor?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] save at bottom of page can be confusing in text editor &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;  use wikieditor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] help pages - upload all my training materials &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] moderation notice fails to load when using text editor?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] can we make the search do an OR rather than an AND?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] I&amp;rsquo;m worried the first page has far too much text &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] spaces on end of email address causing problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] creating an account does not log you in, or even guide you to log in or lead you towards what to do next&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] hide the bitnami management corner element&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] help pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got open support tickets with various of these items.  I&amp;rsquo;d also like to be doing a full documentation of the entire wiki setup from scratch and practising recovery drills on another box, but it feels like I must focus the morning on triaging all the usability issues that came up this week and either fixing, working around or leaving as future work.  The danger is that any individual item could be dived in too deep, at the expense of getting a slew of other items sorted.  It&amp;rsquo;s maybe time to break out a Pivotal Tracker, or perhaps a Trello instance to start tracking everything that&amp;rsquo;s going on.  So I went ahead and did that.  Trello made more sense as I can&amp;rsquo;t immediately see us voting on the complexity of the issues (although maybe we should), and Waffle doesn&amp;rsquo;t make so much sense as we&amp;rsquo;re not tightly integrated with GitHub for this project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="trello for hlp wiki" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/e55gki5ir4aeq4o/Screenshot%202017-05-12%2010.30.23.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made this Trello private to the team rather than public as this is a paid project, and we&amp;rsquo;ve got the double concern of our client sensitivity and also having some motivation for people to pay our Premium fees to get access to extra material.  I was also distracted from blogging, helping an HLP staff member sort out a table in one of the wiki pages.  Again the NHS firewall prevents us doing screenshare via Hangouts or Skype with anyone there, so a series of screenshots in Slack let me show the change manager what I had done, but I&amp;rsquo;m not confident that I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to transfer the skill of doing the task itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, getting the Trello up has paid down my day&amp;rsquo;s anxiety debt a little.  There&amp;rsquo;s still lots to do, but at least I&amp;rsquo;ve got a better way of coordinating what we&amp;rsquo;re doing.  The frustrating thing here is that the budget is on a scale that has prevented me from financially incentivizing more Premium members to get involved.  This project is actually a perfect microcosm of all the issues that Agile is supposed to handle.  It just doesn&amp;rsquo;t have large tracts of programming activity.  Is that the fundamental mismatch here?  That I&amp;rsquo;m really interested in the problem solving and how the coding relates to project managment and delivering on client needs, when the majority of others are much more interested in just the code?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
