<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>All Good Things ...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/</id>
    <published>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-10T21:54:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="good things" src="/images/good_things.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been daily blogging for a year now.  Working day blogs that is.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging on weekends, or national holidays, or during my vacations.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty consistent.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of days where work was super busy due to the tail end of a design sprint or something, but I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to retro-actively blog and keep it one per work day.  I started blogging in June last year doing a blog on a different platform each day of the week, but fairly soon I fell into a pattern of blogging to our AgileVentures middleman site, and then re-releasing to Medium after I&amp;rsquo;d got a little distance from the blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the purpose of this blog frenzy?  My memory is that it was about trying to communicate more effectively.  I often end up assuming that people understand my thoughts and intentions and it turns out that actually they don&amp;rsquo;t.  Of course why would they?  There are few telepaths around.  I&amp;rsquo;m also a bit of a gabbler and my sense is that it&amp;rsquo;s not super easy to understand what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to communicate.  So blogging, get all the thoughts down in text, provide them in an accessible form for everyone to read, and maybe reduce my need to gabble on and on about things.  Win win, no?  There&amp;rsquo;s also the motivation that blogging at the start of each day is a kind of &amp;ldquo;morning pages&amp;rdquo; activity such as writers use to start off their days and clear their heads.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think writers usually publish their morning brain dump, but I have certainly found the process of starting each day with writing out my thoughts to be reassuring and relaxing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year when I was doing a lot more coding, the blogs tended to be all about the previous day&amp;rsquo;s coding.  As AgileVentures became an official charity and my admin load increased, they have tended to be about prioritization.  Starting the day with a blog is certainly less stressful than starting the day with a review of email and Slack conversations, which will generally lead to many adds to my ever-increasing todo list.  Has the time been well spent?  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had positive reactions to some blogs, but my sense is that the blogs are too long, too stream-of-consciousness, too un-focused to gain much traction.  I think I may have even alienated some with my uncensored and unedited thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was 17 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had trouble just generating text, and from even earlier I was always a talker.  It&amp;rsquo;s like my internal thought wheel is hooked up directly to my mouth, and at will I can hook it up to a pen or a keyboard and just dump my thoughts straight out, for better or for worse.  So I rarely have writer&amp;rsquo;s block, but it leaves me with a different problem.  How to edit the thicket of thoughts and ideas, so as to more effectively communicate them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to the end of a year of blogging prompts thoughts of changing things going forward.  There&amp;rsquo;ve been times in the past when rising early I&amp;rsquo;ve done 3 hours of programming before breakfast.  After recent design sprints I think about doing coding sprints, or other activities that fill the week in different ways.  Should it be one blog a week with the blog being edited and revised each day, so that a single polished blog can be released on Friday?  I guess it all depends on what one wants to achieve, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t the Buddhist in me been trying to follow a path of consecrated action, where one is totally unattached to the outcomes of activities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d have loved my blogs to have provoked more positive responses of &amp;ldquo;yes, let&amp;rsquo;s build a solution to that together &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, although there has been some of that.  What I really would like is for AgileVentures to be a healthy thriving community providing great learning experiences for many, while also helping charitable causes around the world.  The process of reflection over the last year does make me think that we&amp;rsquo;re far too text heavy in many, many parts of our interface with the world.  One of the most attractive ideas for me going forward is that I&amp;rsquo;d spend my blogging time each day focused on a part of the main AgileVentures site, converting it from text heavy to text light and adding images.  I have a hunch that, by doing this in strategic places throughout the site, we could improve the sign up rates, the number of members joining projects and the numbers signing up for Premium subscriptions, the source of our financial sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a feeling I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to shake the blogging habit.  The process has become too solidly part of my daily routine.  The thing that actually gets me started and ready to work in the mornings.  So, anyhow, starting tomorrow, blogs that focus on parts of the main AgileVentures site.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to work through it one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog released early for inclusion in our July newsletter, earlier blogs are all in draft form in GitHub and will be on this site soon&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NHS Wiki Marketing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/08/nhs-wiki-marketing/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/08/nhs-wiki-marketing/</id>
    <published>2017-06-08T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-04T21:38:30+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="marketing" src="/images/marketing.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crazy day yesterday - felt pretty under attack.  I&amp;rsquo;d love to lay it all in text, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can indulge myself beyond what I typed up in private notes yesterday and I have a meeting with the NHS folks tomorrow, and I think highest priority is having at least part of a draft of a marketing report for them to look at.  I&amp;rsquo;m worried if I blog about anything else I&amp;rsquo;ll just not get the report done, as I lost hours yesterday to reacting to what felt like emotionally charged posts on Slack.  So, what is the set of stuff that will go into the NHS Wiki marketing report?  Ironically I go to open Slack to find out as I have recently posted it into the #marketing channel &amp;hellip; here we go (and quickly turn Slack off before getting distracted):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monthly moderation reports need to be submitted including the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of rejected contributions with reasons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capacity required for moderation and time spent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any issues with the process and practice of moderation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other data as agreed to aid evaluation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly reports must also include marketing data including the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number of user log-ins (unique and repeated)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of users that logged in who commented or added to the wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What sections of the resource receive the most activity from users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geographical location and role of user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information of promotion/marketing of the resource&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other data as agreed to assist evaluation (i.e.uptime/downtime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s work through each of these and pull up some numbers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of rejected contributions with reasons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;71 rejected submissions of which 8 were tests by admin staff and 63 were &amp;ldquo;spam&amp;rdquo; (irrelevant) submissions &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capacity required for moderation and time spent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this first month the 63 &amp;ldquo;spam&amp;rdquo; submissions were all very clearly irrelevant to the site, i.e. submissions on topics completely unrelated to healthcare.  The moderation was largely handled by the automated system.  Admins spent at most a couple of hours reviewing submissions, rejecting &amp;ldquo;spam&amp;rdquo; submissions and marking spammers as such.  Existing stakeholders were quickly marked as moderator approved (requiring no more than a couple of hours over the month), and as such there were no moderated submissions for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any issues with the process and practice of moderation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment the ratio of spam to normal submissions is rather high and created the slight risk that a normal submission may be lost in the spam listings.  These automated spam submissions might be handled more effectively with MediaWiki policing like AbuseFilter, SpamBlacklist or ConfirmEdit, but these need testing to see the impact they might have on the submission process for regular users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other data as agreed to aid evaluation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No other data yet requested&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The number of user log-ins (unique and repeated)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logins are not required to view the site.   Site traffic from Google Analytics indicates that over the last month there were 293 visits to the site, corresponding to 134 different unique users.  The average session&amp;rsquo;s duration was 5 minutes and 40 seconds, which involved visiting on average 4.6 pages. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of users that logged in who commented or added to the wiki&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11 users were active in the last 30 days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;| #Actions   | UserName       |
| ---------- | -------------- |
| 62         | JTong          |
| 30         | Suzi.griffiths |
| 13         | Peterilves     |
| 7          | Prusal         |
| 7          | Whifra         |
| 5          | Kim Hunt       |
| 5          | Dnewton        |
| 4          | Mulash         |
| 2          | JacquiWheeler  |
| 2          | Mags           |
| 1          | Shanooman      |

(from https://wiki.healthylondon.org/Special:ActiveUsers)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What sections of the resource receive the most activity from users&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top ten visited pages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="top ten visited pages" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/xy8ca86qjt9iq6i/Screenshot%202017-06-08%2018.17.25.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top ten accessed pages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;| #Revisions | Page name                                                         |
| &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- | &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;                                                    |
| 48         | Social Prescribing and Self Care Wiki                             |
| 25         | Social Prescribing                                                |
| 14         | Test Page                                                         |
| 14         | Policy and strategy in social prescribing                         |
| 14         | Help                                                              |
| 11         | Steps towards implementation                                      |
| 10         | Social prescribing for children, young people, parents and carers |
| 9          | Making Every Contact Count                                        |
| 9          | Self Management                                                   |
| 7          | Monitoring and evaluating social prescribing                      |&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(from https://wiki.healthylondon.org/Special:MostRevisions)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical location and role of user&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="top ten country visitors" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/y45nxt2d7p6dcp0/Screenshot%202017-06-08%2010.16.06.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="top ten cities" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/37u5brazchus1jt/Screenshot%202017-06-08%2010.16.38.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="demographics" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/y54sw2w7dvyhz1i/Screenshot%202017-06-08%2018.13.52.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information of promotion/marketing of the resource&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AgileVentures has promoted the site through their monthly newsletter to their member base of over 4000 around the world, and linked the wiki into the Social Prescribing page on Wikipedia, as well as reaching out and inviting all the stakeholders involved in the design sprint to contribute.  We&amp;rsquo;ve also developed the following text for promoting the wiki on the HLP website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Healthy London Partnerships (HLP) Proactive Care team presents a shared editable website (a &amp;ldquo;wiki&amp;rdquo;) dedicated to Social Prescribing &amp;amp; Self Care. This wiki is available as an open resource for everyone who is interested in Social Prescribing &amp;amp; Self Care and related subject matters.  The wiki uses the same MediaWiki software that powers Wikipedia, and can be edited by any approved user. In the first instance the wiki is a repository for resources to support NHS commissioners and others to implement and develop social prescribing and self-care in their localities. Social prescribing, sometimes referred to as community referral, is a means of enabling GPs, nurses and other primary care professionals to refer people to a range of local, non-clinical services.  The wiki is hosted by the AgileVentures charity on behalf of the Healthy London Partnership.  AgileVentures ran a design sprint with the Proactive care team and stakeholders from all over London NHS and voluntary sector partners to identify the mediawiki solution as the one most likely to meet stakeholder needs.  Please check out the wiki at https://wiki.healthylondon.org and sign up for a free account in order to start contributing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other data as agreed to assist evaluation (i.e.uptime/downtime)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Azure guarantees a 99% uptime for their Azure service: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/support/legal/sla/cloud-services/v1_0/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There we go, that&amp;rsquo;s a way to stay focused - blog the report that needs to be written &amp;hellip; now to get this off to the NHS &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Life is Complicated</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/07/life-is-complicated/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/07/life-is-complicated/</id>
    <published>2017-06-07T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-08-31T21:19:57+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="life is complicated" src="/images/life_is_complicated.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well no surprise to anyone, but life appears to be rather complex :-) I try to listen to a tech podcast daily to keep up with techworld and I just listened to &lt;a href="https://www.greaterthancode.com/podcast/episode-020-jenn-schiffer/"&gt;Jenn Schiffer on &amp;ldquo;&amp;gt;Code&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; which was a fascinating episode.  Of the many and complex thoughts it spurred, here are two:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I try to blog honestly and thoughtfully every work day, but I know I still hold loads back for fear of offence or creating difficult to manage situations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;personality cult vs open source - I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow managed to miss bad press about the personalities of Linus Torvalds, Eric S. Raymond etc.  I&amp;rsquo;m so impressed with linux/git that it&amp;rsquo;s complicated to hear that Linus &amp;ldquo;isn&amp;rsquo;t a good person&amp;rdquo;.  Less so with ESR, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been pointing people to read &lt;em&gt;The Cathedral and the Bazaar&lt;/em&gt; for many years &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we could definitely do with a lot less hero worship, but I wonder who gets to decide who is and isn&amp;rsquo;t a &amp;ldquo;good person&amp;rdquo;?  I guess if people are on record making certain sorts of statements that&amp;rsquo;s one thing, but I wonder what makes someone fundamentally good or fundamentally bad?  I asked all these questions in the &amp;ldquo;&amp;gt;Code&amp;rdquo; Slack and already I&amp;rsquo;m kind of worried if I&amp;rsquo;m going to have stepped over a line and have rubbed people up the wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things making my brain twist and turn include the camera light on my macbook being stuck on, making me think of the continual cameras in Orwell&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;1984.&lt;/em&gt;  I think I will probably have to reboot the computer to fix it, which takes up a chunk of time to manage all the open stuff on my computer.  I also had a potential Premium member enquiring about how our AgileVentures professional development support works (I accidentally looked at my email before blogging) which is great, but my reply seems to have bounced with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an email abuse report for an email message received from IP 217.70.183.197 on Wed, 7 Jun 2017 01:20:00 -0700.
The message below did not meet the sending domain&amp;rsquo;s authentication policy.
For more information about this format please see http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc5965.txt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Feedback-Type: auth-failure
User-Agent: XMR/2.2
Version: 1.0
Original-Mail-From: &amp;lt;sam@agileventures.org&amp;gt;
Arrival-Date: Wed, 7 Jun 2017 01:20:00 -0700
Message-ID: &amp;lt;c1afb083-78cf-a23a-745c-473a8e1465a0@agileventures.org&amp;gt;
Authentication-Results: hotmail.com; spf=softfail (sender IP is 217.70.183.197; identity alignment result is pass and alignment mode is relaxed) smtp.mailfrom=sam@agileventures.org; dkim=none (identity alignment result is pass and alignment mode is relaxed) header.d=agileventures.org; x-hmca=fail header.id=sam@agileventures.org
Source-IP: 217.70.183.197
Auth-Failure: spf
Reported-Domain: agileventures.org
DKIM-Domain: agileventures.org
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s unclear is whether the email will have been delivered with a flag, or will have bounced.  It&amp;rsquo;s worrying because maybe that means that the email I last sent to LaunchCode about collaboration didn&amp;rsquo;t get through.  I&amp;rsquo;m fairly sure many of my emails do get through.  I&amp;rsquo;ve previously emailed Gandi (my domain hoster) about this, but they haven&amp;rsquo;t responded.  Might it be my email client?  I need to reboot anyway, so time to upgrade my Thunderbird client I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also find that the non-profit discount that we&amp;rsquo;re getting on Hootsuite is 50% rather than 100% - my mistake.  So now we&amp;rsquo;re committed to £40 a month for something that I&amp;rsquo;m not sure we actually need.  I guess we can cancel, but this is something that the marketing folks are interested in having.  Hootsuite (which I don&amp;rsquo;t know well) appears to allow you to set up a Social Media posting plan and sending tweets and facebook posts and things to a branded social media account.  We were introduced to Hootsuite by a Premium member who&amp;rsquo;s been volunteering on the marketing team.  We also now have two marketing interns and several other members regularly attending our twice-weekly marketing meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of things going on under the purview of marketing, including the new monthly newsletter, these social media posting plans, promoting our Agile Book Club podcast, to name a few, as well as trying to work out how to make our websites better communicate what we do.  I&amp;rsquo;m totally convinced that we can&amp;rsquo;t succeed without the right communication, but I&amp;rsquo;m also confused about the value of something like a social media posting plan.  I also worry that questioning the value of it might offend some people, and/or be interpreted as me quashing their ideas.  As a senior AV member it seems that my opinions carry a lot of weight, and I have to be careful about expressing a lack of enthusiasm for a particular approach or direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was something that came up in the context of the MakersAcademy bootcamp where we talked about how CEO&amp;rsquo;s of companies might not realise they were always seen as carrying a couple of pistols.  There&amp;rsquo;s apparently this idea that junior people will sometimes silently throw out their ideas and initiatives if they perceive a senior person is not enthusiastic about something.  It maybe follows that this is a particularly serious issue in volunteer organisations where coming across as negative about a particular idea might lead a volunteer to completely give up and not volunteer their time in the future.  Now of course I don&amp;rsquo;t imagine anyone is going to complain if I say we can&amp;rsquo;t allocate financial budget to something, but why should that be any different to temporal budget, i.e. hours spent on something?  I guess that&amp;rsquo;s where measurement comes in.  Perhaps I should be relying far less on my intuition about what is and isn&amp;rsquo;t an effective approach; embrace all approaches, whatever I think of them, and focus on helping whoever suggests the approaches to get involved in measuring their effectiveness &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thread of complexity that links some of these topics together is that when I reviewed the first Social Media posting plan, I suggested replacing posts including quotes of Mark Zuckerberg with quotes from open source luminaries like Linus Torvalds, ESR and David Heinemeier Hansson.  Posting quotes from Facebook&amp;rsquo;s founder made me feel nervous, because of my misgivings about the facebook system, partly arising from me being hacked on there a few years back, and news stories about the algorithms facebook employs to adjust what you see, and posts from FreeCodeCamps&amp;rsquo; Quincy Larson and a sort of general feeling of unease that I get when I look at a facebook feed mixing updates and images from friends and family with adverts for products whose values I question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the &amp;gt;Code podcast is giving me pause for thought about some of these open source luminaries and even the idea that we should be promoting &amp;ldquo;famous&amp;rdquo; individuals.  I mean the whole concept of the social media posting plan seems rather artificial to me.  I would much rather be having posts about individuals in our organisation, or from individuals in our organisation about what they thought and they were doing.  As I understand it, the social media posting plan is about brand building.  Other brands are regularly posting on social media, so we need to do so as well in order to compete?   Is it dangerous to express concerns since that will demotivate people to try things?  I guess I come back to trying to focus on the measurement process.  But then sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to measure and take time to measure, so in the meantime you try to use your intuition. I&amp;rsquo;m tying myself in knots &amp;hellip; life does indeed appear complicated :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Saddle Sore</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/06/saddle-sore/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/06/saddle-sore/</id>
    <published>2017-06-06T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-08-30T21:07:11+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="saddle sore" src="/images/saddle-sore.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday it was back in the saddle after a break and I&amp;rsquo;m feeling a little saddle sore already :-) Fairly productive first day I guess - a lot of meetings and a few critical admin tasks taken care of.  Let&amp;rsquo;s look back at those meetings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noon Martin Fowler scrum - caught up with Matt and Lokesh, and talked through Lokesh&amp;rsquo;s PR on LocalSupport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1pm  Marketing meeting - caught up with Michael, Lara, Federico, Marufa, Blandine and Matt - managed to finish up in 45 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4:15pm Kent Beck scrum - just me and Michael - just a quick catch up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4:45pm Impromptu WSO coordination meeting - Michael, myself and Matt - talked through SSL certificate upgrade and github issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5:45pm AV Community meeting - Michael, JP, myself and Matt - talked about funding me and the upcoming design sprint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The critical admin things I got done were revising the AV charity tender documents that will hopefully allow me to generate some income from all the work I put into AV, sending emails to a mix of charity and private clients (past, current and potential future), and deploying the latest code for WSO, which had the pleasing side-effect of re-directing all the MOOC student pairing sessions into the correct chat channels (rather than spamming Slack #general).  I also managed to go through another round of creating private premium chat channels and engaging with AV mentors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not much room for coding in all this.  There&amp;rsquo;s a bit of talking about it.  I was able to just snatch at the security renewal issue between the WSO meeting and the AV Community meeting.  It seems like the following is enough to renew the certificate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo certbot certonly --manual
Saving debug log to /var/log/letsencrypt/letsencrypt.log
Please enter in your domain name(s) (comma and/or space separated)  (Enter 'c'
to cancel):develop.agileventures.org
Cert is due for renewal, auto-renewing...
Renewing an existing certificate
Performing the following challenges:
http-01 challenge for develop.agileventures.org
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;assuming that one types in the correct domain.  Given that the challenge is replied to correctly from the server, one gets new certificates saved locally and they can be updated in heroku like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo heroku certs:update /etc/letsencrypt/live/develop.agileventures.org/fullchain.pem /etc/letsencrypt/live/develop.agileventures.org/privkey.pem -r develop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so I need to get that done for the staging and production servers.  It also seems that the fixed part of the challenge key is not changing and so we definitely need to move that into an environment variable (if not change it completely) and then also work out if there&amp;rsquo;s some further way of automating this.  Apparently we can run &lt;code&gt;certbot renew&lt;/code&gt; but when I tried a dry run, it indicates I need to configure an authentication script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;The error was: PluginError('An authentication script must be provided with --manual-auth-hook when using the manual plugin non-interactively.',). Skipping.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to punt on the automation and focus on this first renewal manually and the change that will pull the fixed part of our token into an environment variable.  Going to make that the priority after this blog is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to yesterday&amp;rsquo;s meetings, I had been feeling pretty good about the marketing meeting in that we had worked through all the business pretty efficiently and avoiding long and meandering discussions.  I was focusing on not &amp;ldquo;blocking&amp;rdquo; anyone.  Ideas and suggestions were celebrated.  That they might have been mentioned before, or that they might have logically inconsistencies was only subtly alluded to, if at all.  I had a strong sense of &amp;ldquo;the more people in the meeting, the more important it is to avoid disagreement&amp;rdquo;.  That might sound like awful group think, but meetings are a kind of trap that people often feel they can&amp;rsquo;t leave.  Long discussions with point and counter-point should be moved into other meetings where everyone has &amp;ldquo;opted-in&amp;rdquo; specfically for that debate.  At least that&amp;rsquo;s my best guess at the moment - the &amp;ldquo;efficiently-run&amp;rdquo; meeting seemed to go down well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was confusion in my mind about whether the Agile Book Club podcast would go ahead since one member was suggesting a change of day.  Since we still hadn&amp;rsquo;t mixed episodes 2-10 I was tempted to try and use that slot for mixing rather than recording more.  That didn&amp;rsquo;t work out either and since I&amp;rsquo;m off early on Friday I suggested we try and do an impromptu WebsiteOne meeting.  That backfired in that the podcast member who had suggested the change of day hadn&amp;rsquo;t meant for this week, and my sense was that was frustrating for them.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m imagining a more intense set of emotions from the person than was there.  We were only communicating in Slack.  I ended up feeling pretty bad about it with the incident going round and round in my mind all night and now this morning.  Why should I end up focusing on that negative in a day with several other positives?  Is that evolutionary?  Are hurt feelings the danger signs that paleolithic humans needed to pay attention and sort out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve projected/imagined higher emotional states in the past? Maybe, or perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s that I&amp;rsquo;ve just apologised too profusely to the point where I&amp;rsquo;ve just added irritation to injury?  The podcast member was re-iterating that we should have just asked.  I had an outstanding question to them in Slack about the change of day.  We didn&amp;rsquo;t have the previous week&amp;rsquo;s Slack message confirming the topics that we&amp;rsquo;d talked about having.  The member in question is in a distant timezone which seems to make having the podcasts on Monday somewhat precarious because it makes them first thing on Monday morning for that person, and so there&amp;rsquo;s not much room to give alerts about potential changes of plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I find it difficult if something I&amp;rsquo;m planning for gets changed at the last minute.  I had been hoping that the individual might have joined us for the WSO meeting or AV community meeting, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t push things, sensing (or imagining) their frustration.  Why is this so sticky for me?  Similarly when my son&amp;rsquo;s football team loses (I&amp;rsquo;m the coach).  I think it&amp;rsquo;s my &amp;ldquo;hard ego shell&amp;rdquo; as Eckhart Tolle and Steve Taylor might call it.  I&amp;rsquo;m very attached to an image of myself as a punctual, reliable, organised, dedicated, effective, good and considerate person.  Things that appear to reflect on me as inconsiderate or ineffective are painful.  Logically what they reflect is that I&amp;rsquo;m human and make mistakes.  The stickiness is me beating myself up about the damaged self-image &amp;hellip; maybe :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s something else here I&amp;rsquo;m grappling with.  Communication.  We&amp;rsquo;ve got all these meetings going on, most of them being recorded and shared on YouTube, and that helps the wider team catch up sometimes, but realistically most people are not going to have time to watch the videos.  I think I (and others?) can end up with the false sense of having communicated something.  You say something in five meetings, maybe even to the same small group of people, and you unconciously think you&amp;rsquo;ve communicated it.  That might work well in a paleolithic village where the process of collocated gossiping will mean pretty much everyone knows everything quickly.  Much as I want to spend more time coding, I think the real problem to crack is communication internally and externally.  I suspect most people coming into AgileVentures from outside are confused about what we offer, and I think we have poor information flow internally about things like the AV community meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That came up from a big chat in #av-community-talk and we added an event on the main site, but then there&amp;rsquo;s still the occasional comment about &amp;ldquo;how would I find out about this sort of thing?&amp;rdquo; and I guess it&amp;rsquo;s either accept that you browse your way to knowledge on things and that there&amp;rsquo;s no reliable way of reaching out to everyone, or we solve that problem of working out what is the one correct way to communicate with all the of the people in our distributed team.  I suspect that people are getting their information from different sources &amp;hellip; email, slack, their calender, meetings, private chats with friends etc.  Maybe the AV Community Talk meeting needs to go in the newsletter.  Maybe the site needs more popups to alert people to things in a drip campaign fashion.  There was a great feedback feature on an e-commerce site I was using last night.  When I paused on the payment page for a long time it asked me for quick feedback and I said the shipping prices were too high.  I guess that&amp;rsquo;s the kind of information we&amp;rsquo;ll be hoping to get from the design sprint, but if our site could be rigged to get ongoing quick impressions from people about joining up, making purchasing decisions etc &amp;hellip; Interesting times.  I think the one thing I can be sure of is a few more saddle sores &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Back in the Saddle</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/05/back-in-the-saddle/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/05/back-in-the-saddle/</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-08-29T21:39:49+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="saddle" src="/images/saddle.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m just coming off the back of another half-term that I (mostly) took off to spend time with my family.  Ever since my first son was born and money was a little tight, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to squeeze every working moment out of a day, and I think I may be suffering from a &amp;ldquo;more haste, less speed&amp;rdquo; situation.  Well who knows, I just don&amp;rsquo;t know what the key is.  Pour your energy and effort into something and you can easily burn out, spin your wheels, miss the wood for the trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did work Tuesday last week, in-between trips away to get a few things done, such as pushing out the week 1 MOOC materials, pay some bills and stuff I can&amp;rsquo;t now remember.  I had a few people phoning me while I was away - I need to talk to them about switching to email.  My wife suggested there are two sorts of people - the ones who prefer to commmunicate in writing and the others who prefer to just talk.  I love both, but I really don&amp;rsquo;t like being called out of the blue.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve really got to upgrade to gandi&amp;rsquo;s premium mail plan, or move to a different provider, in order to get proper &amp;ldquo;on annual leave&amp;rdquo; messages from my sam@agileventures.org email address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back at the keyboard again. Listened to another podcast during my morning jog and tweeted and slacked that, without getting too distracted by email and Slack.  Whenever I come back from these little breaks I seem to spend most of the day working through the communications backlog.  I&amp;rsquo;m still nervous about cashflow to support my kids, but there are green shoots.  Next week we&amp;rsquo;ve got our AgileVentures online design sprint.  There&amp;rsquo;s a famous quote about how if you want to get people to build ships, that rather than teach them ship building, that you should inspire them to crave the experience of the wide open sea.  I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the design sprint can be something of a vision quest where the community comes together over a vision that can drive itself forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then two weeks after that I&amp;rsquo;m running an in-person design sprint for a closed source educational project.  Fingers crossed that&amp;rsquo;ll pay for my kids extra-curricular music, sports and travel for when I&amp;rsquo;m taking my seventh week breaks to spend time with them.  As I was saying to a couple of relatives over the weekend, I start to see the appeal of a straightforward job with a job description and a reliable, regular salary; although maybe those don&amp;rsquo;t exist anymore?   Feels like some people must have them.  The difficult with being my own boss (of my private company and the AgileVentures charity) is that every day I&amp;rsquo;ve got to be weighing up the pros and cons of how I spend each minute of each hour.  Will this activity generate value?  Will that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a very in the moment &amp;ldquo;mindful&amp;rdquo; way to be.  I&amp;rsquo;ve just read &amp;ldquo;Leap&amp;rdquo; by Steve Taylor, which suggests that Eckhart Tolle-esque spiritual awakenings are not that rare.  Those are enlightenment moments where future and past disappear and you become totally engrossed in the moment, combined with the dissolution of any sense of separation between yourself and the rest of the world.  There are also overtones of everything (plants, rocks, inanimate objects) all being infused with a benign consciousness or aliveness.  Just typing it out I remember this concept of &amp;ldquo;flow&amp;rdquo; from the gaming and education/skills literature which has some of the first, and maybe second, aspects where you become totally engrossed in a task.  Another thing I did yesterday was write out a list of the different competing narratives that struggle for supremacy in my head - quite a few of them being anxiety strains.  I&amp;rsquo;d love to have an awakening moment.  I managed to sit in a deck chair looking at the sky for half an hour on Saturday.  I&amp;rsquo;d love to have a mechanism to just shut down all the trains of thought when they&amp;rsquo;re not necessary, but I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m a long way from achieving any kind of awakening that&amp;rsquo;s described in these books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the absence of some spontaneous awakening, the key appears to be observing your thoughts rather than getting swept away by them.  I&amp;rsquo;m forever getting swept away in my thoughts and reactions.  Be the mountain, they say. Let the thoughts pass by as clouds.  Easier said than done.  That said, before the break, I did manage to &amp;ldquo;wake up&amp;rdquo; in some conversations and group meetings.  For some reason it&amp;rsquo;s group interaction that&amp;rsquo;s the hardest to stay &amp;ldquo;present&amp;rdquo; in.  People say things, you react, they react; it&amp;rsquo;s almost like running on auto-pilot.  To be able to stop and really consciously respond from a place of consideration &amp;hellip; if there&amp;rsquo;s some other trick, it eludes me.  Till then it&amp;rsquo;s back in the saddle.  Keep observing those thoughts, keep trying to &amp;ldquo;awake&amp;rdquo; in conversations and meetings, try not to let the minute by minute evaluation of the &amp;ldquo;worth&amp;rdquo; of an activity get in the way of mindfulness of the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Year of Blogging</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/05/26/year-of-blogging/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/05/26/year-of-blogging/</id>
    <published>2017-05-26T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-19T22:06:03+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="blogging" src="/images/blog-i-am.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think I&amp;rsquo;m coming up on a year of blogging.  I don&amp;rsquo;t actually know which was the day that I started blogging daily. I can see one that I posted on &lt;a href="http://linklens.blogspot.co.uk/2016/06/moving-beyond-toy-problems.html"&gt;June 20th 2016&lt;/a&gt;.  At the beginning I was posting in different locations each day.  But here&amp;rsquo;s another on &lt;a href="http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2016/06/21/agile-approach-to-login-signup-problems/"&gt;June 21st 2016&lt;/a&gt; so although I did blog on &lt;a href="http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2016/05/17/collaborating-in-software-teams/"&gt;May 17th 2016&lt;/a&gt; I didn&amp;rsquo;t get into the daily rhythm until later in June.  I&amp;rsquo;d almost convinced myself that I started in late May so that I could be wrapping up now, but my obsessive nature means I will probably force myself to go all the way to June 20th.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been an interesting thing to do for a year, but I think a change will also be welcome.  While I&amp;rsquo;ve demonstrated that I can blog daily and there&amp;rsquo;s been some value for me in organising my thoughts, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve gained much of a following or inspired many people.  Part of the idea of blogging is to get all my ideas about the future of AgileVentures out of my head and accessible to others.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been aided by tireless review from Federico and I think there&amp;rsquo;s definitely some extent to which my blogging has distributed my ideas amongst the AgileVentures members, but at the same time my blogs are largely unpolished streams of consciousness and I&amp;rsquo;ve been more focused on cranking them out than I have on making them intelligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there&amp;rsquo;s also an extent to which the frenetic activity on my part drowns out other voices in the community.  We&amp;rsquo;d probably be in a much stronger state as a community if we had four or five different people each blogging weekly.  I sense that my voice is too strong.  I suspect that my too loud voice and my blogging about &amp;ldquo;Legacy Code&amp;rdquo; affected my co-founders decision to step back from the community.   I&amp;rsquo;m going to carry on to June 20th but I&amp;rsquo;m now itching to replace my daily blog with a daily focus on the AgileVentures website.  My latest hypothesis is that if I spent as much time on the tone of voice and content in the AV site as I did on my blogs we might be a bit further along to achieving financial stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll see.  Right now I feel pretty low about the many areas that need fixing up to make the AV site and its value propositions comprehensible to the new members coming in from the MOOC, our Google Adwords grant and my appearances on Ruby Rogues.  I feel pretty down about the MOOC as well, where I would like to have upgraded to Rails 5 and have lots more improved content.  Juggling everything I&amp;rsquo;m just about managing to hold those two properties down to have basic consistency.  I feel a bit better about the NHS HLP wiki project, and of course we&amp;rsquo;re at that point that I have to focus on paid projects.  Yesterday I had a good, albeit cut off, chat with a person based in Myanmar about a non-profit project that might have some funding, and today is the deadline for a local non-profit project bid.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funny thing here is the ongoing decision making about putting in bids - too high and you don&amp;rsquo;t get anything, too low and you&amp;rsquo;re on a deathmarch trying to deliver the goods.  I start to see the attraction of the salaried 9-5 where someone tells you what to do and you get paid a consistent amount.  Still salaried jobs come and go as well.  At least I get to spend more time with my kids working on all this from home.   Time for a break for a week - I&amp;rsquo;m pleased we&amp;rsquo;ve got a design sprint planned for the week of June 12th.  I&amp;rsquo;m hoping we can all get on the same page regarding the AgileVentures experience.  What seems strange to me is that we can get 40 or so Premium members, but we seem to have plateaued.  We&amp;rsquo;re only growing very slowly, getting a few upgrades here and there.  We&amp;rsquo;re doing a lot of marketing activity but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be translating in converting members to Premium.  Hopefully the design sprint might help us get to the bottom of that conundrum.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what the year of blogging achieved - time to try out some alternatives &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
