<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>drie GitHub integration</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/01/09/drie-github/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/01/09/drie-github/</id>
    <published>2017-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-13T21:02:46+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Friday I took a trip down to the drie offices in Hammersmith.  We&amp;rsquo;d agreed before the break that we needed to coordinate our collaboration for the new year.  We&amp;rsquo;d previously agreed a sliding scale of sponsorship support based on outcomes for drie in terms of the number of users adopting drie.  In preparation for the meeting I prepared the following list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What I need

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ability to track the number of people using drie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What I need to do

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;check whether moving drie servers to Ireland is getting the performance increase we hoped for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;migrate more of LocalSupport to drie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prepare for the devops conference talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improve on the document outlining the needs of the different AgileVentures projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get budget details for drie hosting MetPlus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;detailed technical plan for the following year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking through the above with Ben and Tom at drie and the things they wanted to get through we came up with the following agenda:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drie to show new features for drie-push

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub Integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;versioned config&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;appdirect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look at drie pricing models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look at performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conference talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;generate clear features to de-risk the collaboration going forward

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;acceptance criteria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;roadmap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;geek out about the new proxy model (to help understand drie push startup times)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working through the agenda it became clear that at the moment there wasn&amp;rsquo;t an easy way to track which AgileVentures members were using drie, as all that drie records of drie-push users is ssh keys.  However this would change with the introduction of a new GitHub integration which was the first thing Ben and Tom showed me.  Rather than building an entire team&amp;rsquo;s management framework to compete with Heroku and others, Tom came up with the idea of using a &lt;a href="https://github.com/integrations"&gt;GitHub integration&lt;/a&gt; to leverage the existing GitHub teams framework.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AgileVentures already uses a lot of Github integrations such as TravisCI, Semaphore and CodeClimate.  GitHub themselves are &lt;a href="https://github.com/blog/2226-build-an-integration-for-github"&gt;encouraging more and more developers to create integrations&lt;/a&gt;, and the drie GitHub integration looks very similar in that it can be configured and installed via a GitHub interface, and little ticks and crosses are added to the GitHub interface when operations succeed and fail.  &lt;a href="https://github.com/integrations/heroku-review-apps"&gt;Heroku Review Apps&lt;/a&gt; are also a GitHub integration and work in a similar fashion, albeit requiring a complete separate Heroku app set up for them to riff off.  However, we&amp;rsquo;ve had to turn off Heroku review apps as being too expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;drie push GitHub integration goes one step beyond Heroku review apps, by making it possible to set up a repository to just deploy on any push to GitHub.  It&amp;rsquo;s like Heroku Review apps without the overhead of having to deal with Heroku or their new pricing model.  Tom was also showing me other tricks on the backend such as versioned config and reverse proxy tricks that will allow their system to scale effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went through the new drie pricing models which I need to pass on to the MetPlus project who are talking with their client today, and today I&amp;rsquo;m torn between trying to spend the whole day on pushing the LocalSupport app further onto drie (still haven&amp;rsquo;t checked the new performance data), reviewing material for my upcoming devops conference talk, and generating this new roadmap for our drie collaboration, which we did at least agree should follow this format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Dates #free-users #paid-users

include features ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The danger that Ben kept us focused on was whether developing the drie push GitHub integration would suck up time that could be spent polishing the ssh only access to drie push, and slow down our overall timeframe.  It&amp;rsquo;s almost certain that that will happen to some extent, but the problem with the ssh only approach is that the main differentiation from Heroku is on price which will be difficult to compete on in the long term.  Other drie push features such as deployment per branch won&amp;rsquo;t make much of an impact unless the configuration model is sorted out, and to be honest the big win for AgileVentures members will come from ease of use.  Avoiding the need to go to the command line at all, and just make your app deploy directly from GitHub, will remove a major stumbling block. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MrUF68V4WMw"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SttRB9A2bQ0"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YPtN3dQd6Z4"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bob Martin&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog took 33 minutes to write&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Getting Organised</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/01/06/getting-organised/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/01/06/getting-organised/</id>
    <published>2017-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-12T21:05:26+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently we had new windows put in the front of the house, which included replacing my home office windows.  This forced me to have a bit of a clear up in the office to allow the builders access.  I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of having to clear up in the physical world, although it&amp;rsquo;s always great to enjoy the results.  There always seems to be more clearing up than can be fit into a day.  Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s my personality or something about how demanding (or fun?) computers are in terms of getting things working on them.  I&amp;rsquo;d so much rather spend three hours of the afternoon working on code than sorting through my old filing cabinet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of clearing out the office actually involved moving a lot of stuff up to the spare room.  This at least created a tidier office, and a few things did get thrown out.  Then we had relatives staying over the holiday and the spare room had to be sorted for them, so the stuff displaced from my office got moved down to my bedroom, and with help from my wife I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some sorting over the last few days.  Some more stuff has been thrown out, some has been organised a little.  Over the break I did get a new filing cabinet installed in my office, and have begun the slow process of moving over stuff from the old broken plastic cabinet we brought with us from Hawaii.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obsessive in me wants to go through every piece of paper in the old filing cabinet, throwing out what is not needed and classifying everything correctly.  The difficulty is knowing what is actually needed and that many things don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily fit into simple classifications.  It&amp;rsquo;s easy, for me at least, to burn hours dithering on these kinds of things.  And it becomes even more problematic if the materials being sorted include stuff that my kids made or I inherited from my parents.  I just managed to shred a load of my mother&amp;rsquo;s old payslips, although I kept two or three as mementos in a file folder that I discovered in the cleanup.  Now what does that say about me? :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve backed down from trying to do a full re-filing session from old cabinet to new.  I do really want to throw the old one out to create more space in my office to get stuff out of the bedroom! However I don&amp;rsquo;t have the emotional energy to devote a day to doing that, and I feel bad about just dumping everything across.  I&amp;rsquo;ve gone for a compromise (?) approach where I try to become more proactive about filing things day to day.  Part of the problem in my office is that each day I&amp;rsquo;ll get a few things through the mail at a random point in the morning.  More often than not I am in the middle of working on some coding problem or set of admin tasks.  I&amp;rsquo;ll go down to get tea or coffee, will open the letters (depending on my mood) and will be tempted just to dump them on my desk rather than file them because I&amp;rsquo;m more interested in the coding or admin task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you might imagine this can lead to a situation where my desk surfaces are obscured by piles of stuff.  It&amp;rsquo;s not too bad at the moment in that, following the new window installation, I can see perhaps 35% of the desk surface clearly.  If I carried on as usual this year, that might drop to 5% before too long.  However, one of my many new year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions is to process one item on my desk every morning.  This morning it was sending an RSVP to my cousin&amp;rsquo;s wedding.  While I was in the moment I also texted my sister to check arrangements at the half term break so I can get to the point of booking my sons&amp;rsquo; dentists appointments for when they are off school.  The letter from the dentist is another item sitting on my desk to the left.  Yesterday a bank statement arrived and since that required filing, I used it as an opportunity to move the bank-related files from old filing cabinet to the new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan here is to ruthlessly and relentlessly reduce the number of items on my desk, and to gradually move the items from old filing cabinet to new, but to do it as part of the ongoing sorting.  I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this might make everything a little less painful, and introduce a new rhythmn of filing and organising things as I get them, rather than allowing them to build up.  We&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also measuring the time it takes me blog, in an attempt to keep it under 20 minutes, but so far this year it&amp;rsquo;s still stretching to 40 minutes each day.  Trying to be more organised in my office is part of an ongoing attempt to be more organised in my work generally.  It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to get distracted by whoever is sending the latest email or the latest Slack message.  The blogging itself is part of trying to give me space to get stuff done proactively rather than doing everything reactively.  Other things I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make regular are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) reviewing my action plan daily&lt;br&gt;
2) creating a blog draft in under 20 mins daily&lt;br&gt;
3) reviewing and posting the previous days blog&lt;br&gt;
4) reviewing and sending an older blog to Medium/Twitter/FB/LinkedIn&lt;br&gt;
5) reviewing PRs for LocalSupport, WebSiteOne and the AsyncVoter projects&lt;br&gt;
6) listening to, and Slacking, a podcast  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although maybe I should be dropping this obsession with chipping away at things, clear my desk (metaphorically at least) and focus on coding the key things that I think will bring in more revenue to AgileVentures; and there really needs to be more revenue if I want to continue my current lifestyle.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t do any focused coding yesterday.  It was all scrums, code review, comments in pull requests, scripts for merging edX courses, responding to email from instructors using the ESaaS textbook, sorting out the meetup group, and trying to get registered as a charity with TechSoup, which is what Slack is asking us to do to be confirmed as a non-profit.  That last seems to involve us having to submit accounts, and so I have to make a financial projection for the year &amp;hellip;?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I look back at the last year it feels like the efforts that brought in revenue were reaching out to AV members via email, many of whom converted to Premium plans, and hooking up with a Sponsor through my personal network.  So far all my attempts to gain additional sponsors through emails have produced some interesting leads, but no results.  At the moment my mind is buzzing with the idea of reaching out to all the AV Slack members in DM to let them know that now AgileVentures is an official charity, Premium plan payments are tax deductible, hoping that this will be good news for those who are already signed up, and might encourage a few more to consider the option; as well as get feedback on the offering.  Doing that sounds like a lot more interesting and productive than sorting out my filing cabinet &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LPb6K9oksxI"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mARKUGnA4Pc"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. there were also a lot of interesting technical things that came up yesterday, such as the Avdi Grimm code we looked at in Mob Programming, all the stuff I was putting in PR review about managing project work that I should be writing in my book proposal, the MongoDB security issue we talked about in the &amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum and the twitter disabling hook in the twitter PR for WebSiteOne to name a few &amp;hellip; and I have to restrict myself to one blog a day?!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.p.s this blog took 33 minutes to write&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Slow but Steady</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/01/05/slow-but-steady/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/01/05/slow-but-steady/</id>
    <published>2017-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-11T21:23:08+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m finding my pace rather slow after the break.  At least I&amp;rsquo;m sleeping through my 6:30am alarms and not really rousing myself til 7:30am.  That&amp;rsquo;s fine this week as my two youngest don&amp;rsquo;t start school till next Monday so there&amp;rsquo;s not a hard &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;ll take you to court if you&amp;rsquo;re kids are not in school on time&amp;rdquo; deadline that I&amp;rsquo;m breaking by catching some extra zzz&amp;rsquo;s.  I assume my body just needs it after the rigors of last year and the holiday season.  I&amp;rsquo;m 45 this year, and I know that I&amp;rsquo;ve tended to work all my life (or at least since I was 23 or so) by pushing myself as hard as I can.  I think I&amp;rsquo;ve probably pushed too hard in the past to the detriment of personal relationships.  I might be in a different place if I&amp;rsquo;d been less aggressive in my relentless pursuit of a dozen &amp;ldquo;next things&amp;rdquo; in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Xmas my wife bought me &amp;ldquo;Buddhism, Plain and Simple&amp;rdquo; by Steven Hagen.  It&amp;rsquo;s similar in some ways to the &amp;ldquo;Power of Now&amp;rdquo; by Eckhart Tolle, a book my mother bought me before she died.  I&amp;rsquo;ve read the &amp;ldquo;Power of Now&amp;rdquo; about five times, it&amp;rsquo;s quite gripping.  I found the Buddhism book similar.  Both books talk about life at a level completely different from most works of fiction or pretty much any technical book I&amp;rsquo;ve read, asking you to think about how you interact with people, how you set your life goals etc.  The funny thing is that I feel I&amp;rsquo;ve had an intellectual insight into the whole thing that fits together elements from both books and various other experiences.  Ironically this has not allowed me to achieve Nirvana, Sartori, or become a Buddha :-)  It hasn&amp;rsquo;t actually made much difference in my day to day, with the possible exception of not giving myself too much of a hard time about the extra hour of sleep this week - but then I was leaning in that direction anyway &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Buddhism Plain and Simple" src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/41XE1NKY9DL._SY344_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The insight, if I can call it that, is that the Buddha-mind, or the &amp;ldquo;Power of Now&amp;rdquo;, etc. the spiritual component that could be argued to underly many major religions, is about slowing your high level reasoning and processing, and just allowing yourself to float in the raw sensory data that you&amp;rsquo;re experiencing.  The ever present, ongoing &amp;ldquo;now&amp;rdquo;.  I suspect that this is the state that very small infants and children are in.  As we become adults, many of us become increasingly wrapped up in the conceptual world.  For example, on my morning walk I was listening to a software engineering podcast because I&amp;rsquo;m trying hard to keep up with all the latest trends so that I can do the best job I possibly can to support all the AgileVentures members, particularly the Premium ones, and turn AgileVentures into a sustainable charitable enterprise.  As I&amp;rsquo;m listening to the podcast I&amp;rsquo;m also slighly anxious about how to achieve that sustainability, how to ensure that we can afford our family trip to Japan this summer so that my children can spend time with their elderly Japanese grand-parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Power of Now" src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/411nlAJXoJL._SX320_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the &amp;ldquo;secret&amp;rdquo; of the Buddha or the &amp;ldquo;Power of Now&amp;rdquo; is being able to drop into that raw sensory experience at will.  It&amp;rsquo;s not really a secret as all the books describe it in various ways and make the point about that you need to experience it yourself before it makes any sense.  The key is not that you stop planning or worrying about the practicalities of life, but that you are able to drop into a kind of no-worry, enjoyment of just &amp;ldquo;having senses experience&amp;rdquo;, that helps you maintain a well-adjusted attitude to everything else.  When you&amp;rsquo;re operating in the planning/conceptualizing level you are doing so in a more relaxed way because you see all the things as just concepts without concrete reality, and you can always drop back to the level of pure-sensory experience if it&amp;rsquo;s getting too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about it at the moment, and surely my current &amp;ldquo;conceptualization&amp;rdquo; of this way of being is just that; only a partial representation of something; wrong in parts, maybe wrong entirely  It just all seems to fit together in my mind, connecting the &amp;ldquo;mysterious figure&amp;rdquo; in Steve Hagen&amp;rsquo;s book, with the story of a Buddhist Master staring at a wall for seven years and 
Eckhart Tolle sitting on benches in parks for hours just reveling in the underlying beauty of reality.  If you&amp;rsquo;re really connected to the pure sensory experience of the world, it&amp;rsquo;s always enough by itself.  You could spend seven years staring at a wall appreciating the details of the experience you were going through and not be too affected by concepts like &amp;ldquo;you are wasting your time&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;what are you doing with your life&amp;rdquo;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent several years researching NeuroScience as part of my PhD and this idea all fits in with how I see the brain as working; going from raw sensory data to concepts of increasing abstraction as we move further into the brain.  What&amp;rsquo;s the upshot for me?  If AgileVentures doesn&amp;rsquo;t achieve sustainability, and we end up not being able to afford the trip to Japan in the summer so my kids can spend time with their grandparents, it won&amp;rsquo;t be the end of the world.  We&amp;rsquo;ve been the last five years in a row at considerable expense, but it will cause me grief at some level because by taking my kids to Japan to spend time with their grandparents I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make up for the early death of my parents.  My wife and I had our kids in Hawaii, many thousands of miles away from our extended family.  My parents both visited Hawaii and met my eldest son, but by the time he was two and a half they were both dead from cancer, and they never got to meet my youngest two boys.  I spent a year shuttling back from Hawaii to the UK trying to maximise the time I spent on developing my career in Hawaii and looking after my mother in the UK, and allowing her to spend time with her grandson.  We weren&amp;rsquo;t sure when she was going to pass on, and she survived 18 months, but passed away just before we were returning to the UK for three months to be with her.  I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get there to be with her when she died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the biggest regret of my life.  Not so much that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be with her on that day, but more that we should just have quit our life in Hawaii while she was ill and stayed in the UK.  I was trying to carefully split the difference.  We weren&amp;rsquo;t sure how long she had.  I made a gamble to hold on to career and life abroad, spending &amp;frac14; time in the UK and &amp;frac34; time in Hawaii.  I couldn&amp;rsquo;t know at the time if it was the right gamble, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until after I&amp;rsquo;d lost my mother that I realised how I&amp;rsquo;d calculated everything wrong.  Also my mother wanted me to follow my dreams and so although I think she wanted me to stay, she didn&amp;rsquo;t ask me to.  Of course all of this is me conceptualizing about the past.  From one point of view, all these thoughts and ideas are just illusory with no concrete reality compared to the ever-present now.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know, it all seems very real.  I cried when I wrote the end of the previous paragraph.  Something I rarely do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that all got rather intense.  I perhaps should have mentioned that my sister bought me a book called &amp;ldquo;The Orphaned Adult&amp;rdquo; by Alexander Levy for Xmas, and so I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading alot about parental bereavement recently.  I guess the point I was struggling towards was about unearthing the source of the anxiety I have about making AgileVentures succeed.  It&amp;rsquo;s bound up with so much stuff.  I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go back to a job in the city where everything is about making money for shareholders, and I don&amp;rsquo;t get to spend so much time with my wife and kids.  I can&amp;rsquo;t bear working in corporate secrecy.  I think information wants to be free; I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to spend every other moment thinking about whether I can reveal part of a code base or not, although I realise that with AgileVentures I still have a big obligation to privacy for our members, clients and sponsors regarding aspects of the data they share with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Orphaned Adult" src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/41z9F%2BQU4pL._SY344_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AgileVentures&amp;rsquo; mission of &amp;ldquo;in-context education&amp;rdquo; and working on projects to help the greater good is something I really believe in and something I feel I can dedicate myself to with an open heart.  But I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t push myself too hard, and I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too attached to some end goal of sustainability.  There&amp;rsquo;s food on the table for the moment and lots of green shoots in our organisation.  I need to enjoy the process and occasionally take some breaks to revel in raw sensory data :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slow, but steady.  That&amp;rsquo;s what I meant to write about.  How I got a new filing cabinet for Xmas and how I&amp;rsquo;m steadily moving across chunks of things from the old broken down cabinet that came with us from Hawaii.  How every morning I&amp;rsquo;m trying to take at least one thing off my desk and file it.  How we&amp;rsquo;re trying to chip away at all the little things in the AgileVentures technical and social eco-system.  It feels to me like there&amp;rsquo;s so many little (and big) things to fix, and it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to know which ones are highest priority.  Every little decision is a gamble.  There&amp;rsquo;s no way to know which is the right way to go.  I&amp;rsquo;ve made some big gambles and I lived to regret them.  Enjoy the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Books&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Buddhism-Plain-Simple-Arkana-Steve/dp/0140195963"&gt;Buddhism Plain and Simple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Power-Now-Guide-Spiritual-Enlightenment/dp/0340733500"&gt;The Power of Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Orphaned-Adult-Understanding-Coping-Parents/dp/0738203610"&gt;The Orphaned Adult&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We Are Charity!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/01/04/we-are-charity/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/01/04/we-are-charity/</id>
    <published>2017-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-05T21:10:15+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It finally happened!  The UK government&amp;rsquo;s charity commission approved AgileVentures as an official UK charity.  About 9 months from our original submission, a few emails back and forth, and an apology from the charity commission for accidentally closing our case, we are now a UK registered charity.  A great way to start 2017, and hopefully something that will make our mission a whole load easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="announcing charity status on slack" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/13vldre5edvledp/Screenshot%202017-01-04%2010.10.10.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our official charity number is 1170963, and my next tasks will be to go round email signatures and websites adding that.  I can re-apply to Slack to get their non-profit tier, however I&amp;rsquo;m not sure we can afford the per user fees even after the nonprofit discount given we have over 1500 in our Slack instance.  Worth a discussion though.  I&amp;rsquo;ll reach out to all our sponsors and pass on the news and the possibility for tax relief on their contributions.  Same for our Premium members.  Will have to check how all that works. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The charity approval capped a big day of admin yesterday, shaking off the holiday cobwebs.  I caught up with my email and Slack and reviewed all the open pull requests from premium members on WebSiteOne and LocalSupport.  The big things to sort out are the new Agile Development using Ruby on Rails MOOC, a grant application with the Wikimedia edu dashboard folks, and the pricing and support package for the MetPlus project.  MetPlus is nearing the release stage and that links in to our new &lt;a href="http://www.agileventures.org/nonprofit-basic-support"&gt;non-profit support plans&lt;/a&gt;, which themselves need fleshing out and some payment endpoints merged into the generic plan support code we were working on before the break.  I&amp;rsquo;d also love to make more progress on the AsyncVoter bot code, to help projects chug through voting on their ticket backlog, but one thing at a time :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The non-profit support plans are an idea from Armando, since he often has non-profit groups wanting codebases maintained after student teams have built things for non-profits in his class and then moved on.  I have a slightly nervous feeling that this is the way to have me spending even more and more time supporting legacy codebases with serious shortcomings, when what I&amp;rsquo;d really like to be doing is be more involved in the creation of maintainable codebases; but perhaps supporting legacy codebases is actually what I&amp;rsquo;m destined to do, and we can&amp;rsquo;t fight out destiny :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of legacy codebases the current PR for supporting generic plans includes a feature to allow subscription to the NonProfit Basic Support plan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight gherkin"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;@stripe_javascript&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;@javascript&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kd"&gt;Feature&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Subscribe to NonProfit Basic Support
  As a nontechincal admin of a nonprofit or charity
  So that we can maintain our technical offerings
  I would like to subscribe to AV NonProfit Basic Support for charities

  &lt;span class="kn"&gt;Background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Given&lt;/span&gt; the following plans exist
      &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;                    &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;             &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;amount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;free_trial_length_days&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;NonProfit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Basic&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Support&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;nonprofitbasic&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;2000&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;                      &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="kn"&gt;Scenario&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Sign up for nonprofitbasic  support
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Given&lt;/span&gt; I visit &lt;span class="s"&gt;"subscriptions/new?plan=nonprofitbasic"&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;And&lt;/span&gt; I click &lt;span class="s"&gt;"Subscribe"&lt;/span&gt; within the card_section
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;When&lt;/span&gt; I fill in appropriate card details for nonprofitbasic
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; I should see &lt;span class="s"&gt;"Thanks, you're now an AgileVentures NonProfit Basic Support Member!"&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The background step is an indicator of how this PR is evolving the simple Plan class (that was hidden at the end of the &lt;code&gt;SubscriptionsController&lt;/code&gt;) and has changed into a full Active Record model.  Initially I had resisted this change as I was thinking that plan information stored in the Stripe database (and accessible via API) would be our single source of information about Plan data.  However the inclusion of PayPal support made it clear that the concept of a Plan was something firmly in our AgileVentures WebSiteOne domain model.  It seems like PayPal may be sufficiently flexible that plan details such as price and trial length etc. don&amp;rsquo;t need to be stored on PayPal, but the idea of us being dependent on the Stripe API to display information about our Plan pricing etc. seemed unappealing.  Stripe have good servers, but we don&amp;rsquo;t want to wait for a response from them to have authorative information about our Plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This actually highlights one odd thing about the Stripe setup.  You can display any number in the Stripe popup, but what actually gets charged depends on the data stored on the Stripe servers.  We&amp;rsquo;ve been bitten by this when one Stripe plan had the wrong value and one Premium member was charged incorrectly.  It was quickly fixed, but it&amp;rsquo;s not ideal.  Another issue with Stripe is the pro-rated payment when members upgrade from one plan to another.  This leads to an unexpectedly large payment at the beginning of the next month.   I feel like it would be better to have a single payment at the point of upgrade, at least from a customer surprise point of view.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that there&amp;rsquo;s any easy fix for either of these two, but some possible solutions to the first might be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) have the checkout popup grab the amount displayed from the Stripe server rather than from the local system&lt;br&gt;
b) have our system lookup the amount on the stripe servers and then fill into the checkout (something we could do ourselves)&lt;br&gt;
c) allow local systems to specify plan details dynamically rather than via an id lookup (paypal seems to do this)  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As regards the second issue, it would be great if we had a third option (as an alternative to two current two options of either prorating, or upgrading the next month), which would be to charge the customer the cost of the upgrade for the rest of the month now, and then just charge the normal amount of the upgraded amount at the beginning of the next cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I sent Stripe the above section of this blog, and we&amp;rsquo;ll see what they say.  Getting back to the current PR on WebSiteOne, the refactoring of Plan from &amp;ldquo;cyst class&amp;rdquo; to AR model has shrunk the SubscriptionsController down to a more manageable level, and allowed us to delete a number of views and mailer endpoints, so that signing up for a Plan involves a single template for both mailing and web pages, modified according to the plan being subscribed to.  Beautiful DRYness.  We&amp;rsquo;re also dropping &lt;a href="http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2016/09/26/confident-coding/"&gt;Single Table Inheritance (STI)&lt;/a&gt; from the Subscription model, since having plans be different sub-classes implies changes to the codebase to support them, which is not as flexible as we need at this point.  PaymentSources still use STI (PaymentSource::PayPal and PaymentSource::Stripe) and that seems reasonable for the moment as the number of Payment sources will likely expand more slowly and each new one will probably need new code.  So Subscriptions now belong to plans.  I&amp;rsquo;d love to dash off a quick UML diagram but maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for my book on Agile Project management :-)  I&amp;rsquo;m already over time on this blog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the PR is pretty much good to go. I even added a rake task to migrate the data from the old to the new structure.  Only thing is that the language of the templates for the individual premium users doesn&amp;rsquo;t make so much sense for the organisations that would be signing up for NonProfit Basic Support, so I think we need another field on the Plan model to indicate whether it&amp;rsquo;s a plan for an individual or an organisation and then we can modify the template language correctly, but I&amp;rsquo;ll save those details for another PR.  Also the crossover on templates means we now in principle support Paypal payment for the higher level plans, although that emergent feature isn&amp;rsquo;t covered by feature tests, and we still don&amp;rsquo;t have good upgrade paths, but this PR is already large and needs testing on staging.  Could we hide part of it behind feature flags?   I think at this point we just need to get it out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels like if we can get this out, add the org/personal element, test all the payment options, and do the upgrade functionality (i.e. make it generic), we&amp;rsquo;ll have most of what we need on the payment side and perhaps we can move on to other features and systems.  Fingers crossed! :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OUeZEoN_JbY"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n1Xn5_qBFJE"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Blogs:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2016/09/26/confident-coding/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2016/10/27/red-green-refactor/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2016/11/03/frustratingly-slow-debug-cycle/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2016/11/04/light-at-the-end-of-the-tunnel/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2016/11/07/refactoring-ftw/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Downtime</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/01/03/downtime/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/01/03/downtime/</id>
    <published>2017-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-04T21:28:32+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Right then, back from a two week blogging break.  I was still working the week before Xmas, but thought I&amp;rsquo;d put down the blogging baton to try and catch up on other things.  I had fantasies of making a lot of coding progress, but while there was some coding done, I think it was more admin catchup.  I had a couple of Premium pairing sessions, meetings with UCBerkeley to sort out the next run of the Agile Development using Ruby on Rails MOOC and got Xmas cards sent off to the premium members.  I got complimentary textbooks sent out to several instructors (yay automation!) and got set up for making the new SPOC versions of the MOOC for our beta gold instructors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was some coding being done.  I continued work on the support for &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/pull/1465"&gt;making the different kinds of subscription generic&lt;/a&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;d started with Marian in a Premium Plus session.  Michael and Marian had done some more work but had come up against some road blocks.  Matt was also trying to make progress on &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/pull/1469"&gt;checking that a video exists before tweeting the YouTube link&lt;/a&gt;.  I pushed Michael to pair with Matt while I worked solo on the generic subscription refactoring.  In a break Michael was telling me that he saw a problem with the logic in the events instance controller where the tweets were only being sent out when the youtube id changed.  The new EventInstance object would have a nil YouTube id, and the first incoming ping from our Google Hangout plugin would update the EventInstance to have a YouTube id.  However, the current logic would only tweet when the YouTube id changed, meaning that although we could now check whether the stream associated with the YouTube id was live, we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to tweet to that effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the problem here was exposing the flaw, given the current single step cucumber tests that were relying on both VCR and RSpec &lt;code&gt;receive&lt;/code&gt; expectations (with follow through) of specifics in our system.  I&amp;rsquo;d been uncomfortable with this arrangement and &lt;a href="http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2016/12/08/agile-dev-ops/"&gt;blogged about it previously&lt;/a&gt;, but had held off from diving into the possible solutions I could imagine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) using RSpec spies to check the tweet had gone out afterwards, e.g. &lt;code&gt;have_received&lt;/code&gt;
b) somehow checking that the VCR cache had been hit in the way we expected
c) switching to WebMock&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d held off to avoid the previous pull request getting too large and force myself to stay focused on a different (financial) feature.  Michael said Matt had spent several hours investigating spies and not getting anywhere.  Now maybe I should again have been focusing on the (possibly) more important financial features, but I dived into this with Michael while Matt was on a break.  I was very interested to see whether RSpec spies would do the job allowing us to unwind the Cucumber step so that we could have the Hangout plugin ping as one step, and then a second step check that the tweet had gone out.  At the same time my deep discomfort about having an acceptance test checking our system internals (with spy or expectation) made me start looking through the WebMock documentation.  A complete switch from VCR to WebMock would be a huge pain, but VCR was using WebMock under the hood anyway, so wasn&amp;rsquo;t there some way to use WebMock to check what elements in the VCR cache had been hit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was it!  A couple of step definitions like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sr"&gt;/^the youtube link will not be sent$/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;WebMock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;not_to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;have_requested&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'https://api.twitter.com/1.1/statuses/update.json'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;twice&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="nf"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;req&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;req&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;body&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=~&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="sr"&gt;/youtu\.be\/11/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and our scenarios became appropriately sequential:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight gherkin"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class="kn"&gt;Scenario&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Event going live without valid live stream does not cause youtube link to be tweeted
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Given&lt;/span&gt; the live stream has not started
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;When&lt;/span&gt; the HangoutConnection has pinged to indicate the event start
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; the youtube link will not be sent
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I left Michael to explain the new setup to Matt and got back to the Generic Subscription feature where I crashed through the road blocks and got something working before the complete coding/blogging/admin break I took between Xmas and New Year.  The Generic Subscription feature involves deleting a lot of replicated templates and making the Plan class a full ActiveRecord Model, with the idea that when we want to deploy a new plan, we just add the appropriate items on the PayPal and Stripe sides, and don&amp;rsquo;t have to push any code to our own site; just add the new plan to the database.  I had been hoping to deploy that before Xmas, but it was not to be, and I&amp;rsquo;ll get into the refactoring I did there in another blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been thinking to do some work between Xmas and New Year, but I found myself needing some more serious downtime.  I kept up with email and very occasional Slack in case there were any emergencies, but the kids were off school and it had been a busy year.  I needed some serious downtime where I wasn&amp;rsquo;t pushing myself to get things done every day.  It was pretty damn pleasant, but all good things come to an end. Now I&amp;rsquo;m just getting myself back into the saddle for another busy year.  New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions?  Take more time off before I burn out :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Blogs:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2016/11/15/multiple-pull-request-learning/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2016/12/07/meetings-vs-coding/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http://nonprofits.agileventures.org/2016/12/08/agile-dev-ops/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mobbing and Face 2 Face</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/12/16/mobbing-f2f/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/12/16/mobbing-f2f/</id>
    <published>2016-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-12-22T12:42:55+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thursday was taken at quite a rush.  I moved the Premium Mob programming session forward half an hour so I could attend my twin boys&amp;rsquo; carol concert.  We got deeper into Avdi Grimm&amp;rsquo;s Confident Ruby, where the patterns were starting to combine to create code like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;Graphics&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;Conversions&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="kp"&gt;module_function&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Integer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;':'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:to_i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;arg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;){&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;arg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;respond_to?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:to_point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to_point&lt;/span&gt;  
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;arg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;){&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;arg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;respond_to?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:to_ary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to_ary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="k"&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;raise&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;TypeError&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"Cannot convert &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;inspect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt; to Point"&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="no"&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Struct&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;:y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;inspect&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;}#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;to_point&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="nb"&gt;self&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="no"&gt;Pair&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Struct&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;:b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;to_ary&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="k"&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nc"&gt;Flag&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;initialize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;flag_color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="vi"&gt;@x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="vi"&gt;@y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="vi"&gt;@flag_color&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;flag_color&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;to_point&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="no"&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="vi"&gt;@x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="vi"&gt;@y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="kp"&gt;include&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Graphics&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kp"&gt;include&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Graphics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;Conversions&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nb"&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;([])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"1:2"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;Pair&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;23&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;Flag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;42&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;24&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;:red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mobbers seemed pretty happy with the concepts of Idempotency, the splat argument (&lt;code&gt;*args&lt;/code&gt;) and the lambdas (&lt;code&gt;-&amp;gt;(arg)&lt;/code&gt;) in the case statements.  The big discussion was about the use of Structs vs Classes, and Matt was able to use the shared C9 workspace to good effect to show me the alternatives he was thinking about.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that we&amp;rsquo;re yet truly mobbing, but I think the others are gaining in confidence and we&amp;rsquo;ll get there.  Mobbing completed, it was time for a carol service, and I was hardly back from that before it was time for the Kent Beck scrum.  I had managed to review a few LocalSupport pull requests, prioritising input for the Premium members who&amp;rsquo;d submitted code or questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ed had booked me for a Premium F2F session immediately after the Kent Beck and we dived into user stories and cucumber to drive the creation of a new EventManager project in Rails 5.   Within the hour we got everything set up and had our first feature/scenario failing at the point where it would need ActionCable working in order to pass:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight gherkin"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;Feature&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Joining the Event
  As a busy AV member
  So that I can work out if I want to join an event
  I'd like to see who is present in the event, updated in real time

  As a new member
  So that I can join the event on time
  I would like to have a real time view of whether the hangout is live

  &lt;span class="kn"&gt;Background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Given&lt;/span&gt; an event exists

  &lt;span class="kn"&gt;Scenario&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; see event status
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Given&lt;/span&gt; I visit the page for an event
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; I should see &lt;span class="s"&gt;"event not live"&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;When&lt;/span&gt; the event goes live
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; I should see &lt;span class="s"&gt;"event live"&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was pretty satsifying, and I was riding high on possible nibbles from a few prospective AgileVentures sponsors.  In terms of financial stability we&amp;rsquo;re about half way there.  If I can land another sponsor and double the number of Premium members it will be a very happy 2017 indeed.  My dream is a sustainable framework for open education for all, where we&amp;rsquo;re all learning through the process of trying to make the world a better place.   The mob sessions are private at the moment, but I get permission from the F2F and Plus members to make their sessions available in the project channels to help the open source projects we work on, and of course all the resulting code is open.  We will need to throw the right sort of licenses in there.  Is it too crazy a dream that we could all be learning and growing without fear?  All benefiting from each other&amp;rsquo;s courage to share the learning experience and process with each other?  And splitting our objective of personal growth with that of helping others?  Call me a dreamer, but I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one &amp;hellip; :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a two week break from blogging now, like I did over the summer so I can calm down a bit and catch up with admin, coding and polishing and distributing some of the older blogs.  Hope you all have a very cool yule and I&amp;rsquo;ll look forward to seeing you all in the New Year! :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lrw0R8YbxXU"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LkagGRnOorI"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;F2F pairing on Rails 5?  Navigate to the #event_manager channel on AgileVentures slack to catch the link before we lose the slack history :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
