<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Back To Premium Analysis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/17/av-ecosystem-review-back-to-premium-analysis/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/17/av-ecosystem-review-back-to-premium-analysis/</id>
    <published>2017-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-19T21:23:36+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="premium stats back" src="/images/premium-stats-back.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there&amp;rsquo;s feedback from the APSoc client, and clearly some more work to do on the LibreOffice Base application, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can delay a review of the AV Premium members.  I used to be doing weekly reach outs, but with the new pairing and mobbing sessions I&amp;rsquo;m several weeks behind.  I also need to generate the latest monthly report for the trustees.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been adding data on mobs/pairing/meetings as I have them so that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take so much time, but I also need to get the data in the WSO site accurate for Michael&amp;rsquo;s machine learning enterprise.  For that purpose we&amp;rsquo;ve created an API that allows us to get a list of the status of all the Premium users.  Using the great &lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt; library I can get nicely formatted json on the command line using a command like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -H "Authorization: Token token=1234" https://www.agileventures.org/api/subscriptions.json | jq
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and that gives me data like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"email"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"&amp;lt;email&amp;gt;"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"sponsor_email"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kc"&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"started_on"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"2017-03-06"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"ended_on"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kc"&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"plan_name"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"Premium"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"payment_source"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"PaymentSource::PayPal"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"email"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"&amp;lt;email&amp;gt;"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"sponsor_email"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kc"&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"started_on"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"2017-03-09"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"ended_on"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kc"&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"plan_name"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"Premium"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"payment_source"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"PaymentSource::Stripe"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now what I need to do is go through ensuring this data is accurate and up to date.  First up I have an honorary member who hacked the PayPal endpoint in a security intrusion test.  This is not relevant data for the machine learning system.  The next is one who was sponsored, but now has a full time job and hasn&amp;rsquo;t been making use of the Premium Mob membership.  They&amp;rsquo;ve demurred paying their own way, saying they need time to get things organised.  I think I could sensibly mark these two as honorary members since they both contributed so much on the open source side.  I go ahead and create an honorary membership:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;irb(main):003:0&amp;gt; Plan.create name: 'Honorary Premium'
=&amp;gt; #&amp;lt;Plan id: 12, name: "Honorary Premium", free_trial_length_days: nil, third_party_identifier: nil, amount: nil, created_at: "2017-12-18 09:58:46", updated_at: "2017-12-18 09:58:46", category: nil&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set the first user to honorary, and that bumps them to the bottom of the list, so I can try and hook up the correct sponsor email to the second premium.  That was pretty easy, but now I also need to indicate the end of the sponsorship and that it&amp;rsquo;s passed on to another member.  I add an end to the sponsorship, but leave the &amp;ldquo;passing on&amp;rdquo; till I get to that sponsee.  I start making lists of who to check in with, who to send follow up forms to, and about which sponsee positions we need to fill.  Problem with this is that it seems to be taking me ages to crawl through making updates, considering whether to reach out to people, whether to follow up on inactive members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed the first five in the list and now we come up against a subscription with no associated user.  It was started on &amp;ldquo;2017-04-25&amp;rdquo;, so can I match that with someone in the Stripe interface, since that&amp;rsquo;s the payment type &amp;hellip; but none of the Stripe customers was created even close to that date (according to the stripe interface). Doh, no, ugh, it&amp;rsquo;s PayPal.  Where we do have a member who started at that time.  It looks like I also created a subscription for that user a few days afterwards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"email"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"&amp;lt;email&amp;gt;"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"sponsor_email"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kc"&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"started_on"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"2017-04-29"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"ended_on"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kc"&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"plan_name"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"Premium Mob"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;"payment_source"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"PaymentSource::PayPal"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sensibly I hook that up correctly, and delete the inaccurate account, ah, but actually that&amp;rsquo;s the initial Premium that the member had for four days before upgrading to Premium Mob, so to hook that up we need to adjust the database model to support multiple subscriptions.  Hmm, looks like I&amp;rsquo;ll need to hit this every morning this week to get things sorted &amp;hellip; and maybe more &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Recording Help Videos</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/15/av-ecosystem-review-recording-help-videos/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/15/av-ecosystem-review-recording-help-videos/</id>
    <published>2017-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-19T21:19:12+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="camera recording" src="/images/camera-recording.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I must be several weeks (months even?) and several layers of procrastination out from actually reviewing the AV ecosystem, since I&amp;rsquo;m pretty much using my blogging time to get focused work done on client projects and our main website project management.  It&amp;rsquo;s all still part of the AV ecosystem of course.  The client projects I&amp;rsquo;m working with are clients of AgileVentures, as is, naturally, the main website.  My days are full of mobs and f2f pairings, again all part of the AV ecosystem.  One day, one day, I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to the big picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime the Anthony Powell Society client is apparently pretty happy with the screenshots of the forms for their membership database.  I did say we&amp;rsquo;d have an alpha version of their system ready for them today, but I&amp;rsquo;m reasonably confident I can make a few tweaks and get that done later today.   What I really haven&amp;rsquo;t got done yet is the help videos for the NHS wiki, which really needs to get done, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to switch to that in my blog time this morning.  I was trying to get it done last night, but quicktime kept crashing.  I did manage to get my computer re-booted, so let&amp;rsquo;s have another go and drive through them.  My plan is to make draft videos off the cuff (more or less) and then take the transcript and use it via auto-prompt to make them sound a bit more professional. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I, or the backdrop of my home office, look good enough at the moment (maybe after Xmas), so I&amp;rsquo;ll not do any in picture video of my talking head this time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the first one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Z21mZqNTPMQ"&gt;Search Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I went on to record another six of varying quality, but at least we have something done.  These can individually be re-recorded to improve them.  I&amp;rsquo;ve created a playlist for those:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLuyBZ95Nkc4aqffFG436Xcn3HaJF7xRzO"&gt;Video Playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And also managed to get a last round of changes to the APSoc database and send them an alpha version before scrum, so I&amp;rsquo;m making some progress today.  Really need to get the reports sorted too &amp;hellip; back to the grindstone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review LibreOffice Locking Up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/14/av-ecosystem-review-libreoffice-locking-up/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/14/av-ecosystem-review-libreoffice-locking-up/</id>
    <published>2017-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-28T21:09:12+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="lock" src="/images/lock.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating the new forms on the PC seems to be leading to lots of LibreOffice locking up &amp;hellip;, and now in the process of trying to transfer it back to the Mac I seem to have lost two days worth of work, argh!  I had set the PC system on auto-save to every one minute &amp;hellip; something about using dropbox?  I can review all the past versions on dropbox, but none of them have the work from yesterday.  Somehow whatever I did yesterday didn&amp;rsquo;t get saved to dropbox.  Frustrating.  At least I still have the knowledge of how to get things done.  Practice run I guess.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if the locking up and crashing is due to basic instability in the software or my overall approach of copy and paste.  I can&amp;rsquo;t bear re-creating items from scratch, particularly when I have to then re-set all the fonts individually.  Alright here we go again &amp;hellip; so new devops feature, create a cold backup at the end of each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m back on the mac where things are running a bit more smoothly - maybe developing out of dropbox was a bad idea.  Things running okay at the moment, allowing me to get a screen shot of the subscription payment screen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/d5a6ja8jvokiut4/Screenshot%202017-12-14%2010.35.49.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now on to where I got in trouble on the PC.  Copying the subscription payment form to make the GiftAid and StandingOrder forms.  This time around I recreate the table element from scratch and it is pretty smooth:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/b9epna64eh9ty85/Screenshot%202017-12-14%2011.25.05.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, on to standing order details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/63a2g5s1hgra9t2/Screenshot%202017-12-14%2010.48.44.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, I think I might have done it and I now have mockups to show to the client &amp;hellip; no point tweaking them till we hear all that they want updated.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Client Project Focus</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/13/av-ecosystem-review-client-project-focus/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/13/av-ecosystem-review-client-project-focus/</id>
    <published>2017-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-27T21:23:50+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="focus" src="/images/focus.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So despite pushing out fresh code all the dokku/azure bots still appear to be offline.  Would love to fix that, but yet I feel I should prioritize the client work.  I guess I can restart the dokku containers.   Has something in azure changed, blocking a new port?  Has rolling out metplus into dokku had some knock on impact?  Ah, I&amp;rsquo;m wrong; it looks like the main greeting bot did work overnight.  So I go back and post the welcome message manually to the few new slack folk.  Not sure about the greeter bots, but I&amp;rsquo;ve posted all the active project links in &lt;code&gt;#new\_members&lt;/code&gt; channel, so maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll see a few folks join channels and then we can tell if the project greeter bot is working again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I found the little widget that allows me to embed a spreadsheet view of another table in a LibreOffice Base form.  Now I need to be able to embed list boxes in it (which is relatively easy) and maybe have them point to other tables, which perhaps needs a sub-form in the table widget, hmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the background someone has answered my &lt;a href="https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/140501/base-dropdown-country-list/"&gt;question about countries in list boxes on ask libreoffice&lt;/a&gt; pointing to a countries table that comes with MySQL. Not sure if LibreOffice has MySQL installed, or that&amp;rsquo;s just a suggestion about where to get the data from, but they also point out that the SQL query needs to return the name of the country twice, so I try that, but the program locks up on me.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s something about list boxes in LibreOffice that I haven&amp;rsquo;t got quite down yet.  In the table widget I&amp;rsquo;ve got listboxes that are giving drop downs from the table data, but aren&amp;rsquo;t showing the relevant field itself &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a funny thing here - should I be trying to read the documentation about how to get it to work - I keep falling asleep whenever I try to read almost any documentation.  I generally make more progress just bashing on the interface and posting to help forums.  But perhaps I should just be getting mockups of the last two forms and sending them to the client, for what I will assume is reams of feedback that I could easily get distracted by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I force quit LibreOffice on the PC and re-start and adjust the query to return &amp;ldquo;Name&amp;rdquo; twice, but that leads to no particular change to the countries list box.  I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll need to re-import the data, since the countries column got wiped out last time around.  There&amp;rsquo;s also the issue that the country names in the existing data don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily match the spelling/abbreviations in the list that I added.  Need to leave that for now; does the double name return help in the subscriptions payment form? &amp;hellip; it does, but needed to be combined with intelligence from another answer on &lt;a href="https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/65146/a-dropdown-list-inside-a-control-grid-table-with-sql-consult-in-base/?answer=65195#post-id-65195"&gt;ask libre office&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so maybe now I can bash out the other two forms &amp;hellip;?  Urgh, but it&amp;rsquo;s locking up on the PC again &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Old School</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/12/av-ecosystem-review-old-school/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/12/av-ecosystem-review-old-school/</id>
    <published>2017-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-26T22:08:15+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bug" src="/images/old_school.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in the second week of a cold - I think it&amp;rsquo;s getting better, but I suspect that not resting properly last week is causing it to drag out for a second.  Totally distracted by Slack and Email this AM, but there we go. At least I have my PC set up with LibreOffice so that I can develop on a similar machine to that of the client.  What I also notice is that the project greeter bots seem to have stopped.   Would like to be working on them, but have to prioritise client work (I think).  Maybe I can just push an empty commit to see if they start up &amp;hellip; so I merge the outstanding pull request:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/project_greeter_bot/pull/26"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/project_greeter_bot/pull/26&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and push that out to production.  And then I get sucked in, shaving several yaks, I update the installation docs for project greeter bot and asyncvoter so that I can link them into greeting bot messages for those channels, and then I push that out from a branch.  Okay, totally distracted; might as well go on twitter and tweet the podcasts I just listened to.  Okay procrastination explosion; now I need to get to the list of follow up items I had from yesterday&amp;rsquo;s client work &amp;hellip; the outstanding issues were that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all dates should have 4 digit years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explain the significance of white vs grey boxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first line of address in top box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;country drop down should be full list of countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adjust DB schema?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add second email address to schema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Last Update”, “Date Joined” and “Member#” should be automatically generated and not keyable – these should have a grey background; other fields a white background. All other fields are potentially changeable although some will default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also notice that the mobile phone text is the wrong font &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to make these changes on the PC and see how they transfer back to the mac.  I start by fixing up the mobile phone text field.  The 4 digit year thing is interesting in that the data that we&amp;rsquo;ve imported has two digit years, although that might be an artifact of the import process.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if we have the date fields in the right format &amp;hellip; ah, it appears we do, so then there&amp;rsquo;s a question about how they are presented in the form.  There&amp;rsquo;s a section on date formats in the docs, but as with many things in LibreOffice it&amp;rsquo;s not clear if it&amp;rsquo;s specific to the base component:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://help.libreoffice.org/Common/Number_Format_Codes#Date_Formats"&gt;https://help.libreoffice.org/Common/Number&lt;em&gt;Format&lt;/em&gt;Codes#Date_Formats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not very googleable, this issue, but when I edit the database table itself, I see an option to set a default format, so that sorts that.  The other non-trivial one is the list of countries for a dropdown menu, so I ask a question about that on the libreoffice forum:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/140501/base-dropdown-country-list/"&gt;https://ask.libreoffice.org/en/question/140501/base-dropdown-country-list/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but I get side-tracked into that when what I should probably be doing is mocking up the other interface screens &amp;hellip; and now I&amp;rsquo;ve got the country thing working, but I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow blown away a load of country data.  Frustrating; I&amp;rsquo;m getting distracted by additional work requested when I should be focused on the core &amp;hellip; at least I will force myself to copy the existing form and make it into the &amp;ldquo;Subscription Payment&amp;rdquo; form.  However now the software has locked up on the PC &amp;hellip; so I killed it and now I have it giving me a copy of the form which I&amp;rsquo;m working up to be the Subscription Payments form.  I&amp;rsquo;ve added a subform and I can see that migrating to new membership IDs is going to be non-trivial, given they are the primary keys for relating all these tables.  And then I&amp;rsquo;m sort of stuck on displaying a sort of spreadsheet view of all the subscription payments in the new form.  I can create tables, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that&amp;rsquo;s the right thing, but aha, I have found the &amp;ldquo;table control&amp;rdquo; form element that I think we need, and that looks about right.  Phew, so looks like we can probably get all the functionality we need, although the migration feels like it will be painful &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/dm3liajv1l0lflh/Screenshot%202017-12-12%2011.40.52.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Client Feedback</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/12/11/av-ecosystem-review-client-feedback/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/12/11/av-ecosystem-review-client-feedback/</id>
    <published>2017-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-22T20:54:02+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="client feedback" src="/images/client_feedback.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got out a screenshot of the main APSoc LibreOffice Base Member Information form to the client late Friday, and over the weekend they&amp;rsquo;ve given me very detailed feedback on changes they want to the form.  Agile is all about providing working software as early as possible, but this seems like a nice shortcut to increase the chances that the resulting system will be what the client wants.  I&amp;rsquo;ve ordered a new HDMI cable so I can start developing on my windows machine (although will that just be a distraction?), and so I&amp;rsquo;m going to have a go at making all the changes requested on my mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjust label font (Liberation Sans &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Tahoma)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have membership number be numeric only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align last updated field with Member Information title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align all field names with left edge of inputs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce size of date fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All dates should have 4 digit years  &amp;lt;&amp;mdash; not sure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce size of &amp;ldquo;Known as&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Salutation&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wants to know signficance of white vs grey boxes &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; can explain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First line of address in top box &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; data issue - some addresses in odd places&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move &amp;ldquo;Local Group&amp;rdquo; up to address along with &amp;ldquo;N/L&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move up &amp;ldquo;NM N/L&amp;rdquo; also&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove KCM only text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move &amp;ldquo;City &amp;hellip; Country&amp;rdquo; row up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align Country field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Country drop down should be full list of countries &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; will need to investigate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Mobile Phone font&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove Fax field (and data from DB) &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; we don&amp;rsquo;t have final DB - am I supposed to provide a new schema?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove &amp;ldquo;Dietary Requirements&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace with &amp;ldquo;Email Address 2&amp;rdquo; &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; need to add this to DB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove “Gift Membership &amp;hellip;” from screen and DB (again the info can be moved to “Notes” by me after migration).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand “Notes” top full width of screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Align check boxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Last Update”, “Date Joined” and “Member#” should be automatically generated and not keyable – these should have a grey background; other fields a white background. All other fields are potentially changeable although some will default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Work Phone&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Mobile Phone&amp;rdquo; fields should align with the fields in the row above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve done most of the cosmetic changes and some of the data ones:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/oz1u6wksr1c40mw/Screenshot%202017-12-11%2010.25.27.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In about 30 minutes, but that leaves me with a set of things I need to check &amp;hellip; over the course of the day I also got LibreOffice installed on my Windows machine where it seems to run a little faster, and I can confirm that it looks sensible on Windows; and seems to have all the right basic functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feedback from the client is very specific.  Some of the items are just tiny ones that I would have fixed in a subsequent pass.  Others are micro-changes for alignment and so on that I would have got to eventually.  It feels like many of these changes are ones that they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to make themselves when they are all set up with the software.  Others are more substantive.  Great to keep them in the loop.  For some reason I bristled at the font change suggestions; I think partly because I was having such trouble setting a default font, but as I familiarise myself further with the software I was able to make the requisite changes in short order.  It is great when one is able to show clients/users that you respond to their requests.  I think it builds a really positive relationship, but of course one needs to be able to say no when the amount of work explodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m optimisitic I can get the majority of the work done over the course of the next week without having to break stride, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see.  The interesting question is whether we want to start paying for Chatlio since this work was generated through that system, or if there&amp;rsquo;ll be any kind of similar work generated if we complete well on this.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got other people asking for quotes on website refreshes, so that&amp;rsquo;s probably the place to start before re-opening the web-chat deluge &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
