<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2018-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Sorting and Reporting</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/18/av-ecosystem-review-sorting_and_reporting/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/18/av-ecosystem-review-sorting_and_reporting/</id>
    <published>2018-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-06T21:34:07+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="deploy" src="/images/deploy.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t complete the AV report yesterday, or deploy the new premium model code. All booked up with exciting Premium F2F sessions, and this morning I had to spend an hour catching up with emails for various possible gigs to cover what the charity work does not.  So, right, let&amp;rsquo;s get that new code on staging &amp;hellip; which involves me rebasing to staging and pushing that up.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t manually check develop &amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s partly because I&amp;rsquo;m turning the servers off to save money.  Funny, if I&amp;rsquo;d left them on over night I&amp;rsquo;d immediately have something I could check; it only takes 30 seconds (navigating to heroku, flicking a switch) to get them on, but sometimes that can feel like a real pain.  Anyway, got the develop server up, not even sure how to really check that things are really working &amp;hellip; I guess I sign up random guy as a premium member:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/oyvrnyrbso5ouy4/Screenshot%202018-01-18%2010.37.43.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and then upgrade to mob:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/i95alz97si8nra1/Screenshot%202018-01-18%2010.38.28.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I don&amp;rsquo;t get any errors and the site looks okay.  And so I should be able to see the subscription relations in the rails console:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[tansaku@Samuels-MBP:~/Documents/Github/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne (staging)]$ 
→ heroku run rails c -r develop
Running rails c on ⬢ websiteone-develop... up, run.5865 (Hobby)
Loading production environment (Rails 4.2.10)
irb(main):001:0&amp;gt; u = User.find_by email: 'random@random.com'
=&amp;gt; #&amp;lt;User id: 88, email: "random@random.com", created_at: "2016-02-24 11:09:56", updated_at: "2018-01-18 10:38:22", first_name: "Random", last_name: "Guy", display_email: false, slug: "random-guy", youtube_id: nil, display_profile: true, latitude: nil, longitude: nil, country_name: nil, city: nil, region: nil, youtube_user_name: nil, github_profile_url: nil, display_hire_me: false, bio: "rektktktk", receive_mailings: true, country_code: nil, timezone_offset: nil, status_count: 0, deleted_at: nil&amp;gt;
irb(main):002:0&amp;gt; u.subscriptions
=&amp;gt; #&amp;lt;ActiveRecord::Associations::CollectionProxy [#&amp;lt;Subscription id: 12, type: nil, started_at: "2018-01-18 10:38:22", ended_at: nil, user_id: 88, plan_id: 2, sponsor_id: 88&amp;gt;, #&amp;lt;Subscription id: 11, type: nil, started_at: "2018-01-18 10:37:49", ended_at: "2018-01-18 10:38:22", user_id: 88, plan_id: 1, sponsor_id: 88&amp;gt;]&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is all looking exactly as it should with one subscription being closed out and the new one started, so this code is winging its way to staging, where we can test with some more realistic data.  The build just passed there, but deploy will take a little longer - will leave that till tomorrow and push on with this report. Time to work out what AsyncVoter meetings we ran.  Hmm, maybe I need to bring up with the trustees some modifications to the report format &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the background I&amp;rsquo;m seeing if I can get Heroku managing the SSL certs for HarrowCN for us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[tansaku@Samuels-MBP:~/Documents/GitHub/AgileVentures/LocalSupport (develop)]$ 
→ heroku certs:auto:enable -r staging
Enabling Automatic Certificate Management... done
=== Your certificate will now be managed by Heroku.  Check the status by running heroku certs:auto.
[tansaku@Samuels-MBP:~/Documents/GitHub/AgileVentures/LocalSupport (141687181_import_charity_data_from_commission)]$ 
→ heroku certs:auto -r staging
=== Automatic Certificate Management is enabled on harrowcn-staging

Domain                   Status
───────────────────────  ───────
staging.harrowcn.org.uk  Waiting
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that all works and we could get the AV WSO certs self-managed that would be one less thing I need to worry about, i.e. renewing letsencrypt certificates every three months.  Okay, so now the new code is deployed to staging - probably best to get that deploy completed, so that I can uncover any pain that might lurk there - creating the report doesn&amp;rsquo;t pose such risks.  Okay, so tested on staging, looks good - pushing to master, and HarrowCN SSL looks good self managed (I guess?).  Could try production update there too &amp;hellip; updated the AsyncVoter report a little, still lots to do &amp;hellip;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Monthly Reporting</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/17/av-ecosystem-review-monthly-reporting/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/17/av-ecosystem-review-monthly-reporting/</id>
    <published>2018-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-05T21:02:08+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="monthly reporting" src="/images/monthly_reporting.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve got in my &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/pull/2039"&gt;PR for updating the premium/sponsor model&lt;/a&gt; to have the system maintain records of the different subscriptions a user has over time.  The PR is green and there is at least one refactorings that could be done, but I think I sensibly open that as a &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/2103"&gt;refactoring ticket&lt;/a&gt; rather than slowing the release of this.  In the process of doing so I end up closing the 20 or so airbrake errors about overrunning requests, that seem to have been fixed with the performance fix I released (taking the countdown to next scrum off the homepage).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, so I want to get that deployed today if I can.  In the meantime I&amp;rsquo;m trying to finish up the monthly report for the AgileVentures trustees.  What I&amp;rsquo;d love to be able to do is get this change deployed and then review all the premium accounts as I did before Xmas and ensure that we have all the subscription history changes sorted, and then I can have the report include some sort of up to date stats for the trustees.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m kind of struggling with the reports, trying to make the stats reported be something that&amp;rsquo;s actually of use to us.  Is it sensible for me to be reporting data like this about the WebSiteOne coordination meetings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/r4fsvru82gmpu38/Screenshot%202018-01-17%2009.57.57.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s relevant in that part of my responsibility to the trustees is to ensure that the WebSiteOne coordination meetings are held.  I guess it&amp;rsquo;s not an unhelpful summary for me to remind me who&amp;rsquo;s attended the meetings over the course of the last month.  I also report various google analytics and new relic stats for the month.  Keeping my eye on these is good, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got into this habit (in both AV and NHS reports) of creating little paragraphs like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month: From Dec 17 to Jan 15 we had 294 unique visitors to the site, of which 70% were new visitors.  The average session length was 3 minutes and 31 seconds and the bounce rate was ~47%.  Pages per session was 3.39. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which are slightly fiddly to pull out of the Google Analytics interface and I wonder if I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t just stick in the graphic that Analytics provides, or even whether these are statisics of consequence?  I know that most of the trustees are not interested in the real specific numbers here, and that part of the point of the report is that someone is keeping an eye on these things.  It would be great if the report was totally automated.  At least I&amp;rsquo;d be interested in reading it &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;d be even more interested in better understanding what viewers of the website were really thinking as they viewed the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had meant to come back and finish this during the day, but no rest for the wicked - okay, onto the next one &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Damned JavaScript Acceptance Tests</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/16/av-ecosystem-review-damned-javascript-acceptance-tests/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/16/av-ecosystem-review-damned-javascript-acceptance-tests/</id>
    <published>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-04T20:53:26+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="acceptance tests" src="/images/acceptance_testing_diagram.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the APSoc client has approved the MSAccess alpha and the new timescale, so I can spend a week on the AV website and the rest of the ecosystem.  I made some progress with the Premium/Sponsor domain upgrade yesterday, and I suspect I have everything in place, but I&amp;rsquo;m getting what look suspiciously like a series of intermittent javascript acceptance test failures.  These really do seem to be the bane of our projects.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got a series of failures that disappear when I pop in the debugger.  For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[tansaku@Samuels-MBP:~/Documents/Github/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne (1429_have_premium_upgrades_close_out_old_subscription)]$ 
→ be cucumber features/premium/upgrade_membership.feature:36

Using the default profile...
@stripe_javascript @javascript
Feature: Allow Users to Upgrade Membership
  As a site admin
  So that we can achieve financial stability
  I would like users to be able to upgrade their premium plans

  As a software developer
  So that I can receive additional support in my professional development journey
  I would like to be able to upgrade my support plan, and understand what that plan includes

  Background:                       # features/premium/upgrade_membership.feature:11
    Given the following plans exist # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:58
      | name        | id         | amount | free_trial_length_days |
      | Premium     | premium    | 1000   | 7                      |
      | Premium Mob | premiummob | 2500   | 0                      |
    And the following users exist   # features/step_definitions/user_steps.rb:228
      | first_name | last_name | email                  | github_profile_url         | last_sign_in_ip |
      | Alice      | Jones     | alice@btinternet.co.uk | http://github.com/AliceSky | 127.0.0.1       |

  Scenario: User upgrades to premium from free tier                 # features/premium/upgrade_membership.feature:36
    Given I am logged in                                            # features/step_definitions/user_steps.rb:63
    When I am on my profile page                                    # features/step_definitions/user_steps.rb:389
    Then I should see a tooltip explanation of Premium              # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:121
    And I click "Upgrade to Premium"                                # features/step_definitions/basic_steps.rb:90
    And I click "Subscribe" within the card_section                 # features/step_definitions/contained_search_steps.rb:33
    When I fill in appropriate card details for premium             # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:6
    Then I should see "Premium Member"                              # features/step_definitions/basic_steps.rb:202
    And my profile page should reflect that I am a "Premium" member # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:131
      expected to find text "Premium Member" in "Anders Persson ABOUT PROJECTS MEMBERS PREMIUM EVENTS GETTING STARTED Anders Persson 0 Premium Sweden Europe/Stockholm (UTC+01:00) Member for less than a minute Edit Set status Basic Member About Skills About me Omnis voluptatem voluptatem in et asperiores eveniet. Anders Persson has no publicly viewable Youtube videos. Learn More About Us Getting Started Dashboard Opportunities Blog Press Kit Social Facebook Twitter Our Sponsors Standup Bot Craft Academy Mooqita RubyMine Becoming a sponsor AgileVentures - Crowdsourced Learning Contact us Send a traditional email to info@agileventures.org. We are a Charitable Incorporated Organisation (CIO) in the UK. Ref #1170963" (RSpec::Expectations::ExpectationNotMetError)
      ./features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:134:in `/^my profile page should reflect that I am a "([^"]*)" member$/'
      features/premium/upgrade_membership.feature:44:in `And my profile page should reflect that I am a "Premium" member'
    And I should see button "Upgrade to Premium Mob"                # features/step_definitions/basic_steps.rb:232
    And I should see myself in the premium members list             # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:75
WARN: Screenshot could not be saved. `page.current_path` is empty.

Failing Scenarios:
cucumber features/premium/upgrade_membership.feature:36 # Scenario: User upgrades to premium from free tier

1 scenario (1 failed)
12 steps (1 failed, 2 skipped, 9 passed)
0m18.349s
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In principle this test could be affected by the changes I&amp;rsquo;ve been making to the domain model, but if I stick in a debug breakpoint at the point that the view is trying to check the status of the member, it comes up as Premium and the test passes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Then I should see "Premium Member"                              # features/step_definitions/basic_steps.rb:202

[68, 77] in /Users/tansaku/Documents/GitHub/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/app/views/users/profile/_summary.html.erb
   68:                          class: 'user-profile-btn',
   69:                          type: 'button' %&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
   70:         &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
   71:     &amp;lt;% end %&amp;gt;
   72:       &amp;lt;% byebug  # the presence of this allows features/premium/upgrade_membership.feature:36 to pass for me locally %&amp;gt;
=&amp;gt; 73:       &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;%= presenter.user.membership_type %&amp;gt; Member&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
   74:       &amp;lt;% if presenter.user.membership_type == 'Premium' %&amp;gt;
   75:         &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;%= render 'users/profile/premium_mob_upgrade', presenter: presenter  %&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
   76:       &amp;lt;% elsif presenter.user.membership_type == 'Basic' %&amp;gt;
   77:         &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;%= render 'users/profile/premium_upgrade', presenter: presenter %&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
(byebug) presenter.user.membership_type
"Premium"
(byebug) c
    And my profile page should reflect that I am a "Premium" member # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:131
    And I should see button "Upgrade to Premium Mob"                # features/step_definitions/basic_steps.rb:232
    And I should see myself in the premium members list             # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:75
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and similarly if I slap in a byebug at the point that the user&amp;rsquo;s plan is updated we get the same pass:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;    When I fill in appropriate card details for premium             # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:6

[3, 12] in /Users/tansaku/Documents/GitHub/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/app/services/add_subscription_to_user_for_plan.rb
    3:   def self.with(user, sponsor, time, plan, payment_source, subscription_klass = Subscription)
    4:     ensure_all_previous_subscriptions_are_ended(user, time)
    5:     user.subscriptions &amp;lt;&amp;lt; subscription_klass.new(started_at: time, sponsor: sponsor, plan: plan, payment_source: payment_source)
    6:     user.title_list &amp;lt;&amp;lt; plan.name
    7:     byebug
=&amp;gt;  8:     user.save!
    9:   end
   10: 
   11:   def self.ensure_all_previous_subscriptions_are_ended(user, time)
   12:     unended_subs = user.subscriptions.select { |s| s.ended_at.nil? }
(byebug) c
    Then I should see "Premium Member"                              # features/step_definitions/basic_steps.rb:202
    And my profile page should reflect that I am a "Premium" member # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:131
    And I should see button "Upgrade to Premium Mob"                # features/step_definitions/basic_steps.rb:232
    And I should see myself in the premium members list             # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:75
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my hypothesis is that the request to check the profile page is going through so fast that the request for data about the user is coming back before the update has taken place.  The changes I&amp;rsquo;ve made mean the update does take longer.  If my hypothesis is correct, the question is how to make sure that the cuke step to look up the profile page waits until the previous operation has executed.  It occurs to me that Cucumber steps that hit a new endpoint on the server can be treated almost like fire and forget operations. Makes me think of JavaScript non-blocking activity.  Maybe this isn&amp;rsquo;t at all about JavaScript, sorry JavaScript.  Maybe the check that I have &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Then I should see &amp;quot;Premium Member&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; is passing too quickly?  Strange though, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that page won&amp;rsquo;t have Premium Member in it until the transaction has gone through, but is the database in a separate thread?  I didn&amp;rsquo;t think the page would update until the database action completed, but I guess that we go to the create method in the subscriptions controller via a redirect that&amp;rsquo;s triggered from our javascript Stripe form &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I change the step to be &lt;code&gt;Then I should see &amp;quot;Thanks, you&amp;#39;re now an AgileVentures Premium Member&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;, which really can&amp;rsquo;t display until the create method has completed, but I get the same error.  Nice hypothesis, but not supported by the data &amp;hellip; hmm, so I create a new step that will check the member status has changed under the hood:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;And(/^I am a "([^"]*)" Member$/) do |type|
  expect(@user.membership_type).to eq type
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and that fails too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Then I should see "Thanks, you're now an AgileVentures Premium Member" # features/step_definitions/basic_steps.rb:202
    And I am a "Premium" Member                                            # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:144

      expected: "Premium"
           got: "Basic"

      (compared using ==)
       (RSpec::Expectations::ExpectationNotMetError)
      ./features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:145:in `/^I am a "([^"]*)" Member$/'
      features/premium/upgrade_membership.feature:44:in `And I am a "Premium" Member'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which makes me wonder if this something to do with our database transaction and cleaner.  I was skeptical but I found this &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/40185853/316729"&gt;SO answer&lt;/a&gt; which suggesting changing our cleaner from &lt;code&gt;after(:each)&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;append_after(:each)&lt;/code&gt; and it appears to have worked &amp;hellip;?  This is the change:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class="n"&gt;config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;append_after&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:each&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="no"&gt;DatabaseCleaner&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;clean&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in &lt;code&gt;spec_helper.rb&lt;/code&gt;, but after two passes, I cleaned up the extraneous steps and I get a fail again.  Rats.  Again, a feature that takes X amount of time to develop, but takes 5X time to sort out its flaky acceptance tests.  Anyhow, so now I print out the user subscriptions at the point the user has been updated and in the new step to check:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;    When I fill in appropriate card details for premium                    # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:6
#&amp;lt;Subscription id: 1, type: nil, started_at: "2018-01-16 10:07:10", ended_at: nil, user_id: 2, plan_id: 1, sponsor_id: 2&amp;gt;
    Then I should see "Thanks, you're now an AgileVentures Premium Member" # features/step_definitions/basic_steps.rb:202
    And I am a "Premium" Member                                            # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:144
      ["#&amp;lt;Subscription id: 1, type: nil, started_at: \"2018-01-16 10:07:10\", ended_at: nil, user_id: 2, plan_id: 1, sponsor_id: 2&amp;gt;"]

      expected: "Premium"
           got: "Basic"

      (compared using ==)
       (RSpec::Expectations::ExpectationNotMetError)
      ./features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:146:in `/^I am a "([^"]*)" Member$/'
      features/premium/upgrade_membership.feature:44:in `And I am a "Premium" Member'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weird thing here is that both the subscription states look correct, so why does the membership type not report correctly &amp;hellip; which leads me to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;current_subscription&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_subscriptions&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;where&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;ended_at: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kp"&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;where&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'started_at &amp;lt; :now'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;now: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;DateTime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;now&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kp"&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;nil?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;empty?&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ah, so maybe that &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/code&gt; should be &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/code&gt;.  So that helps it pass, but the problem with an intermittent fail is that a single pass is not enough and I clean up and then I get another fail again &amp;hellip; okay, so I then manage to catch another fail with some more logging:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;current_subscription&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nb"&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"all user subs: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;inspect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;}"&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_subscriptions&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;where&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;ended_at: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kp"&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;where&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'started_at &amp;lt;= :now'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;now: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;DateTime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;now&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nb"&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"current subs: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;current_subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;inspect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;}"&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kp"&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;nil?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;empty?&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_subscriptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;#&amp;lt;Subscription id: 1, type: nil, started_at: "2018-01-16 10:17:55", ended_at: nil, user_id: 2, plan_id: 1, sponsor_id: 2&amp;gt;
    Then I should see "Thanks, you're now an AgileVentures Premium Member" # features/step_definitions/basic_steps.rb:202
all user subs: ["#&amp;lt;Subscription id: 1, type: nil, started_at: \"2018-01-16 10:17:55\", ended_at: nil, user_id: 2, plan_id: 1, sponsor_id: 2&amp;gt;"]
current subs: []
    And I am a "Premium" Member                                            # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:145
      ["#&amp;lt;Subscription id: 1, type: nil, started_at: \"2018-01-16 10:17:55\", ended_at: nil, user_id: 2, plan_id: 1, sponsor_id: 2&amp;gt;"]

      expected: "Premium"
           got: "Basic"

      (compared using ==)
       (RSpec::Expectations::ExpectationNotMetError)
      ./features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:147:in `/^I am a "([^"]*)" Member$/'
      features/premium/upgrade_membership.feature:44:in `And I am a "Premium" Member'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we can somehow have a situation where the current subs query does not report what we expect.  The datetimes appear to be specfic to seconds &amp;hellip; maybe I should grab all the subscriptions and filter on the ruby side?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  def current_subscription
    puts "all user subs: #{subscriptions.map{|s| s.inspect}}"
    now = DateTime.now
    puts now
    current_subscriptions = subscriptions.select{|s| s.ended_at.nil? and s.started_at &amp;lt;= now}
    puts "current subs: #{current_subscriptions.map{|s| s.inspect}}"
    return nil if current_subscriptions.nil? or current_subscriptions.empty?
    current_subscriptions.first
  end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but that also fails!  Weird - I even print out the time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;all user subs: ["#&amp;lt;Subscription id: 1, type: nil, started_at: \"2018-01-16 10:27:11\", ended_at: nil, user_id: 2, plan_id: 1, sponsor_id: 2&amp;gt;"]
2018-01-16T10:27:11+00:00
s.ended_at.nil?: true
s.started_at &amp;lt;= now: false
current subs: []
    And I am a "Premium" Member                                            # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:145
      ["#&amp;lt;Subscription id: 1, type: nil, started_at: \"2018-01-16 10:27:11\", ended_at: nil, user_id: 2, plan_id: 1, sponsor_id: 2&amp;gt;"]

      expected: "Premium"
           got: "Basic"

      (compared using ==)
       (RSpec::Expectations::ExpectationNotMetError)
      ./features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:147:in `/^I am a "([^"]*)" Member$/'
      features/premium/upgrade_membership.feature:44:in `And I am a "Premium" Member'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes it look like when the time exactly matches the equality is not there.  Guess I should drop to a unit test:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;    context 'just started a new plan' do
      before { subscription2.ended_at = now ; subscription2.save }
      let!(:subscription3) { FactoryGirl.create(:subscription, user: user, plan: premium_f2f, started_at: now, payment_source: payment_source) }

      it 'returns subscription that has started right now and has not ended' do
        expect(user.current_subscription.id).to eq subscription3.id
      end
    end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t fail in the way I expect, but it looks like the following tip about converting the datetimes to integers seems to work from the print out I&amp;rsquo;m getting running the cuke test &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Then I should see "Thanks, you're now an AgileVentures Premium Member" # features/step_definitions/basic_steps.rb:202
1: s.ended_at.nil?: true
1: s.started_at &amp;lt;= now: false
1: s.started_at.to_i &amp;lt;= now.to_i: true
1: s.ended_at.nil?: true
1: s.started_at &amp;lt;= now: false
1: s.started_at.to_i &amp;lt;= now.to_i: true
    And my profile page should reflect that I am a "Premium" member        # features/step_definitions/premium_steps.rb:131
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how the &lt;code&gt;s.started_at &amp;lt;= now&lt;/code&gt; is false while &lt;code&gt;s.started_at.to_i &amp;lt;= now.to_i&lt;/code&gt; is true.  I got the idea from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://makandracards.com/makandra/1057-why-two-ruby-time-objects-are-not-equal-although-they-appear-to-be"&gt;https://makandracards.com/makandra/1057-why-two-ruby-time-objects-are-not-equal-although-they-appear-to-be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I use &lt;code&gt;to_i&lt;/code&gt; to compare the dates all the tests pass in batch and in the CI, making it seem like we&amp;rsquo;ve licked the intermittent fail issue, which seems to have been completely unrelated to JavaScript, but a function of the system looking for subscriptions that started in the past, and the cuke tests running fast enough that sometimes (and only sometimes) when the new subscription was created in the same second as the check for the current_subscription, the user would still be reported as not having upgraded to the new subscription.  The fix should have been just changing &amp;rsquo;&amp;lt;&amp;rsquo; to &amp;rsquo;&amp;lt;=&amp;rsquo; but the date comparison seems to require switching to integers to make it work as we expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s frustrating is that the new unit test checks for the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/code&gt; but somehow using factory girl (or something) does not replicate the exact way that the dates get set up when the whole thing runs in the acceptance test, so I have the system working now, but not a nice unit test precisely nailing the concealed bug &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to wrap up for now - I&amp;rsquo;ll leave notes in the code - I wonder if this is a known Rails issue &amp;hellip; anyway, apologies to JavaScript for thinking it was all your fault - not in this case :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Getting Back on Track</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/15/av-ecosystem-review-getting-back-on-track/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/15/av-ecosystem-review-getting-back-on-track/</id>
    <published>2018-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-24T21:25:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="track" src="/images/track.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bit of a wreck this morning.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep well - woke up at 4am brain full of kids football.  I did write down a new drill for training (I coach 7aside soccer for nine year olds) and then listened to standup comedy on audio for 2 hours to stop my brain endlessly turning over the same thoughts again and again.  Not dissimilar to last Sunday night/Monday morning.  Emotionally charged football matches.  This weekend&amp;rsquo;s was less intense (draw instead of a loss), but I worked three hours in the afternoon to get the APSoc&amp;rsquo;s membership database recreated on MS Access now that I got the green light from the client to switch.  This is all because LibreOffice is crashing too frequently and ZohoCreator looks like it doesn&amp;rsquo;t might not have all the functionality we need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made reasonable progress yesterday although I was popping paracetamol and ibuprofen to push on in the last hour.  I think I&amp;rsquo;ve got us back to the place we were in LibreOffice, and actually got a few more supporting tables to populate the dropdown lists correctly.  However there&amp;rsquo;s a clear additional chunk of functionality that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really been focusing on.  A load of specification for default values, computed fields and so forth.  I&amp;rsquo;d love to have a break from the project this week, so I think the thing to do is label what we have as an MS Access alpha version and re-work the schedule.  Here are screenshots of the different forms done in Access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ydoubyw95wb1zhc/Screenshot%202018-01-15%2009.28.44.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/eoi4nm5e655wnhq/Screenshot%202018-01-15%2009.29.14.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/rel3yqy4ur1rujc/Screenshot%202018-01-15%2009.31.58.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/jqch3s2dbyujrzi/Screenshot%202018-01-15%2009.32.19.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wonder if I should set up a Trello board for all the different bits of functionality?  I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll get the new schedule approved.  The old schedule had been:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Dec 8th - screenshots of membership database interface for you to approve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Dec 15th - alpha version of membership database for you to approve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 5th - beta version of membership database adjusted as per feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 31st - release version of membership database adjusted as per feedback, including full migration &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so if we have the alpha version now, then perhaps we can set the beta version for Jan 26th, and then release version on Feb 9th, so that&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 26th - beta version of membership database adjusted as per feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Feb 9th - release version of membership database adjusted as per feedback, including full migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which I put in an email to the client:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your email - hope you had a good weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now have an alpha version in MSAccess, which you can access here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[DROP BOX LINK]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you don&amp;rsquo;t have a copy of MSAccess please find screenshots of all the forms attached.
Thanks so much for all the detailed feedback over the last few weeks.  I believe we have a good chunk of the issues addressed in this MS Access alpha version, but certainly not all. In particular, as you noticed, the majority of fields are not folllowing the defaulted/calculated/midified rules from the database definition.   This is simply as we hadn&amp;rsquo;t started work on implementing them yet.   Please rest assured that they will be implemented in the next version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the software issues we encountered with LibreOffice we&amp;rsquo;d like to propose the following new schedule for delivery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Jan 26th - beta version of membership database adjusted as per feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by Feb 9th - release version of membership database adjusted as per feedback, including full migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our sincere apologies for the slippage and we hope the new schedule meets with your approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best, Sam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I&amp;rsquo;ll send that later today.  Now what I really want is some coffee and perhaps I can dive into my outstanding pull request on updating the WSO Premium model so that it can support the sponsor relations we need to more accurately represent our Premium membership data &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Starting Over</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/12/av-ecosystem-review-starting-over/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/12/av-ecosystem-review-starting-over/</id>
    <published>2018-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-21T21:15:23+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="starting over" src="/images/starting_over.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I sent the APSoc client the following email:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think we need to make some decisions about how to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment we are thinking that the best alternatives are to either go with MS Access, or with Zoho Creator.  Using the XLSX you just provided we&amp;rsquo;ve started projects in both MS Access and Zoho Creator.  It&amp;rsquo;s obviously not ideal to have to switch platform at this stage, but the instability of LibreOffice Base makes it seem like we can&amp;rsquo;t continue with that platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zoho Creator is a cloud solution that replicates much of the MSAccess/LotusApproach functionality, and comes with a £10 a month price tag, but reduced to £8 for charities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MS offers Access as part of Office 365 for £1.50 a month (for charities), and Access is also available standalone.  Access 2013 is available for £12 for charities and Access 2016 is available for about £95.  I&amp;rsquo;m keen to know if you already have a copy of Access and whether you have strong preferences here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that you were looking to avoid any monthly charges, and anticipate that you might prefer the standalone MS Access option.  If you do currently have a copy of MS Access please let us know which version you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let me know if you&amp;rsquo;d like a call to discuss the alternatives.  We&amp;rsquo;re planning to work through the weekend to get the project back on schedule on a new platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best, Sam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard back yet, so I guess I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a stab at moving the MS Access version forward.  Zoho Creator was nice and zippy, and MS Access feels sluggish, but I suspect that the monthly charge for Zoho could be a dealbreaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took about 40 minutes but I got a draft form for members up in Access 2007:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/5khkijp2qr728gj/Screenshot%202018-01-12%2011.33.31.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With at least one dropdown linking to a different table.  Overall the UI is easily better than the latest LibreOffice even though I&amp;rsquo;m using MSAccess from 10 years back.  Hmm, maybe I should have just started with Access for a simple life, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see.  Now I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to see what&amp;rsquo;s the best I can get out of Zoho &amp;hellip; I immediately run up against a couple of (perhaps minor) issues, which are that we can&amp;rsquo;t easily convert fields from multi-line to single-line and back again.  Also my attempts to adjust a drop down field to radio buttons fails.  I think I&amp;rsquo;ll give up there.  I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the client is going to be much happier with the results from MSAccess, and I can develop faster there too &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Review Painful Decisions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/11/av-ecosystem-review-painful-decisions/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/11/av-ecosystem-review-painful-decisions/</id>
    <published>2018-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-17T20:43:48+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="hardest thing and the right thing" src="/images/hardest-and-right.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The APSoc has responded calmly to the email I sent about the problems with LibreOffice Base.  Here&amp;rsquo;s what I sent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s disturbing to hear that you&amp;rsquo;re experiencing lock up.  We have been experiencing that too, but only with the system in edit mode, i.e. editing the UI, tables etc.  updates to tables have been working fine.  These lock ups are pretty much what caused us to be late delivering last week.  That you&amp;rsquo;re encountering them to makes me think that we have a particularly tricky issue to solve here and some important decisions to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rest assured that the problems fall on our side and not yours.  We&amp;rsquo;ve given a fixed quote for this, and will do whatever is necessary to deliver robust and stable software by the final deadline however many additional hours are required on our side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to be discussing the options in a team meeting today, and will come back to you with some alternative approaches to consider by the end of the day.  In the meantime I notice that, in the database pack we originally received from you, there are a number of file formats including XLSX, but notably we do not have an XLSX formatted file for the subscription or members tables; while we do have them for the gift aid, member types and recurring subs tables.  Is there any chance you could provide XLSX files for the subscription and members tables as this would help with debugging and testing alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks in advance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best, Sam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They responded with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah-ha … thanks for this … I’m glad it isn’t just me getting lock-ups and being stupid!  The lock-ups seem to happen as soon as I select “Queries” and use the Wizard.  Sometimes it just locks Libre and I can continue with other things; at other times everything locks until I kill Libre.  If I then try to restart Libre and access the beta file I get “General Error: General input/output error” until I refresh the Libre file from the supplied one.  This also happens if I try creating anything more than a very simple report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as including the files I requested and answering a few other outstanding questions and some other feedback on the interface.  I also had a call yesterday from Zoho indicating that the non-profit discount is 20% if we pay a year up front (instead of the usual 10%), which is not a huge boost, but I guess I at least use the new file from the client to check out Zoho&amp;rsquo;s offering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short order it gives me the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/3g8557dfmr00nzq/Screenshot%202018-01-11%2010.08.47.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see I can also import different sets of choices for the country field&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/c3nw135pu5wn6f2/Screenshot%202018-01-11%2010.12.35.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but I can see a fair chunk of work required to get this set up to where the client might be passing happy (including being able to generate all the forms and reports they like), and then there&amp;rsquo;s the question of the monthly fees.  In the meantime I got MS Access 2013 for £14.40 through the tt-exchange using AgileVentures charity status.  And &amp;hellip; they are going to physically deliver shrink-wrapped software to my address?  What, no download?  Seems like we won&amp;rsquo;t receive anything for five days, hmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see MS Access 2016 being offered for close to £100 from Tekgia on a charity offer.  Hmmm. So I had another go at getting in through the MS portal to no joy.  I did seem to be able to get access to the basic office suite through our existing nonprofit setup by going through the sam@agileventures.org login in my safari browser.  I finally found a help request form and submitted a help request:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://nonprofitcontactus.microsoftcrmportals.com/contact-us/"&gt;https://nonprofitcontactus.microsoftcrmportals.com/contact-us/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I would have pasted in here the help request but super-irritatingly I can&amp;rsquo;t go back to the form and they don&amp;rsquo;t send me a copy &amp;hellip; although they send me a notification that they&amp;rsquo;ll get back to me in about 5 business days:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/qwm32xhnsr14tuk/Screenshot%202018-01-11%2010.45.32.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ugh, I guess the main question on my mind is whether Zoho can produce the reports the client needs, and maybe more importantly the complex subforms &amp;hellip; the other alternatives I have are build their system from scratch in LibreOffice on PC, and/or force through and buy a copy of MS Access 2016.  £100 is not insane from Tekgia, but will be frustrating if we can get it for £1.50 a month as part of our MS nonprofit status, of I&amp;rsquo;ve doubled up having already spend £12 on MS access and I&amp;rsquo;ve missed the download button or it will arrive tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do have MS Access 2007 on my machine - should I perhaps start playing with that?  Quick answer is that I can&amp;rsquo;t import the LibreOffice odb format into MS Access 2007.  Also, it looks like Zoho does support subforms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.zoho.com/creator/help/forms/creating-subforms.html"&gt;https://www.zoho.com/creator/help/forms/creating-subforms.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been able to import the XLSX table into MS Access 2007, so that&amp;rsquo;s a basic route forward I guess &amp;hellip; painful decisions ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
