<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-10-18T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Emotional Hurdles</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/10/18/av-ecosystem-review-emotional-hurdles/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/10/18/av-ecosystem-review-emotional-hurdles/</id>
    <published>2017-10-18T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-04T22:24:30+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="hurdles" src="/images/hurdles.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late to the blogface due to feelings of lethargy and accidentally reading all my Slack and Emails.  Not so many of them as I was checking them pretty late last night as well - blurgh.  However the mixed strategy of investigating performance and a new static landing page site in parallel seems to be going reasonably well.  At least I&amp;rsquo;m making some progress on both fronts.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got the loaderio tag on staging:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://staging.agileventures.org/loaderio-bd60fb88537b106821044fd9098f271c.html"&gt;https://staging.agileventures.org/loaderio-bd60fb88537b106821044fd9098f271c.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the helpful folks at loaderio showed me how I could get the load test to hit &lt;a href="https://staging.agileventures.org"&gt;https://staging.agileventures.org&lt;/a&gt; rather than the herokuapp URL, so time to kick off a load test.  But actually no, because now we have a new hash code lookup, blargh.  So I could try and make this dynamic, but perhaps it won&amp;rsquo;t change now that we have fixed to staging.agileventures.org, but then again perhaps it will change for every new test we create.  Verification via DNS is now an option &amp;hellip; either way it&amp;rsquo;s going to take an hour or two to actually get to the load test.  So I set up a dynamic approach with the following in the routes file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;loaderio_token&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;ENV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'LOADERIO_TOKEN'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;||&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"loaderio-296a53739de683b99e3a2c4d7944230f"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="no"&gt;WebsiteOne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;Application&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;routes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;draw&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="n"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;loaderio_token&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'static_pages#loaderio'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and this in the static pages controller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;loaderio&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;render&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;plain: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;ENV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'LOADERIO_TOKEN'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;||&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"loaderio-296a53739de683b99e3a2c4d7944230f"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;layout: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kp"&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I get a pull request in, but now I have to wait for the CI to pass.  So I have to task swap somewhat.  It&amp;rsquo;s all about the emotional hurdles.  I was de-motivated to look into performance testing as I thought it would be a pain to set up and difficult to get to the bottom of the problem.  I&amp;rsquo;m reinvigorated by having found loaderio, even though I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually got it working yet.  Conversely while I was more excited about getting a middleman landing page set up, I&amp;rsquo;ve now taken an emotional knock due to the challenges I encountered yesterday with middleman-deploy.  And that&amp;rsquo;s even when I got it all working, but the knock is from finding that both middleman-gh-pages and middleman-deploy are looking a little under-maintained.  Middleman-deploy is marginally more active, and does have some nice functionality.  My next task there is sorting out the asset pathways, and actually maybe they will just start working when we deploy to a custom domain &amp;hellip; although I was pestering myself with instead staying focused on the performance issue and reading more about Ruby memory management.  Here&amp;rsquo;s what Heroku says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re getting R14 - Memory quota exceeded errors, it means your application is using swap memory. Swap uses the disk to store memory instead of RAM. Disk speed is significantly slower than RAM, so page access time is greatly increased. This leads to a significant degradation in application performance. An application that is swapping will be much slower than one that is not. No one wants a slow application, so getting rid of R14 Memory quota exceeded errors on your application is very important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The suggested solutions include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/ruby-memory-use#ruby-2-0-upgrade"&gt;Upgrading to at least Ruby 2.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/ruby-memory-use#memory-leaks"&gt;Looking for memory leaks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/ruby-memory-use#too-many-workers"&gt;Avoiding too many webserver workers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/ruby-memory-use#forking-behavior-of-puma-worker-processes"&gt;Forking behavior of Puma worker processes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/ruby-memory-use#too-much-memory-used-at-runtime"&gt;Too much memory used at runtime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/ruby-memory-use#gc-tuning"&gt;GC tuning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/ruby-memory-use#dyno-size-and-performance"&gt;Dyno size and performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we&amp;rsquo;re already on Ruby 2.3.1, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think we spent any time looking for memory leaks yet, and the project &lt;a href="https://github.com/schneems/derailed_benchmarks"&gt;derailed_benchmarks&lt;/a&gt; appears to be something we can run locally to check, so we can quickly get into that while we wait for the load test environment to be ready &amp;hellip; I follow the install instructions and kick off &lt;code&gt;bundle exec derailed bundle:mem&lt;/code&gt; to profile our gems.  I think must have done this before as I recognise the output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[tansaku@Samuels-MBP:~/Documents/Github/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne (1826_derailed_benchmarks)]$ 
→ bundle exec derailed bundle:mem
TOP: 120.8359 MiB
  nearest_time_zone: 48.3281 MiB
  rails/all: 17.0625 MiB
    active_record/railtie: 7.7188 MiB
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and the identification of &lt;code&gt;nearest_time_zone&lt;/code&gt; as the most memory consuming gem, more even than Rails itself.  After Rails the following three are the biggest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  pivotal-tracker-api: 9.3438 MiB
  bootstrap-sass: 6.1289 MiB
  octokit: 5.1992 MiB
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what I don&amp;rsquo;t think we ran before was the check for leaking memory &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[tansaku@Samuels-MBP:~/Documents/Github/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne (1826_derailed_benchmarks)]$ 
→ bundle exec derailed exec perf:mem_over_time
Booting: production
/Users/tansaku/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1/gems/airbrake-ruby-2.2.2/lib/airbrake-ruby/notifier.rb:33:in `initialize': :project_id is required (Airbrake::Error)
    from /Users/tansaku/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1/gems/airbrake-ruby-2.2.2/lib/airbrake-ruby.rb:135:in `new'
    from /Users/tansaku/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1/gems/airbrake-ruby-2.2.2/lib/airbrake-ruby.rb:135:in `configure'
    from /Users/tansaku/Documents/GitHub/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/config/initializers/airbrake.rb:2:in `&amp;lt;top (required)&amp;gt;'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which gets stuck because trying to run in production we need an airbrake id, amongst many other things &amp;hellip; so in a flurry of firing and forgetting I get an AIRBRAKE token and id in and create a production database:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ pg_dump -U postgres websiteone_development | psql -U postgres websiteone_production
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and also deploy the loaderio dynamic token to staging and also set up a landing.agileventures.org domain and configure that &amp;hellip; now the deploy to staging won&amp;rsquo;t finish till the CI passes so I can&amp;rsquo;t actually fire and forget that.  I can try &lt;a href="http://landing.agileventures.org"&gt;http://landing.agileventures.org&lt;/a&gt; and in fact that does exactly what I suspect - it&amp;rsquo;s working and the CSS/JS assets are being pulled in correctly.  So that&amp;rsquo;s a nice unblocked feeling &amp;hellip; but with derailed_benchmarks I&amp;rsquo;m stuck on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;→ AIRBRAKE_PROJECT_ID=6 AIRBRAKE_API_KEY=XXXX bundle exec derailed exec perf:mem_over_time
Booting: production
Endpoint: "/"
/Users/tansaku/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1/gems/derailed_benchmarks-1.3.2/lib/derailed_benchmarks/tasks.rb:72: warning: already initialized constant DERAILED_APP
/Users/tansaku/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1/gems/derailed_benchmarks-1.3.2/lib/derailed_benchmarks/tasks.rb:23: warning: previous definition of DERAILED_APP was here
PID: 79590
211.39453125
/Users/tansaku/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1/gems/derailed_benchmarks-1.3.2/lib/derailed_benchmarks/tasks.rb:92:in `call_app': Bad request:  (RuntimeError)
    from /Users/tansaku/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1/gems/derailed_benchmarks-1.3.2/lib/derailed_benchmarks/tasks.rb:174:in `block (3 levels) in &amp;lt;top (required)&amp;gt;'
    from /Users/tansaku/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1/gems/derailed_benchmarks-1.3.2/lib/derailed_benchmarks/tasks.rb:173:in `times'
    from /Users/tansaku/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.3.1/gems/derailed_benchmarks-1.3.2/lib/derailed_benchmarks/tasks.rb:173:in `block (2 levels) in &amp;lt;top (required)&amp;gt;'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so after a few searches I open an issue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/schneems/derailed_benchmarks/issues/110"&gt;https://github.com/schneems/derailed_benchmarks/issues/110&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and call it a day &amp;hellip; but no I see that staging has depoyed so I kick off a test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="config the homepage test" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/f5e6tu71lctah7o/Screenshot%202017-10-19%2010.53.45.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which gives these results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/5han2hh44m7n1bx/Screenshot%202017-10-19%2010.54.38.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which I now need to work out how to interpret - apparently the test was aborted due to reaching an error threshold.  I think what we are seeing here is the requests timing out as the server comes under heavy load.  I need to run this again while watching the logs &amp;hellip; and when I do I see the memory errors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;2017-10-19T09:58:58.775050+00:00 heroku[web.1]: Process running mem=680M(133.0%)
2017-10-19T09:58:58.775050+00:00 heroku[web.1]: Error R14 (Memory quota exceeded)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so at least now we have a way to test possible solutions to the problem &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Death Warmed Up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/10/17/av-ecosystem-review-death-warmed-up/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/10/17/av-ecosystem-review-death-warmed-up/</id>
    <published>2017-10-17T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-03T22:18:21+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="death" src="/images/death.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am having trouble getting started this morning.  &amp;ldquo;Death warmed up&amp;rdquo; is hyperbole, but despite my best efforts it&amp;rsquo;s 10am before I&amp;rsquo;ve hit the blogface.  Various things interfered.  A 2.5 km jog with my twin boys, although to be honest they weren&amp;rsquo;t slowing me down.  Doing extra long Japanese tests for my older boy now (he&amp;rsquo;s 12); five Karate kata&amp;rsquo;s - my morning routine is starting to take a fair chunk of time.  I felt lethargic independently of all that - my stomach is a bit off.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with reducing the amount of dairy in my diet.  Also I gave up coffee for the last three weeks.  This really is the sort of situation I&amp;rsquo;d self-medicate with caffeine to get going, but I have this idea that that isn&amp;rsquo;t a good approach for me in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also there&amp;rsquo;s the never-ending sets of chores.  Ordering new contact lenses this morning (should I get laser eye-surgery? or am I too attached to my look with glasses? I only use contact lenses for sport), driving to three supermarkets last night to finally find small bottles of carbonated water (my vice) and to the hardware store to buy equipment to help with redoing the front yard during my time off next week (kid&amp;rsquo;s half term).  And then I&amp;rsquo;m fielding quotes from builders to re-do our upstairs bathroom.  So many things suck up time :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d had the idea this week to start building a middleman site to begin prototyping new front pages for the main AgileVentures website.  I did make some tweaks to the Getting Started pages yesterday, although Federico had got an animation in there and made other changes.  The blog I pushed out last night had more stats on the Getting Started pages from a few months back, but right now I&amp;rsquo;ve got no head for stats.  What&amp;rsquo;s fun?  What&amp;rsquo;s the priority for the community?  I guess it&amp;rsquo;s a toss up between the two things we were looking at in our design sprint.  Adjusting the home pages to try and better explain what we&amp;rsquo;re all about, or a structured guide that gets folks really engaged in projects (attending scrums, submitting PRs etc.), and maybe tracks their progress to boot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m fearful of adding more complexity to the WebSiteOne Rails monolith, and so I think I&amp;rsquo;d like to experiment with a middleman front end that I have high confidence won&amp;rsquo;t run into performance issues.  Maybe the time should be spent on investigating the Rails performance issues we have, but I&amp;rsquo;m suspicious that that will take more time for an uncertain result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tricky bit (or just the bit we have to be careful with) for the middleman approach will be the switch over to point http://www.agileventure.org to the GitHub pages, and then creating https://projects.agileventures.org or something to point to the Rails app &amp;hellip; or I just start reading the Heroku notes on memory errors again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/optimizing-dyno-usage"&gt;https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/optimizing-dyno-usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/ruby-memory-use"&gt;https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/ruby-memory-use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficulty here is with being able to test the impact of changes that we make.  Unless we get some load testing set up.  Heroku has guidelines on that, and an &amp;ldquo;add on&amp;rdquo; to get us started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/load-testing-guidelines"&gt;https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/load-testing-guidelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://elements.heroku.com/addons/loaderio"&gt;https://elements.heroku.com/addons/loaderio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to get much done today, but I guess I can throw up a quick middleman app and perhaps alternate these two approaches to feel out which one is going to reap the biggest reward:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/middleman/middleman"&gt;https://github.com/middleman/middleman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;because I can&amp;rsquo;t bear just reading docs and slow turnarounds for debugging - I want to be making something and encountering issues in real time! :-) Just installing the latest middleman I realise that maybe I should upgrade Ruby.  Ruby 2.4.2 wouldn&amp;rsquo;t install so I backed out to Ruby 2.4.1.  This was the error from Ruby 2.4.2 on OSX:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;/usr/local/Homebrew/Library/Homebrew/brew.rb:12:in `&amp;lt;main&amp;gt;': Homebrew must be run under Ruby 2.3! (RuntimeError)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmmm &amp;hellip; 2.4.1 installed and I set it to default:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[tansaku@Samuels-MBP:~/Documents/Github/AgileVentures ]$ 
→ rvm use 2.4.1 --default
Using /Users/tansaku/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.4.1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I note c9 is on 2.4.0, so I guess I should install that too; ah, but I have it already &amp;hellip; so then I install middleman in the 2.4.1 space.  Although I&amp;rsquo;m actually in the 2.4.0 - maybe I need the ruby version on the command prompt &amp;hellip; anyway, in fairly short order I have boiler plate middleman code at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tansaku/av-landing-page"&gt;https://github.com/tansaku/av-landing-page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;ll look at deploying to github pages and seeing if I can get the CSS pipeline set up &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Tweaking Getting Started</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/10/16/av-ecosystem-review-tweaking-getting-started/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/10/16/av-ecosystem-review-tweaking-getting-started/</id>
    <published>2017-10-16T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-02T22:13:56+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Busy weekend and errands this morning mean I&amp;rsquo;m late to the blogface again, but perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s a good excuse to just focus on tweaking the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page, rather than building a middleman site as a performant home page replacement.  I start with the initial &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page where I remove some inactive projects and add some new ones. I see that over the weekend Federico has edited the same page, to add an animation of the flow about how to get started saying hello in Slack, which is great.  There&amp;rsquo;s also a color scheme change.  I go in and make my project edits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was going to add a screenshot of the welcome process, but as I look carefully I see Federico is actually copy/pasting from the precise text in the page.  Text I was hoping to remove and replace with an image to make the whole thing less wordy &amp;hellip; hmm, I put back the text I removed and remove the image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/53sng86et75cwou/Screenshot%202017-10-16%2010.18.34.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the projects to include Y and peer power:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/hcsfi6z771pvyb6/Screenshot%202017-10-16%2010.22.26.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I leave it at that.  I go on to step 2, and think it seems odd not to be using hyperlinks on all these terms that are being described here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/0nabm1p22p6ggk8/Screenshot%202017-10-16%2010.23.55.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, maybe we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t hyperlink off our site here, but people can use the back button and this should be a resource that can allow folks to get more information.  All the more reason we should store progress through the getting-started track I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/6tu2ooyrp4ccj4l/Screenshot%202017-10-16%2010.30.47.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I add optional to the hyperlink to step 7 (since that is optionally starting your own project), and leave it at that.  I recall that Will was saying that the &amp;ldquo;listen in&amp;rdquo; phrase in the non-logged in version of the link to the scrum was the key thing that got him involved.  Perhaps we could adjust the phrasing for logged in users too, to get more in the scrums &amp;hellip;  I create a ticket for that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1915"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1915&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but I have added &amp;ldquo;All Welcome! Discuss Any Project, Ask Any Question!&amp;rdquo; to the title of the events.  Maybe I can just tweak that &amp;hellip; or will this be enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/rnlzuzl9tobqp3c/Screenshot%202017-10-16%2010.47.01.png?dl=0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem How to Get Started</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/10/13/av-ecosystem-review-how-to-get-started/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/10/13/av-ecosystem-review-how-to-get-started/</id>
    <published>2017-10-13T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-21T22:13:35+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="how do you get started" src="/images/how_do_you_get_started.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, too much food and a late night means I&amp;rsquo;m late to the blog-face again.  There&amp;rsquo;s also the Slack and email messages that somehow distracted me too &amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s think about some of the sources of folks coming to our site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Adwords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Adwords is dropping a lot of people on our site, and a fair number of them are signing up and giving us their email address.  Far fewer are getting into Slack and getting active.  We&amp;rsquo;re running social media campaigns that are giving us likes on Twitter and Facebook, but according to analytics they&amp;rsquo;re miniscule in terms of getting folks signed up on our site.  About 20 users between them compared to over 10,000 from Google Adwords and organic Google search.  I&amp;rsquo;m posting my own materials on Twitter and Facebook as well, and we&amp;rsquo;re running campaigns to get free mob programming and F2F sessions if folks follow us on Twitter and like us on facebook.  From my own experience that&amp;rsquo;s got at least one member signed up to Premium Mob who&amp;rsquo;s also just upgraded to F2F.  The last few Premium sign ups seem to have come from folks who came in through the MOOC or from one of my podcast appearances.  Our most recent paid project came in through chatlio, but how did that charity find our nonprofits site?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think about re-enabling chatlio (or something similar) on just our premium pages on the main site - and putting it back on the nonprofits site.  Maybe complete the charity contract first.  The other idea I have here is what about we put our Premium Mob and F2F campaigns in Google AdWords and advertise them directly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing I said I was going to do today was look at our new getting started pages and how they are fairing in Google Analytics.  So what&amp;rsquo;s strange is that the behaviour flow doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to show anyone clicking through on the second page of &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/0bnhelyc4qni9xf/Screenshot%202017-10-13%2010.27.19.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the &amp;ldquo;30 more pages&amp;rdquo; shown, none of them are any of the subsequent getting-started page sequence I previously created.  However if I look at the analytics via the chrome plugin I see 11% clicking through on step 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/6ekiiw9ayjf1vxy/Screenshot%202017-10-13%2010.29.22.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I open the sequence of pages I can see a steady drop off in the number of visitors reaching each page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting-started: 705 unique page-views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting-started-2: 102 unique page-views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting-started-3: 72 unique page-views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting-started-4: 64 unique page-views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting-started-5: 60 unique page-views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting-started-6: 54 unique page-views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting-started-7: 48 unique page-views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So at least we can clearly see folks progressing along the funnel there, but what we don&amp;rsquo;t have is a strong call to action; a conversion step.  Even just getting folks to click &amp;ldquo;join project&amp;rdquo; on the project pages to register their interest in a project could be a good goal.  We also see a fairly strong trend that on the first page a lot of folks are clicking through to see the individual project pages, with the top project &amp;ldquo;WebSiteOne&amp;rdquo; receiving the lion&amp;rsquo;s share.  Maybe we could mix up that list a bit, and also take a look at all the project pages and how inviting and action focused they are &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there are lots of things we could be doing here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) replacing some text instructions with animations (e.g. how to say hello in Slack)&lt;br&gt;
b) adding more images throughout&lt;br&gt;
c) deciding on a clear goal state (&amp;ldquo;joining&amp;rdquo; a project, saying hello in Slack)&lt;br&gt;
d) dynamic interventions such as saving progress, or modifying the contents based on a selected project?&lt;br&gt;
e) allowing the user to search for project via tech stack  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also start to think if there&amp;rsquo;s some way we could just drop folks in a fresh C9 instance with the project of their choice and a simple chore to work on?  Or would folks be more engaged if a human from their selected project reaches out &amp;hellip;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or would it be better to focus earlier in the flow on the landing page itself.  I also think about doing some landing pages in middleman that would be more performant and allow us to test getting the concept of AgileVentures across more strongly.  I&amp;rsquo;m encountering performance issues using the site.  According to New Relic it&amp;rsquo;s our static pages in Visitors Controller and Documents Controller that are performing the worst:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/78z9ugrvabo8f7h/Screenshot%202017-10-13%2010.44.57.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are a series of Rails caching operations that we could use to improve these, but tuning the current monolith while trying to work out what&amp;rsquo;s happening with really slow feedback about whether site performance is improving does not fill me with excitement &amp;hellip; well I&amp;rsquo;ll think about it over the weekend.  I guess next week I could spend the morning av ecosystem review blogs setting up a middleman site and seeing how easily I can re-create the current home page in it &amp;hellip; Or is there something I should tweak in getting started first?  Maybe just encouraging folks to click join on the project pages?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Big Picture</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/10/12/av-ecosystem-review-big-picture/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/10/12/av-ecosystem-review-big-picture/</id>
    <published>2017-10-12T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-20T21:11:54+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="big picture" src="/images/big_picture.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, time to get back up to the big picture.  What I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to do for a while is try and draw the flow of folks exposure to AgileVentures through to varying levels of engagement.  I wanted to start by embedding some images of the ads we have served by Google, but first up they are taking me through a tutorial for their new site layout:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/accgwjtlosy9tv9/Screenshot%202017-10-12%2009.45.20.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we need something similar to make AV.org more understandable perhaps?  Anyway, previously there was a &amp;ldquo;tools&amp;rdquo; menu in AdWords or something that is supposed to allow us to see what our ads look like.  One might expect to see them when doing a search for keywords on Google, but we&amp;rsquo;re usually competing with so many other campaigns from other parties that&amp;rsquo;s not usually reliable.  I just tried and got distracted for 10 minutes checking out &lt;a href="http://www.opencharityuk.org/"&gt;http://www.opencharityuk.org/&lt;/a&gt;  I can&amp;rsquo;t see our ads, and I can&amp;rsquo;t find the tools section in the new AdWords interface, but they did say some things weren&amp;rsquo;t available - so I go back to the old interface where I find the tool, but I get the usual, your ad not available for one reason or another:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/12jtlh9bcbdw66t/Screenshot%202017-10-12%2009.56.57.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try for different regions, UK, SA, India. No joy.  Now I saw Lara catch an ad and she did post it in the marketing Slack for me, and I think I even saved it, but for the life of me I can&amp;rsquo;t find it now.  Five minutes of searching on Slack and I have it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/jdaescgckn00v5o/Screenshot%202017-10-12%2010.02.43.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to our Adwords dashboard we&amp;rsquo;re serving over 200,000 ads a month(?) with over 10,000 click throughs, mainly for ads like these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/04x3ffk8lsynpsl/Screenshot%202017-10-12%2010.03.01.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where the message is &amp;ldquo;level up your coding skills&amp;rdquo;, and that settles my paranoia slightly that we&amp;rsquo;re only targeting novice coders.  Although it would be great if we could be targeting folks who want to level up their &amp;ldquo;tech team skills&amp;rdquo;, their &amp;ldquo;agile development&amp;rdquo; and so on.  What&amp;rsquo;s so frustrating about the AdWords interface is that I can&amp;rsquo;t easily see what the ads look like.  Although actually this panel comes close:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/zfw778rqt55v8v6/Screenshot%202017-10-12%2010.07.24.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah and then I can click through, okay &amp;hellip;, so this ad was served 14.25% of the time (to those who are searching &amp;ldquo;open-source&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;developers&amp;rdquo;) - weird how it looks like a link to a sub page, but actually we just link to the top page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/axq4e4qlba677vu/Screenshot%202017-10-12%2010.08.37.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ad served 31.85% of the time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ua9fg0lyekwqzh2/Screenshot%202017-10-12%2010.10.56.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and most of the rest on the level up your coding skills, and we have an overview showing the number of conversions for each:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/764gqj5wwqa3zv3/Screenshot%202017-10-12%2010.12.31.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And these four ads are all being served as part of a campaign that has multiple keywords associated with it, but particularly &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;open source&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;[coding]&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/xl4v308cwdqacia/Screenshot%202017-10-12%2010.15.17.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new AdWords inteface is not making any of this much clearer.  According to Google Analytics a huge proportion of our click throughs are coming from India and we don&amp;rsquo;t know why.  Is that just a reflection of India&amp;rsquo;s large population being interested in Agile coding, or some settings artifact?  In analytics I can&amp;rsquo;t even be sure if the majority of the Indian visitors are actually coming in through ads, or from some other source, and AdWords doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to let me see the location of where click throughs are coming through, frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I push through to a breakdown of the Indian sub-continent and add &amp;ldquo;Source/Medium&amp;rdquo; as a secondary dimension, which makes it look like everyone there is coming in through Google ads, although I can&amp;rsquo;t be sure &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/2ns92oi7ao69tca/Screenshot%202017-10-12%2010.26.47.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we could burn more time drilling into this, but I&amp;rsquo;m not feeling like for all the AdWords we&amp;rsquo;ve served we&amp;rsquo;ve converted many users to paying for Premium.  We&amp;rsquo;re certainly getting sign ups for the main site, which is great for bulking out our mailing list, but far fewer are signing into Slack and becoming active.  I&amp;rsquo;m out of time today, but so perhaps where I need to focus tomorrow is our different marketing channels:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Google Adwords
2) Twitter
3) Facebook
4) LinkedIn
5) Medium&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and that flow through from one of or other of these sources to landing on our site and what the users sees - and whether we get them to the &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; page and get them activated &amp;hellip; of course it&amp;rsquo;s all in vain if the site has serious performance issues &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AV EcoSystem Late to the Blogface</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/10/11/av-ecosystem-review-late-to-the-blogface/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/10/11/av-ecosystem-review-late-to-the-blogface/</id>
    <published>2017-10-11T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-19T21:57:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="late" src="/images/late.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I am very late to the blogface this morning after doing a 7.5km jog and then experimenting with making an eggs benedict for the first time in my life.  To compound it I had two podcasts to post to Twitter and Slack and in an exhausted over-fed state I had little resistance to reviewing all my Slack and email messages.  I stopped short of looking at all the Twitter notifications.  There&amp;rsquo;s definitely some kind of micro-message addiction going on here.   I can&amp;rsquo;t remember what it was I was excited to work on.  Maybe it was clipping the time/dates off the Slack messages.  I&amp;rsquo;m pretty pleased with how far we&amp;rsquo;ve come in dropping the old Agile bot (leading to $21 a month savings), and producing a new Ruby agile-bot as part of our Rails monolith that is now messaging like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/wo71jxlx2knvr6m/Screenshot%202017-10-11%2010.31.38.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve added what I hope is a welcoming tone to both the reminder and the event title.  I suspect that the time/date stamp is being added to the event instance title, so that the date is available in views like &amp;ldquo;Previous scrums&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/998m7v4fzmc747h/Screenshot%202017-10-11%2010.33.29.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but it makes no sense in the context of the Slack chat.  We did have one member a bit confused by the new syntax, since the direct links to the hangouts etc. were no longer visible.  Not ideal - perhaps we need a click to join message?  What I&amp;rsquo;d really like to work out is where in the code flow the date/timestamp is getting added to the event instance title &amp;hellip; a little search and I think it&amp;rsquo;s being set in the form that starts the event instance in the event show page, which uses a topic helper in the EventHelper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;topic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;event_schedule&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt; - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;current_occurrence_time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;event_schedule&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now rather than changing that - perhaps I can set it up so that the post to Slack uses the event name and not the event instance title.  That would mean adding more mocks to the slack Service spec - and also highlights the need for acceptance tests that exercise this pathway (and make the high level motivations clear).  If I&amp;rsquo;d got to the computer at 9am maybe - right now I just want to get a quick fix and move on.  Particularly I want to move on to even higher level review for Thursday and Friday, so can I slip this out?  Or will I get distracted by replacing the ActiveRecord models in the SlackService spec with mock_models &amp;hellip; which I do, but then I think, actually perhaps displaying the UTC time and day is kind of useful in our Slack since people are in different timezones and often referring to UTC can be helpful as a kind of baseline.  Hmmm, maybe I should just go for a quick refactoring ticket to scratch my code itch?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also got the dependabot upgrades to work through &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve merged in the bump to rails 4.2.10.  I&amp;rsquo;m wondering if I should just splurge in all the rest that are passing &amp;hellip; well, anyway, I got a chunk of the SlackService spec working with mock_models:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class="n"&gt;context&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'PairProgramming'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="n"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:websiteone_project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mock_model&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;slug: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'websiteone'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:websiteone_hangout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mock_model&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;EventInstance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;title: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'MockEvent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;category: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"PairProgramming"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;hangout_url: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"mock_url"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;user: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;project: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;websiteone_project&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'sends the correct slack message to the correct channels when associated with a project'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:chat_postMessage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;general_channel_post_args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:chat_postMessage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;websiteone_project_channel_post_args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:chat_postMessage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pairing_notifications_channel_post_args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_service&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;post_hangout_notification&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;websiteone_hangout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;gitter_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:no_project_hangout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mock_model&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;EventInstance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;title: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'MockEvent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;category: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"PairProgramming"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;hangout_url: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"mock_url"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;user: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;project: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kp"&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'does not fail when event has no associated project'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:chat_postMessage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;general_channel_post_args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:chat_postMessage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pairing_notifications_channel_post_args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_service&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;post_hangout_notification&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;no_project_hangout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;gitter_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:cs169_project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mock_model&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;slug: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'cs169'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="n"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:cs169_hangout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mock_model&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;EventInstance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;title: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'MockEvent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;category: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"PairProgramming"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;hangout_url: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"mock_url"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;user: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;project: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;cs169_project&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'should ping gitter and slack (but not general) when the project is cs169'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;gitter_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:messages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'56b8bdffe610378809c070cc'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;limit: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;and_return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;([])&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;gitter_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:send_message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'[MockEvent with random](mock_url) is starting NOW!'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"56b8bdffe610378809c070cc"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:chat_postMessage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;cs169_project_channel_post_args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:chat_postMessage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pairing_notifications_channel_post_args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_service&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;post_hangout_notification&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;cs169_hangout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;gitter_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:missing_url_hangout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mock_model&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;EventInstance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;title: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'MockEvent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;category: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"PairProgramming"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;hangout_url: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"  "&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;user: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;user&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'does not post notification if hangout url is blank'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;not_to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:chat_postMessage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_service&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;post_hangout_notification&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;missing_url_hangout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;slack_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;gitter_client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which is kind of an improvement - slightly faster than creating real ActiveRecord models.  Slightly less realistic, so pushing this away from integration and towards unit testing.  Re-arranging deck chairs?  I&amp;rsquo;d love to boil this code down to make it clean and transparent, but perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s something for a pairing session where my pair partner can keep me on the straight and narrow.  Time to jump back up a few levels, starting tomorrow - let&amp;rsquo;s check in on the changes to the &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; page and the flow of how people arrive there.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
