<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>All Good Things ...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/</id>
    <published>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-10T21:54:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="good things" src="/images/good_things.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been daily blogging for a year now.  Working day blogs that is.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging on weekends, or national holidays, or during my vacations.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty consistent.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of days where work was super busy due to the tail end of a design sprint or something, but I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to retro-actively blog and keep it one per work day.  I started blogging in June last year doing a blog on a different platform each day of the week, but fairly soon I fell into a pattern of blogging to our AgileVentures middleman site, and then re-releasing to Medium after I&amp;rsquo;d got a little distance from the blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the purpose of this blog frenzy?  My memory is that it was about trying to communicate more effectively.  I often end up assuming that people understand my thoughts and intentions and it turns out that actually they don&amp;rsquo;t.  Of course why would they?  There are few telepaths around.  I&amp;rsquo;m also a bit of a gabbler and my sense is that it&amp;rsquo;s not super easy to understand what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to communicate.  So blogging, get all the thoughts down in text, provide them in an accessible form for everyone to read, and maybe reduce my need to gabble on and on about things.  Win win, no?  There&amp;rsquo;s also the motivation that blogging at the start of each day is a kind of &amp;ldquo;morning pages&amp;rdquo; activity such as writers use to start off their days and clear their heads.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think writers usually publish their morning brain dump, but I have certainly found the process of starting each day with writing out my thoughts to be reassuring and relaxing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year when I was doing a lot more coding, the blogs tended to be all about the previous day&amp;rsquo;s coding.  As AgileVentures became an official charity and my admin load increased, they have tended to be about prioritization.  Starting the day with a blog is certainly less stressful than starting the day with a review of email and Slack conversations, which will generally lead to many adds to my ever-increasing todo list.  Has the time been well spent?  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had positive reactions to some blogs, but my sense is that the blogs are too long, too stream-of-consciousness, too un-focused to gain much traction.  I think I may have even alienated some with my uncensored and unedited thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was 17 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had trouble just generating text, and from even earlier I was always a talker.  It&amp;rsquo;s like my internal thought wheel is hooked up directly to my mouth, and at will I can hook it up to a pen or a keyboard and just dump my thoughts straight out, for better or for worse.  So I rarely have writer&amp;rsquo;s block, but it leaves me with a different problem.  How to edit the thicket of thoughts and ideas, so as to more effectively communicate them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to the end of a year of blogging prompts thoughts of changing things going forward.  There&amp;rsquo;ve been times in the past when rising early I&amp;rsquo;ve done 3 hours of programming before breakfast.  After recent design sprints I think about doing coding sprints, or other activities that fill the week in different ways.  Should it be one blog a week with the blog being edited and revised each day, so that a single polished blog can be released on Friday?  I guess it all depends on what one wants to achieve, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t the Buddhist in me been trying to follow a path of consecrated action, where one is totally unattached to the outcomes of activities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d have loved my blogs to have provoked more positive responses of &amp;ldquo;yes, let&amp;rsquo;s build a solution to that together &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, although there has been some of that.  What I really would like is for AgileVentures to be a healthy thriving community providing great learning experiences for many, while also helping charitable causes around the world.  The process of reflection over the last year does make me think that we&amp;rsquo;re far too text heavy in many, many parts of our interface with the world.  One of the most attractive ideas for me going forward is that I&amp;rsquo;d spend my blogging time each day focused on a part of the main AgileVentures site, converting it from text heavy to text light and adding images.  I have a hunch that, by doing this in strategic places throughout the site, we could improve the sign up rates, the number of members joining projects and the numbers signing up for Premium subscriptions, the source of our financial sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a feeling I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to shake the blogging habit.  The process has become too solidly part of my daily routine.  The thing that actually gets me started and ready to work in the mornings.  So, anyhow, starting tomorrow, blogs that focus on parts of the main AgileVentures site.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to work through it one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog released early for inclusion in our July newsletter, earlier blogs are all in draft form in GitHub and will be on this site soon&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Private Design Sprint Day Three</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/29/private-design-sprint-day-three/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/29/private-design-sprint-day-three/</id>
    <published>2017-06-29T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-22T21:21:28+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m heading into London on the train for day 4 as we have a location switch for the last two days.  The last three days we&amp;rsquo;ve been in a somewhat remote location which would be difficult for testers to reach, so the last two days are in central London.  Yesterday (day 3) involved the usual art museum, heat maps and speed critiques of our three different prototype designs.  Given there were only three of us, there was plenty of time to discuss them, reflect on them and vote on them.  By lunch we&amp;rsquo;d ended up with most of the votes on my own design, and there seemed agreement that we were all pretty much on the same page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch we started storyboarding and it was clear that there was some confusion.  There was the issue of the extent to which our small prototype would reflect the operation of the rest of the site.  It had seemed that we had agreed on a particular prototyping approach by selecting a particular prototype, but there was concern from one member that what we prototyped wouldn&amp;rsquo;t reflect the overall site experience.  As we went back and forth, the terms &amp;ldquo;press-pack&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;trailer&amp;rdquo; floated out.  It came down to distinguishing between sites where the experience before you signed in reflected what you got once you were signed up, and those where that wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case.  Both valid approaches and their effectiveness dependent on the nature of your target demographic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a fairly long debate, but ultimately we settled on the prototype that was largely as I had envisioned.  Offering the user a small sense of one particular aspect of the site experience and seeing how they would react to that and to the idea that they&amp;rsquo;d need to sign up (and pay) to access more.  Ultimately we had our storyboard and agreement on our storyboard, and hopefully a shared understanding about what we would be achieving over the next two days.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Private Design Sprint Day Two</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/28/private-design-sprint-day-two/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/28/private-design-sprint-day-two/</id>
    <published>2017-06-28T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-21T21:31:32+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day two of our design sprint was a slightly calmer affair.  One member had left us since they couldn&amp;rsquo;t stay the whole week, so we were down to three on the sprint team.  I&amp;rsquo;d also come down with a head cold that was making me move and talk slower; probably a good thing for all concerned, but not very pleasant for me.  We spent the morning doing lightning demos, and then the afternoon sketching interface designs, &amp;ldquo;working alone together&amp;rdquo; as they say in the sprint book.  I got my interface sketch done fairly quickly and decided to move on to sorting out the screening survey and putting up an ad on Craigslist and Indeed to recruit testers for Friday.  I&amp;rsquo;ve woken up this morning to see that four people have applied so far, and probably there&amp;rsquo;s only one that meets our testing criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It occurs to me that recruiting people who have an hour free during the middle of a work day on Friday creates its own bias, in that one is unlikely to get lots of people who are in full time employment.  Challenging if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to test that demographic.  That&amp;rsquo;s not particularly the demographic we are looking for in this design sprint, but it seems inevitable that there&amp;rsquo;s some degree of skew there.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll have to supplement this week by distributing the ad through some of my personal networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to judge day two of the sprint, as we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen each other&amp;rsquo;s sketches yet; we&amp;rsquo;ll have to see if three is too small a number.  Certainly we had no shortage of lightning demos, and there was lots to learn from looking through all the different sites that the team members suggested.  Today we&amp;rsquo;ll be reviewing those sketch ideas and coming up with a storyboard for the prototype that we need to build on Thursday.  I wonder if I got into problem solving mode too early on day one, as my sketch is not wildly dissimilar from some of the components I was sketching on the map on Monday.  I guess rather than interface elements it would have been better to map interactions, drawing the person interacting with the computer, or talking to another person.  We&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, we&amp;rsquo;re changing location after today.  For logistical reasons we&amp;rsquo;re in one location Mon/Tues/Wed and then a different location Thu/Fri.  I&amp;rsquo;m quite pleased as Thu/Fri I&amp;rsquo;ll be closer to home, and I&amp;rsquo;m not particularly enjoying my current hotel-bound cold.  The cold is also making it difficult for me to focus on administrative matters that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to juggle around the design sprint, which pretty much blocks out the sun while it is running.  The nice thing about having a physical space and these table top flip charts is you can draw out large and then take them off and stick them on the wall, so we have the different sketches from our lightning demos etc. covering the walls of the room that we&amp;rsquo;re working in.  Perhaps ideally we&amp;rsquo;d still have these up on Thursday as we work on our prototype, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem completely critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing the AV design sprint online I think it&amp;rsquo;s quite important to have multiple monitors so that one can put up the different digital documents in multiple locations and use one&amp;rsquo;s physical space management skills, but so many people don&amp;rsquo;t seem to have a second or third monitor &amp;hellip; anyway, fascinating to contrast the online and in-person sprint.  There&amp;rsquo;s certainly an aspect of this that feels very marketing orientated, but I guess for any organisation to be successful it has to have the right communication &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Private Design Sprint Day One</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/27/private-design-sprint-day-one/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/27/private-design-sprint-day-one/</id>
    <published>2017-06-27T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-20T20:01:45+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in the Premier Inn restaurant again after day one of the sprint.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also come down with a cold which is not much fun.  Don&amp;rsquo;t really have time to write a blog, as I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be updating part 2 of the MOOC, but I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just take a few minutes to get down some reflections on yesterday&amp;rsquo;s day one of the design sprint.  We had four of us in person in a lovely room with an ocean view, and we used a couple of flipboard markers and whiteboard rolls (that stick on windows and walls and allow you to draw on them).  It seemed to go pretty well.  This was probably the closest I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten so far to a day one of Design Sprint as intended, with the exception that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have any expert interviews joining us, for one logistic reason and another.  We improvised there by taking turns to be experts and have each of us present the concepts to the rest of the group, and then all ask questions of the &amp;ldquo;expert&amp;rdquo;.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think we got the full benefit of outside input, but there was definitely some benefit derived from re-articulation of the idea from different perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first map we made was maybe too detailed.  I was almost drawing interface elements, and one of the other team members did a revised simpler map.  The maps in the book are really simple, but they look simplified for the purpose of the book compared with the whiteboards I&amp;rsquo;ve glimpsed in the videos from Google, but Pat did seem to criticise our overly complex map from the AV design sprint; so perhaps this is a pattern of poor behaviour on my part.  Looking back I think it might have been more effective to avoid interface elements completely and focus on interactions; drawing person at computer, person talking to other person as the elements of the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the slide deck from the GV site to introduce the sprint in the morning and that seemed to work quite well.  Everyone seemed happy with me as the facilitator and the main client being the decider.  My handwriting for the sprint questions was not outstanding, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how powerful they were for the rest of the sprint.  I guess they were re-articulated by the presenters in the afternoon.  Interestingly people started writing &amp;ldquo;how we might fail&amp;rdquo; questions on post-it notes and there was a process of integration as I re-wrote them.  The others didn&amp;rsquo;t join in the initial map drawing in the way that the AV folks did, collaborating in the drawing of the online map.  I did my best to map out what they were talking about, and it was great that they re-drew the map in simpler form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was interesting to see outbreaks of what might be called &amp;ldquo;argumentative&amp;rdquo; behaviour during the day.  Not in a negative sense, but more in a point and counterpoint, and point and counterpoint, that goes round and round.  I know I&amp;rsquo;ve been super guilty of this in the past, and it&amp;rsquo;s interesting being a facilitator and working out how to move on from those areas.  From one perspective when both people have made their points, the key thing is to record the positions and allow the process to move on to generate more ideas.  That can be derailed when both parties feel the need to explain their position further, falling into a kind of &amp;ldquo;No, but &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; where effectively the same point (with minor nuances) gets repeated.  Is it partly about having the last word.  Why do I (and many others) want that last word so much?  I&amp;rsquo;ve often felt that if someone makes a statement that I feel is incorrect, that if I don&amp;rsquo;t make the counterpoint then that&amp;rsquo;s the statement that&amp;rsquo;s being accepted by the room.  I guess I should trust people better that they won&amp;rsquo;t think just because someone said something last that it&amp;rsquo;s being accepted as truth.  Still it&amp;rsquo;s a difficult character flaw to let go of.  If someone makes a point and you have no comeback then it can seem like you are conceding the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fascinating to look at it from a third person point of view.  I can see how others can get frustrated with the debate where they feel they&amp;rsquo;ve heard both points of view in painful detail and just want to move on.   And it&amp;rsquo;s clear how a debate can block the floor and prevent other issues being raised, other ideas being heard &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Private Design Sprint Day Minus One</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/26/private-design-sprint-day-minus-one-blog/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/26/private-design-sprint-day-minus-one-blog/</id>
    <published>2017-06-26T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-19T20:53:42+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I find myself in a Premier Inn in Felixstowe on the west coast of the UK to run a design sprint for a private client. I&amp;rsquo;ve just been adapting my morning schedule to the slight change in location.  Jog along the front listening to SoftSkillsAudio podcast.  Get distracted on LinkedIn trying to contact the show&amp;rsquo;s hosts to get my skill recommendation for &amp;ldquo;Artisanal Egg Scrambling&amp;rdquo; for being their new unpaid marketing intern.  Getting caught up with Slack and Email (before blogging!) in the hotel restaurant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got another 45 minutes before going off for this private in person sprint, which I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to blog about more than tangentially since I have signed an NDA (Non-Disclosure Agreement).  Hopefully I should be able to provide some general insights into the design sprint process face to face versus online, in comparison with the fully online sprint with AgileVentures the week before last.  The private project seems reasonably stimulating, but will be fully closed source for the forseeable future.  In some ways it&amp;rsquo;s frustrating to be taken away from my focus on AgileVentures.  The NHS project took me away from AV too, but at least it was open source and something I could share with the Premium members; although to be honest there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a huge rush of people to get involved, and/or it wasn&amp;rsquo;t accessible because I was doing lots of face to face meetings that were not completely digitised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically this is also the week where I&amp;rsquo;m working out the governance framework to allow the current AV income from the NHS project and subscriptions to actually cover my basic living expenses.  I&amp;rsquo;m right up against the limit on my bank account and about to go overdrawn if I don&amp;rsquo;t get that sorted by the end of the week.  If that is all sorted, things are basically covered, but I&amp;rsquo;ll still need extra, like this private design sprint, in order to cover luxuries like taking my children to see their grandparents in Japan this summer and to pay for their music lessons, fix up the house, take my wife away for our anniversary etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are new pull-requests in on the WebSiteOne and LocalSupport projects; neither of them from Premium members.  I do wonder if we don&amp;rsquo;t need a complete revamp of our AgileVentures Premium packages, and if we even need some sort of structured decision making process for AgileVentures, even if it&amp;rsquo;s just a mechanism to allow people to hear about any changes we make.  Despite being distracted by Adobe Illustrator on the way up to Felixstowe, I did manage to pull out the set of Premium benefits and do a little translation into questions that might relate to our target demographic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Premium&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RubyMine/WebStorm IDE license&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Private support channels (jobs, tech tests, professional develop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional code review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eligibility for paid projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supporting the AV mission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support on SO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CodeSchool NonProfit Discount&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Related Questions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to find great developer jobs? Get help on the job search process?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to ace technical tests required to get interviews?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to accelerate your professional development?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to improve your coding and development skills?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to put paid coding projects on your resume?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to make the world the better place?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to feel confident asking technical questions online?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to get discounts on important software and services for developers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Premium Mob&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mob programming sessions with an assigned AV Mentor each week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional Development Planning Support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free accesss to Udemy Complete Elixir &amp;amp; Phoenix Bootcamp course (usual price $50)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free accesss to Udemy React Redux course (usual price $180)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25% discount on &amp;ldquo;Effective Testing with RSpec 3&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10% discount on Upcase membership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Related Questions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to level up on the latest hot technologies like Elixir and React?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to get a personalised professional development plan to achieve your goals?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to master mob programming online?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Premium F2F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One hour of pair programming time with an AV Mentor on an AV project each month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voting rights in AV general meetings &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Related Questions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want personalised individual support to improve your coding and pairing skills?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to influence the future direction of the AgileVentures charity?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a funny trade off between having nothing and when something is already existing.  Before Premium existed I could create anything in my mind and put it out there.  And I&amp;rsquo;ve also been tweaking it since, but we end up with this state where different people have different impressions of what Premium is, based on when they most recently read about it, how they interpreted the words through their own personal filters, and what sorts of interactions they&amp;rsquo;ve had over time.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then if you start making changes, it takes time for them to propagate into people&amp;rsquo;s understanding.  Depending on how they hear about it, some people might be frustrated that things are changing out from underneath them.  In the regular AV team I think there&amp;rsquo;s some agreement that how we present the Premium benefits should change.  It&amp;rsquo;s easy to change the text, and I could just do it bang bang, but once something&amp;rsquo;s out there frequent change can be disconcerting.  Perhaps the better approach is softly, softly - try and get a proportion of the existing Premium members to answer a survey with questions like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which Premium benefit do you value the most?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which Premium benefit is of least value to you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What additional Premium benefits would you like to see?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How likely would you be to recommend AV Premium to a friend (scale 1-10)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How happy are you with the Premium benefits package?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and maybe others that the rest of the team can think of.  The survey would play a dual role in terms of soliciting input to better help us evolve the Premium packages, and also letting people know about impending changes.  I did do a &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/forms/ll5lfMu1PCtgDRW63"&gt;survey of AV members last year&lt;/a&gt; before we even had Premium - I should share that with the marketing team.  Perhaps we could send out a revised version as part of the newsletter?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s definitely time to get another read there, and also a read from those who&amp;rsquo;ve signed up for Premium as we evolve the next version.  Perhaps the private design sprint will help focus my mind on getting these things done &amp;hellip;?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Prioritization Motivation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/23/prioritization-motivation/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/23/prioritization-motivation/</id>
    <published>2017-06-23T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-18T20:53:58+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="prioritization" src="/images/prioritization.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prioritization and motivation is complicated.  Each day I&amp;rsquo;m sitting down and trying to have myself focus on the things that will actually generate revenue.  That said there are things that I&amp;rsquo;m motivated to do (or have fallen into a pattern of doing) that are several steps removed from any revenue generation.  Some things are a pattern that I at least partially enjoy, e.g. blogging, publishing blogs, jogging, listening to podcasts, preparing Japanese language tests for my kids.  Doing them makes me feel centered and organised, but none of them are likely to lead to any revenue generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The late night on Wednesday put paid to any jogging and podcast-listening on Thursday morning.  I thought I&amp;rsquo;d recover for Friday, but then I ended up staying up late after my regular late night blog publishing.  The thing that caught me was fixing up the InVision app that we&amp;rsquo;d created as part of the design sprint so that it would run on GitHub pages.  You can see it there now at &lt;a href="http://why.agileventures.org"&gt;http://why.agileventures.org&lt;/a&gt;.  We&amp;rsquo;d been redirecting the URL to the InvisionApp itself, but in the marketing meeting yesterday Lara raised the issue that Google Adwords might have a problem with the redirection and it might raise an issue of trust with our users.  She asked if we couldn&amp;rsquo;t export the app, but over lunch I googled and discovered that we could export a zip of the app in order to run it offline.  I&amp;rsquo;d quickly uploaded the app into the GitHub pages site &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/why"&gt;https://github.com/AgileVentures/why&lt;/a&gt; and saw that we could host it directly, so no need to redirect away from the &lt;a href="http://why.agileventures.org"&gt;http://why.agileventures.org&lt;/a&gt; domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great, but a half an hour of kicking things about at the end of the day hadn&amp;rsquo;t resolved one part of the app that didn&amp;rsquo;t work.  The final &amp;ldquo;sign up&amp;rdquo; button external link to the main AgileVentures sign up page at &lt;a href="https://www.agileventures.org/users/sign_up"&gt;https://www.agileventures.org/users/sign_up&lt;/a&gt; was attempting to load the following URL &lt;code&gt;/redirect?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.agileventures.org%2Fusers%2Fsign_up&lt;/code&gt;, which is presumably an endpoint on the InVision app, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist in our GitHub Pages app.  I tried a few tricks to get round this, such as just adding a file called &lt;code&gt;redirect&lt;/code&gt; with the contents &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&amp;quot;refresh&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;0; url=https://www.agileventures.org/users/sign_up&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.  That didn&amp;rsquo;t quite work, with clicking the sign up link leading to the browser downloading a file rather than redirecting.  The problem was that GitHub pages (Jekyll) wasn&amp;rsquo;t serving the file with the correct media type.  I tried using &lt;code&gt;redirect.html&lt;/code&gt; and some under the hood jekyll redirection, but it still suffered from the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I emailed InVision support and GitHub support, and InVision came back saying that the downloaded app didn&amp;rsquo;t support the full functionality, and GitHub were asking for clarification on what I was trying to achieve.  I tried MarvelApp (an Invision competitor) and saw that I could quickly recreate the app there, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t download without upgrading.  So I&amp;rsquo;d kind of given up for the time being, but after my late night blog publishing session I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help tinkering.  The late night blog publishing session is also a strange prioritization/motivation conundrum.  In days gone by I used to try and publish the previous days blog after having just written the new days one, i.e. in the morning each day.  That had the advantage of keeping all the blog action within my working day, but I was finding that having written one blog I was struggling to do another blog related activity, and the blog publishing was being put off and forgotten.  Then I started doing the publishing component late in the evening, often in parallel with giving my eldest son a little time on his iPad before I read him a story.  Then I decided it wasn&amp;rsquo;t so good for my eldest boy to be getting that iPad stimulation before bed (all the boys get 20 minutes iPad in the morning if they&amp;rsquo;ve finished getting completely ready), and so I ended up shifting to doing the blog publishing after all the boys were asleep, i.e. in my own winding time before going to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reasonably efficient, but sometimes I am too tired to get to it, and on occasion I get distracted because I&amp;rsquo;ve opened up Slack to post my blog, or like last night where just thinking about work brings me back to a problem like this redirection issue.  As it happens, another thirty minutes of fiddling fixed things up.  The problem seems to be an issue in the Jekyll redirection syntax.  I&amp;rsquo;d been experimenting with Jekyll syntax in &lt;code&gt;redirect.html&lt;/code&gt; like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight yaml"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nn"&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;redirect_from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="pi"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;/redirect&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;redirect_to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="pi"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;https://www.agileventures.org/users/sign_up&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nn"&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but it seems that trailing slashes are necessary to ensure that Jekyll serves things in the right media type, so the following worked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight yaml"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nn"&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;redirect_from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="pi"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;/redirect/&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;redirect_to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="pi"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;https://www.agileventures.org/users/sign_up/&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nn"&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was finding issues like &lt;a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-redirect-from/issues/37"&gt;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-redirect-from/issues/37&lt;/a&gt; that helped me fix things up.  So now, whatever the shortcomings of the prototype app, we have all the functionality working at &lt;a href="http://why.agileventures.org"&gt;http://why.agileventures.org&lt;/a&gt;.  The question now was whether this was good enough to start testing, which prompted a little discussion on Slack:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam Joseph:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;question is whether this is good enough to start testing (@joaopereira @mtc2013 @mlindsey @lara-t)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federico:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@tansaku by “this” you mean what’s up now at http://why.agileventures.org ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam Joseph:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;right - I downloaded the invisionapp and hosted it on github pages so the user stays on why.agileventures.org the whole time - that was the concern that @lara-t raised in the meeting - clearly the app could still be improved in many ways - I know you don&amp;rsquo;t like the font, the buttons could be more clickable etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federico:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the button colors, all the tester feedback. :grimacing:
It’s good enough to test, but it’s serving one purpose: a larger sample size &lt;em&gt;test&lt;/em&gt; of the prototype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam Joseph: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally the design sprint prototype is supposed to be thrown away, and a better one rebuilt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we are operating on a shoestring and in principle the content test could redirect 10% of our clickthroughs to why.av.org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we can increase as we improve it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at the moment our clickthroughs are not driving any revenue so in principle there&amp;rsquo;s nothing too much to lose &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federico:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’ll just be additional data to reinforce the verbal feedback from the testers. &lt;em&gt;That’s obviously appealing. I’m not opposed to it.&lt;/em&gt; I’m excited, however, to help build a &lt;em&gt;slick coded version, that takes into account the tester feedback. Please let me know when that starts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think why.av.org looks pretty good now and we should start 50/50 A/B test whenever @lara-t is able to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lara:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@here great job, I will get everything setup this weekend for AdWords A/B Testing. Well done everyone I really love the new page :slightly&lt;em&gt;smiling&lt;/em&gt;face:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there we go.  I failed to get up for my jog or podcast listening this morning :-( I got my kids Japanese tests written up, and I&amp;rsquo;m over time on my blogging.  Funny thing is about the moment that motivation seizes you.  It seized me several times yesterday trying to get this fixed up.  It&amp;rsquo;s slowly running out now as I spend too long on this blog and my motivation to make all the points I was originally thinking about gradually drains away.  I stopped to email GitHub to tell them how I solved the issue and how their redirection documentation needs updating.  I was trying to make a point about motivation and prioritization.  There are at least two items I should get to, now, that directly relate to getting paid and there&amp;rsquo;s the MOOV/AV102 emails I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting off all week.  I used to be motivated to do them and now &amp;hellip; I guess I&amp;rsquo;ve got sick of the little dance I do to get the old updates from the previous MOOC and put them into the new one.  There&amp;rsquo;s a fiddly updating of the links and no particular positive feedback - as opposed to the likes I get when I tweet about other people&amp;rsquo;s podcasts &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the thing I&amp;rsquo;m stuck on is that, given that I can&amp;rsquo;t automate these MOOC postings (due to the way that edX works), I should delegate them off to someone, but I recoil at the process of trying to get someone to understand how to do it, and that it will probably be screwed up a couple of times before it&amp;rsquo;s done right.  And then there&amp;rsquo;s the thought that we won&amp;rsquo;t even have the need for these emailings once the course goes self paced (from fall?).  Or maybe we will - or maybe no one cares if these things get sent or not.  We&amp;rsquo;re not measuring the impact of doing them or not - I&amp;rsquo;m just sending them because if I was doing a course I&amp;rsquo;d like to get a reminder when new material and assignments are released &amp;hellip; In previous runs I was in a solid pattern of getting the emails out and now I&amp;rsquo;m all over the place &amp;hellip; partly it&amp;rsquo;s my faltering motivation and also trying to prioritize things that have a more direct connection to revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motivation and prioritization.  Right, must finish up blog, leave the A/B testing to Lara and make sure that I get they key revenue generating work done this AM (mainly paperwork), get those MOOC posts out, and keep going with balancing what I have motivation for in the moment, and what really has to get done to pay the bills &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
