<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>All Good Things ...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/04/all-good-things/</id>
    <published>2017-07-04T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-10T21:54:43+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="good things" src="/images/good_things.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been daily blogging for a year now.  Working day blogs that is.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging on weekends, or national holidays, or during my vacations.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty consistent.  I think there&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of days where work was super busy due to the tail end of a design sprint or something, but I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to retro-actively blog and keep it one per work day.  I started blogging in June last year doing a blog on a different platform each day of the week, but fairly soon I fell into a pattern of blogging to our AgileVentures middleman site, and then re-releasing to Medium after I&amp;rsquo;d got a little distance from the blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the purpose of this blog frenzy?  My memory is that it was about trying to communicate more effectively.  I often end up assuming that people understand my thoughts and intentions and it turns out that actually they don&amp;rsquo;t.  Of course why would they?  There are few telepaths around.  I&amp;rsquo;m also a bit of a gabbler and my sense is that it&amp;rsquo;s not super easy to understand what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to communicate.  So blogging, get all the thoughts down in text, provide them in an accessible form for everyone to read, and maybe reduce my need to gabble on and on about things.  Win win, no?  There&amp;rsquo;s also the motivation that blogging at the start of each day is a kind of &amp;ldquo;morning pages&amp;rdquo; activity such as writers use to start off their days and clear their heads.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think writers usually publish their morning brain dump, but I have certainly found the process of starting each day with writing out my thoughts to be reassuring and relaxing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year when I was doing a lot more coding, the blogs tended to be all about the previous day&amp;rsquo;s coding.  As AgileVentures became an official charity and my admin load increased, they have tended to be about prioritization.  Starting the day with a blog is certainly less stressful than starting the day with a review of email and Slack conversations, which will generally lead to many adds to my ever-increasing todo list.  Has the time been well spent?  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had positive reactions to some blogs, but my sense is that the blogs are too long, too stream-of-consciousness, too un-focused to gain much traction.  I think I may have even alienated some with my uncensored and unedited thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was 17 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really had trouble just generating text, and from even earlier I was always a talker.  It&amp;rsquo;s like my internal thought wheel is hooked up directly to my mouth, and at will I can hook it up to a pen or a keyboard and just dump my thoughts straight out, for better or for worse.  So I rarely have writer&amp;rsquo;s block, but it leaves me with a different problem.  How to edit the thicket of thoughts and ideas, so as to more effectively communicate them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to the end of a year of blogging prompts thoughts of changing things going forward.  There&amp;rsquo;ve been times in the past when rising early I&amp;rsquo;ve done 3 hours of programming before breakfast.  After recent design sprints I think about doing coding sprints, or other activities that fill the week in different ways.  Should it be one blog a week with the blog being edited and revised each day, so that a single polished blog can be released on Friday?  I guess it all depends on what one wants to achieve, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t the Buddhist in me been trying to follow a path of consecrated action, where one is totally unattached to the outcomes of activities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d have loved my blogs to have provoked more positive responses of &amp;ldquo;yes, let&amp;rsquo;s build a solution to that together &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, although there has been some of that.  What I really would like is for AgileVentures to be a healthy thriving community providing great learning experiences for many, while also helping charitable causes around the world.  The process of reflection over the last year does make me think that we&amp;rsquo;re far too text heavy in many, many parts of our interface with the world.  One of the most attractive ideas for me going forward is that I&amp;rsquo;d spend my blogging time each day focused on a part of the main AgileVentures site, converting it from text heavy to text light and adding images.  I have a hunch that, by doing this in strategic places throughout the site, we could improve the sign up rates, the number of members joining projects and the numbers signing up for Premium subscriptions, the source of our financial sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a feeling I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to shake the blogging habit.  The process has become too solidly part of my daily routine.  The thing that actually gets me started and ready to work in the mornings.  So, anyhow, starting tomorrow, blogs that focus on parts of the main AgileVentures site.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to work through it one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. this blog released early for inclusion in our July newsletter, earlier blogs are all in draft form in GitHub and will be on this site soon&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Design Sprint Aftermath</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/21/av-design-sprint-aftermath/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/21/av-design-sprint-aftermath/</id>
    <published>2017-06-21T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-14T21:49:56+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been looking forward to a normal week following the AV design sprint, getting back to having standups and project meetings.  Frustratingly Monday was scattered with problems with hangouts that seemed to be specific to me.  The &amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum went okay, but I was unable to participate in the Monday marketing meeting due to my computer slowing to a crawl when I was running hangouts.  There was so much to discuss in the marketing meeting and I was effectively excluded on technology grounds.  Matt, Federico and Michael all tried to help me get to the bottom of it later in the day.  We thought we&amp;rsquo;d tracked it down to either the LAN cable or thunderbolt monitor as things seemed to improve when I switched to Wifi on my backup laptop.  However, broadband speed tests were showing the same results on both computers.  I managed normal participation in the AV community meeting using my backup laptop on the Wifi. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I swapped out one LAN cable and it seemed like my main laptop improved in hangouts, but then they got worse and Wifi didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to help.  The following day I phoned Apple and got advice to upgrade to OSX Sierra, which I reluctantly did.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been frustrated with Apple upgrades before, particularly since you can&amp;rsquo;t back out of them.  I upgraded to Sierra over lunch yesterday and the computer seems to be working okay, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried some of the trickier coding things that involve libraries installed via brew.   The &amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum was just about manageable, but I was carefully monitoring my CPU&amp;rsquo;s and noticing that things went a bit nuts occasionally with all eight cores maxing out.  I tried to switch to my backup computer with Wifi (that had worked for the AV community meeting) but the hangout wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even finish loading.  I switched off my video on the main computer and watched the CPUs come back under control, and was able to complete the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s super frustrating that when a hangout related CPU max out occurs that I can hardly do anything else.  I can&amp;rsquo;t navigate in Slack, can&amp;rsquo;t get other web pages to load.  My ability to function resolves around the ability to paste people links about things they are talking about in the hangout.  Following the scrum I ran a couple of NHS HLP hangouts.  Michael was in both.  We managed okay, but I definitely noticed illustrator being sluggish in the second one.  It really makes me thing we need an open source alternative to hangouts to be able to get to the bottom of these kinds of problems.  If I had the spare cash I&amp;rsquo;d love to just buy a new MacBookPro and exlude exotic hardware failures from the equation, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really have that luxury at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling my own mental CPUs thrashing trying to work out what to focus on each day.  My mood had been dipping but I found myself buoyed yesterday as we managed to identify the font that had been used in the AgileVentures logo, import that and create a &amp;ldquo;customized by AgileVentures&amp;rdquo; logo for the NHS HLP wiki site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="customized by AgileVentures" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/1kekg96rkndea64/customized-by-agileventures-176wide.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d been putting off working on this, but as part of the design sprint we&amp;rsquo;d been using an &lt;a href="https://www.fontsquirrel.com/matcherator"&gt;online font matching tool&lt;/a&gt; and we used the same technique to identify the AgileVentures logo font as &lt;a href="https://www.fontsquirrel.com/fonts/bree-serif"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bree Serif Regular&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.  It&amp;rsquo;s available for free, so I downloaded and installed on my newly upgrade OSX Sierra running mac, and the font became available in Illustrator.  A bit of playing around the gradients made it look similar enough to the existing &amp;ldquo;powered by MediaWiki&amp;rdquo; button to have it not look too out of place, and I found that adding these footer icons is a &lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Manual:$wgFooterIcons#Site_customization"&gt;trivial config operation&lt;/a&gt; in MediaWiki.  Still frustraing that the hangout that allowed me to share and record all of this was slowing the process of experimenting with Illustrator.  I really prefer to just bang on things and look stuff up on Google rather than taking courses and reading documentation &amp;hellip; is that bad?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s more I could keep tweaking, but diminishing returns?  At least with the gradients created for that &amp;ldquo;customized by agileventures&amp;rdquo; logo could be used to make the rounded rectangles in the Design Sprint&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Agile Journey&amp;rdquo; prototype more &amp;ldquo;clickable&amp;rdquo; looking.  That feels like nice cross-fertilization.  Moving forward I guess I just keep monitoring my CPU loads and see if we can&amp;rsquo;t use things like &lt;a href="https://github.com/muaz-khan/WebRTC-Experiment"&gt;https://github.com/muaz-khan/WebRTC-Experiment&lt;/a&gt; to create some transparent open source pairing/meeting solution where anyone who&amp;rsquo;s interested can work on fixing issues with performance rather than closed source Google offerings.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Design Sprint Day Five</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/20/av-design-sprint-day-five/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/20/av-design-sprint-day-five/</id>
    <published>2017-06-20T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-13T22:01:16+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Friday morning was fairly frantic.  I&amp;rsquo;d gone to sleep thinking that the last day testing of the design sprint had been postponed, and woke to find we were &amp;ldquo;game on&amp;rdquo; with testers booked into slots and a half-finished prototype that needed completing by noon my time.  Quick AgileVentures trustee meeting out of the way and I was working away in illustrator to finish the rest of the interactive popups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was getting the hang of illustrator layers and didn&amp;rsquo;t have too much trouble extracting the rest of the images we had downloaded from ShutterStock and getting things set up.  What was immediately clear was that we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get away with a background image with popups being displayed over the top.  There was a noticeable delay in that background loading so what we had was a sequence of main images like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="all screens from the prototype" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/uglnko00ybpwalu/Screenshot%202017-06-20%2009.25.02.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and used InVision hotspots to link them together so that it appeared that you got a popup when you clicked on the relevant part of the image.  We were ready with time to spare and I was able to review the videos of the GV test sessions and re-read the sections of the design sprint book that outline a five-act interview, which we modified ever so slightly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Friendly welcome: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Welcome the customer and put him or her at ease. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain that you’re looking for candid feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Context questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start with easy small talk, then transition to questions about the topic you’re trying to learn about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduce the prototype:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remind the customer that some things might not work, and that you’re not testing him or her. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask the customer to think aloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tasks and nudges: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch the customer figure out the prototype on his or her own. Start with a simple nudge. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask follow-up questions to help the customer think aloud.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Debrief:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask questions that prompt the customer to summarize. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thank the customer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ask about sharing video for training and education purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;say gift card will be taken care of by colleague&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d been volunteered as the interviewer, and while Matt ran a separate hangout for the rest of the team, I set up individual hangouts for the testers so we could record and stream separately.  Federico was working furiously in the background managing the screening spreadsheet to identify individuals in the target demographic.  Basically it all went off pretty well.  One individual tester was a no show, and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get any backups in time, so we only had four sessions.  The second tester found the cursor key navigation was still on so we turned that off.  Testers one and three were from a very similar background, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t ideal from the point of view of getting a diverse range of input on the prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had quite a long chat with each individual about their background, goals, hopes and dreams; before ultimately segueing into introducing the prototype.  Although, by the end I was getting tired and not filling the full hour.  The patterns that emerged from these sessions was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Negatives&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some terminology was confusing, e.g. MOOC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AV&amp;rsquo;s purpose somewhat unclear. NGO? Learning/mentoring?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prototype sections not obviously clickable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too much text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unclear who owns code - is this open source?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unclear if meetings online or in person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Neutrals&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testers wanted to know how to share with friends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Positives&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concept and social aspect appreciated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images and roadmap appreciated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the really solid takeaways were how people seemed to really appreciate the visualization of the journey and the images and how the text needed to be both shortened and tightened up.  We were pretty shattered after over 30 hours in hangouts for this online design sprint, and ended up reviewing the next steps in our AV Community meeting the following Monday.  Some possible follow up actions included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Releasing a static site with the interactive infographic that points to our main site on the sign up link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjust the landing page of our site to better reflect the journey concept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start creating a new main site perhaps in new tech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the community meeting I asked everyone to suggest what they thought was the highest priority.  Michael&amp;rsquo;s was that we get a static site up (even just the InVision site) and A/B test the impact on signups via Google AdWords.  The measurement component of this really appealed to me, and so this morning I snapped to it by setting up a GitHub Pages account and having that redirect to the InVision app.  I set up http://why.agileventures.org to point to that and the sign up button now goes to our main site.  The annoying things are the InVision URL showing as well as their loading screen.  In principle we could put image maps directly into our GitHub pages site &amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think either way the design sprint has weened me off large amounts of text and addicted me to small amounts of text with images.  Will be interesting to see if we can get any substantive change in signups - stay tuned to this blog to find out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vVwO94ae96w"&gt;Day five video, part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BM7A-SBiFqk"&gt;Day five video, part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/Uao3p4k6qs0"&gt;AV community meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Design Sprint Day Four</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/19/av-design-sprint-day-four/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/19/av-design-sprint-day-four/</id>
    <published>2017-06-19T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-12T21:56:06+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I was about to write up the events of our day four design sprint on Friday morning, when it was suddenly all hands on deck.  Actually I had been anticipating a busy morning.  When we had finished the design sprint regular hours on Thursday we had a partially working prototype and I was the person with illustrator installed that could get the rest of the components working.  In the background Federico had put together an advert and screening questionnaire that he put out on Craigslist in a number of cities in order recruit testers for Friday.  However, late Thursday it was looking like we didn&amp;rsquo;t have anyone from the target demographic in those that were applying to be testers.  As I went to sleep on Thursday Federico and I were agreeing we might need to put the testing off to the following week; however, when I woke up we&amp;rsquo;d had another 150 applications from posting the ad on the Indeed network and we had a handful of people in the target demographic.  Overnight Michael had made the decision to push ahead with testing to complete the design sprint within the week as intended.  It was a good call, but it was also relying on my completing the prototype in my Friday early hours.  I had said that I&amp;rsquo;d be able to do that, and I still was, but it meant blogging and other station keeping went out the window, particularly since I&amp;rsquo;d scheduled an important trustee meeting.  That meeting out of the way, I got down to finishing the prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having had the full day of testing on Friday and a camp over the weekend I&amp;rsquo;m struggling to remember how we got to where we did on the end of Thursday.  Fortunately our Google doc for the day reminds me; we started off comparing prototyping tools, specifically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SquareSpace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keynote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Middleman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we discussed, it became clear that Keynote wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to work since we were testing remotely and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t assume that we could get keynote running on the user&amp;rsquo;s remote system in the fashion necessary.  Middleman was an option if we had form heavy interactions, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t, and if possible we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to burn time coding.  Matt and I had some experience with InVision, and I had installed Adobe Illustrator and checked that we could use it to take apart eps files that were available for sale on Shutterstock and others.  I&amp;rsquo;d tried Sketch and Inkscape and a few others and hadn&amp;rsquo;t quite got the ability to take apart stock graphics in the way that we&amp;rsquo;d need.  Michael had some limited experience with SquareSpace and Lokesh even more limited with Wix.  I suggested that they look at those two respectively while Matt looked at InVision and I focused on Illustrator.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael made some progress with SquareSpace, but it was unclear if we could easily get an image map set up.  Lokesh made good progress with Wix, but it seemed like he couldn&amp;rsquo;t immediately lock click-through elements to part of a background image.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure we could have achieved some version of our imagined infographic with each system, but it was a question of how quickly we could get a relatively professional looking system into place.  We decided to go with Illustrator/Invision and Lokesh/Michael switched to image search.  Michael found another image on ShutterStock that he felt captured more of the ethos of his original design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="infographic ecology concept design landscape" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/vg8oncdpeez1af9/Screenshot%202017-06-19%2009.41.51.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d managed to wrangle it into illustrator, and get some alternate text in there that we could get to go operate like a popup in InVision using their hotspot tool.  We pretty much failed to follow the later script of the Thursday in that we didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to do a trial run or work up an interview script.  As the day drew to a close Michael and Matt had found other &amp;ldquo;flat style&amp;rdquo; images to illustrate different parts of the journey, and I&amp;rsquo;d got the first one in a pop up that could be &amp;ldquo;clicked and closed&amp;rdquo; using screens in InVision:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="&amp;quot;you are here&amp;quot; popup" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/iryq4hah16np3ip/Screenshot%202017-06-19%2009.45.05.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a mechanism for constructing a professional looking interactive infographic, and it was now just a question of putting the rest together.  Michael and Matt had selected text and images for the other popups.  I called it a day and promised to complete the work with illustrator the following morning.  Lokesh also did some great follow up work in Wix, making it look like we could make a pretty professional looking website there quicky - good to know for a future design sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned at the start, later in the evening I was on Slack hearing about the trouble recruiting testers and I drifted off thinking I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have such a rushed day on Friday &amp;hellip; how wrong I was.  Stay tuned to this blog for more about how it all went down on Friday :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rnyzabQkoAQ"&gt;Day four Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Design Sprint Day Three</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/15/av-design-sprint-day-three/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/15/av-design-sprint-day-three/</id>
    <published>2017-06-15T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-11T21:38:01+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Thursday and I&amp;rsquo;m looking back at day three of our design sprint that we did on Wednesday.  I think all of our energy was down after having done two full days in a single hangout.  I&amp;rsquo;d been out in the morning to attend an NHS meeting and I think that was pushing it.  Hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll all have got a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep last night and be somewhat refreshed for day four.  But so what did we actually do in day three?  We started by taking a look at the four different prototypes that we had designed independently on day two.  We did heat map stickers to highlight aspects of the designs we liked, and then Matt nominated me to talk through each in speed critique mode while he took notes on the standout ideas:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1. Journey to Agile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;first image&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Journey to Agile first image" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/inga2yiyziy6a4v/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.19.33.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* You are Here 
* Benefits hilight list
* Job Seeking Network
* Scrum Bridge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;second image&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="How long does it take" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/8fc33tpapiec120/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.21.36.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* Start the journey (clickable)
* The AV journey (graph showing faster progress)
* Premium benefits indicated on graph (graph goes faster)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2. Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First image&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/nwgr50a8fudg61m/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.22.50.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* Badges/Milestones
* Profile rating (ambiguous)
* Project rating&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second Image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ek4ctr1uzjlvf58/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.23.54.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* Link to verified Certificate
* Certificate details right on certificate (appeals to companies) = Value to customer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third Image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/n8vv8wbgohxjruv/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.24.38.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* Project performance 
* Most influential contributor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3. Seeker on the Path&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/nsf052ds1usaqg3/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.25.57.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* Video Pitch (maybe put on top)
* Different Paths (depending on …)
* Guided Navigation with SubTasks
* List of Projects
* Badges/Certificates on the Path&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4. Guided Interactive Map&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/hk6o0hjcti7s7k5/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.28.14.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standout Ideas:
* Diagram (clickable) perhaps cold lacking motivation, needs video(?)
* Description of value
* Time per week, updates map focus
* Popup of values
* Value proposition
* Multi-select of tech&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was relatively straightforward to allow us to put heat map stickers in the Google doc once all the images had been added to drawings where we could overlay dots.   Here&amp;rsquo;s the full sequence we were following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Art museum. Tape the solution sketches to the wall in one long row.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat map. Have each person review the sketches silently and put one to three small dot stickers beside every part he or she likes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speed critique. Three minutes per sketch. As a group, discuss the highlights of each solution. Capture standout ideas and important objections. At the end, ask the sketcher if the group missed anything. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Straw poll. Each person silently chooses a favorite idea. All at once, each person places one large dot sticker to register his or her (nonbinding) vote.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supervote. Give the Decider three large dot stickers and write her initials on the sticker. Explain that you’ll prototype and test the solutions the Decider chooses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above images you can also see some of the straw poll votes.  We were divided pretty evenly between the first and third. That&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Journey to Agile&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Seeker on the Path&amp;rdquo;.  So there was a decision to make, go with one or the other, or combine them in some fashion.  After some debate we narrowed it down to the following options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rumble (building two prototypes and two fake brand names)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge where click through on Agile Journey has pathways (multiple steps) (single prototype)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge where Seeker on the path has video or infographic of Agile Journey (single prototype)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just do Agile Journey (single prototype) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just do Seeker on path (single protoype)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took another poll on this, but as the decider the final decision was up to me.  We had votes for items 1 and 2, but I thought with a sprint team of four we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the resources to make two prototypes, and I thought that we needed a single clear idea to make most effective use of the time and energy we were putting in.  In the background Federico was sorting out the advert for testers, the screening form, and getting the ads up onto craigslist around the world.  This was outstandingly helpful as I think our whole sprint team was exhausted and the logistics of managing the testers just seemed beyond us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federico joined the hangout on a couple of occasions to get input and decisions.  We decided to go for remote usability testing, and the full $100 Amazon gift card as compensation.  That&amp;rsquo;s $500 which is a lot of money for our non-profit charity, but I thought we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t skimp here and that we should be trying to get outside, unbiased input on the AgileVentures concept that we were trying to get across.  Our sprint focus was on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure that developers understand how they will benefit from AgileVentures (before looking for projects)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having made the decision, we moved on to making a storyboard to help structure the prototype we would build on Thursday.  I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed my computer getting slower and slower as these long hangouts run on with multiple large google doc windows open.  I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to quitting Slack and having that on another machine (if I need it) and even after a Chrome restart yesterday it was tough going trying to make the storyboard in a Google doc.  We got as far as this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/qoukd7h052vpko0/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.41.16.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;before I gave up, rebooted Chrome and started sketching on paper.  My memory is that shared editing of the Google drawing on day one had been a pretty efficient group operation.   I hadn&amp;rsquo;t rebooted my computer since then and I think we were all mentally flagging.  As the computer starts to lag it becomes increasingly frustrating.  I thought that, based on the concept we were working on, the storyboard was pretty straightforward.  I uploaded what I had drawn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ay5i33jehioui5m/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.44.23.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either others were reasonably happy with it, or too tired to argue.  Matt said there weren&amp;rsquo;t many &amp;ldquo;call to actions&amp;rdquo; and I pointed out the four &amp;ldquo;Learn More&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Sign me up&amp;rdquo; buttons.  I started pushing to say that we should do a little work on what goes into the map, so we moved the diagram into a fresh location and I went round each person asking if there were items they wanted to add or remove:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ukgpl9zhv6bewm6/Screenshot%202017-06-15%2009.45.34.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and wrote up this list of tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding Themed clipart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What goes in the map (ordering)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making individual subtopic info sites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does info popup (scroll, new page, popup)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keynote vs Invision vs Middleman?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt was telling us he was getting to the point that he could only do simple tasks.  I thought I might be able to write up some subtopic text, at least if I did it locally in Keynote.  We spent twenty minutes more with me going to each person and trying to ask what they would like to work on the list.  Maybe that was the wrong way to go.  It felt like we were moving in treacle.  Michael was talking through what each task involved.  I think there was confusion about whether we could work on things in parallel.  Ultimately Matt left, Lokesh started working on finding themed clipart, which Michael was doing in parallel.  I started on a Keynote with subtopics, but got distracted searching for clipart.  The remaining time was spent looking at Shutterstock and other images like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/623cie39vefg6p9/stock-vector-mountain-hiking-infographic-template-design-in-flat-style-386934532.jpg?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think any of us thought much of our artistic skills so the idea of having a pre-designed map showing a journey that we could put our own text into seemed pretty appealing.  The question was whether we had the software to edit the EPS files.  I played around with Sketch and Inkscape but ultimately made more progress downloading a free trial of illustrator.  Then we called it a day.  Now it&amp;rsquo;s Thursday and the Friday tests are looming.  Big day today to turn actually create our interactive infographic so that we can learn as much as possible from our randomly selected testers on Friday.  Stay tuned to this blog to find out how it all goes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/0TKPezdmui0"&gt;Day Three Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Design Sprint Day Two</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/06/14/av-design-sprint-day-two/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/06/14/av-design-sprint-day-two/</id>
    <published>2017-06-14T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-08T20:23:35+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="design sprint" src="/images/design_sprint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Squeezing in too much? Me? I&amp;rsquo;m just on the train coming back from a NorthWest London CCG meeting, where I had been invited to present the HLP Social Prescribing and Self Care wiki.  It was an all morning meeting and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stay for the second half as I had to get back to my home office for day three of the design sprint.  It could have been useful to stay for the second half of the meeting where they were going to be talking about a digital health app, and giving me the chance to network with people after the meeting, but I&amp;rsquo;m committed to completing this design sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a face to face design sprint there&amp;rsquo;d be no time for me to squeeze in additional meetings (I&amp;rsquo;ve scheduled a Trustee meeting for Friday morning as well), but because we are running the meetings noon-6pm so that the East coast participants can join, there is in principle time, but whether it&amp;rsquo;s sensible is another question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back at day 2 we fairly quickly polished off the remaining agenda items that were left out on Monday afternoon due to our plethora of expert interviews.  Tuesday started with further organising of our &amp;ldquo;how might we&amp;rdquo; notes and voting on them.  At the end of that process the board looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="HMW notes voted on" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/0e4c2nc3lw39zah/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.04.39.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bit of negotiation we had four notes with at least 2 votes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ensure that developers understand how they will benefit from AgileVentures (before looking for projects)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get sustaining revenue?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better activate new signups into active community members?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make it clearer what project opportunities exist in terms of languages/frameworks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We added those to the appropriate places on our map, and as the decider I chose what the focus would be for the remainder of the sprint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="map with HMW notes added" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/lniu3rnvs2vgexw/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.07.36.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose &amp;ldquo;ensure that developers understand how they will benefit from AgileVentures (before looking for projects)&amp;rdquo; at least partly swayed by what Michael said that if you can&amp;rsquo;t get people in the door then it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to build anything further.  After a quick break we went into a series of lightning demos.  Here&amp;rsquo;s what we each showed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sam&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.headspace.com/"&gt;Headspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=502ILHjX9EE"&gt;Agile Product Ownership Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://freecodecamp.com/"&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=eisenhower+matrix"&gt;Priority Matrix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lokesh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showcase achievements(Github)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel prideful and helpful (StackOverflow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promote we are for good cause (https://campus.mozilla.community/)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michael&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon Prime Benefits Sell Page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile Ventures Signup Page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we doodled design components while each other presented, which either went on paper or into our shared Google doc.  When we finished presenting to each other we spent some more time trying to write up the components. Here are some:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="components" src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ifohrjqhs3vso6m/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.12.26.png?dl=1" /&gt;
&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/v9j18l28ahvmwwp/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.12.45.png?dl=1" /&gt;
&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/f8o39mvquwu61xo/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.13.01.png?dl=1" /&gt;
&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/m1ym4qygf8h1f99/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.13.15.png?dl=1" /&gt;
&lt;img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/wrmdjrusjfxuypx/Screenshot%202017-06-14%2011.13.26.png?dl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we moved on to the group (but alone) interface/storyboard sketching activity where we each worked on making notes, doodling more components, crazy 8 doodle variation generation with time constraints, and then finally a big chunk designing an interface/storyboard.  We were all in the hangout coming and going.  There was nothing much happening for the outside viewer as we were all trying to avoid showing what we were working on to each other.  Some of us were sketching on paper, and we had a debate about whether the final versions should all be in google doc format, or just scans from the paper, and ultimately I proposed that everyone should just use whatever medium allowed them to work most efficiently and we would worry later about anonymity of design.  At the end of the day we had four different storyboard prototypes that we put on the shelf to review in day three!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/mvv2GPivSGo"&gt;Day Two Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
