<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Balance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/06/balance/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/06/balance/</id>
    <published>2017-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-28T22:05:58+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="balance" src="/images/balance.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any Premium pairing this Sunday, and my twin boys&amp;rsquo; football match was rained off, so I had a relatively calm day, staying completely off Slack and Email.  I collapsed after lunch and slept for three hours - catching up lost sleep from the week where I&amp;rsquo;d been up in the night a few times.  The last couple of weeks haven&amp;rsquo;t been great sleep-wise.  A sudden alertness at 4am and then an inability to get back to sleep without listening to an hour of audio comedy.  Not that I don&amp;rsquo;t try just relaxing back into sleep, but after an hour of the same work and relationship thoughts going round in my head I get sick of it, and find audio comedy is a reasonably pleasant way of changing my internal dialogue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do end up feeling a bit of a failure when Steve Hagen and Eckhart Tolle say that there&amp;rsquo;s a simple step to enlightenment or awakeness available in every moment, and that we&amp;rsquo;re all supposed to be equipped to realise it. I had lots of moments of awareness/self-observation over the weekend, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t stop me from blowing up in a rage at my kids on two or three occasions.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got to balance that against the points when I didn&amp;rsquo;t blow up in a rage, or didn&amp;rsquo;t resist the moment and wrestle it forcefully into something that it currently wasn&amp;rsquo;t.  It&amp;rsquo;s funny, but I see an analogy with the Empire Strikes Back where Yoda tells Luke that he shouldn&amp;rsquo;t go off to help his friends (Han and Leia), because by turning aside from his main task he&amp;rsquo;ll threaten what they fight for.  Ironically Luke rushes to save his friends, but they save themselves and he isn&amp;rsquo;t the one who effects their escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved Star Wars growing up, but with the subsequent movies and a jaundiced adult eye it all seems rather trite and very militaristic; sort of glorifying a sanitised violence where no one actually bleeds.  Still I can&amp;rsquo;t help but notice that when I try to resist my children&amp;rsquo;s moods directly; when I try to prevent one from screaming their displeasure at another, that I seem to make the situation worse and not better.  Far more effective recently is not to resist their upset.  Naturally I still physically intervene if it&amp;rsquo;s actually coming to blows; but what I&amp;rsquo;m reducing is my protestations of &amp;ldquo;of course if you scream at him he&amp;rsquo;s not going to let you have it&amp;rdquo;, and so the reactions that I would get to those statements, e.g. &amp;ldquo;well he&amp;rsquo;s being rude to me and has made me upset!!&amp;rdquo; don&amp;rsquo;t fly back at me.  If I try to control my kids behaviours too strongly what I get is lots of justifications from each child about why their own bad behaviour is inevitable as a result of the poor behaviour of other parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly a lot of adult conversations can go the same way, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been guilty in the past of making justification after justification, when I&amp;rsquo;m starting to realise that &amp;ldquo;defending your corner&amp;rdquo;, so to speak, has a tendency to provoke additional attack.  I still have huge trouble with statements I disagree with.  I really find it difficult not to respond to them.  I feel like not responding is somehow tacit agreement.  That letting a statement stand unopposed is tantamount to conceding that it is the truth.   That&amp;rsquo;s just my perception - is there any truth in it?  Do other people think that the last unopposed statement reflects the group concensus? I&amp;rsquo;d be interested to know &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday we had various meetings, and what I&amp;rsquo;m grudgingly realising more and more is that my tendency to challenge statements I disagree with can make for longer and longer meetings.  I think I actually did a better job than usual.  I stayed in the moment in one meeting, frustrated that someone had said something that contradicted my own assertion, but realising to confront it would be to drag out part of the meeting, when I was judging that actually it was more important to move on to other things.  Who knows if that was the right decision?  Like the foolish(?) neighbour who keeps congratulating the wise(?) farmer in the Zen riddle, when does the story ever end?  When do we find out the true extent of all the consequences of every decision?  Never?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the most important thing is not being taken over by the &amp;ldquo;unconscious&amp;rdquo; reaction to any situation?  Let the situation be; give yourself time to observe your internal mental state and then allow a &amp;ldquo;conscious&amp;rdquo; reaction to emerge?  Will that allow things to get better?  Let&amp;rsquo;s not attach ourselves to outcomes.  Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on being conscious in the current moment.  Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s the way to achieve true balance &amp;hellip; but then life&amp;rsquo;s such a complex puzzle, could managing it really be that simple?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=drjxg5Gc_tQ"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3OZx8NrT2FA"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum and WSO Kick Off&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8tY4Tvew9Xs"&gt;BetaSaaSers AutoGraders meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bids and Coding Zen</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/03/bids-and-coding-zen/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/03/bids-and-coding-zen/</id>
    <published>2017-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-27T21:58:09+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="zen stones" src="/images/zen.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I got disenchanted with academia was the process of writing grant applications for research funds.  It seemed to involve a huge amount of work to describe the work you would do if someone gave you some money.  There&amp;rsquo;d be several weeks&amp;rsquo; work writing a 10 or 20 page document followed by an all-nighter to get it all together for the deadline and then submit through some complex web interface.  Then wait six months to get three or four paragraphs of feedback about why the proposal hadn&amp;rsquo;t been accepted.  While some people in academia were successful recipients of government grants, I was much more successful in bringing in industry money where I could talk to someone face to face.  The problem with industry grants is that they would dry up when the market turned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, fast forward to my current focus on charities and freelancing.  It&amp;rsquo;s grant writing all over again, although the turn-around time is a bit faster.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been receiving a lot of support from lovely people in the charity sector regarding fund-raising, but I seem to be back in this situation of asking for money and getting turned down for one reason or another.  I wonder if the problem is that I&amp;rsquo;m always hedging my bets.  Being completely unable to quantify the chances of receiving a grant, it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to work out how much effort to put into the application process.  I just went through one where the person guiding me was saying we were pretty much guaranteed to get the contract, just to be phoned late last night and told that another bidder had unexpectedly been able to come in and offer an existing solution and point to a much stronger background in the area the grant was focused on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward I&amp;rsquo;ll have to make it clear that phoning me late at night is not on.  I&amp;rsquo;m involved in a couple of other bids for freelance work at the moment.  All of them difficult to quantify in terms of how much money they&amp;rsquo;ll bring in and the likelihood of actually landing them.  I&amp;rsquo;ll give it till April and then I&amp;rsquo;ll have to put the search for income into a higher gear &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that speculative bidding process juxtaposes with moments of coding zen I&amp;rsquo;ve felt this week.  I was tidying up the three WSO PRs I made this week while my twin boys were doing their Karate class, and starting to add comments about issues I was seeing.  I managed to pull some logic out of a view into a helper, so that the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight erb"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;event_name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_user&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'name'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Want to learn more? Listen in. Next projects review meeting '&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;became&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;event_name_or_invitation_to_guest_user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_user&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'name'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Want to learn more? Listen in. Next projects review meeting '&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in &lt;code&gt;layout_helper&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;making the original erb become:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight erb"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;link_to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;event_name_or_invitation_to_guest_user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;event_path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'id'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;])&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which I think is an improvement.  I think the intent is conveyed a little more succinctly now, although I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that LayoutHelper is necessarily the best place for the code, but one thing at a time.  Getting that in place and adding a few &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/pull/1566"&gt;inline comments on my own PR&lt;/a&gt; I experienced a moment of coding zen.  My concerns about a couple of places in the code were addressed with changes, and I was recording other concerns.  Next step&amp;ndash;refactoring tickets.  The Zen feeling came from a brief sensation of wholeness - that it was okay for the code to have issues, but that we have a mechanism for addressing those issues over time.  Now if only there was some way to achieve a similar Zen state as regards funding applications :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XbbTJQYNMeQ"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fsHiZG2_UjQ"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Distracted</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/02/distracted/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/02/distracted/</id>
    <published>2017-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-23T21:05:28+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="distracted" src="/images/distracted.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after taking a full week away from Slack and Email I managed to start work again without too much obsessive checking of Slack and Email on my phone.  At least for the last ten days I&amp;rsquo;m not checking it when I first wake up and, instead, leaving it till after my morning blog.  I&amp;rsquo;m pretty much avoiding looking at it during the evenings, although I tend to have a last Slack check around 9:30pm when I post my blog.  Pretty good for a week and a half, but last night I ended up looking at my email while my eldest was reading to me, and then this morning I ended up looking at it while I was getting dressed, as I tried to send myself a reminder email.  There wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything urgent to deal with, but in both cases I did manage to load chunks of work worry into my mind.  And then just now I seem to have reviewed all my Email and Slack before getting down to the blog.  There wasn&amp;rsquo;t so much to deal with, but I feel a little unsettled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I need to move the Slack and Email icons on my phone deeper into a nested directory and make sure that I shut down Slack and Email when I finish on my laptop each day, so that I don&amp;rsquo;t accidentally look at them before blogging.  My tweet/slacking of the podcast I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to in the morning interferes with that.  I guess I should get into the habit of tweeting and then re-posting that to Slack after the morning blog is completed.  Not that I&amp;rsquo;m sure that I&amp;rsquo;m achieving much with the blogging.  It may be an interesting historical record to look back on for me.  Not sure about anyone else :-)   I continue to post out older blogs on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@tansakuu"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.  My blogs from last October were much more coding focused, and my rambling blogs don&amp;rsquo;t compare favourably (in my mind) with the ultra-focused &amp;ldquo;learn this!&amp;rdquo; blogs that others stamp out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s March and I committed to myself to keep daily blogging to June and I like to stick to my commitments.  I am getting a bit of coding done this week, following the WebSiteOne kick off with Michael and Raoul last Friday.  I&amp;rsquo;ve got three pull-requests open, one for each of the three tickets I committed to working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/pull/1564"&gt;spikes some example tooltips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/pull/1566"&gt;less intimidating invitations to scrums for non-logged in users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/pull/1568"&gt;adjust intial messaging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re all relatively simple view changes.  Most of the work so far has been fixing failing regression tests (i.e. other tests that were relying on the view looking a certain way).  Some of it is a bit spikey.  I&amp;rsquo;ve created acceptance tests in Cucumber for the last two, and the middle one above has some logic in the view that I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to pull out.  The blog from early Feb that I was reviewing last night also spiked something with a fair amount of code in the view.  Early February I was focused on getting the escalating call to action out, in the hope that it might impact the number of people upgrading to Premium plans, but as far as I can see it&amp;rsquo;s had no impact.  We&amp;rsquo;ve had a new Premium Mob member join, but I think that&amp;rsquo;s come entirely through Slack interaction.  Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a value in the long run with the name of the next upgrade being repeated to folks whenever they are coming to the site, but then again we&amp;rsquo;re not really tracking how often the different types of member view the home page &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just created a &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1569"&gt;refactoring ticket&lt;/a&gt; to pull code out of the &amp;ldquo;escalating call to action&amp;rdquo; view.  I&amp;rsquo;ve heard Armando say &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t put code in your views&amp;rdquo; umpteen times as I&amp;rsquo;ve re-viewed the MOOC videos. Clearly coding in ERB isn&amp;rsquo;t pretty - moving the code into a helper would reduce the number of symbols to look at.  It could go in a presenter, or be refactored into a model.  The code in the current feature I&amp;rsquo;m working on is less heinous.  That&amp;rsquo;s just the addition of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight erb"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;event_name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_user&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'name'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Want to learn more? Listen in. Next projects review meeting '&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m experimenting with the look and feel of the site, I find it easier just to be focusing on a single file.  The code in the escalating call for action view is more heinous:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight erb"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_user&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;membership_type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Basic'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;new_subscription_path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Upgrade to Premium for additional support'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;elsif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;current_user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;membership_type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Premium'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;new_subscription_path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;plan: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'premiummob'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Upgrade to Premium Mob for group sessions with a Mentor'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;new_user_registration_path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Get started now to begin coding!'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to pull the logic from either into the controller.  The code could be going into the Event or User models, but that feels like overloading them.  What we have here is sort of business logic about how we communicate with the different types of user.  Would it help to get the strings into the I18n setup so that we can refer to them via a constant string, the meaning of which can be looked up in a text file?  Or is that getting distracted from the business logic experiments we are trying to carry out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is refactoring these things for code cleanliness pulling time that could be spent on measuring their impact more accurately?  My temptation is to deploy the new language and see if the Scrum masters conclude that more new folks are coming into online hangouts.  That&amp;rsquo;s effectively what I&amp;rsquo;ve done for the &amp;ldquo;escalating call to action&amp;rdquo;.  I&amp;rsquo;m set up to be alerted whenever anyone signs up for a Premium plan and I&amp;rsquo;m in regular contact with all the Scrum masters.  Setting up extra code for measurement seems excessive at this stage.  I&amp;rsquo;m confused; what&amp;rsquo;s the distraction and what&amp;rsquo;s the focus? :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad we had this chat though - I&amp;rsquo;m thinking a presenter object is the way to go and that it might make the business logic clearer for the point when we want to focus on that without being distracted :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1nWmG1f529c"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=29Y3Chv8WjE"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Commmunication and Coding</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/03/01/communication-and-coding/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/03/01/communication-and-coding/</id>
    <published>2017-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-22T22:23:33+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="feedback" src="/images/feedback.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I got some great feedback from FutureLearn after I&amp;rsquo;d followed up to say how much I enjoyed their technical test and interview process (which included discussion and pair programming).  Here&amp;rsquo;s what they said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again for coming in — I’m glad you enjoyed the process.  We really liked your technical skills, initiative and enthusiasm. You obviously have a lot of programming and agile experience, and have a lot to offer the team in terms of coaching, mentoring and supporting other developers. Ultimately we didn’t make you an offer because we had concerns about your communication skills. Your interviewers sometimes found it difficult to follow the conversation and get direct answers to the questions they asked; there was a general sense that your answers were sometimes circuitous or unclear, and that you didn’t express very much curiosity about what exactly the job would entail or what working at FutureLearn more generally would be like. In the end it was a very difficult decision given your high level of technical skill, but overall we felt it was unlikely to work out given the difficulties that your interviewers had in communicating comfortably with you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to which I responded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for coming back to me - that&amp;rsquo;s wonderful feedback, and I really appreciate you sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It gives me great food for thought, and I think the concern about communication is a valid one.  It&amp;rsquo;s something I definitely need to work on.  I tend to think out loud, and so going forward I&amp;rsquo;m going to try some experiments with different layers of filtering on how I respond to questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As regards curiousity for what the job would entail and what working at FutureLearn would be like, I thought I was getting a really clear idea from the interview process itself.  Having taken courses on FutureLearn in the past, as well as having developed software and courses for edX as well as serving as a community manager for groups of edX instructors, everything I was hearing in the interview process gelled with how I imagined things would be, but it sounds like I could have worked harder to confirm my impressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way I can certainly understand how a perceived lack of curiosity would impact your decision.  Thanks again for taking the time to interview me and sorry it didn&amp;rsquo;t work out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best of luck with everything at FutureLearn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I was disappointed not to have been made an offer, particularly since it would have helped address some of the financial concerns I have at the moment, and it would have been exciting to explore the codebase of the FutureLearn MOOC platform.  That said, I really am extraordinarily grateful for the extra feedback from FutureLearn.  In the absence of those specifics I might have imagined that the code that I wrote as part of the technical test, or something about my pair programming style might have been at fault.  However the concern about my communication skills in the technical interview fits in rather well with feedback and comments that I&amp;rsquo;ve got from other quarters.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting question now is how to go about leveling up my communication skills. It sounds like it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hurt to try a period where I spent additional time constructing answers before starting to speak.  It&amp;rsquo;s funny, there are so many online resources to help one learn to code, but level up your communication skills?  Well I googled for &amp;ldquo;improve your communication skills&amp;rdquo; and Google immediately highlighted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;5 Ways to Improve Your Communication Skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Never talk over people&lt;br&gt;
2) Don&amp;rsquo;t finish other people&amp;rsquo;s sentences&lt;br&gt;
3) Paraphrase&lt;br&gt;
4) Listen actively&lt;br&gt;
5) Maintain eye contact  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;from &lt;a href="www.lifehack.org/articles/communication/improve-communication-skills.html"&gt;www.lifehack.org/articles/communication/improve-communication-skills.html&lt;/a&gt; which is fairly clear.  Maybe not too hard then :-)  Stay tuned to this blog to hear about the results of my attempt to level up my communication skills &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Commitment</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/02/27/commitment/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/02/27/commitment/</id>
    <published>2017-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-21T21:41:52+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="commitment sign" src="/images/commitment.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Urgh, another mild cold :-( but a productive few days.  We had our new style WebSiteOne kick-off meeting on Friday following Michael&amp;rsquo;s suggestion that we re-start the meetings, but that we each bring up to three tickets that we care about; rather than just working through whichever tickets are in the backlog.  This approach came out of discussions around the AgileBookClub podcast, with an emphasis on focusing on the &amp;ldquo;business&amp;rdquo; value associated with each ticket.  I chose the following tickets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1530"&gt;Add tooltips for &amp;ldquo;upgrade to mob&amp;rdquo; to explain and/or add info buttons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1555"&gt;Adjust initial messaging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1554"&gt;Adjusting how &amp;ldquo;next scrum&amp;rdquo; is displayed to new users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;while Michael chose the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1560"&gt;Change call to action button verbiage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1487"&gt;Alternatives to google hangouts for pairing and scrums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/WebsiteOne/issues/1523"&gt;Convert Sign up links into big, orange buttons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and we worked through each, writing new user-stories informed by our recent AgileBookClub podcast discussions.  Here are Michael&amp;rsquo;s tickets and the user stories we added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Convert Sign up links into big, orange buttons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;As an AgileVentures Admin
So that more people ultimately sign up for paid plans
I would like prominent buttons for sign up on the plan description pages
Whereas currently they are simply hyperlinks
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Alternatives to google hangouts for pairing and scrums&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;As AgileVentures Admin
So that we can analyze usage patterns and reflect teleconference participation in member profiles
I would like some mechanism of tracking teleconference participation 
Instead of the Google Hangouts API which is being removed in April

As AgileVentures Scrum master
So that I don't have to manually copy and paste teleconference details into other media
I would like some mechanism to alert potential participants that a teleconference is taking place (hangout and video stream)
Instead of the Google Hangouts API which is being removed in April
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Change call to action button verbiage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;As an AgileVentures Admin
So that as many people as possible click through and sign up for membership and subscriptions
I want consistent and simple messaging on buttons (e.g. get started) that lead them to sign up/subscription pages
Instead of the current variation in messaging
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also voted on the tickets using Arreche&amp;rsquo;s new AsyncVoter system which worked really well, and we were very pleased to have Raoul join us.  We got through the 6 tickets in good time, and most of them, with the exception of the hangout API one, were one point stories.  Following what I had been hearing from Pat and his running of the WikiEduDashboard scrum/sprint I committed to completing my three tickets before another meeting the following Friday.  Michael committed to doing one of his, and I asked if he could investigate &lt;a href="https://github.com/AgileVentures/av-static-website/issues/206"&gt;another ticket&lt;/a&gt; related to the static site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d been reading about the importance of these kind of commitments in Agile as part of research for a chapter on a book I&amp;rsquo;m writing on Agile methods in Open Source development.  According to Wikipedia, the Scrum methodology includes &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrum_(software_development)#Values"&gt;five values&lt;/a&gt; which include &amp;ldquo;Commitment&amp;rdquo;, specifically that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team members individually commit to achieving their team goals, each and every Sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last year I&amp;rsquo;ve been gradually sliding away from any formal sprint cycle on the projects I&amp;rsquo;m managing, as I get dispirited and demotivated by the difficulties I&amp;rsquo;ve faced trying to arrange regular meetings at times that everyone can attend.  I was also getting the sense that folks were not enthusiastic about such meetings, and so it&amp;rsquo;s kind of a breakthrough with Michael to discover that the problem was not necessarily the presence of a meeting, per se, but the structure of that meeting.  Michael&amp;rsquo;s enthusiasm for the new structure is helping me feel more motivated for sprint cycle meetings.  I asked Michael at the end of the meeting on Friday if things had gone as he had hoped, if the discussion had been at the right level and he said yes, and so hopefully we can continue this format next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny - I&amp;rsquo;m just really happy to keep bashing away at tickets - happy with little structure, but I do notice that without a commitment to getting particular things done, all my different admin tasks can trump development work.  Maybe I do need a little more structure and commitment &amp;hellip; although trying to get people to make committments to doing things makes me feel strange.  In some ways I would rather they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t commit and then either or do, or not do.  In the absence of any committment there is no disappointment :-) Then again maybe making small structured committments is a framework and more folks will feel positive in the long run?  We&amp;rsquo;ll see :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/-MeZJ3-Vy6o"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; Scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2lXoxNzX2Cw"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; Scrum and Kickoff meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Not Much Programming</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/02/24/not-much-programming/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/02/24/not-much-programming/</id>
    <published>2017-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-21T21:35:42+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="typing at keyboard" src="/images/coding.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I review and publish blogs from several months ago to medium, it&amp;rsquo;s clear I&amp;rsquo;m doing a lot less programming than I was.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing more charity admin and, I guess, &amp;ldquo;business development&amp;rdquo;.  I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped pair programming regularly with Michael at least partly so that I can easily switch tasks through the day, but it is meaning that I won&amp;rsquo;t do a big chunk of coding unless I really clear space for it.  I am still reviewing a lot of code, looking at a lot of pull-requests, tech-tests, deploying code (devops?), running mob sessions and other bits and pieces.  I think the main things we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to achieve over the last year with the AgileVentures site is that it now looks better on mobile, the event creation process is more streamlined, and we have the Premium payment frameworks in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that&amp;rsquo;s reasonable progress, but it feels like we&amp;rsquo;ve plateaued in terms of income from Premium members, for the moment at least.  Official approval as a Charity has unlocked Google&amp;rsquo;s AdWords grant which has quadrupled traffic to our site, and is slowly pushing up our free members, but not leading directly to any increase in income so far.  We did land a small grant from the WikiMedia EDU group which is now paying for project management for the WikiEduDashboard project, which is a significant step forward in terms of sustainability, and that seemed to come almost directly from my appearing on the Ruby Rogues podcast.  We have corporate sponsorship from drie, but further collaboration with drie and the edX MOOC collaboration are both held up by negotiations between UCBerkeley and edX about technicalities related to the re-release of the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all my effort reaching out to potential sponsors online I&amp;rsquo;ve generated nothing concrete outside of introductions through friends.  Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s time to withdraw from all this online networking and focus on coding again?  The marketing team is looking like they are going to be perfectly capable of making great progress with just occasional input from me.  The first round of Premium signups came largely, I think, through me reaching out to people via email.  Alot of the upgrades have come through me reaching out to folks on Slack.  The things blocking the marketing team are coding and infrastructure issues, so me coding is probably going to be the thing that helps the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I&amp;rsquo;m also trying to write a book and start a podcast as long term &amp;ldquo;lead generation&amp;rdquo;, but I feel like it might be time for a coding binge &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Videos:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fV1JYPRXCiw"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Martin Fowler&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x14sVgrKeoc"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kent Beck&amp;rdquo; scrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
